< >
同日　午後　１時２１分
地方裁判所　被告人第１控え室
January 8, 1:21 PM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 1

<Maya>
‥‥いよいよ出てくるね、
ゼニトラ。
So we're finally going to see
The Tiger on the stand!

ここまで来たら、
あとヒトイキだよ！
We've almost got this case won
now, Nick.

<Phoenix>
だといいけど‥‥
I wish I could agree.

<Maya>
え‥‥？
Huh?

<Phoenix>
本土坊さんの、さっきの尋問‥‥
When I cross-examined
Mr. Armstrong just now...

たしかに“ゼニトラに命令された”
‥‥そう証言したけど‥‥
...he said he was just doing
what The Tiger told him to do.

ゴドー検事も、言ってただろ？
But Godot picked up on it,
remember?

証言が《真実》だったかどうか？
‥‥証拠はないんだよ。
He pointed out that without
proof, we don't know if what
he testified is the truth.

<Maya>
本土坊さんがウソを
ついてた、ってコト？
You mean, you think
Mr. Armstrong was lying?

<Phoenix>
検察側が、そう主張してきたら
ヤッカイなことになるだろうね。
I don't know. But if that's
the line the prosecution
takes, we could be in trouble.

（とにかく‥‥決定的な証拠が
　足りない気がする‥‥）
(I get the feeling that we
don't have the case-making
evidence we're going to need.)

< >
コラァッ！　アンタ！
Hey, pal!

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥イトノコさん‥‥
Detective Gumshoe!

<Maya>
なに、コーフンしてるんですか？
アタマ、逆立てちゃって。
What are you so jumpy about,
Detective!? Your hair's
standing on end!

<Gumshoe>
アンタこそ、ノンキにチョンマゲ
結ってる場合じゃないッス！
Hey, that's the pot calling
the kettle black, little
Ms. Topknot!

<Maya>
チョンマゲって言うな！
It's not a topknot!

<Phoenix>
と‥‥とにかく、落ちついて
くださいよ、イトノコ刑事！
Never mind about the hair!
Just calm down, alright?

<Gumshoe>
ううう‥‥ミョーに時間があいて、
じっとしてられないッス！
I-I-I can't stand still when I
don't have a job to do! I-I-I
kinda get wound up.

うほほおおおおおおおおおおおい！
Aaaaaaargh!

<Phoenix>
（うるさいな‥‥）
(No kidding!)

<Gumshoe>
‥‥ナニか！
ナニか、シゴトはないッスかッ！
You gotta have something
you need me to do, pal!
Anything!

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
Well, um...

<Gumshoe>
ちょっと、署まで
ひとっ走り、行ってくるッス！
Hey, I'm gonna take a jog back
down to the precinct.

１時間もあれば、指紋の
検査ぐらい、できるッスよ！
I could get some prints
analyzed for you if you've got
an hour!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥“１時間”って、審理が
　再開しちまうぞ‥‥！）
An hour!? The trial will have
reconvened by then!

<Maya>
でも。でも。ないんでしょ？
“決定的な証拠”が！
But, Nick! We still don't have
a really decisive piece of
evidence, right?

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥切りフダがなきゃ、
　戦えないな‥‥）
(True. Without some kind of
trump card to pull out of the
bag, we're really stuck...)

‥‥１時間あれば、
“指紋”の検査ができるんですね？
You said you could get some
fingerprint analysis done in
an hour?

<Gumshoe>
そッス！
You bet!

<Phoenix>
それなら‥‥この証拠品の
指紋、詳しく調べてもらえますか？
In that case, would you mind
checking the prints on this
for me?




<Maya>
ちょ、ちょっと待ってよ
なるほどくん！
What are you doing, Nick!?

せっかく指紋を調べるんなら、
こっちにしようよ！
If Detective Gumshoe's going
to check some prints for us,
shouldn't he be checking this?

<Gumshoe>
それは‥‥今朝、自分が
持ってきた小ビン、ッスな。
That's that small bottle I
gave back to you this morning,
right?

<Phoenix>
キッチンで拾った、
岡　高夫の耳のクスリ‥‥か。
The victim's ear medication
that we found in the kitchen?

<Maya>
《正体不明の指紋が付着》って
法廷記録に書いてあったし。
Look, it even says, "covered
in unidentified fingerprints"
right in the Court Record!

<Gumshoe>
そッスね！　ジツは
自分も気になっていたッス！
You're right! Actually, that's
been gnawing at me, too.

<Maya>
いっちょ、たのみますよ！
イトノコさん。
So you'll look into it for us?
Awesome!

<Phoenix>
あの。ぼくが見せた証拠品は‥‥？
Um, what about the thing I
asked you to run a check on?

<Gumshoe>
ああ。そっちも、ヒマがあったら
調べてみるッス！
Oh, that. Sure, I'll see what
I can do if I've got any spare
time.

<Phoenix>
（ひ、ヒマがあったら‥‥）
(Spare time...?
I feel so unimportant
right now...)


<Phoenix>
じゃ、せっかくですから、
コイツの指紋を調べてください。
If you're going back to the
station anyway, could you find
out whose prints are on this?

<Gumshoe>
それは‥‥今朝、自分が
持ってきた小ビン、ッスな。
Oh, hey. That's the small
bottle I gave back to you
this morning, right?

<Phoenix>
証拠品の中で“正体不明”なのは、
この指紋だけですからね。
Yeah. I think it's time we
solved the last mystery of who
the prints on it belong to.

<Gumshoe>
そッスね！　ジツは
自分も気になっていたッス！
Sure thing, pal! Actually,
that's been gnawing at me,
too!




< >
証拠品《小ビン》を
イトノコ刑事にあずけた。
Small Bottle given to
Detective Gumshoe.

<Gumshoe>
じゃッ！　自分はさっそく、
調査に行くッス！
OK, I'll get this off to the
lab right away.

自分が戻るまで、
負けちゃダメッスよ！
Just make sure you don't lose
the case before I get back!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥勝負は、
　いよいよ大詰めだな‥‥）
(This is pretty much the final
showdown, I guess...)

<Maya>
どっちがホンモノか‥‥
決着をつけてやろうね！
It's time to separate the
phonies from the real guys!




< >
同日　午後　１時５６分
地方裁判所　第４法廷
January 8, 1:56 PM
District Court
Courtroom No. 4

<Judge>
それでは、審理を再開します。
ゴドー検事。芝九蔵さんは‥‥？
Court will now reconvene.
Mr. Godot. Did you find this
Furio Tigre...?

<Godot>
‥‥捕獲してきた。コーヒー３杯の
安いシゴト‥‥だったぜ。
I even tamed him for you.
It was a 3 cup job.
No problem.

<Phoenix>
（ほ、ホカク‥‥？）
(T-Tamed him...? The guy's
name may be Furio Tigre,
but come on...)

<Godot>
‥‥やっこさん、そうとう
盛り上がってるからな。
He's pretty lively.

噛まれないよう、注意するコトだ。
Be careful...
He still bites.

<Judge>
それでは、芝九蔵　虎ノ助さんを
入廷させてください！
Very well. Please show
Mr. Tigre to the stand!

<Judge>
‥‥ええと、それでは証人。
名前と、職業を‥‥
...Um... Witness. Please state
your name and occupation
for th--

<Tigre>
おらあああぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁッ！
Grrraaaaaaaargh!

<Maya>
きゃきゃわわわはああああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、テーブルの下に
　かくれちまったぞ‥‥！）
(Don't hide under the table
Maya! ...Unless there is room
for me down there too!)

<Judge>
あ、あの‥‥。よよよよよ、
よろしいでしょうか‥‥
I, uh... Um...
W-W-W-Would you mind...?

<Tigre>
ンなんじゃいィィィィィッ！
What'youse say to me!?

<Judge>
ンなんでもないですゥゥゥゥゥッ！
N-N-N-Nothing!
I didn't say nuddin'!
Honest!

<Phoenix>
（なんだそりゃ！）
(Who could've guessed that
fear would induce a bad
Brooklyn accent in the judge?)

<Tigre>
ワイはこれから、ダイジな
取り引きに出るトコロやったんや！
I got business to take care
of, ya hear me?

ダレやァッ！　いったいダレが、
ワイを呼び出したんやぁぁっ！
So who the hell called me into
dis hole?

‥‥キサマかッ！
Was it you', spikey!?

<Phoenix>
え、ええと、それは‥‥
もちろん、裁判長‥‥
Ack, no. Of course not...
It was... the judge...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
さ、裁判長ッ！
...
Y-Your Honor!?

<Judge>
あ！　ちょっとボールペンを
落としてしまってですね‥‥
Oh, dear! I, um... I seem to
have dropped my pen. Where on
earth is it...?

私にかまわず、みなさんで
やってください！
Don't mind me! Just carry on
with the proceedings as
normal.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ‥‥）
(That's it. We're doomed.)

<Tigre>
ダレやァッ！　いったいダレが、
ワイを呼び出したんやぁぁっ！
Maybe youse didn't hear me!
I said, who the hell was it
dat called me in here!?

<Godot>
‥‥いくら叫んでもムダだぜ。
There's no need to shout.
We can all hear you.

<Tigre>
なんやてェ‥‥？
Whad'youse say?

<Godot>
アンタは、とらわれたのさ。
法廷という、オリの中に。
There's no point struggling.
You're caught in a snare. The
relentless snare of the law!

裁くのは、このオレだぜ！
And I'm the one that hauled
you in!

<Tigre>
‥‥ぐ‥‥ッ！
Grrr...

<Phoenix>
（か‥‥カッコイイ‥‥）
(T... Too cool...)

<Maya>
なるほどくん！　負けちゃダメ！
Don't let him get the better
of you, Nick!

<Godot>
‥‥最初にカクニンしておくぜ。
Let's start with the basics.

アンタ‥‥この事件について、
知ってるコトはあるかい？
You know about the incident
in question, correct?

<Tigre>
ハッ！　なんのことかサッパリや！
Incident!? I don't know
nuthin' about no stinkin'
incident, mask boy!

<Godot>
須々木　マコの前回の法廷に、
傍聴人として来たことは？
You mean you didn't attend the
previous trial of Maggey
Byrde?

<Tigre>
あらへんワ！　裁判見物するほど、
ヒマやないッ！
Maggey who!? I've got more
important things to do dan
watch courtroom dramas!

<Judge>
‥‥わかりました。では、
証言をおねがいできますかな。
Of course.
Well, perhaps you could give
us your testimony, then?

事件当日のコトについて。
Please tell us about what
you did on the day of the
murder.

<Tigre>
‥‥フン！
成歩堂　龍一ィ‥‥
...Hmph.
Phoenix Wright!

<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

<Tigre>
おおかた、キサマの
サシガネなんやろう？
Youse de one who set dis up,
didn't you'?

‥‥一生かかっても後悔しきれへん
ようにしたるでェ‥‥
Youse gonna regret the day
you ruffled The Tiger's fur.
You' hear what I'm sayin'?

<Phoenix>
うううう‥‥
（‥‥やっぱり、恐ェ！）
*gulp*
(Maybe I should've brought a
diaper with me today...)

<Maya>
なるほどくん！　しっかり！
Get a grip, Nick!

< >
～事件当日のアリバイ～
-- The Tiger's Alibi --

<Tigre>
殺人事件なんて言われても、
ワイはなんにも知らんでェ。
I don't know nothin'
about no murder.

去年の１２月は忙しくてなあ。
ずっと事務所におったからのぉ。
I was tied up with business in
December last year. Spent
all'a my time in my office.

カリヨーゼには毎日、カネを求めて
シャチョーさんが行列を作るんや！
I got whales lined up to
borrow cash from Tender
Lender every single day.

‥‥ワイのアリバイなら、
うらみちゃんが証明してくれるで！
Youse wanna check my alibi,
just ask Violetta.

<Judge>
いやいや。やっとボールペンが
見つかりました。
Ah, at last I found my pen.

それでは、弁護人。
尋問をおねがいします
Very well then, Mr. Wright.
Your cross-examination,
plea--

<Tigre>
うらああァァァァァァァァッ！
Aaaaaargh!

<Judge>
ななな、なんですか！
急に大きな声、出さないように！
Wh-What is it!? Please,
witness, if you could refrain
from shouting out like that.

<Tigre>
‥‥そこのニイちゃんのコトは、
よぉく知ってるでェ‥‥。
I know de kinda games dat
guy in the blue plays!

ちっちゃなコトをチクチクつつく
ことしかできない、ヨゴれ弁護士！
That lowlife ain't no lawyer!
He just punches away at stupid
details 'til he wins.

<Phoenix>
よ、ヨゴれ‥‥
L-Lowlife...? Me?

<Tigre>
ええかァ。事件に関係ないコトを
聞こうとしたら‥‥
Listen up, smarty! Every time
you' ask me some'ding dat
doesn't relate to dis case...

１回、５００万円！
ウチから借りてもらうでェ‥‥
...I'm gonna bill you 50,000
dollars! And youse gonna
borrow the cash from me!

<Phoenix>
え‥‥。
（借金の押し売りかよ！）
Uh...
(That's one loan contract
I refuse to sign!)

<Tigre>
‥‥ヒリつくような、タマの
取りあい、しようやないかィ！
And don't think it ain't gonna
hurt when you' get tangled
with The Tiger!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　おもしれえぜ。
‥‥見ているぶんには。
Ha...!
I love a good spectator sport.

<Judge>
ちょちょちょちょっと！
さすがにそれは‥‥
J-J-Just a minute!
That's really not...

<Godot>
‥‥この証人はなぁ。
This witness is...

いわば、都会のジャングルに
放たれた、ハラペコのトラ。
How can I put it? A hungry
tiger roaming the urban
jungle!

逆らうと‥‥そのジマンのアタマ、
噛まれちゃうぜ！
Get on his bad side, and he'll
bite everyone's heads off.
Yours, too!

<Judge>
しかたないですな。私のほうから、
ペナルティを与えましょう。
Very well. I have no choice
but to impose a penalty system
here.

<Tigre>
‥‥ワイはこれから、ダイジな
取り引きがあるんや。
Youse better be listening.
I said I got business to take
care of. Big business!

そろそろ、バスに
とび乗る時間やでェ‥‥
If I don't split now, I ain't
gonna catch my bus...

<Judge>
事件に関係のない《ゆさぶり》には
ペナルティを与えます。
The court will impose a
penalty for any irrelevant
pressing of witness testimony.

‥‥そのつもりで、
尋問をおねがいしましょう。
Keep that in mind as you begin
your cross-examination,
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
わ‥‥わかりました。
Y-Yes, Your Honor.

<Maya>
がんばれ！　なるほどくん！
You can do it, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥いいかげん、出てこいよ。
Come out from under there
already, would you, Maya?

< >
～事件当日のアリバイ～
-- The Tiger's Alibi --




<Tigre>
殺人事件なんて言われても、
ワイはなんにも知らんでェ。
I don't know nothin'
about no murder.


<Tigre>
去年の１２月は忙しくてなあ。
ずっと事務所におったからのぉ。
I was tied up with business in
December last year. Spent
all'a my time in my office.








<Tigre>
カリヨーゼには毎日、カネを求めて
シャチョーさんが行列を作るんや！
I got whales lined up to
borrow cash from Tender
Lender every single day.


<Tigre>
‥‥ワイのアリバイなら、
うらみちゃんが証明してくれるで！
Youse wanna check my alibi,
just ask Violetta.


<Maya>
関係ないところをゆさぶると、
もれなく５００万円もらえるんだ！
Just think! All you have to do
is press him on something
irrelevant, and bam! $50,000!

<Phoenix>
ば、バカ言え！　おこづかいで
返さなくちゃいけないんだぞ。
Get real, Maya! How about you
pay back the money then. Your
allowance should cover it!

<Maya>
ナニよそれ！
バカにしてるよ！
Hey! I'm no idiot, you know!

<Phoenix>
（５００万円もらうつもりでいる
　ほうが、バカにしてるぞ‥‥）
(Well, I'M certainly not the
one who thought the $50,000
was free money!)

‥‥できれば、ゆさぶらずに
スパッと決めたいな。
Anyway, I need to work this
guy without pressing his
testimony too hard.

<Maya>
でも‥‥ムジュンなんて
あるかなあ、この証言‥‥。
But his testimony is pretty
solid as it is...

<Phoenix>
（たしかに、アキラカな
　ムジュンは見あたらない）
(I admit nothing jumps out at
me as a contradiction.)

（とにかく、攻撃の突破口を
　作るしかないな‥‥！）
(But I've got to find an
opening somewhere...
Or I need to make one.)

<Tigre>






<Tigre>
事件当日もトーゼン、事務所や。
そんなワカゾウ、見たコトないワ！
The day youse talkin' about,
I was in de office, too. I
never saw that kid before.





<Phoenix>
吐麗美庵の事件を知らない‥‥
そんなハズはありません！
I don't buy that you haven't
even heard of the incident
that occurred at Trés Bien!

<Tigre>
ほっほお‥‥オモロイこと、
言うてくれるなァ‥‥。
Heh heh. Youse got a big
mouth, Wright!

ワイが、そのケチな事件に
関係しとる、言うつもりなら‥‥
Youse tryin' to say I was in
on some mob hit? Is dat what
you' tryin' to say?

ショーコ見せんかいコラァ！
Where's your proof, then!?

<Phoenix>
しょ‥‥証拠‥‥ですか。
Um... E-Evidence, yes...
Well...

<Tigre>
《法廷で発言力を持つのは
　証拠だけ‥‥》
"For an attorney to make
an accusation in court, he
must have evidence."

『入門シリーズ・弁護士になろう』
に、そう書いてあったでェ！
That's from "Loan Shark to
Lawyer: A Beginner's Guide",
yeah?

<Judge>
お！　証人。なかなか
ベンキョウ家ですなあ。
Ah! I see you're the studious
type, Mr. Tigre. Very good.

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　弁護をたのんだら
どうだ？　まるほどう‥‥
Ha...!
Why don't you ask him to
represent you sometime, Trite?

<Phoenix>
（くやしいな‥‥どうする？）
(Grrr... What should I do?)



<Phoenix>
‥‥証人ッ！
Mr. Tigre!

<Tigre>
なんじゃいィィィィッ！
Whad'youse want!?

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥。よろしかったら、
もう少し詳しく証言を‥‥
Err... If you wouldn't mind
going into a bit more
detail...

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥無用なゆさぶりは不要‥‥
ヤクソクだぜ、まるほどう！
This is a dead end, Trite, and
you know it. Remember the
rules!

<Judge>
証拠を持たないゆさぶりは
禁じているはずです。
Pressing the witness without
evidence to back up your
attack is prohibited.

‥‥ヤクソクどおり、
ペナルティを与えましょう。
As I said earlier, the court
will impose a penalty for such
behavior!

<Phoenix>
（やりにくいな‥‥）
(Ouch. The pain...)


<Phoenix>
（‥‥先の見えないゆさぶりは
　キケンだ‥‥）
(It's too dangerous to press
things without knowing where
they might end up.)

（今は、他の情報を見つけた
　ほうがいいな‥‥）
(I'd better just focus on
gathering information at the
moment...)




<Judge>
それでは、証人。
Now then, Mr. Tigre...

もう一度、最初から証言を
おねがいできますかな？
Would you mind repeating your
testimony from the beginning,
please?

<Tigre>
ワイの時間は高いんや。
わかっとるやろうなァ‥‥
My time ain't free, you' hear?
Youse betta remember dat!

バスに間に合わなかったら、
セキニン取ってもらうでェ‥‥
If I miss that bus, someone's
gonna pay!

<Phoenix>
うううう‥‥
Nngh...

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
１ヶ月前のコトですよ。
まちがいありませんか？
Are you sure about that?
We're talking about one month
ago, you know.

<Tigre>
ウチにはなァ。
スゴウデの秘書がいるんや。
You' see these teeth!? That's
how sharp my secretary is.

<Phoenix>
スゴウデ‥‥
（うらみさんのコトか‥‥）
Sharp...?
(Is he talking about
Viola Cadaverini?)

<Tigre>
ワイのスケジュール帳に、
しっかり書かれとったワ！
She writes everything in my
scheduler.

《１２月・おおむね事務所》
‥‥ってなァ！
"December: Mainly in the
office." That's what it says,
so that's where I was!

<Judge>
それは、なんというか‥‥
大ざっぱ、なのでは‥‥
That seems like a rather,
err... sketchy schedule...

<Tigre>
‥‥ギヌロ！
Gwwrrr...

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(There he goes again!
Hmm... What The Tiger did all
December isn't the issue...)

<Phoenix>
（‥‥問題は“事件が起こった日”
　なんだけど‥‥どうする？）
(What's important is what he
was doing on the day of the
murder... So, now what?)



<Phoenix>
‥‥証人ッ！
Mr. Tigre!

<Tigre>
なんじゃいィィィィッ！
Whad'youse want!?

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥。よろしかったら、
もう少し詳しく証言を‥‥
Err... If you wouldn't mind
going into a bit more
detail...

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥無用なゆさぶりは不要‥‥
ヤクソクだぜ、まるほどう！
This is a dead end, Trite, and
you know it. Remember the
rules!

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
しかし！　事件当日のアリバイは、
ハッキリさせるべきです！
No! It's essential that we
establish the witness's alibi
accurately.

<Judge>
‥‥私もそう思いますよ。
...I agree.

<Phoenix>
被害者が殺害された、１２月３日。
この日も、事務所に‥‥？
The victim was killed on
December 3rd. Were you in the
office that day, too?

<Tigre>
アタリマエやッ！
一歩も出てないでェ。
Maybe youse ain't listening.
Of course I was! I never set
foot outside.

事務所で、シャチョーさんの
相手をしとったんや。
I had meetin's all day with
a bunch of cats wantin' to
do business wid me.

そんなワカゾウ、知らんでェ！
I ain't never seen that young
kid before!

<Judge>
‥‥今の証言は、
さすがに重要ですな。
...I do believe the witness's
last statement was important.

あの‥‥ゴドー検事。
おねがいします‥‥
Um... Mr. Godot, if you could
please...

<Godot>
証人。‥‥今の発言を
証言につけ加えてくれ。
Mr. Tigre. The court asks you
to add that last statement to
your testimony.

<Tigre>
‥‥フン！
...Hmph!

<Phoenix>
（自分で言えよ、裁判長！）
(Don't let an animal beat you!
Be a man, Your Honor, and
ask him yourself!)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
そんなに客が来る
ものなんですか？　闇金融って。
So I take it you get a lot of
customers at your black
market loan office?

<Tigre>
今日び、小さな会社は
経営が苦しいからのお。
It's tough for de little guys
these days. Small businesses
are feelin' the pinch.

ワイは、そんなシャチョーたちの
あたたかい味方なんや。
Bosses of companies like that
wanna get in good with me. I'm
deir best friend.

<Judge>
ほうほう。
それはカンシンですなあ。
I see. That's very admirable
of you, witness.

<Tigre>
《三日坊主》‥‥それが、
カリヨーゼのモットーやからな！
Yeah, well, Tender Lender's
motto is "Win Through
Compromise" ya know.

<Judge>
みみ、三日坊主‥‥？
それは、どういうイミですかな？
"Win Through Compromise"?
What is that supposed to
mean?

<Tigre>
“つかまえた客は、３日で
　丸坊主にムシる”というコトや。
"Compromise the customer
to win." That's what it means.
Youse got it?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どこが
　“シャチョーの味方”だよ！）
(...With "best friends" like
you, who needs enemies!?)

<Tigre>
‥‥つまりッ！
Here, let me spell it out
for youse all!

そのニイちゃんのギザギザ
アタマも、あと３日したら‥‥
You' don't pay me back within
3 days, Spikey, I take what's
due, and you' stupid hair!

ああなる、言うコトやッ！
Youse follow what I'm saying!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼく、お客じゃ
ないんですけど‥‥。
Um... But I'm not one of your
customers...

（カリヨーゼのこと、
　もっと聞いてみるか‥‥？）
(Should I ask more about
Tender Lender or not?)



<Phoenix>
“うらみちゃん”というのは、
あの《鹿羽組》の‥‥
By "Violetta", you're talking
about the Cadaverini
family's...?

<Tigre>
せやで。コワいでェ、
あそこの組長さんは‥‥
Yeah. You' don't wanna cross
them, or youse gonna wind up
sleepin' with de fishes.

アンタがうらみちゃんを
疑ってると知ったら‥‥
Once the Godfather finds out
youse been draggin' Violetta
through the mud...

組長の‥‥‥に‥‥‥されるでェ。
...he'll... do you... in...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あの‥‥語尾がよく
聞こえなかったんですけど。
Sorry, I... I couldn't quite
put it all together towards
the end there...

<Maya>
ちょっと“うらみさん風”
だったね、今の。
He said that just like Viola,
didn't he?

<Phoenix>
（今は、彼女のことを聞く
　ときではない気がするけど‥‥）
(I get the feeling this might
not be the right time to probe
him about her...)



<Phoenix>
岡　高夫を知らない‥‥
本当ですか？
You didn't know Mr. Glen Elg?
Really?

<Tigre>
ワイの取り引き相手は
シャチョーさんだけや。
I don't mess with the guppies
when there are bigger fish
to fry.

‥‥アンタもどうや、
シャチョー！
Whaddya say, boss!?

<Judge>
え！　わ、私ですか！
Hmm? Who? Me!?

<Tigre>
ぽぉんと２０００万ぐらい、
つまんでおかへん？
Howse about I hit you with a
fat 200,000 dollars?

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。たしかに。
裁判長ともなれば、外車のひとつも
Hmm... Well, I was thinking
about purchasing a nice car
from Europe...

<Phoenix>
（考えこんでるよ‥‥）
(He's seriously considering
this!?)

<Maya>
ショーバイ上手だねえ、
ゼニトラさん。
Wow, The Tiger's a really good
salesman, huh?

<Phoenix>
こっちも、ショーバイ上手で
行かないとね。
Yeah. And if I want to sell
this case, I need to copy him!

<Maya>
ぽぉんと証拠品の１つも、
たたきつけておかへん？
How about you hit him with
a fat piece of evidence, boss?

<Phoenix>
（そんなカンタンに
　行けばいいけど‥‥）
(I wish it was that easy...)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
ゼニトラさん‥‥
Mr. Tigre...

あなたは“知らない”と
言っていますが‥‥
You claim you didn't know
Mr. Glen Elg.

岡　高夫さんのほうは、
あなたを知っていた。
But it appears that Mr. Elg
knew you.

<Tigre>
なんやてェ‥‥
What!?

<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんのカレンダーに、
メモが残っていたんです。
Mr. Elg left this little note
on his calendar.

《ゼニトラに会う》‥‥
日付は、１２月３日です。
"Meet with The Tiger"...
Dated, December 3rd.

<Judge>
じゅ、１２月３日‥‥
D-December 3rd!?

まさに‥‥
事件当日ではないですかッ！
That's... the day of the
murder!

<Phoenix>
ゼニトラさん！　あなたが
岡　高夫を知らないハズがない！
So, Mr. Tigre, I submit that
you did indeed know one
Mr. Glen Elg!

このとおり‥‥２人は
事件当日、会っているのですから！
Because on the very day of the
incident, you met with him!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Tigre>
ぐわあーッはッはッはッはッはァ！
Grrrah ha ha ha hah!

‥‥合格や、ニイちゃん！
Not bad!
Youse actually not bad.

<Phoenix>
は、はい‥‥？
S-Sorry?

<Tigre>
アンタを試してみたんや。
‥‥なかなかやるのォ。
I was just messin' with youse
to see how good you' were.

<Maya>
なかなかやるって。なるほどくん。
Did you hear that, Nick?
He said you're not bad!

<Phoenix>
（ウソつけ！）
(That's one compliment I can
do without! Plus, he's lying
through his teeth!)

<Judge>
‥‥あの、証人。
ウソはいけないと思うのですが‥‥
Um, witness. Please remember
that you're under oath. Lies
will not be tolerated.

<Tigre>
ウソなんかついとらへんでェ！
Youse callin' me a liar!?
Is that what you' doin'!?

<Judge>
ひひいぃぃっ！
Ruh-roh!

<Godot>
“岡　高夫に会ったことがない”
‥‥その証言は、ホントだ、と？
So you're saying that your
claim to have "never seen that
kid before" is the truth?

<Tigre>
アタリマエやッ！
I said I'm dead serious!
Youse betta believe that's
the truth!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！
Ha...!

どうやら‥‥コーヒーをもう１杯。
‥‥楽しめそうだぜ。
Then I'd say that gives me
time... to enjoy another cup
of pure black magic!

アンタが、もう一度
証言しているあいだにな‥‥。
That is, while you testify
for the court again,
Mr. Tigre.

<Judge>
あ。では、証人。なにとぞ、
証言をよろしくおねがいします。
Oh, yes! Um, would you mind
indulging the court,
witness?

<Phoenix>
（“被害者に会ったことがない”
　‥‥ウソに決まっている！）
(He never actually met the
victim!? That's got to be a
lie right there!)

（一気に追いつめてやる‥‥！）
(It's time I nailed this guy!)

< >
～被害者・岡　高夫について～
-- The Victim, Glen Elg --

<Tigre>
ワイはウソはつかへん。
岡　高夫に会ったことはないで！
I ain't no liar. I never met
Glen Elg.

たしかに‥‥そんな名前のオトコに
融資の相談は受けたけどなぁ。
There was some lame guy
with that name, though. Wanted
to borrow cash from me.

会うヤクソクはあった。ただし‥‥
その場所は《カリヨーゼ》やで。
I set up a meetin' with the
guy... at my office, Tender
Lender.

事務所で待っとったんやけど、
ケッキョク、現れなかったんや。
I waited around for him,
but he ain't ever showed.

ワイは、行ったことないでェ。
《吐麗美庵》とかいうレストラン。
I ain't never even been to
that Trés Bien joint, youse
hear?

<Judge>
なるほど‥‥。
スジは通りますな。
I see... That all seems
perfectly logical.

ヤクソクはしたが、
事務所に現れなかった。
You had arranged to meet with
the victim, but he didn't
show up.

<Godot>
トーゼン、だろうぜ。
‥‥死んじまったワケだからな。
I've heard it's pretty hard to
keep appointments when you're
dead.

<Judge>
それでは、成歩堂くん。
‥‥尋問をおねがいします。
Very well. You may begin your
cross-examination, Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
はい！
Yes, Your Honor!

<Tigre>
‥‥ワイは今日、
デカい取り引きがあるんや。
Didn't I tell you I got a big
deal goin' down today?

もう、バスじゃ間に合わへん。
急行に飛び乗らなアカン。
I ain't gonna make my bus now.
I'm gonna have to take the
express train.

急行代‥‥アンタに払って
もらうでェ‥‥ニイちゃん！
That bill's goin' straight
to you... Wright!

<Phoenix>
うううう‥‥。
Grr...

< >
～被害者・岡　高夫について～
-- The Victim, Glen Elg --




<Tigre>
ワイはウソはつかへん。
岡　高夫に会ったことはないで！
I ain't no liar. I never met
Glen Elg.


<Tigre>
たしかに‥‥そんな名前のオトコに
融資の相談は受けたけどなぁ。
There was some lame guy
with that name, though. Wanted
to borrow cash from me.


<Tigre>
会うヤクソクはあった。ただし‥‥
その場所は《カリヨーゼ》やで。
I set up a meetin' with the
guy... at my office, Tender
Lender.


<Tigre>
事務所で待っとったんやけど、
ケッキョク、現れなかったんや。
I waited around for him,
but he ain't ever showed.


<Tigre>
ワイは、行ったことないでェ。
《吐麗美庵》とかいうレストラン。
I ain't never even been to
that Trés Bien joint, youse
hear?


<Maya>
岡　高夫さんと会ったコト
ないのかなあ。ゼニトラ‥‥。
Do you think he really didn't
meet Glen Elg?

<Phoenix>
そんなハズはないよ。
Not likely.

この事件は‥‥アイツが
仕組んだことなんだからね。
Because I'm convinced this
guy's behind the whole thing.

<Maya>
じゃあ、今の証言って、
やっぱり‥‥ウソ？
So you mean... that whole
testimony he just gave was a
lie?

<Phoenix>
モチロンさ。アイツに
考えるヒマを与えないように‥‥
Of course. So we can't afford
to give him time to think of
ways to plug the leaks in it.

どんどん攻めていこう！
I've got to nail him while
I still can!

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
しかし！　岡　高夫さんの
カレンダーに、あなたの名前が‥‥
And yet, your name was written
on the victim's calendar!

<Tigre>
ウマのカレンダーがなんじゃい！
こっちは《トラ》やでェ！
Get that horse calendar outta
my face! I'm The Tiger, not a
lame horse, you' porcupine!

そんなウマなんぞ‥‥
このトラが食ったらァァッ！
Tigers like me eat horses like
that for breakfast!

<Judge>
いやいや！　証拠品を食べる
証人がありますか！
No, no, no! Witnesses aren't
permitted to eat evidence.
Not that they ever would!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

いや。そういえばムカシ、
１人だけ、いたような‥‥
Well, there's was a case once,
where a young lad ate--

<Phoenix>
とと、とにかく！
A-Anyway!

被害者に会ったことがないのなら、
このメモの説明をおねがいします！
If you had never met the
victim before, how do explain
this note he left?

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
‥‥おかしいですね。
彼の会社の社長の話では‥‥
That's very strange. According
to the manager of the firm
where the victim worked...

１２月３日は、《返済の期限日》
‥‥つまり。
...December 3rd was the date
he had to repay his loan.

《借りる》相談ではなくて
《返す》話をするはずだった‥‥
He wasn't due to discuss
borrowing money, but repaying
what he owed...

<Tigre>
あ‥‥ああ。
そうやったかもしれんなぁ。
Oh. Yeah.
Maybe youse right.

まあ、なんにせよ、たしかに
１２月のはじめのコトやったワ。
Whatever it was, it was goin'
down at the beginnin' of
December.

<Phoenix>
それじゃあ‥‥
岡　高夫に会ったワケですね！
So you did meet Mr. Elg,
then!?

<Tigre>
‥‥あわてちゃアカンで、
ニイちゃんや‥‥。
Hey, Wright. Youse might wanna
cool your jets a sec.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
‥‥《吐麗美庵》じゃ
なかったんですか？
So your meeting wasn't
supposed to be at Trés Bien,
then?

<Tigre>
なんで、そんなレストラン
行かなアカンねん。
Why would I wanna go to a
dump like dat?

話があれば、ウチの事務所で
すればエエ。
If I wanna talk with my
clients, I got an office
decked out for the job.

‥‥ゴツいサンドバッグもあるし。
I got the best punching bag
youse ever saw in there.

<Phoenix>
（ゼッタイ行きたくないな‥‥）
(Not exactly a professional
office you've got there, you
know...)

じゃあ‥‥事件当日は、
事務所にいたわけですか？
So you were in your office on
the day in question?

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
現れなかった‥‥？
He didn't show up?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　トーゼン、だぜ。
Ha...!
What do you think, Trite?

現れたくても‥‥死んでた
ワケだからな。レストランで。
Let's see. How does a dead man
get from a French restaurant
to a loan shark's office?

<Phoenix>
あなた自身は、吐麗美庵に
行かなかったんですか？
And you yourself didn't go to
Trés Bien?

<Tigre>
ほほお。このゼニトラに
アヤをつける気ィか‥‥？
What are you' tryin' to pin on
me here?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥。
Um...

<Tigre>
今度、ウチの事務所で
ハラぁ割って語り合おかァ。
Why don't youse come down to
my office? We can chat about
this thing my way, yeah?

‥‥ゴツいサンドバッグもあるし。
I got the best punching bag
youse ever saw in there.

<Phoenix>
い、いえいえ！
エンリョしておきます！
No, no! No need!
I'm good, thanks!

<Tigre>
ええかァ！　これだけは
言うとくでェ‥‥。
Listen up!
I ain't got nothin' more to
say, except this.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
行ったことがない‥‥
一度も、ですか？
Never? Not even once?

<Tigre>
せや。トーゼン、事件当日も
事務所にいたで。
Not even once. I was in my
office the day that went
down.

ワカゾウのコーヒーに、毒なんぞ
入れられるワケ、ないのォ。
I didn't put no poison in no
kid's coffee. Capice?

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...


<Phoenix>
芝九蔵さん。
‥‥このマッチはなんですか？
Mr. Tigre. Is there something
you'd like to tell the court
about these matches?

<Tigre>
マッチ‥‥やて？
Matches?
What youse talkin' about?

<Phoenix>
《カリヨーゼ》で見つけました。
あのレストランの紙マッチです。
We found them in your office
at Tender Lender. They're
from "that" restaurant.

<Tigre>
う‥‥ッ！
Wh...!?

<Phoenix>
《吐麗美庵》に行ったことが
ないのならば‥‥
If you've really never been to
Trés Bien before...

どうして、あの店のマッチが
あなたのデスクにあったのですか！
...what was a book of the
restaurant's matches doing on
your desk!?

<Tigre>
ダマらんかいィッ！
店のマッチ、店のマッチって‥‥
Youse been snoopin' around
in my stuff now too, wiseguy!?

テメェはワイの新妻かいィッ！
What are you', my ball
and chain!? Ain't no broad
controlling me!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！
いかがでしょう？　証人。
Order! Order!
Well, witness?

そろそろ、ホントのコトを
ワレワレにぶつけてみては‥‥
I think it's time you started
telling us the truth, don't
you?

<Tigre>
うらああァァァァァァァァッ！
Grrraaaaargh!

<Judge>
ご‥‥ごめんなさいごめんなさい！
S-Sorry! I'm terribly sorry!
Forgive me!

<Tigre>
オトコは、一度言うたコトは
そうカンタンに曲げへんでェ‥‥。
I ain't no pussy-cat! I don't
go back on what I said!

たしかに‥‥ワイはあの日、
レストランに行った！
But, OK... I was at the
joint that day.

<Phoenix>
な‥‥なんですって！
Whaaat!?

<Tigre>
だがなァ、ニイちゃん‥‥
But listen good, alright?

それでもワイは、その
ワカゾウには会ってないんや！
I might've been there, but I
still never met that kid.

<Godot>
どうやら‥‥
Well, well...

もう一度、おしゃべりを
したほうがいいみたいだぜ‥‥。
Looks like an order just came
in for another testimony.

<Phoenix>
（あと、一歩‥‥
　なんとしても、認めさせる！）
(I'm this close to proving it
was him!)

（アイツは、あの日！
　岡　高夫に会って、そして‥‥）
(He did meet Glen Elg that
day.)

（毒を入れたんだ！
　被害者のコーヒーに‥‥）
(And he did put poison in his
coffee! He must have!)

< >
～事件当日‥‥吐麗美庵～
-- At Trés Bien --

<Tigre>
あの日の午後、‥‥レストランで
会うことになっていたんや。
I was supposed to meet wid
the kid at the restaurant
that afternoon.

入り口のドアを開けた瞬間‥‥
イヤなものが見えた。
When I opened the door to the
joint, I saw one ugly scene.

あのワカゾウ、机につっぷして
ピクとも動かへんやないか！
The guy was laid out over
the table, stiff as concrete.

こりゃヤバい‥‥ピンと来た。
その場で回れ右、や。
I figured if the place wasn't
hot already, it was gonna be,
so I split.

パトカーのサイレンも聞こえたし。
そのまま事務所に帰ったワケや。
I heard the cop's sirens on my
way out, and I went straight
back to my office.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。ケッキョク、
岡　高夫さんとは会っていない‥‥
I see... You didn't actually
meet with him in the end,
then.

‥‥では、弁護人。尋問を。
Well, Mr. Wright. Your cross-
examination, please.

<Phoenix>
‥‥はい。
Yes, Your Honor.

<Tigre>
アカン！　そろそろ特急に
乗らなアカン時間や！
Hold it! If I wait around here
any longer, I ain't even gonna
make the normal express.

‥‥これ以上、ムダな質問は
ユルされへんでェ‥‥
No more stupid questions.

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　問題、ねえぜ。
Ha...!
No problem.

必要のない《ゆさぶり》には、
オレからペナルティを与えてやる。
Any time Trite presses you on
something irrelevant, I'll see
he pays a penalty.

<Judge>
ちょ、ちょっと！　それは
私のシゴトですから‥‥
M-Mr. Godot! That's my job!

<Godot>
アンタのシゴトは、木槌を叩いて
《有罪！》と叫ぶコトだけ、だぜ！
Your job is to slam that
little hammer of yours and
call a guilty verdict.

キチンとシゴトしなッ！
So do it!

<Judge>
は、はいッ！
Y-Yes, sir!

<Tigre>
‥‥それから。特急代は
アンタ持ちやで、ニイちゃん‥‥
The special express ain't
cheap, Wright! Just so youse
know since youse payin'!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥
　無法地帯かよ、ここは‥‥）
(Oh, man. Doesn't the rule of
law mean anything around
here!?)

< >
～事件当日‥‥吐麗美庵～
-- At Trés Bien --




<Tigre>
あの日の午後、‥‥レストランで
会うことになっていたんや。
I was supposed to meet wid
the kid at the restaurant
that afternoon.


<Tigre>
入り口のドアを開けた瞬間‥‥
イヤなものが見えた。
When I opened the door to the
joint, I saw one ugly scene.


<Tigre>
あのワカゾウ、机につっぷして
ピクとも動かへんやないか！
The guy was laid out over
the table, stiff as concrete.


<Tigre>
こりゃヤバい‥‥ピンと来た。
その場で回れ右、や。
I figured if the place wasn't
hot already, it was gonna be,
so I split.


<Tigre>
パトカーのサイレンも聞こえたし。
そのまま事務所に帰ったワケや。
I heard the cop's sirens on my
way out, and I went straight
back to my office.


<Maya>
ど、どうよ。なるほどくん！
Well, Nick? What do you think?

<Phoenix>
そろそろ、ゴマかしきれなく
なってきているみたいだ。
He's running out of ways to
avoid the truth.

とにかく、ウソを考える時間を
与えないことだよ。
I need to press him fast
before he has time to think
things through.

ムジュンを暴くんだ！
‥‥振り向きざまに！
I've got to come right back at
him with a contradiction!

<Maya>
ヘタにゆさぶっちゃうと、
ペナルティを食らうしね！
Be careful what you press him
on, though, or you'll get
penalized, OK?

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
《カリヨーゼ》の事務所じゃ
なかったんですか？
So the meeting wasn't due to
take place at Tender Lender
at all then?

<Tigre>
どうしても、事務所に来たくないと
ゴネやがったんや、あのワカゾウ。
The kid was makin' a fuss
about comin' into de office.

なんでやろ。返済のハナシになると
みんな、ウチに来たがらへんねや。
It's always that way when I
wanna talk about repayments.

ゴツいサンドバッグもあるのに。
Even though I got the best
punching bag you' ever seen
if there are any "issues".

<Phoenix>
（サンドバッグがあるから
　じゃないのか‥‥？）
(Maybe it's because of the
punching bag that people are
scared to come?)

それで‥‥《吐麗美庵》で
会うコトにしたワケですか。
So that's why you decided to
meet at Trés Bien?

<Objection!>

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　まるほどう。
そのハナシ、さっきも聞いたぜ。
Ha...!
You're going over old ground
again, Trite.

<Phoenix>
そ、そうでしたっけ。
S-Sorry.

<Godot>
ヤクソクどおり、ペナルティを
オゴるぜ。‥‥飲みほしな。
You just earned yourself a
penalty. Now suck it down!

<Judge>
飲みほすように、弁護人。
You will suck down the
penalty, Mr. Wright.
And you will like it!

<Phoenix>
（マイったな‥‥）
(Thank you, sir, may I have
another!)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
“イヤなもの”というのは、
いったい‥‥
An "ugly scene"?
What do you mean?

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥言ったはずだぜ。イミのない
ゆさぶりはユルさねえ、と‥‥。
The witness has already told
us, Trite. Which makes that
question... irrelevant!

<Phoenix>
し、しかし‥‥！
B-But...!

<Godot>
‥‥オレは、裁判中のコーヒーは
１７杯まで、と決めている。
I limit myself to 17 cups of
coffee during a trial. That's
the rule.

アンタも、裁判中に食らう
ペナルティ、回数を決めることだ。
You better limit the number of
times you take a penalty,
Trite.

胃が、まっ黒になっちゃうぜ！
Or your guts will look like
the inside of a chimney!
Ashen!

<Judge>
まっ黒になっちゃいますよ、
弁護人。
Don't make me burn you again,
Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥今のゆさぶりは
　軽はずみだったか‥‥）
(I guess I shouldn't have
pressed him on that.)

<Tigre>
どうやら、特急には
乗れそうやなぁ、ニイちゃん‥‥
Guess I'm gonna make that
special express after all.

<Judge>
それで‥‥、あなたが見た
“イヤなもの”というのは‥‥？
So, to recap... This "ugly
scene" you saw was...?

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
‥‥岡　高夫の死体を
見たわけですか？
You mean you saw Glen Elg's
dead body?

<Tigre>
まあ、それらしい背中しか
見えなかったけどな。
I guess I did. But I only saw
him from behind.

たしか、うすぎたない毛糸の
キャップをかぶっていたでェ。
He was wearin' some raggy bit
of cloth he called a hat.

<Phoenix>
それは、何時ごろの
ことでしたか？
And what time was this?

<Tigre>
‥‥知らん。
I dunno.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
Huh?

<Tigre>
ワイがこの世で最もユルせんのが、
丸ぅい時計やッ！
You' know what winds me up
more than anythin' else in the
world? Watches! Round watches!

そないなモン、
ウデにつけるワケ、あらへん！
I ain't gonna pollute my paws
wid some tickin' henpecker!

<Judge>
あの‥‥ちなみに、２番目に
ユルせないのは‥‥？
Out of interest, Mr. Tigre,
what winds you up the
second most?

<Tigre>
決まっとるやろがァ！
‥‥四角ぅい時計やッ。
Huh? Whatd'youse think!?
Square watches!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Is this guy for real!?)

<Tigre>
とにかく、何かマズいことが
起こったのはマチガイあらへん！
Look, all I needed to know
was that somethin' bad was
goin' down in that place.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
じゃあ‥‥店の中には
入らなかったワケですね？
So you didn't actually set
foot inside the restaurant,
then?

<Tigre>
‥‥ワイの時間は高いからのォ。
The Tiger is a busy cat. I
don't hang around for no one.

ムダな事件に巻きこまれとる
ヒマはないんや。
I ain't got time to be caught
up in no murder investigation.

<Phoenix>
じゃあ‥‥このマッチは、
いつもらったんですか？
So, when exactly did you
pick up the matches?

<Godot>
‥‥マッチは、入り口のそばに
置いてあった。
There are matches just inside
the front door.

ウチの刑事が５個、持って帰ろうと
して、シェフに怒られてたぜ。
Our detective friend wound
up in trouble with the chef
after taking 5 books home.

<Phoenix>
（イトノコ刑事‥‥泣かせるなあ）
(Poor Gumshoe...
It's almost enough to make
a man cry...)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
何か、やましいコトでも
あったんですか！
You went straight back?
Did a bout of guilt suddenly
hit you for what you did?

<Tigre>
なんやとコラァッ！
What're youse trying to say!?

やましいコトがないニンゲンが
いるかァ、このボケがッ！
You' tryin' to tell me youse
ain't never been guilty of
nothin'?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
Um...

<Godot>
‥‥ヒトはだれでも、いくつもの
ツミを抱えているんだぜ。
We all have our crosses to
bear.

その暗い闇を、ただ飲みくだして
生きてゆくのさ。
We all have to swallow the
dark secrets we hide...

こんなふうにッ！
...Like this!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥裁判所でする会話とは
　思えないな‥‥）
(The courtroom's not exactly
the place to talk about dark
secrets, is it?)

<Judge>
どうやら‥‥また
やってしまったようですな。
It seems you've done it again,
Mr. Wright.

イミのない“ゆさぶり”を。
‥‥ペナルティを与えます！
Another irrelevant line of
questioning. I must impose a
penalty accordingly!

<Phoenix>
（あの連中の問題発言に
　ペナルティはないのかよ！）
(How about a penalty for those
two jokers and the garbage
they keep coming up with!?)


<Phoenix>
‥‥証人は、
おカネを貸すプロでしたね？
You're something of a loan
collecting pro, aren't you,
Mr. Tigre?

<Tigre>
せやでェ。このゼニトラから
逃げることはでけへんねん。
No one escapes The Tiger's
clutches!

<Phoenix>
ゼニトラさん。‥‥ぼくは、
ウソを見破るプロなんですよ。
Well I'm something of a lie
detecting pro.

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
ぼくから逃げることはできません。
And no one escapes The
Phoenix's clutches!

‥‥そろそろ、気づいても
いいころですね‥‥。
I think it's time we got
something straight.

<Godot>
どういうコトだ‥‥まるほどう。
What's this, Trite? A new line
of irrelevant questioning?

<Phoenix>
ここに、現場の上面図があります。
These are the floor plans of
the crime scene.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ゼニトラさん。あなたは
入り口に立っていたそうですね。
You say you were standing at
the entrance, Mr. Tigre?

そのポイントから見えるエリアは、
‥‥こうなります。
From there, your field of
vision would have covered an
area something like... this.

<Judge>
たしかに、被害者の席が
目に入りますな‥‥。
Indeed. The witness would have
had a clear view of the
victim's seat.

<Tigre>
アタリマエや。
ワイは、見たんやからなァ‥‥。
Isn't that what I just said?
I saw the back of the kid's
head.

<Phoenix>
ザンネンながら‥‥
そうはいきません。
Unfortunately for you, that
is not possible.

<Phoenix>
‥‥思い出してください。
店内のテーブルの間には‥‥
If the court would think back,
you'll remember that between
each of the tables...

高い仕切りが立っているんですよ。
...is a tall partition!

<Judge>
あ‥‥そ、そういえば‥‥！
Why...! That's true!

<Phoenix>
もう一度、上面図を見てください！
‥‥すべてはアキラカです。
Now look at the plans again!
The truth is painfully
obvious!

入り口のポイントから
ジッサイに見えるのは‥‥
From the entrance, the field
of vision of any customer
walking in...

ここまでなのです！
...ends here!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
吐麗美庵の入り口からでは、
被害者の席は見えない！
So, from the entrance of
Trés Bien, you couldn't have
seen the victim's seat.

‥‥あなたは事件当日、
岡　高夫と会っていたのです！
But you did see the victim
that day... because you met
with him!

<Objection!>

<Godot>
バカな！　きのうのジイさんの
証言を忘れたのか！
Wrong!
Have you forgotten the old
man's testimony yesterday?

テーブルには、被害者しか
いなかったハズだぜ！
The victim was alone at his
table.

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
弁護側は、先ほど
立証したばかりです！
But the defense just proved
that point to be moot!

五十嵐　将兵の見た“被害者”は
ニセモノだった、と！
The "victim" witnessed by
Mr. Kudo was not Glen Elg,
but a fake!

<Godot>
なんだと‥‥！
What!?

<Phoenix>
《真犯人》は、五十嵐さんに
まちがった証言をさせるために‥‥
In order to have Mr. Kudo
falsely testify...

被害者を殺害したあと、彼に
なりすまして、シバイをしたッ！
...the real killer posed as
the victim he had just killed
and acted out a charade!

<Judge>
‥‥そこまで！
That will do!

審理がここまで来た以上、
うかがわないわけには行きません。
This trial has gone on long
enough without the obvious
question being answered.

その“ニセモノ”になりすました
真犯人の名前を‥‥
Who exactly was this "real
killer" who impersonated the
victim?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥！
...!





<Judge>
《犯人》は、岡　高夫さんを
毒殺したあと‥‥
You say the killer murdered
Glen Elg...

彼になりすまして、その姿を
五十嵐　将兵に目撃させた。
...and then impersonated his
victim in a performance for
Victor Kudo?

その《真犯人》！
いったい、ダレだったのですか！
In that case, Mr. Wright,
reveal the identity of this
"criminal" to the court!




<Phoenix>
こういう場面では、《意外な人物》
と相場が決まっています！
Obviously, it's the person
you least expect!

あの‥‥。
どうしましたか？　裁判長。
Um... What's the matter,
Your Honor?

<Judge>
あ！　ちょっとボールペンを
落としてしまってですね‥‥
Oh, nothing! I just dropped my
pen again.

私にかまわず、みなさんで
やってください！
Don't mind me. Carry on with
the proceedings as normal.

<Maya>
ボールペンを探しているあいだに
もう一度、考えなおそうよ。
Better think again while he's
down there, Nick.

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり、意外性だけで
　選んだのがマズかったか‥‥）
(I guess I should've picked
the obvious choice...)

<Judge>
‥‥それでは、ボールペンも
見つかったので、うかがいます。
Very good. I've found my pen
now. So, allow me to pose the
question again, Mr. Wright.


<Phoenix>
もちろん‥‥
Obviously...

芝九蔵　虎ノ助さん！
あなたしかいません！
...the killer is Furio Tigre!
No one else could have done
it.

<Judge>
そ‥‥そうなのですか！　証人！
Wh-What!?
Well, witness?

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥カカカカカカカカ‥‥‥‥
オモロイやないかい。
...
Grrrah ha hah!
Now that's cute!

このゼニトラに
言いがかりをつけるたぁ‥‥
Youse think you can pin this
on The Tiger!?

‥‥命知らずやのお‥‥‥‥
Maybe youse don't understand.
The Tiger is king of the
jungle!

ダレやァッ！　いったいダレが、
ワイとやり合うっちゅうんじゃい！
So I dares you' to say it
again! Come on! You' got the
guts!?

<Judge>
わわ、ワレワレをオドしても
む、む、む、ムダですぞ！
Y-Y-You can't threaten m-me,
Mr. Tigre!

ホレ、弁護人！
カツンと言っておやりなさいッ！
I-It's the defense!
Go ahead and tell the
witness, Mr. Wright!

‥‥成歩堂くんんんんんッ！
Mr. Wriiight!

<Tigre>
そうか‥‥アンタか、ジイさん。
‥‥エエ度胸やあああァァァッ！
Sounds to me like it must be
you', old man. Youse got
guts, I'll give you that.

<Judge>
べべべべ、弁護人！
私をヒトリにしないように！
M-M-Mr. Wright!
Do not leave me to handle this
alone!

<Godot>
　　　　‥‥‥クッ‥‥‥
...Ha...!

情けねェ連中だぜ‥‥
Perhaps I can end this
embarrassment.

<Judge>
ご‥‥ゴドー検事ぃぃ！
M-Mr. Godot!

<Godot>
‥‥よおく思い出すんだな。
五十嵐　将兵の証言を、もう一度。
Let's just go back over
Mr. Kudo's testimony one
more time.

ジイさんが目撃したのは、
被害者だけじゃねえんだぜ！
The old man didn't see just
the victim! Oh, no, no, no.

<Kudo>
女給さんがコーヒーを運んできた
のだが‥‥中に、何か入れたのだ！
The serving girl brought
him a javaccino...
But she put something in it!

まちがいない！　ワシに見せつける
かのように、白いコナをッ！
There's no question about it!
She very conspicuously put
some white powder in there!

<Godot>
被害者がニセモノかどうか‥‥？
そんなコトは関係ねえのさ。
Was the victim he saw the
real victim or not? That
doesn't matter.

カップに毒を入れたのが、
被告人である以上は！
The fact remains, he saw the
accused put the poison into
the coffee!

<Judge>
‥‥‥！
...!

い、言われてみれば‥‥たしかに、
毒を入れたのはウエイトレスの
Yes, it was the waitress who
poisoned the coffee--

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼくのルスを狙うとは、
やりますね。ゴドー検事。
V-Very impressive, Mr. Godot.
...Waiting for my absence to
launch your attack!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
Ha...!

ボールペンは見つかったかい、
まるほどう‥‥
Found your pen at last,
Trite?

<Phoenix>
ポケットにさしてありました。
It was in my pocket.

‥‥とにかく。
*ahem* But anyway...

イガラシさんが目撃した
人物は‥‥２人。
Mr. Kudo witnessed two
people that day.

被害者の“岡　高夫”と、
後ろ姿の“ウエイトレス”‥‥。
He saw the victim, the
"supposed" Mr. Glen Elg, and
the "waitress"... from behind.

<Judge>
そのとおりですが‥‥
Yes...
Your point, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
‥‥考えるまでも
ないじゃないですか。
I think the conclusion is
obvious.

“岡　高夫”が、犯人による
シバイだったのなら‥‥
If this "Glen Elg" was really
the killer in disguise...

当然‥‥このウエイトレスも、
シバイだったのではないか‥‥？
...then surely it's possible
the "waitress" was also part
of the show.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですって！
ウエイトレスも‥‥ニセモノ！
What!?
You mean, the waitress was an
imposter as well!?

<Phoenix>
須々木　マコは、事件発生の直後、
“キゼツした”と証言している！
The defendant, Ms. Byrde, fell
unconscious immediately after
the incident.

すべては‥‥被告人の意識のそとで
仕組まれた、ワナだったのです！
And someone used her fainting
to hatch an elaborate plan to
pin the murder on her!




<Judge>
いったい‥‥ダレだったのですか！
Who on earth was it!?

五十嵐　将兵が目撃した
“ウエイトレス”の正体は‥‥！
Who was this "waitress" that
Mr. Kudo witnessed?




<Phoenix>
こういう場面では、《意外な人物》
と相場が決まっています！
Obviously, it's the person
you least expect!

あの‥‥。
どうしましたか？　裁判長。
Um... What's the matter,
Your Honor?

<Judge>
あ！　ちょっとボールペンを
落としてしまってですね‥‥
Oh, nothing! I just dropped my
pen again.

私にかまわず、みなさんで
やってください！
Don't mind me. Carry on with
the proceedings as normal.

<Maya>
ボールペンを探しているあいだに
もう一度、考えなおそうよ。
Better think again while he's
down there, Nick.

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり、意外性だけで
　選んだのがマズかったか‥‥）
(I guess I should've picked
the obvious choice...)

<Judge>
‥‥それでは、ボールペンも
見つかったので、うかがいます。
Very good. I've found my pen
now. So, allow me to pose the
question again, Mr. Wright.


<Judge>
ど‥‥
どなたですか？　この方は‥‥
W-Who is this woman?

<Phoenix>
‥‥鹿羽　うらみ。
《カリヨーゼ》の従業員、です。
Her name is Viola Cadaverini.
She's an employee of
Tender Lender.

<Tigre>
‥‥アンタ‥‥
Youse makin' a big mistake...

<Tigre>
うらみちゃんが、ダレのマゴか、
知っとるやろうなァ‥‥
D'you know who Violetta's
grandfather is?

<Tigre>
今日、裁判所からブジに
帰れると思わんほうがええでェ‥‥
You' betta be goin' home in an
armored truck tonight, if you'
know what I mean...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ふるえちゃダメ！　なるほどくん！
Stop shaking, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥と、とにかく！
Wh-Where was I?

被告人・須々木　マコは、
こんな証言をしています！
Yes, the defendant, Ms. Byrde,
has stated the following...

<Byrde>
スズキが、あのテーブルに
コーヒーを運んだとき‥‥
Well, when I took the coffee
over to the victim's table...

店内には、お客さんが
もう１人、いたッス。
...it's true there was another
customer in the restaurant.

たしか、ちょっと
ジメッとしていて‥‥
Umm... She was sort of
creepy...

イミありげに“ククッ‥‥”と
笑っていたッス。
And she had a kind of
cackling laugh.

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥この事件には、
ムジュンが多すぎました。
There are just too many
contradictions in this case.

被害者のテーブルから
消えた“もう１人のオトコ”‥‥
The "second man" at the
victim's table who nobody but
Ms. Byrde seems to have seen.

聞こえるはずのない耳に
ついていたヘッドホン‥‥
The earpiece worn by the
victim in his left ear when
that eardrum was ruptured!

とっくに終わっていたはずの
ラジオ番組‥‥
And the radio show he was
supposedly listening to half
an hour after it was over.

すべてにスジが通る
コタエは、たった１つです。
There is only one logical
explanation that clears up
all of these contradictions!

事件は、２回起こった！
‥‥ホンモノと、ニセモノと‥‥。
The whole incident took place
twice! Once for real, and once
for show!

そして‥‥犯行が可能だったのは、
‥‥芝九蔵　虎ノ助さん。
And, Mr. Furio Tigre, the
only person who could have
committed the crime...

あなたしかいない！
...was you!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...
......

<Judge>
しょ‥‥証人。
いかがですかな‥‥？
W-Witness?
What have you got to say?

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥オモロイなァ。
...
That's cute!

<Judge>
は‥‥？
S-Sorry?

<Tigre>
アンタら、なかなかの
役者やのォ‥‥
Youse alright.
I could do with a guy like
you' around.

<Phoenix>
ど‥‥どういうコトですか？
Wh-What do you mean?

<Tigre>
ええワ！　つきあったる！
OK, I'm in on this game!

取引先まで、ジェット機を
チャーターせにゃならんが‥‥
I'm gonna have to charter a
jet to get me to my meetin'
now, but...

最後にもう一度だけ、
オモロイこと、聞かしたるわ！
...I'm gonna give youse one
more thing to think about
before I go.

<Phoenix>
お、“オモロイこと”‥‥？
Something to think about?

<Tigre>
ニイちゃん、もっともらしいコト
言うとるがなァ‥‥
Youse got it all wrapped up
nice, huh, Wright?

とんでもない見落としを
しとるっちゅうコトやッ！
But youse missed out one
real important thing!

<Phoenix>
そ、そんなハズは‥‥！
But that can't be!

<Tigre>
‥‥ワイはたしかに、あの日。
あのワカゾウと会ったワ。
I was in the joint that day.
And I met that kid, too.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Tigre>
せやけど‥‥ワイが、ワカゾウに
毒を盛るハズがないんや。
But I couldn't have poisoned
him, youse hear?

<Judge>
な、なんですと‥‥！
それは、いったいなぜ‥‥
What!?
Do you really expect us to
believe you now, Mr. Tigre?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
Ha...!

‥‥まったく、とんだ
いたずらボウヤだぜ。
What a troublemaker.

<Phoenix>
い、いたずら‥‥
T-Troublemaker...?

<Godot>
どうやら‥‥最後に
もう一度、必要みたいだぜ。
Looks like we're going to
need another one for the road.

とびきりホットな《証言》が‥‥！
One more steaming cup of hot
testimony!

<Judge>
‥‥そのようですな。
それでは、証人。
Indeed.
Witness, you will explain
yourself to the court.

もう一度だけ、
証言していただきましょう。
I will give you one more
chance to testify.

事件当日‥‥吐麗美庵で
被害者と、何があったか‥‥？
What happened that day at
Trés Bien between yourself
and the victim?

< >
～被害者との関係について～
-- Ties to the Victim --

<Tigre>
岡　高夫には、カネを貸してたんや
‥‥１０００万円ほどなァ。
Yeah, I loaned Elg cash. About
100,000 dollars.

あの日は、融資の話やなかった。
返済の期限日やったんや。
That day, we was due to have
a little chat. The kid had hit
his payback date, see?

ところが、あのワカゾウ。
カネがないと言いだしやがった。
So anyway, he tells me he's
got no way to pay up.

ペチャンコにしたろ思ったとき。
突然、アイツが騒ぎ出したんや。
I'm about to flatten the guy,
when he starts screamin'.

“５０００万円当たったァ”
‥‥ってな。運のいいやっちゃア。
"Yesss! I won! Half a million
bucks!" He got lucky, you'
know. Real lucky.

‥‥あのウエイトレスが妙なコトを
しなければ、丸く収まってたんや。
If that waitress hadn't done
what she done, everythin'
woulda been over.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。借金の額面は
５００万円、ですか。
Now, I see that the principal
amount you loaned to Mr. Elg
was 50,000 dollars...

<Tigre>
まあ‥‥利子やらナニやらで
少し、ふくらんだワケやな。
Yeah, well. Youse got the vig
to take into account. Interest
builds up fast, you' know.

<Phoenix>
（１０００万円って、２バイ
　じゃないか‥‥）
(That's faster than fast!
100,000 dollars is twice
his principal!)

<Judge>
返済期限は、１２月３日。
たしかに、事件当日です。
And the repayment deadline was
December 3rd, the day of the
incident in question.

<Tigre>
‥‥まったく、
とんだシンデレラ・ボーイやで。
Yeah. He was one lucky kid!

あのドタンバで、５０００万円
当てるとはなァ。
He got that half a million
just in time.

<Tigre>
そう‥‥。ワイには、
《理由》がないんや。
So I ain't have no reason to
kill the kid.

‥‥あのワカゾウを殺す、
《動機》ってヤツがなァ‥‥！
And if I ain't got no motive,
you ain't got no case!

<Phoenix>
（芝九蔵　虎ノ助の
　“動機”‥‥か！）
(His motive? Hmm... He has
to have one, but what is it?)

< >
～被害者との関係について～
-- Ties to the Victim --




<Tigre>
岡　高夫には、カネを貸してたんや
‥‥１０００万円ほどなァ。
Yeah, I loaned Elg cash. About
100,000 dollars.


<Tigre>
あの日は、融資の話やなかった。
返済の期限日やったんや。
That day, we was due to have
a little chat. The kid had hit
his payback date, see?


<Tigre>
ところが、あのワカゾウ。
カネがないと言いだしやがった。
So anyway, he tells me he's
got no way to pay up.


<Tigre>
ペチャンコにしたろ思ったとき。
突然、アイツが騒ぎ出したんや。
I'm about to flatten the guy,
when he starts screamin'.


<Tigre>
“５０００万円当たったァ”
‥‥ってな。運のいいやっちャア。
"Yesss! I won! Half a million
bucks!" He got lucky, you'
know. Real lucky.








<Tigre>
‥‥あのウエイトレスが妙なコトを
しなければ、丸く収まってたんや。
If that waitress hadn't done
what she done, everythin'
woulda been over.


<Maya>
ゼニトラ、おカネを返して
もらうつもりだったんだよね？
So The Tiger was meeting Glen
Elg to get his money back.

それなら、たしかに‥‥
クジをもらえば済むハナシだよ！
If Mr. Elg had just given him
the lottery ticket, that would
have been the end of it.

<Phoenix>
でも、それじゃあ
殺人の動機にはならないよ。
Yeah, so what's The Tiger's
motive?

（‥‥ここが、
　最大の勝負どころだ！）
(This is the big one.)

（この証言をくずさなければ
　‥‥勝てない‥‥！）
(If I don't manage to
undermine this testimony,
it's all over for us.)

なぜ、岡　高夫に毒を
盛らなければならなかったのか？
Why would he have to poison
Mr. Elg?

そして、そもそも‥‥なぜ、返せる
アテもない男に、カネを貸したか？
And why did he loan him the
money in the first place, when
he knew he couldn't repay him?

<Tigre>






<Tigre>
被告人が毒を入れてくれたおかげで
ワイの取り引きはパアや！
Thanks to what she did, my
business with that kid was
over!








<Tigre>
ワイの目当ては、１０００万円や。
他にヤツを殺す理由、あらへんで！
I was after the $100,000.
I didn't have no other reason
to kill the guy!





<Phoenix>
‥‥返せるアテはあったんですか？
Did he have any way of paying
the loan back?

<Tigre>
まあ‥‥あのワカゾウは
なかなかのギャンブラーやった。
The fool was a gambler.

“デカいのをイッパツ当てるまで、
　やめられない”なんて言うて。
He said he couldn't give it
up 'til he landed a big win.

‥‥だからワイも、できるかぎり
協力してやったんや。
So I agreed to help him.

<Judge>
‥‥協力？　あなたが？
Help him? You?

<Tigre>
デカいギャンブルのハナシを
次々に持ちかけてやったワケや。
I kept hittin' him with ideas
for ways he could getta big
win.

‥‥ゼンブ負けたみたいやけど。
But the guy kept losin'.

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥やっぱり、
岡　高夫さんのためを思って‥‥？
So you were helping him for
his sake? Or yours?

<Tigre>
まあ‥‥。ウチのモットーは
《三日坊主》やからなァ。
"Win Through Compromise"!
Youse help me, I help youse!
What's the difference, huh?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ひでェ！）
(...I don't believe this!)

<Maya>
でも‥‥返せるアテのないヒトに
おカネなんか貸すかなあ。
Nick, would anyone really ever
loan money to someone they
thought was unreliable?

あたし、なるほどくんには
５００円までしか貸さないから。
Like, for example, if it were
you, I'd only loan you five
bucks, max.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥シツレイな子だな）
(Thanks a lot, Maya.)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
期限日‥‥というと、いくらぐらい
返すヤクソクだったんですか？
So how much were you
expecting him to pay you back
on that day?

<Tigre>
利息をふくめた１０００万円、
全額に決まっとるやろ！
What d'youse think!? The
whole package! $100,000,
including interest.

<Maya>
ヘビー級のパンチだね、それは‥‥
That's a real heavyweight
punch!

<Tigre>
月々の返済が、１回でも
おくれたら、全額いただく！
Once a client misses a
repayment, you' call the whole
loan in.

‥‥金融界のジョーシキやで、
ホンマ、コイツだけは。
You' wanna make it in my
world, that's all youse gotta
know.

<Judge>
あの。何回目の返済で
おくれたんですか？　被害者は。
And how many times had Mr. Elg
been late with his repayments?

<Tigre>
１回目や。
Once.

<Phoenix>
‥‥月々、いくらずつ
返すハズだったんですか？
And how much was he supposed
to pay back every month?

<Tigre>
５０００円や。
50 bucks.

<Maya>
‥‥なんか、岡　高夫さんが
ワルモノに見えてきたよ。
Sounds like Mr. Elg was in
a real sticky spot.

<Phoenix>
（まあ、５０００円ずつ返しても
　借金、へらないんだけどな）
(Yeah, at 50 dollars a month,
he'd never pay that huge loan
off!)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
あの‥‥
いくら足りなかったんですか？
How much did he have left
on his debt?

<Tigre>
おおまかに言って‥‥
１０００万円やな。
You want it in round figures?
About 100,000 bucks.

<Phoenix>
（全額じゃないか！）
(That's the whole amount!)

<Godot>
‥‥死亡当時、被害者のサイフには
５８円しか入っていなかったぜ。
We're talking about a guy who
had 58 cents in his wallet.

<Tigre>
なんや！　アイツ、コーヒー代
払うつもり、なかったんかい！
What!? Youse tellin' me he
wasn't even gonna pay for
the coffee!?

<Judge>
ものスゴい度胸ですな‥‥。
He certainly seems to have
been a brave man, this
Mr. Elg.

<Tigre>
ミョーに落ちついとったんや、
あのオトコ‥‥。
That guy was smooth, I tell
youse. Real smooth!

“あと５分以内に、カネは返す”
‥‥なんて言うて。
"You'll have your money
in less than 5 minutes!"
That's what he says to me.

“ホトケのゼニトラ”と言われた
ワイも、それはゴキゲンナナメや。
The guy then calls me the
"Tender Tiger". He was skatin'
on thin ice with me!

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
もしかして、それが‥‥？
Was that because he...?

<Tigre>
‥‥宝クジや。
ヤツの最後の大勝負やった。
The guy won the lottery.
Was his last chance at
a big win.

<Judge>
そのクジは‥‥
もちろん、これですね？
And you can confirm that this
is the ticket in question?

<Tigre>
‥‥せや。
...That's it.

<Judge>
《長者ラジオ》の番組は、
午後１時半から１０分間‥‥。
The "Millionaire Radio" show
starts at 1:30 PM and runs for
10 minutes...

どうやら、２人が会っていた
時間が、ハッキリしましたな。
That fixes the time you two
met with some accuracy.

<Phoenix>
（このときのシーンが、３０分後に
　くり返されたワケだな）
(And the whole scene was
acted out again 30 minutes
later.)

（‥‥五十嵐　将兵に
　見せるために‥‥！）
(All so that Mr. Kudo would
see it!)

<Tigre>
あのときのワカゾウのカオ‥‥
今でも忘れんのォ。
I can still see the kid's face
now. I ain't never gonna
forget it.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
そのとき、店には他に
だれかいましたか？
Was there anyone else in the
restaurant at the time?

<Tigre>
‥‥さあなあ‥‥
おぼえてへんワ。
I don't remember.

<Phoenix>
（ジッサイには、
　このとき、店内には‥‥）
(If there was no one there,
I'll wear that ridiculous
tiger shirt for a month!)

（本土坊さんに、マコちゃん‥‥
　そして、うらみさんがいたはず）
(Mr. Armstrong, Maggey and if
I'm right, Viola Cadaverini,
were all there at that time.)

<Judge>
では‥‥被害者は、最初から
宝クジで借金を返そうと‥‥？
So, the victim had intended to
repay you from his lottery
winnings from the beginning?

<Tigre>
そのツモリやったみたいやで。
Seems dat way to me.

<Judge>
当たるワケないでしょう、
フツウは‥‥！
B-But you wouldn't normally
expect to win the lottery,
would you!?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
Ha...!

絶対的なピンチにいても、
自分の勝ちしかイメージしない。
The undying belief that your
next roll will end the worst
losing streak you ever had...

それがギャンブラー‥‥だぜ。
That's what defines a true
gambler.

<Phoenix>
（カッコイイな、なんか）
(He makes it sound so cool...)

<Maya>
ダメだよ、ナットクしちゃ。
なるほどくん、弱いんだから！
Don't be tempted, Nick!
You haven't got the will-
power for it!

<Tigre>
とにかく‥‥最後の大勝負で、
アイツはついに、勝ったんや。
All I know is, the kid took a
shot and he got lucky in the
end.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
ウエイトレス、というのは‥‥？
The waitress. You mean...?

<Tigre>
被告席でちっちゃくなってる
メガネに決まっとるやろがァ！
The girl with the glasses in
the defendant's chair! Who
else could I mean!?

ソイツのせいで、丸く収まるモンが
メチャメチャになったんや！
If she hadn't got in the way,
things woulda been, bada-bing,
bada-boom, over and done with!

<Phoenix>
（もっと‥‥詳しくハナシを
　聞いてみるか‥‥？）
(Maybe I should push a little
on this...)



<Phoenix>
被告人が‥‥ナニをしたと
言うんですか？
What exactly are you implying
the defendant did?

<Tigre>
あのメガネ、聞いとったんや！
５０００万円のクジのコトをなァ！
How about you go ask
four-eyes about that half
a million dollar ticket!

それが、どうしても
ほしくなった。だから‥‥
She wanted it so bad...

コーヒーに毒を入れたワケや！
...she poisoned Elg's coffee.

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
そ‥‥それは、証人の
勝手な言いぶんです！
A likely theory! Your word
hasn't held water lately,
Mr. Tigre.

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥そうは行かねえさ。
この証人は、現場にいたんだ。
Let's not forget this witness
was actually at the scene,
Trite.

<Tigre>
ワイは、闇金融なんて商売を
しとるからのお。
The law don't exactly agree
with some of the deals I send
down.

現場にいるワケにはいかん。
急いで立ち去るしかなかったんや。
I couldn't be there when de
cops showed up, so I split.

<Judge>
そ、そうだったのですか‥‥。
I-I see...

<Godot>
裁判長！　今の目撃証言‥‥
コーヒー２杯ぶんの価値があるぜ。
Your Honor! The witness's last
few statements are worth a
good two cups of coffee.

<Judge>
た‥‥たしかに！
証人、証言を修正してください！
I concur, Mr. Godot!
You will amend your testimony
accordingly, witness!

<Tigre>
クックックッ‥‥そういうコトや。
成歩堂　龍一ィィ‥‥
Ha ha ha!
So that's what youse after,
Phoenix Wright!

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
“丸く収まった”というのは？
What do you mean things
would have been over
and done with?

<Tigre>
アホか、アンタ。
借金に決まっとるやろうが！
Are youse all there or what!?
I'm talkin' about the cash!

ワイは‥‥その。１０００万円さえ
返してもらえれば、よかったんや。
I was there to get my 100,000
bucks back. That's all. I'm a
business man.

それを、あのウエイトレスが
ジャマしよってからにィィ‥‥
It was all comin' together
before that waitress got in
the way.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥‥。
証言を聞いているかぎり、
Hmm...
As far as I can tell from the
witness's testimony...

証人にとっての《動機》は、
その借金以外、なさそうです。
...other than recouping his
loan, Mr. Tigre had no motive
for killing the victim.

証人！　今の発言をふまえて、
証言を修正してください！
Witness! You will amend your
testimony to reflect what you
just said.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ゼニトラの“動機”か‥‥）
(The Tiger's motive, huh...)

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
（ゼニトラは、マコちゃんに
　ツミを着せようとしている）
(The Tiger's trying to pin the
crime on Maggey.)

（目撃したことについて聞くのは、
　こちらに不利なだけだな‥‥）
(If I ask him about what he
saw, it's only going to damage
our case.)

その‥‥“パアになった取り引き”
というのは？
What do you mean things
would have been over
and done with?

<Tigre>
アホか、アンタ。
借金に決まっとるやろうが！
Are youse all there or what!?
I'm talkin' about the cash!

ワイは‥‥その。１０００万円さえ
返してもらえれば、よかったんや。
I was there to get my 100,000
bucks back. That's all. I'm a
business man.

それを、あのウエイトレスが
ジャマしよってからにィィ‥‥
It was all comin' together
before that waitress got in
the way.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥‥。
証言を聞いているかぎり、
Hmm...
As far as I can tell from the
witness's testimony...

証人にとっての《動機》は、
その借金以外、なさそうです。
...other than recouping his
loan, Mr. Tigre had no motive
for killing the victim.

<Judge>
いかがですか？　弁護人。
証言を修正してもらいますかな？
Well, Mr. Wright? Are you
happy with the testimony, or
would you like it amended?



<Phoenix>
（このままの証言で、
　もう少し考えてみよう‥‥）
(I better leave it at that
and try to figure something
out...)

‥‥けっこうです、裁判長。
Thank you, Your Honor, but
there is no need to amend
the testimony.

<Judge>
わかりました。
‥‥では、尋問をつづけましょう。
Very well.
Continue with your cross-
examination, then.


<Phoenix>
（このままの証言じゃ、
　ラチがあかないな‥‥）
(I'm not going to get anywhere
with the testimony as it
stands...)

‥‥おねがいします、裁判長。
Your Honor, the defense
would like the testimony
amended.

<Judge>
わかりました。
Very well.

証人！　今の発言をふまえて、
証言を修正してください！
Witness! You will amend your
testimony to reflect your
recent statements, please.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
“他に、動機はない”
‥‥そういうことですか？
Are you saying you had
no other motives that day?

<Tigre>
モチロンや。
Yeah, so what?

<Godot>
それなら‥‥その当たりクジ、
なぜ持って帰らなかったんだ？
Then why didn't you take the
lottery ticket when you left?

<Tigre>
あの、メガネのウエイトレスの
せいに、決まっとるやろがァ！
Why d'youse think!? Because of
four-eyes over there!

<Phoenix>
（マコちゃん、か‥‥）
(Because of Maggey!?)

<Tigre>
あのメガネ、聞いとったんや！
５０００万円のクジのコトをなァ！
How about you go ask
four-eyes about that half
a million dollar ticket!

それが、どうしても
ほしくなった。だから‥‥
She wanted it so bad...

コーヒーに毒を入れたワケや！
...she poisoned Elg's coffee.

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
そ‥‥それは、証人の
勝手な言いぶんです！
A likely theory! Your word
hasn't held water lately,
Mr. Tigre.

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥そうは行かねえさ。
この証人は、現場にいたんだ。
Let's not forget this witness
was actually at the scene,
Trite.

<Tigre>
ワイは、闇金融なんて商売を
しとるからのお。
The law don't exactly agree
with some of the deals I send
down.

現場にいるワケにはいかん。
急いで立ち去るしかなかったんや。
I couldn't be there when de
cops showed up, so I split.

<Judge>
そ、そうだったのですか‥‥。
I-I see...

<Godot>
裁判長！　今の目撃証言‥‥
コーヒー２杯ぶんの価値があるぜ。
Your Honor! The witness's last
few statements are worth a
good two cups of coffee.

<Judge>
いかがですか？　弁護人。
証言を修正してもらいますかな？
Well, Mr. Wright? Are you
happy with the testimony, or
would you like it amended?



<Phoenix>
（このままの証言じゃ、
　ラチがあかないな‥‥）
(I'm not going to get anywhere
with the testimony as it
stands...)

‥‥おねがいします、裁判長。
Your Honor, the defense
would like the testimony
amended.

<Judge>
わかりました。
Very well.

証人！　今の発言をふまえて、
証言を修正してください！
Witness! You will amend your
testimony to reflect your
recent statements, please.

<Tigre>



<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんから、１０００万円を
返してもらうつもりだった、と？
So you just intended to get
back the 100,000 dollars
Mr. Elg owed you, correct?

<Tigre>
そうや。ワイには、
そのケンリがあるからのォ。
I loaned the guy the cash,
so that's my right.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ザンネンながら‥‥
Unfortunately for Mr. Elg...

１０００万円では、足りなかった。
‥‥それはもう、ゼンゼン。
...100,000 dollars wasn't
enough to cover it, was it?

<Tigre>
なんやて‥‥
Huh?

<Phoenix>
今から半年ほど前‥‥
あなたは、交通事故を起こした。
About 6 months ago, you were
involved in a traffic
accident, weren't you?

スクーターとクルマの接触事故。
ひとりの女性が、ケガを負った‥‥
An accident involving a car
and a scooter, in which a
young woman was injured.

女性は病院に運びこまれて、
手術を受けたそうです。
She was taken to the hospital,
where she underwent surgery.

<Tigre>
‥‥あ、アンタ‥‥
どこまで知っとるんやァ‥‥
Wh-Where did youse get all
this info...?

<Phoenix>
これが、そのときケガを負わせた
女性の診断書です。
These medical papers document
the treatment of the young
woman in question.

手術代として‥‥１億円が
請求されています。
According to these, her
operation cost...
one million dollars!

支払い期限は、去年の１２月中‥‥
どうやら、払えたようですね。
Payment for these expenses
was due in December of last
year, and was paid in full!

<Judge>
い‥‥イチオクエン‥‥！
な、なんとバカげた‥‥
O-One million dollars!? A 
preposterous sum! Someone
should sue these HMOs!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　そんな請求、
マジメに払うヤツはいねえぜ。
Ha...!
No one would pay a bill like
that.

医師会に持ちこめば、
その病院はアウト‥‥だ。
If the medical association got
wind of it, the hospital would
end up as dead as a morgue.

<Phoenix>
その金額がいくらであろうと、
彼は支払うしかなかった！
But Mr. Tigre had no choice
but to pay!

なにしろ、自分の命が
かかっているのですからね！
Because his very life depended
on it!

<Tigre>
ぐわおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
Grrraaaaaaaargh!

<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛に！　静粛に！
い‥‥“命”というのは‥‥！
O-Order! Order! Order!
You say his life depended on
it, Mr. Wright!?

<Phoenix>
《ケガをさせた女性》‥‥それが、
鹿羽　うらみさんだったのです。
Indeed it did. Simply because
the injured woman was none
other than Viola Cadaverini.

<Godot>
‥‥‥！
“シカバネ”‥‥だと？
...!
Did you say, "Cadaverini"?

<Phoenix>
この街の闇金融のボス、
《鹿羽組》組長・鹿羽　権太。
Bruto Cadaverini. Mob boss in
charge of all underworld
activities in the city, and...

鹿羽　うらみさんは、
そのマゴ娘です。
...doting grandfather to his
precious "Violetta", also
known as Viola Cadaverini.

<Godot>
ぐふおおおおおおッ！
Bwooooar!

<Phoenix>
“オトシマエ”をつけなければ、
命があぶない。‥‥だからこそ！
Your life was in danger unless
you paid "compensation" to the
boss, correct? It makes sense!

あなたは、なんとしても
１億円を用意するしかなかった！
You were desperate to acquire
the one million dollars
Cadaverini demanded of you!

そのために、岡　高夫さんの
命をギセイにしたのです！
So desperate, in fact, that
you decided to sacrifice Glen
Elg's life to pay your debt!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
しょ‥‥証人！　どうなのですか！
Order! Order! Order!
What do you say to that,
witness?

<Tigre>
‥‥ぐ‥‥ッ‥‥！
...Grrr... urgh...

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥オトナのおとぎ話は
そこまでだぜ、まるほどう‥‥
It's a nice little fairy tale,
Trite.

‥‥仮に、この証人が１億円を
必要としていたとしても‥‥
But even if the witness did
need a million dollars...

そいつは、岡　高夫の殺害とは
結びつかねえ！
...that doesn't tie him to
Mr. Elg's murder.

ヤツに貸した金は１０００万円！
しかも、返せるアテはなかった！
Mr. Elg only owed him 100,000
dollars, and had no hope of
repaying it anyway!

<Tigre>
そ‥‥そうや！　あんなオトコ、
クソほどの値打ちもあらへん！
Yeah. That guy wasn't worth
my spit!

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうじゃない。
“逆”なんですよ。
I don't think so.
In fact, the opposite is true.

<Godot>
ぎゃ‥‥“逆”‥‥だと？
The opposite?

<Phoenix>
返せるアテのない人間にカネを
貸すなど、本来はあり得ない。
Lending money with no hope of
ever seeing repayment would
normally be bad for business.

しかし‥‥
But...

この場合は、“返すアテがない”
ことこそが、重要でした。
In this case, the very fact
that Glen Elg had no way to
repay the money is crucial.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですって！
What!?

<Maya>
自分がナニを言ってるか、
わかってるの！　なるほどくん！
Do you know where you're going
with this, Nick?

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん。‥‥発想を
“逆転”させるんだ。
You've got to think outside
the box, Maya.

<Maya>
ぎゃくてん‥‥
Outside the box?

<Phoenix>
カンタンなコトさ。芝九蔵の狙いは
１０００万円じゃなかったんだ。
It's very straightforward.
Mr. Tigre wasn't after the
100,000 dollars at all.




<Judge>
‥‥弁護人には、何か
考えがあるようですね。
It seems you have a logical
conclusion for this theory,
Mr. Wright.

ここで、提示して
いただきましょう。
Would you care to share it
with us?

いったい‥‥この証人の“狙い”
とは、なんだったのか！
What exactly was Mr. Tigre
"after"?




<Judge>
な‥‥なんですか、
この証拠品は。
What is the meaning of this,
Mr. Wright!?

<Godot>
弁護人が、裁判所に行ったことが
ないことを示す証拠品だろうぜ。
It's evidence... that Trite
has no idea what he's doing.

<Phoenix>
な、何を言ってるんですか！
ぼくは、ここにこうして‥‥
What!?
What do you mean?

<Godot>
それだけ、マトはずれな
証拠だと言ってるんだ！
You're way off track, Trite.
That evidence is irrelevant!

<Phoenix>
（なんでコイツに
　ペナルティを食らうんだよ‥‥）
(Since when did he have the
right to dish out penalties?)

<Maya>
だ、だいじょうぶなの、
なるほどくん！
A-Are you alright, Nick?

<Phoenix>
芝九蔵が必要だったのは、
あくまでも１億円だ。
Mr. Tigre needed one million
dollars.

１０００万円を返してもらうだけ
じゃ、ダメだったんだ！
Recovering a loan worth
100,000 dollars wasn't enough.

（岡　高夫には、その大金を
　生み出すウデがあった‥‥）
(Besides, Elg had the means
to make that kind of money
if he wanted to.)


<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんは、
優秀なプログラマーでした。
Glen Elg was a programmer.
A highly skilled programmer.

この証人は、そのウデを
担保に、カネを貸したのです。
That skill was the collateral
Mr. Elg put up in order to
borrow the money.

<Godot>
プログラマーの‥‥“ウデ”‥‥
Care to explain how skill can
be used as collateral to
secure a loan, Trite?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータ・ウイルスです。
《クリーニング・ボンバー》！
He had the skill to create a
computer virus, and so he did.
A virus known as "MC Bomber"!

<Judge>
こんぴゅーた・ういるす‥‥
いったい、それはッ！
A "computer virus"?
What does one of those do?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータの内部を
破壊するプログラムです。
A computer virus is a program
that wreaks havoc on the
insides of a computer.

<Judge>
その“こんぴゅーた”というのは、
いったい‥‥？
A "computer"?
What does one of those do?

<Phoenix>
（そこから
　わからないのかよ！）
(I guess the beard isn't the
only part of His Honor that
is from the stone age!)

あとで、ゆっくり説明します。
とにかく、重要なポイントは‥‥
I'll explain it to you later,
Your Honor. Right now, this is
the important point...

このプログラムに、数億円の
価値がある、ということです！
A virus like "MC Bomber" would
be worth several million
dollars on the black market.

<Phoenix>
芝九蔵さん！
Mr. Tigre!

あなたは、１０００万円など
どうでもよかった！
You couldn't have cared less
about the 100,000 dollars!
Isn't that right?

狙いは、ただ１つ！　この
プログラムだったのです！
All you cared about was one
thing! The virus!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥ぐ‥‥‥
Grrr...

ぐわああああああああああああッ！
Grrraaaaaaaaaaaargh!




<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんから、１０００万円を
返してもらうつもりだった、と？
So you just intended to get
back the 100,000 dollars
Mr. Elg owed you, correct?

<Tigre>
そうや。ワイには、その
ケンリがあるからのォ。
I loaned the guy the cash,
so that's my right.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ザンネンながら‥‥
Unfortunately for Mr. Elg...

あなたの狙いは、１０００万円
なんかではなかったハズです。
I don't believe the 100,000
dollars is what you were
after.

<Objection!>

<Godot>
どういうことだ‥‥まるほどう。
What are you getting at,
Trite?

金貸しに、カネ以外
なんの狙いがあるというんだ！
What else would a moneylender
be after other than money!?

<Phoenix>
カネはカネでも‥‥
ケタがちがったんですよ。
Oh, the moneylender was after
money. But money in a totally
different league.

この、たった１枚のディスクに、
その価値があるのです！
The kind of money that a
single disc like this would
fetch!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Judge>
そ、それは‥‥？
What is that?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータ・ウイルスです。
《クリーニング・ボンバー》！
A computer virus, Your Honor.
A virus called "MC Bomber"!

<Judge>
こんぴゅーた・ういるす‥‥
いったい、それはッ！
A "computer virus"?
What does one of those do?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータの内部を
破壊するプログラムです。
A computer virus is a program
that wreaks havoc on the
insides of a computer.

<Judge>
その“こんぴゅーた”というのは、
いったい‥‥？
A "computer"?
What does one of those do?

<Phoenix>
（そこから
　わからないのかよ！）
(I guess the beard isn't the
only part of His Honor that
is from the stone age!)

あとで、ゆっくり説明します。
とにかく、重要なポイントは‥‥
I'll explain it to you later,
Your Honor. Right now, this is
the important point...

このプログラムに、数億円の
価値がある、ということです！
A virus like "MC Bomber" would
be worth several million
dollars on the black market.

<Judge>
す‥‥すうおくえん‥‥！
S-Several million dollars!?

<Phoenix>
返せるアテのない人間にカネを
貸すなど、本来はあり得ない。
Lending money with no hope of
ever seeing repayment would
normally be bad for business.

この場合‥‥“返すアテがない”
ことこそが、重要だったのです。
But in this case, the very
fact that Glen Elg had no way
to repay the money is crucial.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですって！
What!?

<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんは、
優秀なプログラマーでした。
Glen Elg was a programmer.
A highly skilled programmer.

この証人は、そのウデを
担保に、カネを貸したのです。
That skill was the collateral
Mr. Elg put up in order to
borrow the money.

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Objection!>

<Godot>
そのプログラムを手に入れる‥‥
それが《動機》だと言うつもりか？
You're trying to suggest the
witness's motive was to get
hold of that program?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そのとおりです。
Exactly.

<Godot>
そこの証人は、バカじゃねえ。
The witness may have poor
fashion sense, but he is by no
means an idiot, Trite.

殺人なんかしなくても
１億ぐらい、かせげただろうぜ。
A man like him could get his
hands on one million dollars
without resorting to murder.

<Phoenix>
あるいは、そうかもしれません。
‥‥時間さえあれば。
Of course he could...
Provided that he had time.

しかし‥‥どうしても、
その金が、“今”必要だとしたら？
But what if he had needed the
money right then?

緊急事態で‥‥手段を選ぶ
ヨユウがなかったとしたら‥‥？
When the pressure's on, the
luxury of choice tends to
disappear.




<Judge>
‥‥弁護人には、何か
考えがあるようですね。
It seems you have a logical
conclusion for this theory,
Mr. Wright.

ここで、提示して
いただきましょう。
Would you care to share it
with us?

この証人が、なぜ‥‥
億単位のカネを必要としたのか？
Why did Mr. Tigre need money
to the tune of one million
dollars?




<Judge>
な‥‥なんですか、
この証拠品は。
What is the meaning of this,
Mr. Wright!?

<Godot>
弁護人が、裁判所に行ったことが
ないことを示す証拠品だろうぜ。
It's evidence... that Trite
has no idea what he's doing.

<Phoenix>
な、何を言ってるんですか！
ぼくは、ここにこうして‥‥
What!?
What do you mean?

<Godot>
それだけ、マトはずれな
証拠だと言ってるんだ！
You're way off track, Trite.
That evidence is irrelevant!

<Phoenix>
（なんでコイツに
　ペナルティを食らうんだよ‥‥）
(Since when did he have the
right to dish out penalties?)

<Maya>
だ、だいじょうぶなの、
なるほどくん！
A-Are you alright, Nick?

<Phoenix>
芝九蔵は‥‥１０００万円じゃ
足りなかったんだよ。
100,000 dollars wasn't enough
for Mr. Tigre.

どうしても、もっとカネが
必要だった！　緊急に‥‥。
He needed much more money
than that. And in a hurry!


<Phoenix>
去年の１２月。あなたは多額の
カネが、どうしても必要だった！
In December of last year, you
found yourself in need of a
huge amount of money.

<Tigre>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Phoenix>
今から半年ほど前‥‥
あなたは、交通事故を起こした。
About 6 months ago, you were
involved in a traffic
accident, weren't you?

スクーターとクルマの接触事故。
ひとりの女性が、ケガを負った‥‥
An accident involving a car
and a scooter, in which a
young woman was injured.

女性は病院に運びこまれて、
手術を受けたそうです。
She was taken to the hospital,
where she underwent surgery.

<Tigre>
‥‥あ、アンタ‥‥
どこまで知っとるんやァ‥‥
Wh-Where did youse get all
this info...?

<Phoenix>
これが、そのときケガを負わせた
女性の診断書です。
These medical papers document
the treatment of the young
woman in question.

手術代として‥‥１億円が
請求されています。
According to these, her
operation cost...
one million dollars!

支払い期限は、去年の１２月中‥‥
どうやら、払えたようですね。
Payment for these expenses
was due in December of last
year, and was paid in full!

<Judge>
い‥‥イチオクエン‥‥！
な、なんとバカげた‥‥
O-One million dollars!? A
preposterous sum! Someone
should sue these HMOs!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　そんな請求、
マジメに払うヤツはいねえぜ。
Ha...!
No one would pay a bill like
that.

医師会に持ちこめば、
その病院はアウト‥‥だ。
If the medical association got
wind of it, the hospital would
end up as dead as a morgue.

<Phoenix>
その金額がいくらであろうと、
彼は支払うしかなかった！
But Mr. Tigre had no choice
but to pay!

なにしろ、自分の命が
かかっているのですからね！
Because his very life depended
on it!

<Tigre>
ぐわおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
Grrraaaaaaaargh!

<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛に！　静粛に！
い‥‥“命”というのは‥‥！
O-Order! Order! Order!
You say his life depended on
it, Mr. Wright!?

<Phoenix>
《ケガをさせた女性》‥‥それが、
鹿羽　うらみさんだったのです。
Indeed it did. Simply because
the injured woman was none
other than Viola Cadaverini.

<Godot>
‥‥‥！
“シカバネ”‥‥だと？
...!
Did you say, "Cadaverini"?

<Phoenix>
この街の闇金融のボス、
《鹿羽組》組長・鹿羽　権太。
Bruto Cadaverini. Mob boss in
charge of all underworld
activities in the city, and...

鹿羽　うらみさんは、
そのマゴ娘です。
...doting grandfather to his
precious "Violetta", also
known as Viola Cadaverini.

<Godot>
ぐふおおおおおおッ！
Bwooooar!

<Phoenix>
“オトシマエ”をつけなければ、
命があぶない。‥‥だからこそ！
Your life was in danger unless
you paid "compensation" to the
boss, correct? It makes sense!

あなたは、なんとしても
１億円を用意するしかなかった！
You were desperate to acquire
the one million dollars
Cadaverini demanded of you!

そのために、岡　高夫さんの
命をギセイにしたのです！
So desperate, in fact, that
you decided to sacrifice Glen
Elg's life to pay your debt!




<Phoenix>
あの日！　芝九蔵さんは、この
ＣＤを手に入れるつもりでした！
On the day of the murder,
Mr. Tigre's sole intention was
to get his hands on this CD!

岡　高夫さんに、１０００万円を
用意できるわけがない。
Glen Elg had no way of paying
back the 100,000 dollars,
and Mr. Tigre knew it.

‥‥しかし！　そこで、
《奇跡》が起こってしまった！
But then a miracle happened.

‥‥決して起こっては
ならない、《奇跡》が‥‥！
The kind that Mr. Tigre would
prefer to say never happened.
But he can't. Neither can I.

<Godot>
‥‥宝クジ‥‥か！
The lottery win?

<Phoenix>
最後の最後‥‥岡　高夫さんは
５０００万円を当ててしまった！
Exactly! At the eleventh hour,
Mr. Elg won half a million
dollars on the lottery!

これで‥‥芝九蔵さんは、ＣＤを
手に入れることはできなくなった。
Which left Mr. Tigre with no
way of getting his hands on
the all-important CD.

フツウの手段では‥‥。
At least, no legitimate way.

<Phoenix>
‥‥だから。
フツウじゃない手段を使った！
So he resorted to illegitimate
means.

<Godot>
ば‥‥バカな！
That's crazy!

<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さんを殺害して‥‥
さらに犯人は、次の手を打った。
He murdered Glen Elg, and then
made his next move...

‥‥そのツミを、
須々木　マコに着せる工作です。
To frame Maggey Byrde for
the crime!

岡　高夫になりすました
芝九蔵　虎ノ助と、
Mr. Tigre posed as Glen Elg...

須々木　マコを演じた
鹿羽　うらみ‥‥。
...while Viola Cadaverini
played the role of Ms. Byrde.

２人は、犯行を再現した！
‥‥《目撃者》を作るために。
And then they re-enacted the
whole thing, in order to
establish a witness.

その《目撃者》こそが、
五十嵐　将兵さんだったのです！
The witness being the one we
all heard testify yesterday,
Mr. Victor Kudo.

<Objection!>

<Godot>
バカな！　そんな大がかりな
シカケ‥‥不可能に決まっている！
Like I said, Trite, that's
crazy. No one could pull off
a stunt like that.

どうしたって、あのシェフに
気づかれちまっただろうぜ！
For starters, there's no way
the chef could've been kept
out of it.

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
もちろん、本土坊さんは
計画を知っていたのです！
But Mr. Armstrong knew all
about it.

‥‥お忘れですか？
Have you forgotten already,
Mr. Godot?

店長の本土坊さんは、証人に
５０００万円の借金があった。
Mr. Armstrong owed the witness
money, too. Half a million
dollars, in fact.

だから！　芝九蔵　虎ノ助に
協力するしかなかったのです！
He had no choice but to go
along with Mr. Tigre's plan!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛にぃッ！
静まらなければ、退廷を‥‥
Order! Order!
Silence, or I will clear the
courtroom!

<Tigre>
ぐわーっはっはっはっはっはっは！
Grrraah ha ha ha ha hah!

‥‥アホもここまで来れば
リッパなゲージュツやのぉ‥‥
Youse put on a good show,
Spikey!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Tigre>
金貸しはなァ。用心深くなきゃ
生きていけへんショーバイや。
If youse wanna stay alive in
the loan shark business, you'
gotta be careful.

被害者に変装して、目撃者を作って
ツミを着せる工作をした、やてェ？
Youse sayin' I dressed up
like that kid, created a
witness, and framed someone?

そないなコトしたら、
よけいなショーコを残すだけや！
If I did something crazy
like that, I'd leave a trail
as bright as my shirt!

そんな中途ハンパなコト、
ワイはせえへんでェ！
I ain't dumb enough to do
something sloppy like that!

<Phoenix>
そのとおり。
I agree.

<Tigre>
な‥‥なんや‥‥ッ！
Whaaat!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥あなたは見かけによらず、
用心深い。
Despite your appearance, you
are very careful.

だから‥‥さらに
もう１つ、用意したのです。
That's why you took one more
precaution.

須々木　マコを、カクジツに
有罪にするためのワナをッ！
One more trick to make sure
Ms. Byrde had no way out!

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですって！
まだ、ワナがあったのですか‥‥！
What!? Another one,
Mr. Wright!?




<Godot>
‥‥おもしろい。
見せてもらおうじゃねえか‥‥
Interesting.
Why don't you fill us all in,
Trite?

芝九蔵　虎ノ助が被告人にしかけた
もう１つのワナ、ってヤツを！
What was this trick you say
Mr. Tigre performed to frame
the accused?




<Godot>
‥‥で？　今のコレは、なんだ。
まるほどう‥‥？
And?
What's the relevance of that,
Trite?

<Phoenix>
え！　あの‥‥
ちょっとした、アイサツです。
Um...
It's, uh... just a little
intro...

<Godot>
‥‥まったく、
とんだごアイサツ、だぜ。
An intro into what?

<Judge>
どうやら‥‥すべては、この
弁護人のワナだったようですな。
It seems all this has been an
elaborate trick on the part of
the defense.

<Phoenix>
ま、待ってください！
No! Wait!

芝九蔵　虎ノ助のワナは、
たしかに存在したのです！
Mr. Tigre did play a trick!
A huge trick!





<Judge>
そこまで！
That's enough!

本法廷は、これ以上の審議の
必要性を認めません。
This court sees no reason to
further prolong the trial.

さらに、被告に対する判決を
決める時間も、必要としません。
Nor is there any need for
more time to decide the case
against the defendant.

これは、きわめて明白な事件です。
疑問の余地はない！
This case is extremely clear.
I see no room for mis-
interpretation of the facts.

被告人、須々木　マコに
たった今、判決を言いわたします！
This court finds the
defendant, Maggey Byrde...

被告人はこれより身柄を
司直に預けるものとし、
The accused will surrender
to the court immediately...

１ヶ月以内に、高等裁判所において
通常裁判を受けることとします。
...to be held pending trial at
a higher court within a month
from today's date.

では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
That is all.
This court is adjourned!




