<Atmey>
‥‥どういうコト‥‥ですかな？
貴方の指紋、というのは‥‥
So what is all this fuss
about fingerprints anyway...?

<Phoenix>
哀牙さん‥‥。
きのうのこと、覚えてますよね？
Mr. Atmey...
Do you recall the events
of yesterday?

<Maya>
ほらほら、なるほどくん。
出番だよ。
Hey, Nick! Come on!
Open it up!

<Phoenix>
え！　マズいだろ
勝手にさわっちゃ！
Hey! Wait a minute!
We can't just open his
private property!

<Maya>
いいって、いいって。
さっさと調査する。
Don't be such a fuddy-duddy!
This is an important
investigation!

どう？　何が入ってる？
Well? What's in there?

<Phoenix>
ちょ、ちょっと待てよ。
今、取り出すから‥‥
H-Hang on a sec.
I'm taking it out now...

（どうやら‥‥何か、つるつるで
　カタいもの‥‥みたいだな‥‥）
(Whatever it is, it feels...
kinda hard... and smooth...)

<Atmey>
‥‥あいや、しばらくッ！
...Well, hello there!!

<Phoenix>
あのとき‥‥たしかにぼくは、
バッグの中は見なかった。
It's true that I didn't get
a chance to look in the
bag at that time.

でも‥‥
But!

その中のモノに、
さわっていたんですよ。
I did touch what was inside.

<Atmey>
‥‥な、なんと！
さ、“さわった”‥‥？
Wh-What!?
Y-You touched it...?

<Phoenix>
キオクに残っていますからね。
“つるつるでカタいものだった”
And I remember it very well.
It was "smooth and hard".

<Atmey>
あ‥‥あいや‥‥
それは、しばらく‥‥
W-Well, err...
Th-That was just...

<Phoenix>
裁判長！　そのツボの
指紋を調べてください！
Your Honor! I'd like the court
to examine the fingerprints on
that urn.

もし、ぼくの指紋が
ついていれば‥‥
If my fingerprints are
on there...

あのツボは、哀牙探偵の
事務所にあったことになります！
Then it proves that the urn
was in Detective Atmey's
office!

<Objection!>

<Godot>
ツボに指紋が残っていたとして‥‥
Well, even if your 
fingerprints are on the urn...

それが“いつ”付着したものか、
立証できるのかい？
...it still doesn't prove when
they were put there, does it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥もちろんです。
Of course it does.

<Godot>
な、なんだと‥‥
Wh-What did you say!?

<Phoenix>
秘宝展のセキニンシャ・華宮　霧緒
さんは、こう言っています。
Not what I said, it's what
Adrian Andrews, the person in
charge of the exhibition said.

<Andrews>
でも‥‥私、いっしょうけんめい
ピカピカにみがいて、
I polished it until it was
just about glowing...

少しでも高そうに見えるように
がんばったんですよ！
I thought maybe I could make
it look more valuable!

<Phoenix>
ツボはピカピカにみがかれて、
すべての指紋が消されていました。
If she polished it that much,
she must have removed any
and all fingerprints on it.

ぼくが、ツボに指紋を
つけられるチャンスは‥‥
And the only chance I had
to get my fingerprints on
it after that was...

きのう！　哀牙探偵事務所しか
なかったんですよ！
Yesterday!
At the Atmey Detective Agency!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　この、
ゴドー・ブレンド１０７号‥‥
Ha...!
This blend...
Godot Blend #107...

ちょっとばかり‥‥
苦味がすぎたようだぜ！
I've decided...
It's a little too bitter
after all!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
弁護人の要請を受け入れます！
Order! Order! Order!
I accept the defense's
request!

係官！　至急、このツボを‥‥
Bailiff!
Take this urn and...

<Atmey>
あいやッ！
Wait!

待たれよ、ご老人。
‥‥その必要はございませぬぞ。
Wait a moment, Your Honor!
...There's no need for that.

<Judge>
しょ‥‥証人‥‥？
N-No need you say...?

<Atmey>
さよう‥‥そのツボには、
弁護士殿の指紋が残っている‥‥
Precisely...
I already know Mr. Wright's
fingerprints are on the urn...

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですって！
Wh-What are you saying!

<Phoenix>
（ついに‥‥打ち崩した！）
(Yes! I've finally broken
him down!)

<Atmey>
あーっはっはっはっはっはっは！
はっはっはっはっはっはっ！
Hee hee hee ha ha ha
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ho ho ho hee hee hee!

‥‥さあさあみなさん、
ごらんくださあい‥‥！
Take a good look,
everyone!

天才にふさわしき好敵手を求めて、
ついに自ら犯罪に手を染めた‥‥
Unable to find a rival worthy
of my genius, I was forced to
create one by myself!

あわれなピエロでござあい‥‥
Here I am!
The tragic clown...

<Maya>
‥‥なんかモーレツに
アブないよ、あのヒト‥‥
This guy is nuttier than
a fruitcake...

<Atmey>
やあれ！　この我こそが、
かの仮面マスクだった！
You see! It was me all along!
I am the one and only
Mask☆DeMasque!

さよう！　みなさん、
楽しんでいただけましたかな‥‥！
Ha ha! I hope you all enjoyed
my little performance!

あーっはっはっはっはっはっは！
はっはっはっはっはっはっ！
Hee hee hee ha ha ha
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ho ho ho hee hee hee!



<Judge>
それで‥‥ゴドー検事。
星威岳　哀牙は‥‥？
Well, Mr. Godot...
What's Mr. Atmey's
condition?

<Godot>
控え室で高笑いしているぜ。
He's still in the lobby,
laughing insanely, Your Honor.

‥‥オレも、あれぐらい
楽しそうに笑ってみたいもんだ。
I wish I could enjoy the
joke as much as he seems
to be.

<Judge>
‥‥どうやら‥‥
コタエが出たようですね。
Well, it looks like the
matter has been settled.

ワレワレはもう少しで、無実の
青年に汚名を着せるところでした。
I came perilously close to
besmirching the record of
an innocent young man.

‥‥おぞましき“怪人”の汚名を。
Besmirching him with
the title of "thief"!

<Maya>
やっぱり‥‥
なるほどくんが正しかったんだね！
Nick, you were right
after all!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥‥優作くんは、
　怪人じゃなかったんだ！）
(Yeah! I guess Mr. DeLite
really wasn't the thief!)

<Judge>
それでは、天杉　優作くんに
判決を言いわたします。
The court finds the defendant,
Mr. Ron DeLite...

<Hold it!>

<Ron>
ちがう！　だから、ちがうんです！
‥‥‥‥いや。
You're wrong!
Wrong I tell you!
Err, umm, I mean...

ちがう、っていうか、むしろ
まちがってる、っていうか、それも
Not exactly wrong so much,
but actually not right is what
I was really trying to say

<Phoenix>
（お、おいおい‥‥まさか‥‥）
(Oh no... He's not...
This can't be happening...)

<Ron>
その、おぞましき怪人の件
なんですけど‥‥
The thief... The sneaky,
odious thief who's been
stealing all the treasures...

怪人は、ボクなんです！
っていうか、ボク、怪人なんです！
It's me! I'm him!
I'm the one you want!
I'm the thief I tell you!

だから‥‥有罪にしちゃって
くださーーーい！
So do it...!
Pronounce me guilty!
Pleeeease!!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Godot>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

< >
　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
............

<Judge>
今までの審理は、いったい
なんだったのでしょうか。
I don't know what kind of
a kangaroo court you all
think this is, but...

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
怪人の正体は立証されました！
早いトコ、判決を‥‥
The true identity of the thief
has already been proven!
Please hurry and pass judg--

<Ron>
ナニ言ってるんですか！
だって‥‥怪人はボクなんですッ！
What are you talking about!?
I already confessed!
I'm the thief I tell you!

<Judge>
‥‥ゴドー検事！
そこでコーヒーを飲まない！
...Mr. Godot!
Don't just stand there
drinking coffee!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　おい、怪人さんよォ。
Ha...!
Hey there, Mr. Thief...

<Ron>
は、はい！　なんですか！
Y-Yes! Yes, sir!?

<Godot>
アンタもオトコなら、
自分のケツは自分でふくコトだ。
If you're really a man, then
clean up your own mess.

<Ron>
あの‥‥。スミマセンが
イミがわかりません。
I-I'm sorry...
I'm afraid I just don't have
any idea what you mean.

<Godot>
テメエで証明するんだ。
‥‥仮面マスクは自分だ、ってな。
If you are Mask☆DeMasque...
then prove it.
That's what it means.

<Ron>
は‥‥はい！　よろこんで！
Y-Yes, sir!
I'll be happy to!

<Maya>
よろこんでるよ、なるほどくん‥‥
He says he'll be happy
to, Nick...

<Phoenix>
‥‥正直なところ‥‥
かなり、セツない。
It's kinda cute...
He's 100% committed to his
fantasy.

<Godot>
よおし、イイ子だ。
‥‥ただし！
Good boy!
Just remember one thing.

オトコになるチャンスは‥‥
いつだって、たった一度きりだぜ。
A boy only gets one chance
in his life to become a man!

<Ron>
も‥‥モチロンです！
ボク‥‥ボク、がんばります！
I-I know that!
I-I won't fail! I swear!

<Godot>
じゃあ、話してみな。
‥‥聞いてやるぜ。
OK, then... Talk!
...We're all listening.

<Judge>
ヤレヤレ‥‥しかたありませんな。
聞いてみるとしましょうか‥‥。
Oh well... Let's all have a
listen to this "confession"...

< >
～仮面マスクの正体～
-- Mask☆DeMasque's Identity --

<Ron>
じつは、このボクが
怪人☆仮面マスクだったんです！
The truth is, I've been
Mask☆DeMasque all along!

‥‥逆に、ボクが仮面マスクじゃ
ないって、証明できますか！
I mean, you can't prove
that I'm not actually
Mask☆DeMasque, can you?

ツボが盗まれた夜のアリバイだって
ちゃーんと、ありませんしね！
I don't have an alibi
for the night the urn
was stolen, after all!

あの晩、ボク、仮面マスクのカッコ
をして、現場に舞いおりたんです。
I donned my costume that
night and dancingly descended
upon the scene of the crime!

ホラ。写真にも写ってる
じゃないですか！　このボクが。
Look! You can see right
there in the photo!
That's me!

エンブレムなら‥‥ドアのふちに
引っかけて、取れちゃったんです！
As for my broach, I snagged
it on the door handle and
it got torn off, that's all!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。ヤッカイなことに
なってきましたな‥‥
Hmm...
I don't like the direction
this trial has taken...

<Phoenix>
（いつものことだけど‥‥）
(But this is how every
trial goes...
At least with me, anyway...)

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
やればできるじゃねえか。
Ha...!
You're doing great!

<Ron>
へへへ‥‥。
テレちゃいますね、なんか。
Hee hee hee...
Stop it, Mr. Godot...
You're embarrassing me.

<Godot>
‥‥ヤクソクどおり、アンタの
証言はこれ１回きりだ。
Like I said, you're only
going to get one chance
to testify, alright?

‥‥この証言を守り抜けば‥‥
オレもヤクソクは守るぜ。
But if you make it through
this with flying colors, I'll
keep my promise, too.

怪人☆仮面マスクとして、
アンタの拘留をつづけてやるさ。
I'll make sure you stay locked
up in prison as the one and
only true Mask☆DeMasque!

<Ron>
ヨロシクおねがいします！
ボク‥‥がんばります！
Thanks so much, Mr. Godot!
I... I'll do my best!

<Judge>
‥‥それでは弁護人。
ゴクロウですが、尋問を。
Alright, Mr. Wright.
I'm afraid it's time for the
cross-examination.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥。
*sigh*

< >
～仮面マスクの正体～
-- Mask☆DeMasque's Identity --




<Ron>
じつは、このボクが
怪人☆仮面マスクだったんです！
The truth is, I've been
Mask☆DeMasque all along!


<Ron>
‥‥逆に、ボクが仮面マスクじゃ
ないって、証明できますか！
I mean, you can't prove
that I'm not actually
Mask☆DeMasque, can you?


<Ron>
ツボが盗まれた夜のアリバイだって
ちゃーんと、ありませんしね！
I don't have an alibi
for the night the urn
was stolen, after all!


<Ron>
あの晩、ボク、仮面マスクのカッコ
をして、現場に舞いおりたんです。
I donned my costume that
night and dancingly descended
upon the scene of the crime!


<Ron>
ホラ。写真にも写ってる
じゃないですか！　このボクが。
Look! You can see right
there in the photo!
That's me!


<Ron>
エンブレムなら‥‥ドアのふちに
引っかけて、取れちゃったんです！
As for my broach, I snagged
it on the door handle and
it got torn off, that's all!


<Maya>
なんで優作さん、ここまで
怪人になりたがるのかなあ。
Why does Mr. DeLite want to be
Mask☆DeMasque so badly
anyway? It's kinda disturbing.

目立ちたがり屋、ってワケでも
なさそうなのに。
He doesn't seem like your
typical attention whore to me.

‥‥なるほどくんとちがって。
Unlike, say... you, Nick.

<Phoenix>
ぼくは目立ちたがり屋じゃないぞ。
（とはいえ‥‥）
I am nothing of the sort,
thank you very much.

（たしかに、どうも不自然だよな、
　優作くんのタイドは‥‥）
(But I gotta admit it is kinda
scary the way Ron acts...)

<Maya>
とにかく‥‥この証言の“穴”を
見つけるしかないね！
Anyway...
Time to poke some holes in
that testimony of his!

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
でも‥‥、まれかさんのハナシ
では、そう思いこんでいるだけ‥‥
You may think you're the real
Mask☆DeMasque... but your
wife thinks you're delusional.

<Ron>
まれかちゃんには、まだ話して
いないんです。ボクの正体‥‥
I haven't told Dessie yet...
About my true identity,
I mean...

あの。いろいろ事情がありまして。
Believe me, I've got my
reasons.

<Phoenix>
（話さなくても、あの部屋を見れば
　わかりそうな気もするけど‥‥）
(With the way your room
is decked out, how could she
NOT know about it...?)

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。怪人にも、フクザツな
家庭の事情があるのですねえ。
Hmm...
Even thieves have complicated
family situations, I suppose.

<Phoenix>
（どうする？　あまり、
　カンケイなさそうだけど‥‥）
(What should I do?
It sounds like we're about to
get sidetracked... again.)



<Phoenix>
どうして、奥さんに
キチンと打ち明けないんですか？
So why are you withholding
the truth from your wife?

<Ron>
きっと、話しても
信じてくれないだろうし‥‥
Well... first of all, I don't
think she'd believe me
anyway...

それに、まれかちゃん‥‥
大ッキライなんです。
And second...
If there's one thing that
Dessie absolutely detests...

‥‥その。犯罪者が。
...it's criminals.

<Judge>
それならば、なぜ
怪人業を始めたのですかな？
If that's the case, then
why did you ever start
thieving to begin with?

<Ron>
まれかちゃん。お金を
使うのが大好きで‥‥、
Well, Dessie is crazy about
shopping. She's a real
shopaholic...

そしてボク、お金を使う
まれかちゃんが好きだから‥‥
But she's the love of my life,
Your Honor. I guess you could
say I'm a "Dessie-aholic"...

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。やはり、フクザツな
家庭の事情があるのですねえ。
Hmm...
So you do have a complicated
family situation after all.

<Phoenix>
‥‥もう、いいです。
証言をつづけてください。
...Alright, that's enough.
Please continue with your
testimony. I beg of you.

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
（ヒトの家庭にクチをつっこんでも
　しかたないか‥‥）
(There's no point in digging
through any more of their
dirty laundry...)

じゃあ‥‥とりあえず、
証言をつづけてもらえますか。
Well, why don't you continue
with your testimony for now.

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
あの‥‥今は、きみが自分で
証明するハズでしょう。
Umm... I thought you were
going to be the one to show
US the proof.

“怪人☆仮面マスクの正体が
　天杉　優作である”‥‥って。
You know, that you're the real
Mask☆DeMasque and not just
some kind of obsessed fanboy.

<Ron>
‥‥な。なんでもボクに
押しつけないでくださーーーい！
Hey now, that's not fair.
Why do I have to do all the
hard work anywaaaaaay!?

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Maybe because you're the
one making the outrageous
claim... for a change.)

<Maya>
ダメだよ、なるほどくん。
優作さんにできるワケないって。
Come on, Nick! You know
that Mr. DeLite couldn't have
committed the crime!

ここはあたしたちが、バシッと
証拠をたたきつけてあげないと。
You're the one with the fancy
law degree! It's time to put
it to work already!

<Phoenix>
《優作くんは仮面マスクじゃない》
‥‥っていう証拠か。
I need some kind of proof
that Ron couldn't possibly
be Mask☆DeMasque...

<Maya>
でも‥‥それがあれば、
苦労しないよね‥‥。
Well, I guess if you had that
kind of proof, we wouldn't
still be here, would we...?

<Phoenix>
（とりあえず‥‥）
(For the time being, maybe
I need to shift strategy...)

（優作くんが、ツボを盗めなかった
　‥‥そいつを立証してみるか）
(I should try to show that
Mr. DeLite couldn't have
stolen the urn.)

<Ron>
とにかく、ボク‥‥
Anyway, I...

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
アリバイ‥‥ですか。
You've got no alibi...?

<Judge>
私も、このシゴトはもう
長いのですが‥‥
I've been a judge for a
long time...

アリバイがないのをイバる
被告人は、初めてですな。
And this is the first time
I've ever heard a defendant
brag about having no alibi.

<Ron>
だってボク、あの晩は高菱屋に
いましたから！　‥‥‥‥いや。
But I tell you I was in
Lordly Tailor that night!
...Errr, no.

それじゃアイマイだな。ちゃんと、
高菱屋百貨店の地下倉庫って言って
That's too vague, even for me.
To be more precise, I was down
in the basement warehouse

<Phoenix>
（待てよ‥‥）
(Hold on...)

<Maya>
どうしたの？　なるほどくん。
What is it, Nick?

<Phoenix>
事件があった時間、
優作くんがどこにいたか‥‥？
Where was Ron DeLite when the
crime happened anyway...?

彼のアリバイが立証できれば、
話はカンタンだな、って思って。
If we can prove he had an
alibi after all, this case
will be a piece of cake.

<Maya>
そ、そりゃそうだけど‥‥
W-Well, you're right, but...

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　アンタに
そいつが立証できるってのかい？
Ha...!
You think you can prove that?
Wake up and smell the coffee!

<Phoenix>
そ、それは‥‥
W-Well, I think maybe I can...

<Judge>
成歩堂くん。被告人のアリバイを
立証する、証拠があるのですかな？
Mr. Wright, do you have any
evidence that shows the
defendant has an alibi?



<Phoenix>
あるワケないじゃないですか、
そんな証拠が！
Of course not!
Don't be ridiculous!

<Judge>
す、スミマセン！
I-I'm sorry!

‥‥って、なんで私に
怒るんですか！
...Say!
What am I apologizing for!?

コラ、証人！　あなたが
さっさと証言しないからです！
You! Witness!
Hurry up with your testimony
already!

<Ron>
す、スミマセン！
I-I'm sorry!

‥‥ケッキョク、いっつもボクが
とばっちりを食らっちゃうんだよな
...Why is it that I'm always
the one that has to apologize
to everyone in the end

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
ありますよ、証拠ぐらい！
I have the evidence!
Or do you think I'm still some
sort of third-rate rookie!?

<Judge>
お。めずらしく強気ですね。
Oh...!
I-I've never seen you
this angry before!

<Godot>
‥‥そうだ。オトコは、ミジメな
ときこそ強気でなきゃいけねえ。
...I'm not surprised.
Anger is the last refuge
of the pathetic.

<Phoenix>
（ベツに今は、とりたてて
　ミジメとも思えないけど‥‥）
(I thought I was more
confident than angry...)

<Judge>
それでは、提示して
いただきましょうか。
Well then, let's see
this evidence already.

被告人があの晩、どこにいたか？
‥‥それを立証する証拠品を！
Show to this court evidence
that proves where your client
was on the night of the crime!




<Phoenix>
その証拠は、コイツです！
Here's the evidence!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　そうさ、まるほどう。
Ha...!
It looks like I was right.
...Mr. Trite.

オトコはミジメなときほど、
指をつきつけなきゃいけねえ。
The more pathetic a man is,
the more likely he is to
start pointing fingers!

<Phoenix>
（なんとしても、ぼくを
　ミジメにしたいらしいな‥‥）
For some reason, the good
Prosecutor really wants to
prove that I'm "pathetic"...

<Judge>
ジッサイ、ミジメですからな、
この証拠品は。
That's because you are
pathetic!
And so is your "evidence"!

<Phoenix>
（ぼくの見こみちがい
　だったか‥‥）
(Oops. I guess I was wrong...
Again.)

<Ron>
じゃあ、ボクのアリバイは
やっぱり、なかったってコトで。
Aha! I told you I didn't
have an alibi!

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
舞いおりた‥‥って、
どこからですか？
"Dancingly descended"...?
From where exactly?

<Ron>
え。それは、入り口のドアから
ですけど、モチロン。
Well... From the entrance,
I suppose. Where else?

<Phoenix>
（“舞い”も“おりる”も
　カンケイないじゃないか！）
(So in actuality, he neither
"danced" nor "descended"!
...Someone save me. Again.)

<Maya>
やっぱり、“舞いおりる”って
言ったほうが、怪人っぽいからね。
I guess he thinks "descended"
sounds more heroic or
thief-like or something.

<Ron>
と、とにかく！　ボクが現場に
いたのは、ハッキリしてます！
A-Anyway! I was there at the
crime scene! Just like I said!

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
哀牙探偵の防犯カメラが
撮影した写真ですね‥‥。
This is the photo that was
taken by the security camera
at the crime scene...

<Judge>
‥‥たしかに、仮面マスクが
写っていますな。
No doubt about it.
That's Mask☆DeMasque.

<Phoenix>
しかし‥‥この怪人は、
さっきも問題になりました。
Yes, but don't forget there's
something important missing.

ホンモノの怪人は、ムネに
エンブレムをつけているはずです！
The real Mask☆DeMasque has
a big broach on his chest!

<Ron>



<Phoenix>
‥‥気がつかなかったんですか？
エンブレムが取れたとき。
You didn't notice it when
your broach was torn off?

<Ron>
え！　その‥‥キンチョーします
からね。怪人やってると。
Huh!?
W-Well... I'm always a little
nervous when I'm working.

<Phoenix>
（エンブレムのウラには、
　衣装の切れはしがついていた）
(There's a bit of clothing
left on the back side of
the broach.)

（そうカンタンに取れるとは
　思えないけどな‥‥）
(I don't think it could have
been torn off that easily...)

<Maya>
でも‥‥それって、今は
カンケイないんじゃないかな。
Yes, but... I don't see what
that has to do with anything.

立証するのは《優作さんは
怪人じゃない》ってコトでしょ。
Right now we're trying to
prove that Mr. DeLite isn't
the thief, right?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうだね。
（もう一度、証言を聞いてみるか）
Yeah, I guess so.
(Let me hear that testimony
one more time.)


<Phoenix>
被告人。‥‥これ、
モチロン知っていますね？
Mr. DeLite...
I believe you've seen
this before, correct?

<Ron>
あ‥‥ッ！　それは‥‥！
Ah...! Th-That's...!

<Judge>
なんですか？
What is it?

<Phoenix>
脅迫状です。
‥‥そう書いてありますから。
A blackmail letter.
That's what it looks like
from the contents.

<Judge>
きょうはくじょう‥‥
B-Blackmail...?

<Phoenix>
これによると‥‥
事件当夜の、午前１時。
According to this letter,
at 1 o'clock in the morning
on the night of the crime...

被告人・天杉　優作は、ＫＢ警備
という会社に呼び出されている！
...Mr. Ron DeLite was ordered
to go to the offices of
KB Security!

<Judge>
ご、午前１時‥‥？
1 o'clock in the morning!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうなんです。
その時間は、まさに‥‥
Correct.

犯行写真が撮影された時刻です！
Which is around the time
the security camera
photo was taken!

<Phoenix>
午前１時に、この被告人が
警備会社にいたのならば‥‥
So if the defendant was at
KB Security at 1 o'clock
in the morning...

そのアリバイは、カンゼンに
成立します！
...then that proves that he
has a watertight alibi!

<Ron>
うわわうわわッ！
Noooooo!

<Phoenix>
ちなみに、高菱屋百貨店から
ＫＢ警備会社までのキョリは‥‥
Furthermore, considering the
distance between Lordly
Tailor and KB Security...

クルマで約３０分もあるのです。
（‥‥と、矢張が言ってたな‥‥）
...it would have taken 30
minutes to get there by car!
(According to Larry anyway...)

<Judge>
いかがですかッ、ゴドー検事！
Well, Mr. Godot!?
Do you have anything to say?

だから、コーヒーを飲まない！
And stop drinking that coffee!

<Godot>
‥‥オイ怪人。出番だぜ。
あの弁護士に、反論してやれよ！
...Come on, Mr. Thief.
Don't let this guy beat you!
Tell him why he's wrong!

<Ron>
ボクのコト怪人って呼んでくれるの
‥‥アナタだけです！
You're the only one who calls
me "thief", Mr. Godot...

ボク、やってみます！
‥‥がんばりますッ！
...Alright, I'll try!
I-I'll do it! I will!

<Maya>
‥‥かなりヤル気になってるよ。
...He's really got
Mr. DeLite all worked up...

<Phoenix>
‥‥かなりヤル気をそがれたよ。
Yeah, he's like a kid at his
first day of school...

<Ron>
成歩堂さん！　たしかに、ボク
‥‥脅迫状を受け取りました。
Mr. Wright!
It's true that I received
that blackmail letter.

でもッ！
But...

ジッサイにそこへ行ったかどうかは
ベツの問題‥‥ですよね？
Whether or not I actually
went there is a whole
different story... right?

あ。いや、どうなんだろ。
ボク、ヘンなコト言っちゃったかな
Oh, err, sorry if I'm sounding
dramatic... I guess I don't
know what I'm talking about

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　ボウヤにしては
上出来、だぜ。
Ha...!
That was brilliant!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥どうやら、もう１つ。
証拠品が必要のようですな。
Hmm... Well, Mr. Wright?
It looks like you need some
more evidence after all.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥くそお、怪人め‥‥）
(Grrr! This stupid kid...!)




<Judge>
それでは、弁護人。
証拠品の提示を要求します。
Now then.
Let's see your evidence.

脅迫状で呼び出された被告人が、
本当にＫＢ警備へ行った証拠を！
Demonstrate to this court that
Mr. DeLite actually went to
KB Security that night!




<Phoenix>
その証拠は、これです！
Here is your evidence!

<Ron>
‥‥どういうことですか？
説明してください、成歩堂さん。
...What is this supposed to
mean, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
え！　それは‥‥わかるでしょう？
Huh!? Well, um...
Don't you know?

<Ron>
成歩堂さん。オトコなら‥‥
自分のケツは自分でふかないと。
Mr. Wright...
If you're a real man, you
should clean up your own mess.

<Phoenix>
うぐぐ‥‥ッ！
（‥‥なんか、ハラ立つなあ）
Doh...!
(For some reason, it bothers
me more when HE says it!)


<Phoenix>
優作くん。これ‥‥、
きみのサイフだね？
Mr. DeLite.
This wallet belongs to
you, correct?

<Ron>
あ！　‥‥は、はい。ボク、
落としちゃったんですよ、それ！
Ah!
Y-Yes. It-It does.
I-I had lost it somewhere!

<Judge>
コラ、弁護人。拾ったらすぐ、
交番に届けなさい！
Mr. Wright! When you find a
wallet, you should report it
to the police right away!

<Phoenix>
い‥‥いやいや。
いちおうコレ、証拠品ですから。
Ah! No! You don't understand.
This is an important
piece of evidence.

<Judge>
“証拠品”‥‥‥？
"Evidence"...?

<Phoenix>
優作くん。サイフを落としたの、
いつごろのコトですか？
Mr. DeLite... When did you
first notice that you'd lost
your wallet?

<Ron>
ええと‥‥事件があった夜だと
思いますケド。
Err, let's see...
I think it was on the
night of the crime...

まれかちゃんと晩ゴハンを食べに
行ったときは、まだあったから。
But I know I still had it
when Dessie and I went
out for dinner.

<Phoenix>
このサイフは‥‥午前１時ごろ。
ＫＢ警備のビルで発見されました。
This wallet was found at
approximately 1:00 AM at
KB Security headquarters.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですと！
What...!?
Surely you're not serious!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥結論は、ただ１つ！
Yes... I am serious.

天杉　優作は、あの晩！
ＫＢ警備に行ったのです！
This proves that Mr. DeLite
was, in fact, at KB Security
that night!

<Ron>
うわわうわわッ！
Noooooo!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
Ha...!

‥‥ロマンチストは哀しいぜ。
現実ってヤツを見ようとしねえ。
This is indeed sad...
Romanticists are blind to the
reality that lay before them.

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうことですか？
...Huh? What does that mean?

<Godot>
なぜ、このボウヤが警備会社で
サイフなんて落とす必要がある？
Why did Mr. DeLite drop his
wallet at KB Security?
What purpose did it serve?

まるで、ニセのアリバイを
作るため、ワザと置いたみたいに！
Perhaps it was dropped by his
wife to create a false alibi
for her dear husband instead!

<Phoenix>
それは、きっと‥‥コイツを
使ったときに落としたんでしょう。
Sorry, but Mr. DeLite probably
dropped it himself when he
went to use this!

<Phoenix>
ＫＢ警備会社の社長室に
入るためのカードです。
The key card to KB Security's
CEO's office.

<Godot>
しゃ、社長室‥‥だと‥‥？
CEO's... office?

<Phoenix>
‥‥おわかりになりましたか？
What's wrong?
No snappy comebacks?

優作くんはあの晩の午前１時、
ＫＢ警備の社長室に入ったのです！
The fact is that Mr. DeLite
entered the CEO's office
around 1 o'clock that night!




<Phoenix>
優作くん。これ‥‥、
きみのサイフだね？
Mr. DeLite.
This wallet belongs to
you, correct?

<Ron>
あ！　‥‥は、はい。ボク、
落としちゃったんですよ、それ！
Ah!
Y-Yes. It-It does.
I-I had lost it somewhere!

<Judge>
コラ、弁護人。拾ったらすぐ、
交番に届けなさい！
Mr. Wright! When you find a
wallet, you should report it
to the police right away!

<Phoenix>
い‥‥いやいや。
いちおうコレ、証拠品ですから。
Ah! No! You don't understand.
This is an important
piece of evidence.

<Judge>
“証拠品”‥‥‥？
"Evidence"...?

<Phoenix>
優作くん。サイフを落としたの、
いつごろのコトですか？
Mr. DeLite... When did you
first notice that you'd lost
your wallet?

<Ron>
ええと‥‥事件があった夜だと
思いますケド。
Err, let's see...
I think it was on the
night of the crime...

まれかちゃんと晩ゴハンを食べに
行ったときは、まだあったから。
But I know I still had it
when Dessie and I went
out for dinner.

<Phoenix>
このサイフは‥‥午前１時ごろ。
ＫＢ警備のビルで発見されました。
This wallet was found at
approximately 1:00 AM at
KB Security headquarters.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですと！
What...!?
Surely you're not serious!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥結論は、ただ１つ！
Yes... I am serious.

天杉　優作は、あの晩！
ＫＢ警備に行ったのです！
This proves that Mr. DeLite
was, in fact, at KB Security
that night!

<Ron>
うわわうわわッ！
Noooooo!

<Phoenix>
午前１時に、この被告人が
警備会社にいたのならば‥‥
So if the defendant was at
KB Security at 1 o'clock
in the morning...

そのアリバイは、カンゼンに
成立します！
...then that proves that he
has a watertight alibi!

<Ron>
‥‥うううう‥‥
Noooooo!

<Phoenix>
ちなみに、高菱屋百貨店から
ＫＢ警備会社までのキョリは‥‥
Furthermore, considering the
distance between Lordly
Tailor and KB Security...

クルマで約３０分もあるのです。
（‥‥と、矢張が言ってたな‥‥）
...it would have taken 30
minutes to get there by car!
(According to Larry anyway...)

<Judge>
いかがですかッ、ゴドー検事！
Well, Mr. Godot!?
Do you have anything to say?

だから、コーヒーを飲まない！
And stop drinking that coffee!

<Godot>
‥‥オイ怪人。出番だぜ。
あの弁護士に、反論してやれよ！
...Come on, Mr. Thief.
Don't let this guy beat you!
Tell him why he's wrong!

<Ron>
ボクのコト怪人って呼んでくれるの
‥‥アナタだけです！
You're the only one who calls
me "thief", Mr. Godot...

ボク、やってみます！
‥‥がんばりますッ！
...Alright, I'll try!
I-I'll do it! I will!

<Maya>
‥‥かなりヤル気になってるよ。
...He's really got
Mr. DeLite all worked up...

<Phoenix>
‥‥かなりヤル気をそがれたよ。
Yeah, he's like a kid at his
first day of school...

<Ron>
不自然じゃないですか！
警備会社でサイフを落とすなんて。
Look, it's just ridiculous!
Why would I have dropped
my wallet at KB Security!?

きっと‥‥ボクをおとしいれる
ために、ダレかが置いたんだ！
Someone must have planted it
there to make it LOOK like I
was there and not at the heist.

<Maya>
“おとしいれる”って‥‥
ホント、メチャクチャ言うねー。
"Planted" it there?
He's really reaching now...

<Phoenix>
‥‥優作くん。
Mr. DeLite.

<Phoenix>
サイフは、きっと‥‥コイツを
使ったときに落としたんでしょう。
You probably dropped your
wallet when you took it
out to use this, didn't you?

<Phoenix>
ＫＢ警備会社の社長室に
入るためのカードです。
The key card to KB Security's
CEO's office.

<Ron>
うううう‥‥！
Noooo!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　なかなか
やるじゃねえか、まるほどう‥‥
Ha...!
That was a pretty good
try, Mr. Trite...

<Godot>
だがな‥‥。まだ、
１つだけ、足りねえものがある。
Unfortunately, you've
overlooked one small thing.

<Phoenix>
そ、それは‥‥？
Wh-What...?

<Godot>
‥‥“理由”さ！
"Motive" of course!

この怪人には、夜中、警備会社に
行く理由なんかねえぜ！
Why would this thief go to
KB Security in the middle
of the night anyway!?

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥どうやら、もう１つ。
証拠品が必要のようですな。
Hmm... Well, Mr. Wright?
It looks like you need some
more evidence after all.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥くそお、怪人め‥‥）
(Grrr! This stupid kid...!)




<Judge>
それでは、弁護人。
証拠品の提示を要求します。
Now then.
Let's see your evidence.

被告人が事件当夜の１時、ＫＢ警備
に行った理由を示す証拠を！
The evidence that shows why
Mr. DeLite went to KB Security
at 1 AM that night!




<Phoenix>
その証拠は、これです！
Here is your evidence!

<Ron>
‥‥どういうことですか？
説明してください、成歩堂さん。
...What is this supposed to
mean, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
え！　それは‥‥わかるでしょう？
Huh!? Well, um...
Don't you know?

<Ron>
成歩堂さん。オトコなら‥‥
自分のケツは自分でふかないと。
Mr. Wright...
If you're a real man, you
should clean up your own mess.

<Phoenix>
うぐぐ‥‥ッ！
（‥‥なんか、ハラ立つなあ）
Doh...!
(For some reason, it bothers
me more when HE says it!)


<Phoenix>
被告人。‥‥これ、
モチロン知っていますね？
Mr. DeLite...
I believe you've seen
this before, correct?

<Ron>
あ‥‥ッ！　それは‥‥！
Ah...! Th-That's...!

<Judge>
なんですか？
What is it?

<Phoenix>
脅迫状です。
‥‥そう書いてありますから。
A blackmail letter.
That's what it looks like
from the contents.

<Godot>
きょうはくじょう‥‥だと？
B-Blackmail...?

<Phoenix>
中身をカンタンに紹介すると、
《５００万円もってこい》ですね。
Yes, basically it says,
"bring $50,000 dollars".

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥
それは、リッパな脅迫ですな‥‥
Hmm...
That certainly sounds like
blackmail alright...

<Phoenix>
天杉　優作は、怪人の犯行時間、
脅迫者と取り引きしていたのです！
At the time of the theft,
Mr. DeLite was dealing with
the blackmailer himself...

現場からクルマで３０分のキョリが
ある、ＫＢ警備会社の社長室で！
...in KB Security's CEO office,
a full half an hour away from
the scene of the crime!




<Godot>
‥‥‥ぐぅ‥‥ッ‥‥‥
...Ungh... Urk...

うおおおおおおおおおおおおお
おおおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
No No No No No
NOOOOOOOOOO
OOOOOOOOOOO!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛にィッ！
Order! Order!
OOOOORDER!!

‥‥犯行のあった時間、
被告人はＫＢ警備会社にいた‥‥
So when the theft of the
urn occurred, the defendant
was at KB Security...

どうやら、弁護側は、
カンペキに立証したようです！
It looks like a perfect case
for the defense!

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥その“カンペキな立証”
とやらも‥‥
...You may see it as a
perfect case, Judge,
but to me...

<Godot>
このゴドー・ブレンド１０７号の
味わいほどではなかったようだぜ。
Well, let's just say that my
Godot Blend #107 impresses
me a lot more.

<Phoenix>
ど‥‥どういうことですか！
Wh-What are you trying
to say?

<Godot>
‥‥怪人が、警備会社の
社長に脅迫されていた‥‥
You say the thief was being
blackmailed by the CEO of a
security company...

アンタ、その社長さんを
キチンと調べたのかい？
But... Did you actually
investigate this CEO at all?

<Phoenix>
え！　そ、それは‥‥まだ‥‥
Huh!?
Well, umm...
No... I guess not.

<Godot>
面識のない男を“脅迫者”呼ばわり
するの‥‥どうかと思うぜ。
Accusing a man of blackmail
with no proof? I'm not sure
what I think of that...

<Phoenix>
（面識があるオトコを怪人呼ばわり
　するのも、どうかと思うけど）
("Not sure what I think of
that?"... At least I know
what I think of you...)

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥そうですね‥‥。
Hmm... Good point.
I'm not sure what
I think of it myself...

“被告人・天杉　優作が、
　社長室に入った”‥‥
You claim that the defendant
entered the CEO's office...

‥‥これがジジツだと、証言できる
証人が必要でしょう。
...but you will need at least
one witness to corroborate
your claim, Mr. Wright.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！　いっちょ、
その社長さんを探してこようか？
Nick! I think we're going to
have to track down the CEO
guy...

<Phoenix>
その必要はないよ。
No, we don't have to track
down the CEO at all.

<Godot>
‥‥どういうことだ？
まるほどうさんよ。
What do you mean by
that, Mr. Trite?




<Phoenix>
‥‥ある人物に、それを証言できる
可能性があります。
There is someone else who
can testify.

“事件当夜の午前１時、カードが
　使用された”と証言できる人物！
This is the person who can
testify that the key card was
used at 1 AM that night!




<Godot>
‥‥今日はじめて、アンタの
ジョークがおもしろいと感じたぜ。
Ha...! That's the first time
one of your jokes actually
made me truly laugh.

<Phoenix>
（今日はまだ、一度もジョークを
　言ったおぼえがないぞ‥‥）
(Umm, I haven't actually made
any jokes... Not intentionally
anyway...)

<Judge>
私には、今の冗談のオモシロさが
今ひとつ、ピンと来ませんな。
Well, perhaps you find it
funny, but I fail to see any
humor in it!

<Phoenix>
（問題は‥‥優作くんのサイフに
　入っていた、キーカードだ）
(The problem is the key card
that was in Ron's wallet...)

（午前１時に、あのカードが使用
　されたことを立証できればいい）
(Somehow I need to prove that
the card was used at 1 o'clock
in the morning.)




<Judge>
ダレですか‥‥この、
たよりなさそうな青年は。
Wh-Who is this useless-looking
young man?

<Phoenix>
見おぼえ、ありませんか？
You don't remember him,
Your Honor?

<Judge>
うううん‥‥そうですね‥‥
Hmmmm...
Not exactly...

なぜか、見ていると
イヤな汗がニジんできますな。
But just looking at his
picture makes the bile
start to rise in my throat.

<Maya>
おぼえてないみたいだね。
‥‥２年前の事件。
It looks like he doesn't
remember the case from
2 years ago...

<Phoenix>
キオクを封印しちまったのかも
しれないな。
He probably blocked out that
memory on purpose.

‥‥彼は事件当夜、ＫＢ警備で
ガードマンをしていました。
Anyway, this man was
working as a guard at
KB Security that night.

<Godot>
‥‥ガードマン‥‥？
Oh...?

<Phoenix>
問題は‥‥、このキーカードです。
The question at hand is
this key card.

<Butz>
ああ。そいつはウチの
ビルで使われているカードだぜ。
Yup. That's the key card they
use in the building I work.

シリアル番号によると‥‥
社長室のカードだな。
According to the serial
number, this one is for
the CEO's office.

部屋に入るときに必要でさ。
使うと、記録が残るんだ。
You need it to get into that
room and every time you use
that card, it leaves a record.

<Butz>
ダレが何時に部屋を出入りしたか、
バッチリってワケ。
Yeah, it tells you
exactly who entered
the room and when.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥‥
Hmm...

<Phoenix>
‥‥そう！　社長さんを
調べるまでもありません！
As you can see, there's
no need to investigate the
CEO of KB Security!

キーカードのデータを調べれば、
真相はハッキリするはずですッ！
We should be able to discover
the truth simply by analyzing
this key card's data!

<Godot>
うぶぐほおおお‥‥ッ！
Bwaaaah...!

<Judge>
いかがでしたか？　ゴドー検事。
Well, Mr. Godot?

<Godot>
ＫＢ警備会社の社長の名前は、
毒島　黒兵衛（ぶすじまくろべえ）
The name of the CEO of
KB Security is Kane Bullard.

‥‥そいつと連絡をとるのは
ムリだったが‥‥
I was unable to contact
him directly, but...

キーカードのデータは提出させた。
‥‥コイツだ。
I got the key card data.
...Here.

<Judge>
そ、それで‥‥、そのデータは！
結果は、どうだったのですか！
S-So what does it show!?

<Godot>
このキーカードのシリアル番号が、
使用記録と一致した。
Each key card has its own
serial number and they leave
detailed records of their use.

カードが使用された時間は
‥‥事件当夜の、午前１時。
According to this data...
this card was used at 1 AM
on the morning of the crime.

< >
証拠品《キーカード》の
データを書きなおした。
Key Card updated in the
Court Record.

<Judge>
それでは‥‥仮面マスクとして
この写真に写るのは、不可能です！
But that means... it can't be
Mr. DeLite dressed as
Mask☆DeMasque in this photo!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
たしかに、そのとおりだろうぜ。
Ha...!
It looks like you're right.

‥‥たった２分じゃア、ウマい
コーヒーをいれるヒマもねえ‥‥
Two minutes isn't even
enough time to brew
a good cup o' Joe...

<Phoenix>
じゃ‥‥じゃあ‥‥！
So... So then...!

<Godot>
被告人、天杉　優作は‥‥事件当時
ＫＢ警備会社の社長室にいた。
Ron DeLite was clearly in
the office of KB Security's
CEO at the time of the crime.

‥‥検察側は‥‥
それを事実として認めるぜ。
...The prosecutor's office is
ready to admit that fact.

天杉　優作は、
仮面マスクじゃなかった、ってな。
Therefore, it's impossible
for the defendant to be
Mask☆DeMasque.

<Maya>
やったよ、なるほどくんっ！
Good job! You did it, Nick!

<Judge>
‥‥そこまで！
...That's enough!

ワレワレはもう少しで、無実の
青年に汚名を着せるところでした。
I came perilously close to
besmirching the record of
an innocent young man.

‥‥おぞましき“怪人”の汚名を。
Besmirching him with
the title of "thief"!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
ど、どうしました？　裁判長。
Wh-What's wrong, Your Honor?

<Judge>
これから判決を下しますけど‥‥
今度こそ、異議はありませんよね？
I'm ready to pass judgment...
But before I do that, do you
have any further objections?

<Phoenix>
はいッ！
No, Your Honor!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
Hrpmh...!

<Ron>
うううううう‥‥
Unnnggh...

<Judge>
‥‥よろしい。
...Very well.

では、被告人・天杉　優作に
判決を言いわたしましょう。
The court finds the defendant,
Mr. Ron DeLite...

‥‥では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
Court is now adjourned!




< >
同日　午後　２時２４分
地方裁判所　被告人第４控え室
October 13, 2:24 PM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 4

<Maya>
やっぱり、なるほどくんが
正しかったんだね！
Nick! You did it!
You were right after all!

あたし、ちょっと恥ずかしいよ。
Actually... I'm a little bit
ashamed of myself.

<Desirée>
リューイチくん！
Nicky boy!

<Phoenix>
あ。まれかさん‥‥。
Oh! Ms. DeLite...!

<Desirée>
アタシ、信じてたよ、
リューイチくんのコト！
I knew you could do it!
I believed in you all along,
Nicky boy!

‥‥カンシャしてる。ホントよ。
...I don't know how I can
ever repay you.

<Phoenix>
は、はあ、どうも‥‥
（カオが赤くなるな‥‥）
Aww... Shucks...
Thanks, Ms. DeLite.
(I just know I'm blushing...)

<Pearl>
なるほどくん！
おめでとうございますっ！
Congratulations, Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
あ！　は、春美ちゃん‥‥
（イヤな予感がする‥‥）
Oh! P-Pearls...!
(I've got a bad feeling
about this...)

<Pearl>
まあっ！
どなたですか、その女性は！
*gasp!*
Wh-Who is this woman!

<Phoenix>
い、いや、ベツにその。
このヒトは‥‥
Oh, she... She's nobody...
She's just ahh...

<Pearl>
真宵さまの前で！　他の女性と！
いいムードに‥‥！
You're blushing!
How dare you do this in
front of Mystic Maya!

恥をお知りなさいッ！
You should be ashamed
of yourself!

<Phoenix>
（ううう‥‥ビンタされた）
(Yeowch!
She slapped me...)

<Maya>
あの、はみちゃん。
‥‥このひとはね。
Umm, Pearly...

奥さんなんだよ。
天杉　優作さんの。
This woman is Ms. Desirée
DeLite. She's our client's
wife.

<Pearl>
まあっ！　なるほどくんっ！
*gasp!*
Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
は、はいッ！
Y-Yes!?

<Pearl>
‥‥なんという‥‥
ヒトさまの奥方にっ！
You're even worse than
I thought! Going behind the
back of your own client...!

<Phoenix>
ちちちち、ちが
N-N-No!
You've got it all wrong!

<Pearl>
ユルしませんっ！
I'll never forgive you!

<Phoenix>
（うううう‥‥
　往復ビンタされた‥‥）
(Owww...
A double slap...)

<Maya>
それにしても、よかったねー。
Well, anyway.
All's well that ends well,
right?

倉院のツボは戻ったし、
怪人はつかまったし！
We got the Sacred Urn back
and the thief has been caught!

<Desirée>
そうだねー。
リューイチくんのおかげだよ。
You're so right! And it's all
thanks to Nicky boy here!

<Maya>
でも、ツボを取り戻してくれたの、
まれかさんじゃないですか！
But actually it was you,
Ms. DeLite, that brought us
our urn back!

ありがとうございました！
Thank you from the bottom
of my heart!

<Desirée>
ははっ。‥‥いやいや。
テレちゃうね。こういうの。
Oh, please...
You're embarrassing me!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥と、事件が解決したのに）
(If we won the case...)

（どうして浮かないカオ
　してるんだよ、このヒトは‥‥）
(...then why does this guy
still look so glum...?)

<Ron>
ううう‥‥怪人、ボクなのに。
‥‥いや、でも。むしろそれは今は
Ugggh...
But I am the thief...
Actually, what's the point now

<Desirée>
‥‥どうしたの？
...What is it, honey?

アタシ、ユーサクくんのために
がんばったんだよ！
I did my best for you, Ronnie!

<Ron>
う、うん。それは‥‥とても
ウレシイよ、まれかちゃん。
I-I know that and I appreciate
it, Dessie...

‥‥でも‥‥
But the thing is...

<Godot>
‥‥でも、
よろこんでばかりもいられない。
Come on...
Give the kid some time.

そう。それこそが人生のブルース、
ってヤツさ‥‥なあ、相棒！
He's just got a little touch
of the blues. You know about
feeling blue, right, amigo?

<Phoenix>
ご‥‥ゴドー検事！
どうしてここへ！
M-Mr. Godot!
What are you doing here!?

<Godot>
なあに‥‥オレの相棒に
ヒトコト、礼を言おうと思ってな。
Oh come on! I just came here
to say thanks to my newest
buddy...

‥‥まるほどうさんよォ。
...You, Mr. Trite.

<Phoenix>
（“アイボー”呼ばわりする前に、
　名前おぼえろよ‥‥）
(Maybe you should learn my
name before you call me
"buddy"...)

<Godot>
‥‥さて。お遊びはここまでだ。
Well, playtime is over.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥？
Huh...?

<Godot>
今朝、早く‥‥
毒島　黒兵衛の死体が発見された。
Early this morning...
the body of Kane Bullard
was discovered.

<Maya>
ぶすじま‥‥？　最近、
どこかで聞いたような名前だね。
Kane Bullard...?
Where have I heard that
name before?

<Desirée>
それって‥‥
ＫＢ警備の社長さんじゃない！
Isn't that... the name of
the CEO of KB Security?

<Maya>
し‥‥死体‥‥？
B-Body...?

<Godot>
死亡推定時刻は‥‥
９月１２日の午前１時ごろだ。
The estimated time of death
was 1 AM on October 12th.

<Phoenix>
９月１２日の午前１時‥‥？
そ、それって‥‥まさか！
1 AM on October 12th...?
Y-You don't mean!?

<Godot>
‥‥そうなんだよ、相棒。
...That's right, amigo.

怪人がケチなツボを盗んでいたとき
ＫＢ警備会社では‥‥
At the same time that
a cheap little urn was
being stolen...

ヒトが１人、死んでいたのさ。
...the CEO of KB Security
was being murdered.

<Phoenix>
そ、それで‥‥
なぜ、ここへ‥‥？
S-So then...
What are you doing here?

<Godot>
わかってるだろう？　相棒‥‥
Oh come on. You've figured
it out already, haven't you
amigo? Or...

オレたちが今日、協力して
証明したコト‥‥お忘れかい？
Have you already forgotten
about that piece of info
I helped you out with today?

<Phoenix>
（“協力”‥‥だって？）
("Helped me out"? What!?)

<Godot>
９月１２日、午前１時。
On October 12th, at
1 o'clock in the morning...

天杉　優作は、ＫＢ警備会社の
社長室にいたんだ‥‥殺人現場に。
Ron DeLite was in the
CEO's office...
...The scene of the murder.

被害者から脅迫状で呼び出されて
‥‥やりきれない殺意を抱いて。
After getting that blackmail
letter, he must have been
imbrued with utter rage.

<Maya>
な‥‥なんですって！
‥‥さ、さつい‥‥？
Wh-What are you saying!?
Imbrued with rage...?

<Godot>
まさか‥‥
知らねえとは言わせねえぜ。
Come on! Don't tell me
you didn't know it!

天杉　優作はムカシ、
ＫＢ警備会社の社員‥‥
Ron DeLite was once an
employee of KB Security...

プロの警備員だったんだ。
He was a professional
security guard.

<Phoenix>
（ＫＢ警備の‥‥社員！）
(An employee of KB Security!?)

<Godot>
‥‥アリバイってのは、
“現場不在証明”のコトだが‥‥
It looks like the alibi that
saved him from being convicted
as a thief...

今日の裁判で、オレたちは‥‥
“逆アリバイ”を立証したのさ。
...is going to be the noose
that gets him hanged.
Kind of an "anti-alibi".

<Maya>
ぎゃく‥‥
No way...

<Godot>
『被告人は怪人ではない。なぜなら
　犯行時刻、別の現場にいたから』
He can't be the thief because
he was at the murder scene
when the murder occurred!

<Desirée>
う、ウソよ！　‥‥そんな‥‥
N-No! Th-That's a lie!
It can't be true!

<Ron>
あ、あうう‥‥、ぼ、ボク‥‥
ボクは‥‥怪人であって、その。
Oh! Ohhhh!
B-But I...
I am a thief I tell you!

<Godot>
天杉　優作。アンタの身柄を
引きつづき拘留するぜ。
Ron DeLite.
You're going back to
prison again.

罪名はちょっと変わるがな。
‥‥殺人容疑、に。
This time the charge is much
more serious. This time you'll
be tried for murder.

<Phoenix>
そんな‥‥そんなバカな‥‥
Wh-What!?
This can't...
This is impossible!

<Godot>
弁護士さんよォ‥‥
オレをガッカリさせるな。
I'm looking forward to
another exciting showdown,
Mr. Trite!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Godot>
アンタの“実力”ってヤツは‥‥
You and I aren't through
with each other yet.

まさか、このテイドだって
ワケじゃねえよなあ。
Surely you won't back
down from a challenge!
You've never been a coward!

<Pearl>
なるほどくん！　このけんじさん
‥‥お知り合いなのですか‥‥？
Mr. Nick!
Is there something personal
between you two...?

<Godot>
オレはアンタと戦うために、
地獄から戻ってきたんだ。
I've returned from the depths
of Hell to do battle with you.

‥‥もっと、
楽しませてくれないとなァ‥‥。
...At least let me have
some fun while I'm here!

<Phoenix>
（このオトコ‥‥
　いったい、ダレなんだ！）
(This guy...
Who the heck is he!?)

（静かな‥‥だけど、深い
　“敵意”を感じるぞ‥‥）
(He may be quiet... But
he's the most dangerous
enemy I've ever faced...)

<Godot>
じゃあ‥‥、天杉はつれていくぜ。
Well then... Time to say
goodbye to Mr. DeLite.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
な、なるほどくん‥‥
‥‥いったい、どうなってるの？
N-Nick...!
How could this be happening?

<Phoenix>
ぼくたちの依頼人が、目の前で
タイホされたんだ。殺人容疑で。
Right in front of our very
eyes, our client has been
arrested for murder.

その罪をカンペキに立証したのは
‥‥ぼくたち自身、なんだよ。
And the one who established
his presence at the scene...
was me.

<Desirée>
きゃああああああああああああッ！
ユーサクくうううううううううん！
EEEEEYYYAAAAHHH!
R-RONNNIEEEEEEEE!

<Phoenix>
（無罪判決を受けた天杉　優作が、
　殺人容疑でタイホ‥‥）
(Arrested for murder on the
very same day he's declared
innocent of larceny...)

（いったい‥‥
　これから、どうなるんだ！）
(What the heck's going to
happen next!?)


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.


