９月１３日　午後　３時　２分
成歩堂法律事務所
October 13, 3:02 PM
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Maya>
倉院のツボは見つかったけど‥‥
つかまっちゃったね、優作さん。
You know, I'm glad we found
the urn and all, but poor
Mr. DeLite got arrested again.

<Phoenix>
殺人事件があったとき、優作くん、
現場の社長室にいたんだよな‥‥。
Well, supposedly, Mr. DeLite
was in the CEO's office when
the murder occurred.

<Maya>
そんなの！　きっと、何かの
まちがいだよ！
No way, Jose! I don't buy it!

<Pearl>
でも‥‥それを
チカラいっぱい立証したのは、
But the one who proved
that Mr. DeLite was there...

なるほどくん自身でしたけど。
‥‥お席で見ていた感じでは。
It was Mr. Nick himself...
...At least, from what I can
understand.

<Maya>
まったく、ヨケイなコトしてくれた
モンだよねえ、なるほどくんも。
Looks like you did too good
of a job this time, Nick.

<Phoenix>
ま、まあ、とにかくＫＢ警備の
殺人事件を調べてみようか。
Um, ah... well, how about we
get started looking into the
KB Security murder?

<Pearl>
あ。わたくしは一度、
里のほうへ戻りますね。
I think I'm going to head back
to Kurain Village for a little
while, if that's alright.

<Maya>
あれ。なんで？
Sure. But why?

<Pearl>
倉院のツボを持ち帰って、
大おばさまに見てもらってきます！
I'm going to bring the Sacred
Urn back and have some
people take a look at it!

<Maya>
あ、なるほど！
じゃあ、あたしもいっしょに‥‥
Oh, that's a good idea!
I think I'll go with--

<Pearl>
いえッ！　真宵さまはいいのです！
No, Mystic Maya!
You should stay here!

ふたりっきりで、ムードたっぷりに
お出かけくださいな。
I want you two to spend some
special quality time together,
full of love and happiness!

<Phoenix>
（むーど、って‥‥
　サツジン事件の調査なんだけど）
(...Maybe Pearls is so caught
up in her fantasy she forgot
there's a murder to solve.)

< >
春美ちゃんに、証拠品
《倉院のツボ》をあずけた。
Sacred Urn given to Pearls.

<Pearl>
では。おふたりとも、
ケンカしちゃダメですよ！
Now remember!
No fighting, OK?

<Phoenix>
‥‥行っちまった。
...She's gone.

<Maya>
よおし！　じゃ、なるほどくん。
調べまくるよ、殺人事件！
OK, Nick! Time to get going
on this murder investigation!




<Phoenix>
観葉植物のチャーリーくん。
Charley.
A quite decorative plant.

生前、千尋さんがかわいがっていた
事務所のマスコット。
When she was alive, Mia really
loved it. She even went so
far as to make it our mascot.

どんなにいそがしくても、
こいつの世話だけは忘れない。
No matter how busy I get,
I never forget to water this
little fella.




<Phoenix>
ムズカシイ法律の本が
あざ笑うように並んでいる。
Difficult-looking legal books
stand in a formidable row.
They mock me.

ぜんぶ、千尋さんが
残していったモノだ。
These were all Mia's...

‥‥そういえば、自分で買った本、
ひとつもないな。
Wow, I just realized I didn't
buy a single one of these.




<Phoenix>
窓の向かいがわには、
巨大なビルがそびえている。
There is a giant building
just outside the window.

《ホテル・バンドー》
超ゴウカな超一流ホテルだ。
It's the Gatewater Hotel, a
high-class, luxury hotel.

なんでも、となり街の一角を
ゴッソリ買収して、
The chain is getting so rich
that they bought a whole
chunk of the next town over...

超レジャー施設《バンドーランド》
の建設が始まったらしい。
...and started building a huge
theme park. It's going to be 
called "Gatewater Land".

‥‥２年前は小さな
ビジネスホテルだったのに。
...And to think that two years
ago, it was just a little
hotel for businessmen.




<Phoenix>
ぼくのデスクだ。
It's my desk.

あまり座る機会がないため、
いつもはホコリっぽいんだけど‥‥
I don't get to use it much, so
the dust bunnies are starting
to mount their assault.

今日は、まぶしいほどピカピカだ。
‥‥きっと、春美ちゃんだな。
Hm? Today it's sparkly clean.
I guess Pearls must've wiped
them out for me.




<Phoenix>
古い映画のポスターだ。
An old movie poster.

ムカシ千尋さんが見て、
初めて泣いた映画なのだそうだ。
Apparently, this was the first
movie that made Mia cry when
she saw it, a long time ago.

最近、妹の真宵ちゃんが見て、
一晩中泣いていたらしい。
Maya watched it recently, and
said she cried all night, too!

‥‥ということで、最近は
このポスターを張ってある。
...Which, I guess, is why it's
back up on the wall.

今度、ぼくも見てみるか。
I'll have to check it
out one of these days.




<Phoenix>
どうしたらいいと思う？
これから。
So, what do we do now?

<Maya>
決まってるじゃない！
調べるんだよ！　殺人事件。
Isn't it obvious!?
We should get out there
and investigate the murder!

<Phoenix>
とりあえず、ＫＢ警備会社の
場所がわからないとね。
Well first, we need to
find out exactly where
KB Security is located.

<Maya>
あ。まれかさんに聞けば
いいんじゃないかな。
...Hey!
Why don't we ask Ms. DeLite!
She should know!

<Maya>
あたしも、オートバイのコト
もっと聞きたいし。
Besides, I want to ask her
some stuff about motorcycles!

<Phoenix>
バイク‥‥？
もしかして、乗りたいの？
Motorcycles...?
You're not thinking of getting
one, are you?

<Maya>
いつまでも自転車でマンゾクしてる
真宵ちゃんじゃないからね。
I'm not the same little Maya
who used to be happy with her
dinky little bike, Nicky boy.

<Phoenix>
やれやれ‥‥
*sigh*...

（とりあえず、優作くんの
　話も聞いておかないとな‥‥）
Speaking of asking around,
I've got a few questions of
my own for Mr. DeLite...

<Maya>
じゃ、留置所にも行ってみようよ！
OK, well, let's make sure to
go to the detention center,
too!




<Phoenix>
よかったね。
ツボが戻ってきて。
You must be relieved we got
the Sacred Urn back, huh?

<Maya>
うん！　‥‥とはいえ。
ちょっと、気になるんだよねー。
You bet!
...But there's something
a little different about it.

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
...?

<Maya>
“？”じゃないよ、なるほどくん。
あからさまにヘンじゃない。
Don't "...?" at me!
It's pretty obvious, isn't it?

ホラ。このポスターじゃあ‥‥、
ツボの文字は“子供”なのに。
I mean, take a look at this.
It clearly says, "I AM"
on the urn in the poster.

いつのまにか“供子”
に戻ってるんだもん。
But the urn we got back says,
"AMI", like it always used to.

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥たしかに。
Oh yeah... You're right.

<Maya>
それにさ。見つかったツボ‥‥
ピンクのはん点がついてたよね。
Plus, the vase has pink
splotches on it now...

‥‥あんなの、前はなかったよ。
...I'm sure they weren't
there before!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥真宵ちゃんは知らないけど、
　今から、１年前‥‥）
(Maya doesn't know,
but 1 year ago... when
the urn was broken...)

（ツボは割れて、“供子”の文字は
　“子供”になってしまったんだ）
(...the repairer accidentally
turned Mystic Ami's name
into "I AM".)

（そのハンニンは‥‥手先が
　不器用な、春美ちゃんだった）
(And that repairer was one
mechanically unskilled little
Pearls.)

（でも‥‥）
(But still...)

（あのときは、こんなピンクの
　はん点は、たしかになかった）
(I don't remember ever seeing
pink splotches on it.)

<Maya>
もしかして‥‥
ニセモノなのかな、あのツボ。
Is it possible that urn
is a fake?

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥それは春美ちゃんが、
倉院の里で調べてくれるから。
I'm sure Pearls'll find out
about that once she gets
back to Kurain Village.

<Maya>
うん‥‥
Yeah, I suppose...

<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥）
(Now that I think about it...)

（真宵ちゃん、ここしばらく
　倉院の里に帰ってないな‥‥）
(Maya hasn't been back
to Kurain Village in a
long time...)




<Phoenix>
‥‥倉院の里では、あいかわらず
みんな、修行してるの？
So... I guess people still go
to Kurain Village to do their
training, right?

<Maya>
うん。一人前になるには、
キビしい修行が必要だからね。
Yup. If you want to become
a spirit medium, you need to
undergo severe training.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥最近、真宵ちゃんは
修行してないね。
So why haven't you been
training lately, Maya?

<Maya>
‥‥うん‥‥
Well...

今度、キチンと霊行道場へ行って、
みっちりやろうかな、って。
Lately I've been thinking of
heading to a channeling dojo
to do just that.

<Phoenix>
“どうじょう”‥‥？
なんか、本格的だね。
A "channeling dojo", huh...?
Sounds pretty serious,
whatever that is.

<Maya>
うん。中途ハンパな修行じゃ、
悲しい事件が起こるだけだから。
If you're going to train, you
have to be serious. Otherwise
real tragedies can happen.

<Phoenix>
もしかして‥‥まだ、
去年のコトを‥‥？
Is what happened last year
still bothering you...?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（去年、里で起こった殺人事件は
　‥‥霊媒を悪用したものだった）
(That murder in her village...
It happened because the power
of channeling was misused.)

<Maya>
倉院流の霊媒術で死者を呼ぶと‥‥
霊媒師の意識は、とぎれちゃうの。
When a medium uses the Kurain
Technique, she temporarily
loses her own will.

<Phoenix>
だから、ヘタに思念が強い霊を
呼んでしまうと‥‥
So when an especially strong
spirit is summoned...

霊媒師は身体を乗っ取られて、
トンでもない事件を引き起こす。
...the spirit medium can get
taken over and even forced to
commit terrible crimes.

しかも‥‥霊媒師自身は、
そのときのことはおぼえていない。
What's worse, in those cases,
the spirit medium has no
memory of what happened.

< >
　　　　　バァァァン！
*BANG*

<Phoenix>
あの事件‥‥真宵ちゃんの
せいじゃなかったんだよ。
That murder... it wasn't
your fault, Maya. You know
that, don't you?

<Maya>
そうかもしれないけど‥‥
I suppose not, but...

‥‥なんかね、
コワくなっちゃってさ。
...I guess I'm still a bit
shaken up. That's all.

<Phoenix>
（タイヘンみたいだな。
　霊媒師の家元ってのも‥‥）
(It sounds like being the
Master of Kurain is going to
be a heavy responsibility...)




<Maya>
写真うつり、よくないね。
You're not very photogenic,
are you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

（あんまりヒトに見せないほうが
　いいのかな、この写真‥‥）
(Maybe I shouldn't show this
picture to too many people...)

（いや。でも、ぼくはこのカオを
　ぶら下げて歩いてるワケだし）
(And yet... I've walked around
my whole life, showing this
face of mine to the world...)

（日々、このみっともないカオで
　生き恥をさらしているのか‥‥）
(I wonder if I've just been
making a fool of myself with
this silly face...)

<Maya>
‥‥あの。カルい冗談なんだから、
あんまり悩まないでほしいな。
Um, I was only joking, Nick...
Don't make such a sad face.
You're making me feel guilty.




<Phoenix>
千尋さんがいなかったら、
今のぼくはなかったよ。
If it wasn't for Mia, I
wouldn't be the person
I am today.

<Maya>
ホント、たよりなかったもんねー。
ムカシのなるほどくん。
Yeah, she told me you
used to really be useless.

あまりにたよりなかったから、
今、スゴくたのもしく見えるもん。
Compared to how unreliable
you were then, you actually
seem responsible now.

‥‥じつは、そんなに
変わってないのに。
...Actually, you haven't
changed that much, I guess.

<Phoenix>
（ホメられた‥‥ワケじゃ
　なさそうだな）
(Maya praised me for a change!
...
Hey, wait a second...)




<Maya>
‥‥あたしも、もっと
シッカリしないとね。
I'm going to have to
really buckle down and
get serious.

<Phoenix>
倉院流霊媒道・家元の
ムスメだもんな。
Well, you're the future Master
of the Kurain Channeling
Technique, after all.

<Maya>
そうだよ。‥‥それに、
お姉さんがわりだからね。
Yeah...
That, and I have to play the
part of big sister, too.

はみちゃんと、なるほどくんの。
For Pearly... and you, Nick!

<Phoenix>
ぼ、ぼくもかよ。
Wha-?? Do I look like I was
born yesterday!?




<Maya>
いい子でしょ、はみちゃん。
Pearly sure is a good kid.

<Phoenix>
うん。‥‥ちょっぴり、
思いこみがハゲしいけどね。
Yeah. But she tends to let
her imagination get the best
of her, though.

<Maya>
そこがいいんだって。
That's one of the things
I like about her, silly!

なるほどくんにビンタする
はみちゃん、シビれるもんねー。
Slapping you the way she did!
She's a tough one alright!

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥たしかに
シビれるけど。ほっぺが。
You're telling me!
I think she knocked a
few teeth loose.

（でも、まだ９才なのに、
　がんばってるよな、春美ちゃん）
(Pearls is only 9, but it's
amazing how emotionally
strong she is.)

（“家族”は‥‥もう、イトコの
　真宵ちゃんだけ、だもんな‥‥）
(After all... the only
"family" she has left is
her only cousin, Maya.)




<Maya>
また出てきたね、イトノコさん。
Detective Gumshoe's on
this case too, huh.

<Phoenix>
事件といえば、あの刑事だよ。
‥‥グーゼンとは思えないな。
He seems to show up
during all of our cases.
It can't be a coincidence.

<Maya>
ウンメイの赤いイトで
しばりつけられてるんじゃない？
Maybe it's a sign that our
fates are destined to be
woven together for all time!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちょっとイヤだな、それ。
Yeah, that'd be a real
Beauty and the Beast kind of
fairy tale, wouldn't it.




<Maya>
ケッキョク‥‥仮面マスクは
アイガ探偵だったのかな？
So Detective Atmey was
Mask☆DeMasque after all, huh?

<Phoenix>
そうじゃないか？
本人も認めていたし。
I guess so...
After all, he did admit it.

<Maya>
でも‥‥優作さんだけは
認めてないよね。
Yes, but Mr. DeLite still
hasn't changed his tune.

あいかわらず、
自分が怪人だー、って。
He's still claiming that
he's the real Mask☆DeMasque.

まさか‥‥サツジンヨーギを
逃れるため‥‥じゃないよね？
You don't think he's just
saying that to avoid the
murder charge, do you?

<Phoenix>
（まさか、な‥‥）
(I-I'm not sure...)




<Maya>
まさか‥‥あの探偵さんが
怪人だったなんて！
I can hardly believe that
guy was really the thief
in disguise!

あたし、ヨワいんだよねー。
そういう、ドンデン返し。
I never saw that coming! Then
again, I stink at spotting
those "plot twist" things.

<Phoenix>
哀牙探偵もマンゾクなんじゃ
ないか。楽しんでもらえて。
Detective Atmey seemed to
really enjoy himself today.
Maybe a little too much.

<Maya>
うん。今日の裁判は楽しかったな。
‥‥まんがみたいで。
Ha ha, yeah. Today was pretty
wild. Like the plot of some
crazy comic book!

<Phoenix>
ぼくは必死だったけどね。
‥‥いつもどおり。
Great, glad you had fun while
I was getting abused by the
prosecutor... as always.




<Maya>
カッコイイよねー、まれかさん。
バイクでツッ走るんだよ。
That Desirée sure is cool!
I love that whole motorcycle
thing!

‥‥それも、死のセトギワで。
あたしもやってみようかなー。
The way she laughs in
the face of death...
I want to try it, too!

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん、自転車しか
乗れないだろ？
I thought you only knew
how to ride a bike...

<Maya>
でも、でも！　電動自転車
だからね、いちおう。
Hey! Don't forget, Nick,
that it's an electric bike!

<Phoenix>
‥‥若いんだから、
ちゃんと運動しろよ！
...E-Electric? So young and
already so lazy. Whatever
happened to good old exercise?




<Maya>
ヤッパリさん。なるほどくんの
大親友なんだよね。
Oh, it's Larry. He's your
old childhood friend, right?

<Phoenix>
小学校のころからの
つきあいだからね。
Yeah, I've known him since
elementary school.

<Maya>
ひゃあ‥‥あたしとはみちゃんの
つきあいより長いのかあ。
Wow...!
That's even longer than
I've known Pearly.

きっと、楽しい思い出が
いっぱいだよね！
You two must have lots of
good memories together!

<Phoenix>
まあね。
I guess so.

ヒドい思い出に押しつぶされて、
よくおぼえてないけど。
But I can hardly remember
them... They've been erased
by all the traumatic ones.




<Maya>
今回の被害者だよね。
ムスジマさん。
He's the victim in this case.
"Lame Blowhard"...

<Phoenix>
だから、“ブスジマ”だよ！
No, it's "Kane Bullard"!

<Maya>
だって、ワルそうなカオでしょ！
“ムスッ”としていてさ。
I know, but he looks so ugly!

<Phoenix>
“ブスッ”としている、と
考えればいいんじゃないかな。
Well, why don't you remember
at least the "Bull" part of
his name and riff off of that?

<Maya>
‥‥あ。そりゃそうだね。
だから“ブスジマさん”かあ。
...Now that you mention it,
I guess he does kinda look
like an ugly old bull.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とにかく、今回は
　被害者の情報が少ないな‥‥）
(Hmm... We still don't know
very much about this victim.)

<Maya>
優作さんに脅迫状を
送りつけていたんだよね。
So, he's the one who sent
the blackmail letter to
Mr. DeLite, right?

<Phoenix>
そうみたいだね。
（もう少し、調べたほうがいいな）
It looks that way.
(But we still need to look
into this guy some more.)




<Maya>
ね、なるほどくん。‥‥なあに、
この、カオにつけた機械は？
Say, Nick... What do you think
that thing attached to his
face is anyway?

<Phoenix>
ぼくに聞くなよ。
Don't ask me.

<Maya>
えー。だって、知り合い
なんでしょ？　あの検事さん。
Why not?
You know him, don't you?

<Phoenix>
いやいや！　あんなスゴいヤツ、
見たこともないぞ。
I've never met that guy before
in my life! And believe me,
he's not exactly forgettable.

<Maya>
でもさ。今日の法廷で、
あの検事さん‥‥
Yeah, but at the trial
today, he said...

<Godot>
やっと会えたな。
So we finally meet...

‥‥まるほどう　りゅういち。
Mr. Phoenix Trite!

<Godot>
オレは、アンタと
戦わなけりゃならねえ。
I've returned from the
depths of Hell...

そのために‥‥
地獄から戻ってきたのさ。
To do battle with you.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥向こうは
ぼくを知ってるみたいだったな。
You're right about one thing.
He sure acts like he knows me.

<Maya>
あのさ、なるほどくん。
Hey, Nick?
I was just thinking...

知らないウチに恨みを買うクセ、
なおしたほうがいいと思うな。
Maybe you should try to stop
making people you've never
met before into your enemies.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼくもなおしたいよ、
そんなクセ。
Trust me, I'd like to stop
doing that, too. My poor
body can only take so much.

（アイツが、いったい
　ダレなのか‥‥）
(Who is that guy anyway?
And what's his story?)

（いつか、わかるときが
　来るのかなあ‥‥）
(I wonder if I'll ever
find out...)




<Maya>
かなりカンシャしてるよね、
なるほどくんに。
She certainly seems
grateful to you, Nick.

<Phoenix>
タイヘンだったからね。
あの事件は。
Well, she was in a pretty
tight spot during that
terrible ordeal.

ぼくも彼女には
カンシャしてるよ。
Actually, I'm grateful to
her, too.

<Maya>
うう‥‥なんか
ズルいなあ、なるほどくん。
Hmmm...
It sounds like you're
not telling me something.

今度、こっそり見てみようかな。
その事件の記録‥‥。
I'm going to take a good
look at the case file next
chance I get...




<Maya>
まだ持ってたんだ、そのバッジ。
So you've still got that
badge, I see.

<Phoenix>
そ、そりゃそうだろう。
弁護士なんだから。
Huh!?
Well, I'm a lawyer, aren't I?

<Maya>
いやー、こんなに長く
つづくとは思わなかったよ。
Yeah, but I guess I just
didn't think you'd keep on
being one for this long.

あぶなっかしいからねー、
なるほどくんのベンゴ。
You have to admit, you've had
some close brushes with death
because of your job.

<Phoenix>
（それは、真宵ちゃんの霊媒も
　似たようなモノだと思うけど）
(...I fail to see how being a
lawyer is be more dangerous
than channeling dead people.)




<Maya>
たしかに、
倉院のツボは見つかったけど‥‥
I'm glad we got the
Sacred Urn back and all...

<Phoenix>
なんか、スッキリしない
カオしてるね。
So then how come you don't
look any happier?

<Maya>
するワケないでしょ！
Why should I!?

書いてある文字は《供子》か
《子供》かハッキリしないし、
I don't know if it should say
"AMI" or "I AM" on it
anymore...

なんか、オシャレなピンクの
水玉もようも増えてるし！
...and now it's got big pink
polka dots on it that weren't
there before!

<Phoenix>
気にするほどのコトじゃ
ないんじゃないか？
Don't you think you're
overreacting just a little?

<Maya>
あー、言ったね、なるほどくん！
じゃあ、じゃあ‥‥そうだなあ。
Overreacting!? Nick! I can't
believe you said that! I mean,
it's like... like... I got it!

あたしがピンクの水玉もようの
装束をイキに着こんで、
It's like if I came in wearing
polka dots on my acolyte
costume every day and said...

『あたし、イヨマちゃん！』
なんて言いだしたら、どうよ！
"Hi, Nick! I'm Ayam!"
Well!? Do you still think
it's no big deal?

<Phoenix>
‥‥それは‥‥なんというか、
一大事だな。
...I guess... it would be...
um... a real disaster...?

<Maya>
でしょ！　でしょ！
‥‥そういうコトなんだよ！
You see! You see!
Well that's how I feel!




<Maya>
あたしも知らなかったよ、
こんなものがあったなんて。
You know, even I didn't know
this statue existed until a
little while ago.

<Phoenix>
“倉院流・分家の霊場から
　借りてきた”って言ってたな。
Didn't Adrian say it's from a
Fey branch family's training
hall or something?

<Maya>
全国に、たくさんあるんだよ。
倉院流の修行場。
Yes, there are actually a lot
of training halls scattered
all over the country.

さみしい山奥に、ひっそりと。
いくつあるか知らないけど。
Hidden away deep
in desolate mountains...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥さみしくなくちゃ
　ダメなのかな、修行場‥‥）
(Why does it always
have to be "desolate"
mountains...?)




<Phoenix>
これ‥‥ホンモノの
仮面マスクが作ったんだよな。
So this was made by
the real Mask☆DeMasque, huh?

<Maya>
イトノコ刑事がタイコ判を
押してたからね。
Yup, Detective Gumshoe
said it was the real thing.

“このエンブレムこそ、
　ホンモノの証拠ッス”って。
"One look at this mark
and you know it's the real
deal, pal."

<Phoenix>
あの刑事のタイコ判は、
三文判よりチカラ不足だけどね。
Yeah, but you do realize whose
deductive reasoning skills
we're talking about, right...?




<Phoenix>
あいかわらず曲がってるね。
くにゃっ、て。
It's still bent, isn't it?

<Maya>
アイガ探偵、これで後ろアタマを
殴られた、って言ってたけど‥‥
Detective Atmey said it
got bent when the thief hit
him on the head with it.

<Phoenix>
ウソだったんだろうね。
彼自身が怪人だったんだから。
Well, it looks like he ended
up the bent one after he
turned out to be the thief.

ワザと曲げて、凶器であるように
見せかけたんだ。
He must have damaged the
sword himself to back up his
phony story.

<Maya>
ううん‥‥さすが頭脳派だなあ、
アイガ探偵め‥‥。
Yeah...
I guess he really does have
a brawny mind, huh?




<Phoenix>
このデータによると、
怪人があらわれた時間は‥‥
According to this data,
the thief showed up at the
basement warehouse at...

<Maya>
夜中の１時‥‥なんだよね。
Um, 1 o'clock in the morning,
right?

<Phoenix>
でも、そのデータは哀牙探偵が
用意したものだからなあ。
Yeah, but remember, this
data came from Atmey...

好きに細工できたはずだよ。
For all we know, he might have
somehow tampered with it.

<Maya>
でも、でも。こっちの写真にも
記録されてるよ、時間。
But... But then, what about
this photo? It's got the
time on it, too!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥この防犯カメラは、
　高菱屋側が用意したものだ）
(Yeah, and the security
camera belonged to Lordly
Tailor.)

（哀牙探偵に、この時間表示を
　細工することは、できない‥‥）
(Atmey couldn't have tampered
with the photo's timestamp to
show the wrong time...)

<Maya>
じゃあ、やっぱり
ホンモノなんだよ、この記録は。
I guess that means this data
is accurate after all.




<Maya>
この写真に写っている
仮面マスク‥‥
So the Mask☆DeMasque in
this photo...

‥‥やっぱり、
あのアイガ探偵なのかな。
...is Detective Atmey in
disguise, huh?

<Phoenix>
そうなるね。
It looks that way.

（哀牙探偵は、倉庫に防犯カメラが
　あるのを知っていた‥‥）
(Atmey knew there was a
security camera set up in
the basement...)

（この写真を撮られるのも、
　計画のうちだったのかな‥‥？）
(So I'm guessing this photo
was probably a part of his
elaborate plan...)

< >



<Maya>
優作さん‥‥キョーハク
されていたんだね‥‥。
So Mr. DeLite was being
blackmailed, huh?

自分が、ムカシはたらいていた
会社の社長さんに。
By the CEO of the security
company he used to work for.

<Phoenix>
そうらしいね。
（調べてみる必要があるな‥‥）
Yeah, it looks like it.
(Sounds like we still need to
do some more poking around...)

<Maya>
なるほどくんも、ダメだよ。
ワルいコトしちゃ。
You'd better watch yourself
and not do anything naughty
either, Nick.

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃんに
　キョーハクされるからな‥‥）
(Was that a threat?
Is she trying to blackmail
ME now...?)




<Phoenix>
事件当夜、殺人のあったビルで
このサイフが発見された‥‥
This was found in the building
where the crime took place on
the very night of the murder.

ついでに、中に入っていた
キーカードの使用時刻は‥‥
And according to the time
record on the key card
inside...

<Maya>
ズバリ、殺人の起こった時間。
イヤな感じだねえ‥‥。
Yeah, it was used right around
the time of the murder...
Doesn't sound very good, huh?




<Maya>
それ、現場に落ちていたんだよね。
This was found on the floor
of the basement warehouse.

やっぱり‥‥哀牙探偵が
自分で置いたのかな。
So does that mean...
Detective Atmey put it there
himself?

<Phoenix>
そうじゃないかな。
That's the only explanation
I can think of.

いかにも、現場で格闘があった
ように見せかけるために、ね。
I guess he wanted to make sure
it looked like he'd struggled
with the thief that night.




<Phoenix>
どう思う？　これ‥‥
What do you think about this?

<Maya>
うーん‥‥事件に
カンケイありそうだけど‥‥
Hmmm...
It seems like it has something
to do with this case...

ちょっと、あたしには
わからないな。
But I'm not really sure...




同日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
October 13
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Ron>
だから、ぼくじゃありませーーーん
I already told you!
It's not meeeeeeeee

<Maya>
この、か細く耳をつきさす
もの悲しげなヒメイは‥‥
A sad, pitiful whine that
tapers into silence...

<Phoenix>
‥‥どうやら、優作くんは
取り調べ中らしいね。
Sounds like they're
interrogating Mr. DeLite
right now.

<Maya>
ううう‥‥時間がないのに。
Man, and we don't have
enough time as it is.

<Phoenix>
しかたないよ。警察も
あわててるんじゃないかな。
Yeah, well, I guess the
police are going crazy
just like we are.

きのうまで怪人だと思っていたら、
今日は殺人事件の容疑者だからね。
Yesterday they thought he was
just a thief, but now they got
a murder case on their hands.

<Maya>
たしかに‥‥あそこの看守さんも、
ちょっとそわそわしてるね。
I guess you're right...
That guard over there
looks a bit on edge, too.

<Phoenix>
‥‥とにかく、あとでもう一度
来てみようか。
Come on. We'll just have
to come back later.

<Maya>
よし！　他をあたるよ、
なるほどくん！
OK! Let's go check out
some other place, Nick!




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

どうやら今は、
することがないのだろう。
It looks like he doesn't
have much to do right now.

向かい側のカメラに向かって
おもしろいカオをしている。
I can tell because he's
looking at the camera
and making funny faces.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile, you're on candid
camera.

どうやら今は、
監視するものがないのだろう。
The camera doesn't seem to
have a lot to tape right now.

向かい側の看守を
やさしく見守っている。
The only thing it's watching
now is that guard over there.




同日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
October 13
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Ron>
あ！　な、成歩堂さんッ！
Ah! M-Mr. Wright!

<Maya>
優作さん‥‥。
取り調べ、終わったんですか？
Mr. DeLite...
Did they finish their
interrogation?

<Ron>
はい！　ボクを‥‥ボクを、
見捨てないでくださーーーい！
Yes, but...!
P-Please don't leave
me alone anymoooooore!

<Phoenix>
‥‥優作くん。ぼくたちに、
ウソをついていましたね？
...Mr. DeLite, you lied to us
before, didn't you?

<Ron>
あ。‥‥そ、それは‥‥
W-Well...
Err, you see...

<Phoenix>
あの晩、高菱屋百貨店で
倉院のツボの盗難事件が発生した。
On the same night the Sacred
Urn was stolen from Lordly
Tailor Department Store...

同時に、きみは脅迫状で、
ＫＢ警備に呼び出されていた。
...a blackmail letter you got
summoned you to KB Security
to hand over some money.

そして、そこでは‥‥
毒島社長が殺害されていた。
And then, that's where the
CEO, Kane Bullard, was
murdered.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥天杉　優作は、
ひとりしかいない。
But... there's only one
Ron DeLite, am I right?

‥‥あの晩、きみは
何をしていたのか‥‥？
So the only question is...
Where were you that night?

今度こそ、本当のコトを
聞かせてもらおうかな。
This time I want to hear
the whole truth...
Your life depends on it.

<Ron>
は、はい‥‥。
O-OK...




<Phoenix>
優作くん‥‥。最後に１つだけ、
カクニンしておくよ。
Ron, before we go, there's one
more thing I want to ask you.

<Ron>
な、なんですか。
そんな、アタマをトガらせて‥‥
Y-Yes...?
B-But please don't hurt me...

<Phoenix>
ブスジマ社長を殺害したのは
‥‥本当に、きみじゃないんだね？
Mr. Kane Bullard...
Do you swear that it wasn't
you who killed him?

<Ron>
ち‥‥ちがいます！　もう‥‥
ウソはつきません！
Y-Yes, of course!
I could never...!
I-I'm not lying!

ボク、死体を金庫に
かくしただけなんです。
All I did was hide his
body in the safe!

それがバレるのがコワくて‥‥
きのう、自首したんです。
But then I was afraid they'd
discover what I did. So I
turned myself in yesterday!

<Maya>
どうして、そんなコトを？
Um, why?

<Ron>
怪人として有罪になれば‥‥、
アリバイができますからね‥‥。
Well, if the judge had ruled
that I was guilty of robbery,
then I'd have an alibi, right?

<Maya>
ううん‥‥。
アタマいいんだ、優作さん。
Hmm... I guess so.
You're really clever,
Mr. DeLite.

<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥優作くんを
　信用するしかないみたいだな）
(I guess I have no choice
but to take Mr. DeLite at his
word.)

<???>
‥‥真宵さまっ！
Mystic Maya!

<Maya>
あ‥‥はみちゃん！
Hey...!
Pearly!

<Pearl>
ただいま戻りました！
I'm back!

<Phoenix>
春美ちゃん、今まで
何してたんだっけ‥‥？
Hey Pearls. So what have you
been up to this whole time...?

<Pearl>
このツボです！　倉院の里で、
調べてもらっていたのですよ！
The Sacred Urn, Mr. Nick!
I took it back to Kurain
Village to have it examined!

<Maya>
で？　で？　どうだった？
And? And?
What did you find out?

<Pearl>
はい！　ご心配なく。
まちがいなくホンモノだそうです！
Well there's no need to worry!
They said it's the real urn!

<Maya>
うわあ、よかったねえ！
いやホントに。
Whew! That's a relief!
I was really worried!

<Pearl>
ただ‥‥ひとつだけ、問題が。
But there's one small
problem.

<Maya>
モンダイ‥‥？
Problem?

<Pearl>
この、おちゃめな
ピンクの模様なのですが‥‥
Um, these cute little pink
splotches...

どうやら、ペンキのようで‥‥
しかも、最近ついたものなのです！
They said that it's paint...
And that they were put on
the urn recently!

<Phoenix>
（ツボに現れたピンクの模様、か。
　‥‥ま、どうでもいいけど）
Why are we talking about
the pink splotches again?
What's the big deal?

<Maya>
どうでもよくないッ！
ちゃんと調べるんだよ！
What's the big deal!? We've
gotta find out how they got
there! That's the big deal!

<Pearl>
ちゃんと調べるのですよ、
なるほどくん！
Yes, Mr. Nick!
We've gotta find out how they
got there!

<Phoenix>
わ、わかったよ。
ツボのコトも、調べてみよう。
O-OK, OK!
We'll go find out how they
got there!

<Ron>
あの‥‥ボクのコトも、
忘れないでくださいね‥‥。
P-Please don't forget about
me...

< >
《倉院のツボ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Sacred Urn refiled into
the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

怪人から殺人犯にヘンシンした
被告人を前にして、
He looks pretty nervous...

かなりキンチョーぎみに見える。
...standing near someone who
went from thief to murderer
overnight.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile, you're on candid
camera.




<Phoenix>
優作くん。きみはまだ、
仮面マスクは自分だ、と‥‥？
Mr. DeLite, do you still
insist that you are
Mask☆DeMasque...?

<Ron>
だから、きのうから
そう言ってるじゃないですか。
Isn't that what I've been
saying since yesterday?

<Maya>
‥‥アッサリ言われたね。
That was a quick response...

<Phoenix>
ちょっとだけ、ハラが立つな。
Tell me about it. To be
honest, it's starting to
get irritating.

<Maya>
でも、でも、優作さん！
B-But listen, Mr. DeLite!

今日の裁判で、カイジンの
正体は暴かれたじゃないですか！
At the trial today, we
learned the true identity
of the thief, didn't we!?

<Atmey>
あーっはっはっはっはっはっは！
はっはっはっはっはっはっ！
Hee hee hee ha ha ha
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ho ho ho hee hee hee!

‥‥さあさあみなさん、
ごらんくださあい‥‥！
Take a good look,
everyone!

天才にふさわしき好敵手を求めて、
ついに自ら犯罪に手を染めた‥‥
Unable to find a rival worthy
of my genius, I was forced to
create one by myself!

あわれなピエロでござあい‥‥
Here I am!
The tragic clown...

<Ron>
たしかに‥‥あのツボを盗んだ
のは、ボクじゃないですけど。
I guess it's true...
I wasn't the one who
stole that urn...

<Maya>
そりゃ、そうですよね。
ＫＢ警備にいたんですから。
Of course not. After all,
you were at KB Security
at the time.

<Phoenix>
じゃあ‥‥この写真の怪人の
正体は、やっぱり‥‥
So then the person dressed
up as Mask☆DeMasque in
this photo...

<Maya>
アイガ探偵‥‥
ってコトになるよね‥‥。
...It's gotta be
Detective Atmey.




<Phoenix>
あの晩‥‥きみは、高菱屋ではなく
ＫＢ警備に行ったんだね？
So that night, you didn't go
to Lordly Tailor, you went
to KB Security, right?

<Ron>
はい。‥‥ボク、ヤクソクの時間
どおり、ＫＢ警備に行ったんです。
Yes... I went to KB Security
at the time the blackmail
note said I should.

<Maya>
うんうん。‥‥それで？
Alright... What happened next?

<Ron>
ムカシ社員だったから、
社長室の場所は知っていました。
Well, I used to work there,
so I knew where the
CEO's office was.

ノックしたんですけど‥‥
返事がなくて。
I knocked... but there
was no answer.

だから、キーカードを
使って、ロックをはずしました。
So then I used the key card
to unlock the door.

<Phoenix>
（サイフを落としたのは
　たぶん、そのときだな‥‥）
(That's probably when
he dropped his wallet...)

<Ron>
社長室に入ったら‥‥、
だれかが立っていたんです。
When I went into the
CEO's office... someone
was in there.

<Phoenix>
“だれか”‥‥
"Someone"...?

<Ron>
そいつに‥‥いきなり、
アタマをガツン！　って。
Then suddenly they bashed
me over the head! Bam!

<Maya>
ブスジマ社長さんが
殴ったのかな‥‥？
Was it Kane Bullard that
hit you...?

<Ron>
わかりません。
I don't know.

ボクがクラクラしている間に、
そいつ、逃げちゃったみたいで。
The person ran away while
I was still stunned.

気がついたら‥‥もう、
ビックリしました。
When I came to my
senses, the sight I saw
left me speechless.

目の前に、社長の死体が！
ボクも死ぬかと思いましたよ！
The dead body of the CEO was
right there in front of me!
I thought I'd die myself!

‥‥とにかく、死体をなんとか
しようと思いました。
Anyway, I thought I should
do something with the body...

<Phoenix>
それで、あの金庫に‥‥？
So that's why you put
it in the safe...?

<Ron>
‥‥ええ。そうなんです。
...Yes, that's right.

ボク、警備チームのチーフだった
から、開け方を知ってたんですよ。
I used to be the chief of one
of the security teams, so
I knew how to open it.

<Maya>
それで‥‥そのあとは？
どうしたんですか？
OK... And what did
you do after that?

<Ron>
そりゃもう、とりあえず
逃げましたよ！
Well, I got out of there,
for starters!

あのビルの防犯カメラも、
ボクが設置しましたからね！
I was the one who set
up the security cameras
in that building...

自分の姿が映らないように、
うまーいコト切り抜けました！
...so I knew how to
avoid being spotted
by them!

<Maya>
‥‥なるほどくん。
Nick...

どう考えてもハンニンぽいよ。
‥‥優作さん。
All of a sudden, Mr. DeLite
kinda sounds like the
murderer to me...

<Phoenix>
（それを言っちゃあ‥‥）
(Please don't say that...)

< >



<Maya>
キョーハクジョーって‥‥
コレが初めてじゃないんですか？
This blackmail letter...
Is this the first one you got?

<Ron>
モチロン、ちがいますよ！
No, of course not!

‥‥今回みたいに、どこかに
呼び出されたのは初めてですけど。
But this is the first one
that ever called me out
to a specific location.

<Phoenix>
最初の脅迫状は‥‥
この事件の、すぐあとに‥‥？
So, did you start receiving
blackmail letters after
this incident...?

<Ron>
ええ。《エマノンの涙》事件から
数日たったころでしたね。
Yes. Just a few days after the
"Tear of Emanon" heist...

ウチに脅迫状が届いたんです。
《おまえがやったんだろう》って。
That first letter...
It said, "I know you did it".

<Maya>
いきなりバレちゃったんですか。
So someone found out
about your true identity?
Just like that?

<Ron>
いやー、これでなかなか
ムズカシイですよね、怪人も。
Ah, it's not easy being
a master thief, you know!

《決定的な証拠もあるから、
　カクゴしろ》なんて言われて。
"I've got proof that it was
you, so give up!" it went on
to say.

それで、せっかくのエモノの
宝石も取りあげられちゃって‥‥
So in the end, I had to give
up the treasure I went through
all that trouble to steal...

<Phoenix>
そうなんですか‥‥‥‥
Is that right...

ちょ、ちょっと！
“取りあげられた”というのは？
Hey! Hang on a second!
What do you mean you had
to "give it up"?

<Ron>
あ、シンパイいりませんよ。
指定の貸金庫に宝石を預けたら、
Oh, don't worry. After I put
the jewel in the safe-deposit
box the letter specified...

あとで１００万円も
送ってきてくれましたからね。
...someone sent me $10,000!

<Phoenix>
（だれもシンパイなんか
　してないって‥‥）
(No one said anything about
me being worried, you know...)

<Ron>
それからです。ボクのところに、
計画書が届くようになったのは。
After that, I started getting
the plans in the mail.

<Maya>
け、けいかくしょ‥‥？
P-Plans...?




<Maya>
あの。“計画書”というのは‥‥？
What are these "plans"
you're talking about?

<Ron>
宝冠とか、絵とか、美術品‥‥
狙うエモノと、盗み出す方法。
They were instructions on how
to steal a crown or painting
or some other rare treasure.

警備の盲点や逃げ道、トレーニング
方法までキッチリ書かれていて。
They showed security blind
spots, escape routes and even
suggested training methods.

<Maya>
じゃ、じゃあ、まさか。
犯行の計画を立てたのは‥‥
So you mean that the one
who planned the heists
wasn't you...?

<Ron>
ええ。２回目からは、
ボクじゃないですよ。
No, it wasn't.
I only planned the very
first one.

だれか親切なヒトが、イカした
大作戦を考えてくれるんですよ！
After that, I received plans
from some very kind person!
Incredibly detailed plans!

<Maya>
優作さん、キョーハク者に
カンシャしてるよ‥‥
It sounds like Mr. DeLite is
thankful to the person that
was blackmailing him.

<Phoenix>
（やはり‥‥怪人☆仮面マスクは、
　この優作くんだったのか‥‥？）
(So Ron DeLite was
Mask☆DeMasque after all...?)

（‥‥しかし‥‥）
(But...)

（他にいるんだ。犯罪の計画を
　立てた人物が、もうひとり！）
(Someone else is behind the
thefts. Someone who planned
it all out in detail!)

<Ron>
計画どおりに盗み出したエモノは、
指定の貸金庫に預けるんです。
All I had to do was deposit
the treasures I stole into
the safe-deposit box.

そうすると、おカネが
送られてくるんですよねー。
Then I just waited for the
cash to come in the mail.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そんな、うれしそうな
　カオで言われても‥‥）
(Could you try not to look
so gleeful about it...?)

<Maya>
じゃあ、《倉院のツボ》を
狙ったのも‥‥？
So you went after the
Sacred Urn because of
one of those plans, too?

<Ron>
そんなツボ‥‥じつは、
見たこともないんですよ。
Well, see... truth is, I've
never seen the urn.

ボクは、計画書に書いてあるモノを
計画どおりに盗むだけですから。
All I did was follow the
instructions and steal what
I was told to steal.

<Phoenix>
優作くん‥‥。今の証言、
まちがいないね？
Mr. DeLite... Is everything
you've just told me the truth?

<Ron>
ええ。‥‥でも、
まれかちゃんにはナイショですよ？
Yes...
B-But please don't tell
Dessie. OK?

< >
《天杉優作の証言書》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Ron's Testimony added
to the Court Record.




<Maya>
優作さん。ＫＢ警備、
やめさせられたんですよね？
Mr. DeLite, is it true that
one year ago...

今から、１年ぐらい前に‥‥
...you were forced to quit
KB Security?

<Ron>
あ！　そ、それ！
‥‥まれかちゃんには。
Ah! H-How did you...!?

まれかちゃんには、
言わないでくださーーーい！
I-I'm begging you!
Please don't tell
Dessie! Pleeeease!

<Maya>
い、いえ。
まだ言ってませんけど‥‥
D-Don't worry.
We haven't told anyone yet...

<Ron>
たた、助かった‥‥‥‥いや。
Whew! Thank goodness...
Err, no... I umm...

でも、どうせアレかな。
かくしたって、いつかはバレるしな
But I suppose I'll have
to tell her sometime...
She'll find out eventually

<Maya>
どうして話さないんですか？
まれかさんに。
Why have you been hiding
it from her anyway?

<Ron>
まれかちゃん、曲がったコトが
大キライなんですよ。
Dessie would despise me if
she ever found out I was
living a life of crime.

犯罪者‥‥特に怪人なんて、
ユルしてくれるワケがないから‥‥
A criminal, a thief...
She'd never forgive me!
My marriage would be over!

<Maya>
じゃ、じゃあ‥‥なんで
ワザワザ怪人なんかに？
Knowing that, why did
you become a thief in
the first place?

<Ron>
まれかちゃん、それはキモチよく
おカネを使うんですよ。
Because Dessie spends
money like it's water.

それだけのおカネが
もらえるシゴト‥‥
There's no job in the world
that could bring in enough
money...

ボク、怪人しか
思いつかなかったんです。
Except being a thief.
At least, that's what I
thought anyway.

<Phoenix>
（まれかさんのためだったんだ
　‥‥怪人☆仮面マスク‥‥）
(So he became
Mask☆DeMasque for
Desirée, huh...?)




<Ron>
いやー、スゴいですよね。
弁護士さん、なんて。
A great lawyer and so young!
You really are an inspiration!

さぞかし、かせいで
らっしゃるんでしょうねえ。
I bet you make lots and lots
of money, don't you?

<Maya>
怪人に言われると、ちょっと
イヤミに聞こえるね。
That doesn't sound right
coming from a thief, if you
know what I mean...




<Ron>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

スミマセン‥‥
ボク、なんてヒドいオトコなんだろ
I'm sorry...
I suppose you could say I'm
nothing but a terrible lowlife

<Maya>
ど、どうかしましたか？
Wh-Why do you say that?

<Ron>
‥‥あの、初めてなんです。
盗難事件の被害者とお会いするの。
...This is the first time I've
ever had to actually face a
victim of one of my crimes.

<Phoenix>
（倉院のツボのコトか‥‥）
(I guess he's talking about
the Sacred Urn...)

<Maya>
あ。でも、ツボを盗んだのは
優作さんじゃないんですよね？
Yeah, but I thought that you
weren't the one who stole
my urn...

<Ron>
た、たしかに、
ツボはそうなんですけど‥‥
Th-That's true about
the urn, I guess...

やっぱり、怪人なんかやめて、
ロックンローラーになればよかった
Maybe I should give up this
life of crime and try becoming
a professional cowbell player




<Ron>
このヒト、怪人☆仮面マスク担当の
刑事さんですね。
This is the detective that was
in charge of the Mask☆DeMasque
investigations.

きのう自首したら、ナミダを流して
よろこんでくれました。
He was so happy when I
surrendered yesterday that he
actually shed tears of joy.

<Maya>
へええ。あの、イトノコさんが？
What? Gumshoe cried!? Really!?
Was it a single manly tear or
did he let loose and sob?

<Ron>
ボクもついつい、
もらい泣きしちゃって。
Sobbed. I started weeping
myself, too. It was truly
infectious!

いやあ、カンドーしたなあ。
あのときは。
A truly moving moment,
if I do say so myself.

<Maya>
‥‥さぞ、ソーゼツな光景
だったんでしょうねえ‥‥。
...That must've been one
heck of a beautiful scene.

<Phoenix>
“もらい泣き”のイミが
よくわからないけどな。
(If beauty is in the eye of
the beholder, I'm convinced
that these two are blind.)




<Ron>
怪人になろうと決めて、ボク、
いろいろ勉強したんですよ。
Once I decided to become
a thief, I started studying
like crazy.

<Phoenix>
‥‥怪人について？
Studying!? Like what?
Petty Larceny 101?
The History of Pilfering?

<Ron>
はい。小説や映画を見て、
大センパイたちのカツヤクを。
Ha. No, but I watched a lot
of movies and read a lot of
novels about great thieves.

<Maya>
へええ。ネッシンなんですねー。
Oh yeah?
I admire you for doing your
homework, if for nothing else.

<Ron>
みなさん、とても
はずかしいカッコウをなさって、
All the great ones had their
own trademarks. Flashy
costumes, calling cards...

予告状に高笑い。そして、
キメぜりふは“サラバだ諸君”。
...unique laughs, and catchy
slogans, like, "Farewell,
my friends!"

‥‥このへんは、やはりキッチリ
押さえないと、って思って。
I figured I needed to do a
good job with that if I was
going to make a splash.

<Maya>
ホント、怪人にならないと、
なかなか言えないよねー。
Yeah, I guess you really can't
say goofy stuff like that
unless you're a master thief.

“サラバ”も“ショクン”も。
"Farewell" or "We shall meet
again"... You know, hokey
stuff like that.




<Ron>
さすが、名探偵さんですよね。
He's an Ace Detective,
alright.

１回目の事件から毎回、ボクを
いい感じに追いつめますからねえ。
He's been hot on my trail
ever since the first heist.

<Maya>
でも‥‥今日の法廷で、
ショーゲキの告白をしましたよね。
Yes, but... He made a
pretty stunning confession
in court today.

<Maya>
“この自分こそ、仮面マスクだ！”
‥‥って。
"It was me all along!
I am Mask☆DeMasque!"...

<Ron>
ううん‥‥思いこみがハゲしいん
でしょうね、たぶん。
I don't know what to say...
I guess he's just delusional.

<Phoenix>
（まれかさんみたいなコト
　言ってるぞ‥‥）
(That's exactly what
your wife said about you...)




<Ron>
じつは‥‥ときどき、思うんです。
I'm ashamed to admit it...

もしかして‥‥ボク、怪人には
向いてないんじゃないか、って。
...but sometimes I wonder
if I'm really cut out to
be a thief.

<Phoenix>
そりゃそうでしょう！
Well, isn't that obvious?

<Maya>
ゼンゼン似合いませんよ！
It doesn't suit you at all!

<Ron>
うううう‥‥。やっぱり、
気のせいじゃなかったのか‥‥
Uuugh... I knew it...
I guess I'm not the only one
who came to that conclusion.




<Ron>
まれかちゃん‥‥犯罪者だけは
ユルせないらしいんですよ。
Dessie...
She really has a thing
against criminals.

<Maya>
その理由‥‥優作さん、
ご存じなんですか？
Do you have any idea why
that is, Mr. DeLite?

<Ron>
さあ‥‥。詳しいハナシは、
彼女に聞いてもらえますか。
Well... If you want to
know the details, you'll
have to ask her.

とにかくボク、ＫＢ警備を
クビになっちゃって‥‥
But the thing is, after I lost
my job at KB Security...

まれかちゃんのために、
おカネがほしかったんです。
I needed to earn money to
keep Dessie satisfied...
Lots of money.

でも‥‥なかなかシゴトが
決まらなくて。
But... I just couldn't seem
to find a good job.

ケッキョク、まれかちゃんが
イチバンきらいな、怪人に‥‥
That's why I wound up becoming
the thing that Dessie hates
most... A thief.




<Ron>
あ、シャチョー‥‥
おキノドクです。
Mr. Bullard... my old boss.
It's so sad...

<Phoenix>
何か、思い当たるコトは
ありますか？
Do you have any idea what
might have happened?

‥‥毒島さんが
殺害されたコトについて。
Was there anyone that might
have wanted him dead?

<Ron>
そうですね‥‥なにかと
敵の多いヒトでしたから。
Oh yeah, sure...
Mr. Bullard was the type of
guy who made lots of enemies.

脅迫まがいのコトをしてみたり。
He did lots of threatening
things to people...

<Phoenix>
いやいや。“まがい”じゃなくて、
脅迫そのものじゃないですか。
Wait, wait, do you mean he
scared people, or that he
threaten them with blackmail?

<Ron>
まあ‥‥、そういうヒト
でしたねえ。
Well, I guess they're kind of
the same, right?




<Ron>
カッコイイですよねー、
あこがれちゃうなー。
Isn't he great!
I wish I could be half as
cool as him!

ボクが怪人だって信じて
くれたの、このヒトだけだったし。
Besides, he's the only one
that really believed me when
I said I was the thief!

<Phoenix>
いやいや。それは、きみを殺人罪で
再タイホするためだったんだよ。
Hey, hang on a second!
This is the guy that had
you arrested for murder!

<Ron>
‥‥そんなワルいヒトには
見えなかったけどなあ‥‥
Well, I still don't think
that makes him a bad person...

<Phoenix>
（どんなふうに見えたんだよ、
　いったい‥‥）
(What in the world do you
see in that coffee-crazed
prosecutor!?)




<Phoenix>
どうですか？　これなんですけど。
What do you think about this?

<Ron>
そういうのはボク、ちょっと。
‥‥‥‥いや。
Hmm... I don't really think
I can help you with that.
Err, no, that's not it...

ちょっとちがうか。
“そういうの”って、どういうのか
It's just that the thing is
I don't really know if I can
say one way or the other

<Maya>
よく聞こえないね。
I didn't really catch that.

<Phoenix>
聞くイミもなさそうだよ。
Don't worry, you didn't
miss anything.




<Ron>
いやー、フシギですよねー。
That's kind of strange...

<Maya>
なにがですか？
What is?

<Ron>
仮面マスクのエモノ‥‥今までは
有名な美術品ばかりだったのに。
Up until now, Mask☆DeMasque
has gone after famous works
of art or treasures.

いきなり、こんなシブくてジミな
マニア向けのツボですから。
Why did he suddenly decide to
steal this plain-looking urn
that nobody would want?

<Phoenix>
‥‥他人ゴトみたいに
言わないでほしいな‥‥
You make it sound like
you had nothing to do
with the theft.

<Ron>
だって‥‥このツボをエモノに
選んだの、ボクじゃないですから。
Well... It wasn't me that
chose to steal this urn.




<Ron>
へえ。ボク、こういうの、
けっこう好きなんですよ。
Wow, this is cool!
I'm really into this kind
of stuff.

<Maya>
ホントですか！　あたしたちの
お宝なんですよ！
Oh yeah? It's one of our
most valuable treasures!

<Ron>
もし無罪になったら、ゼッタイ
見に行きますから。
If I ever get out of here,
me and Dessie will go to
Lordly Tailor...

まれかちゃんといっしょに、
真宵さんたちの秘宝展。
...to check out the whole
Treasures of Kurain Exhibit!

<Maya>
‥‥あの、盗まないでくださいね。
あたしたちの、お宝‥‥。
Um, OK, I guess...
Just promise me you won't
steal anything, OK?

<Ron>
やだなあ。シゴト抜きで
行くに決まってるじゃないですか！
Oh don't worry! We'd be going
when I'm not on the job as
Mask☆DeMasque.

<Phoenix>
（ビミョーな会話だな‥‥）
(Well, that's reassuring...)




<Phoenix>
この予告状‥‥
優作くんが作ったの？
This calling card...
Did you send this?

<Ron>
いえ‥‥それが。ボク、
知らないんですよねー。それ。
No...! Err, that is...
I don't know anything
about that.

だって、あの晩は
それどころじゃなかったし。
I mean, I had other plans for
that night already...

<Phoenix>
（脅迫状が届いていた
　わけだからな‥‥）
(That's true...
He did get that blackmail
letter, after all...)

<Maya>
やっぱり‥‥アイガ探偵なのかな。
予告状を書いたの。
What about Detective Atmey...?
Could he be the one that
sent it?

<Phoenix>
そうみたいだね。
他に考えられないし。
It looks that way.
I can't think of anyone else.

<Ron>
あの夜は、しかたなくＫＢ警備に
行ったんです。
Yeah... That night, because of
the letter, I had no choice
but to go to KB Security.




<Maya>
これ‥‥どう見ても、ホンモノの
仮面マスクですよね。
This photo... This has got to
be the real Mask☆DeMasque!

<Ron>
ええ。このボクもタイコ判を
押しますよ！
I'm sure it is. I know
Mask☆DeMasque when I
see him.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥優作くんじゃ
ないんだよね。
Yes, but...
This isn't you, right
Mr. DeLite?

<Ron>
はあ、そうですねえ。
ボク、ＫＢ警備にいましたから。
Well, err... No...
I was at KB Security then.

<Maya>
じゃあ、やっぱり‥‥
アイガ探偵なのかな‥‥。
So then... I guess it really
is Detective Atmey, after all.




<Maya>
この脅迫状‥‥やっぱり、
ブスジマ社長さんが？
So was this blackmail letter
written by KB Security's
CEO, Kane Bullard?

<Ron>
たぶん、そうだと思います。
I-I think so... Probably.

あの社長室、キーカードがないと
入れませんしね。
You can only get into the
CEO's office if you have a
key card.

<Phoenix>
（脅迫状で、取り引きの場所が
　ＫＢ警備に指定されている‥‥）
(The blackmail letter said
to meet at KB Security...)

<Maya>
やっぱり、ブスジマさんしか
考えられないよね‥‥。
Then no one else other than
Mr. Bullard could've have
written the letter...




<Ron>
‥‥あの晩、午前１時‥‥
ボク、ＫＢ警備に行ったんです。
I was at KB Security at
around 1 o'clock that night...

サイフに入れておいたキーカードを
使って、ドアを開けたから‥‥
I took out my wallet to open
the door with the key card...

<Phoenix>
コイツは、そのとき
落としたワケですね？
So is that when you
dropped it?

<Ron>
スミマセン‥‥。今まで
かくしていて。
I-I'm sorry...
I should have told you the
truth earlier.




<Phoenix>
どうして、このカードを
優作くんが持っていたのかな？
What are you still doing with
this key card anyway?

ＫＢ警備をやめたときに、
会社に返さなかったの？
Didn't you return it when you
left your job at KB Security?

<Ron>
か、返しましたよ、もちろん！
Of course I returned it!
Don't be silly!

あの。このカードは、脅迫状と
いっしょに送られてきたんです。
Umm... But it got sent back
to me along with the
blackmail letter.

<Maya>
脅迫状と‥‥？
With the blackmail letter...?

<Ron>
“これを使って社長室に入れ”
‥‥って。
Yes, it said...
"Use this to enter the
CEO's office".




<Ron>
いやー、ここまで人気者に
なるとは思いませんでしたよ！
Oh! I didn't know
Mask☆DeMasque had become
so famous!

<Maya>
このブロマイド、
あたしが買ったんですよ！
Yeah, I actually bought this
publicity photo!

<Ron>
あ。よかったら、サインしますよ！
『怪人参上！』って。
Really? Well, I'd be happy to
sign it if you like! I'll even
add, "Behind Bars!"

<Maya>
え！　ホントですか！
Yes! Please! Please!

<Phoenix>
（優作くん‥‥すっかり
　忘れてるみたいだな‥‥）
(It looks like Ron has totally
forgotten about what happened
at the trial today...)

（今日の裁判で、無罪判決を
　もらったコト‥‥）
(That he was declared
"not guilty" of being
Mask☆DeMasque...)




<Ron>
社長室の非常ブザーですね。
That's the emergency buzzer
from the CEO's office.

鳴らしちゃダメですよ。
ものスゴい音がするから。
Don't press it!
It makes a terrible racket!

<Maya>
へへ。あたし、思いっきり
鳴らしちゃいました。
Hee hee. Sorry. I just love
making a lot of noise.

<Ron>
‥‥あの。そのブザー、
事件にカンケイあるんですか？
Err, umm... Does this
buzzer have something to
do with this case?

<Phoenix>
今のところ、なんとも
言えないですね。
Well, at this point, I don't
really know yet.

（ボタンに指紋は
　なかったわけだし‥‥）
(After all, there were no
prints on it, or anything
else for that matter.)




<Maya>
ブスジマさんが殺害された時間‥‥
一度だけ、鳴らされているんです。
The buzzer went off just once
around the time that Bullard
was killed.

<Ron>
えええッ！　コワいですねー‥‥
Oooh!
Th-That's scary!

<Phoenix>
優作くん、何か知らないかな？
Do you know anything about
that, Mr. DeLite?

<Ron>
‥‥ううん。
特に思い当たるコトはないです。
...Sorry, I'm afraid I don't.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥たよりにならないな‥‥）
(Why am I not surprised by how
clueless he is anymore...)




<Phoenix>
このリスト‥‥
社長室で見つけたんですけど。
This list...
We found it in the office
of the CEO, Mr. Bullard.

<Ron>
これ、仮面マスクが盗んだ
エモノのリストじゃないですか！
Hey! This is a list of all the
things Mask☆DeMasque stole!

<Phoenix>
盗まれたモノの横に、
値段が書いてありますよね。
And that's the value of each
item listed next to them.

《１０００万円》とか
《１５００万円》とか‥‥
"100,000 dollars"...
"150,000 dollars"...

<Maya>
これって、秘宝のお値段‥‥
なんですか？
Are you sure that's the
value of the stolen items?

<Ron>
ううん‥‥それにしては
ヤスい気がしますねー。
Hmm...
The numbers seem a little
low to me.

闇ルートで取り引きしても、
３倍以上の値がつくと思いますよ。
Even on the black market, the
prices should be at least
three times higher than that.

<Phoenix>
（さすが、元警備員。そのへんの
　情報には詳しいみたいだな‥‥）
(I guess he knows about that
stuff because he used to be
a security guard...)




<Phoenix>
優作くん。この証言、
まちがいないね？
Mr. DeLite, are you absolutely
sure about this testimony?

脅迫状で指示されたとおりに、
美術品を盗んだ‥‥
That you stole the treasures
as you were directed by a
series of blackmail letters...

<Ron>
ええ。おカネももらえるし、
“これもアリかな”って。
Yes, and I got money for
them in return. It seemed
like a good deal.

<Phoenix>
（ウソをついてるようには
　見えないな‥‥）
(He doesn't look like
he's lying...)

<Maya>
じゃあ‥‥アイガ探偵の
告白は、なんだったのかな‥‥
So then how do you explain
Detective Atmey's crazy
confession...?




<Ron>
あ、これ！　ボクのデビュー戦の
記事じゃないですか！
Hey! This is an article
about my debut heist!

いやー、タイヘンでしたよ。
いきなり追いつめられちゃって。
Boy, that was a tough one.
Before I knew it, they were
hot on my trail.

<Maya>
でも‥‥仮面マスク、ちゃんと
逃げられたんですよね？
But Mask☆DeMasque...
He must have gotten
away, right?

記事にも《消えた》って
書いてあるし‥‥。
It says in the article that
he "disappeared"...

<Ron>
そうなんです！
とっさにヒラめいたんですよ！
That's right!
I got a sudden burst of
inspiration!

そこにあるポリバケツの中に
怪人の衣装をかくして‥‥
I hid my Mask☆DeMasque
costume in a nearby
plastic bucket...

警備員に早変わりしたんです。
‥‥ミゴトでしょう？
Then I quickly changed into
my security guard uniform.
...Pretty clever, eh?

<Maya>
へええ‥‥って、
ちょっと待ってください！
Wow... Awesome!
...Hey, hold the phone!

この写真の警備員‥‥
優作さん、なんですか！
The guard in this photo...
Is this you, Mr. DeLite?

<Ron>
そうですよ。
意外なトリックでしょう！
Hee hee. That's right.
Nice trick if I do say
so myself!

<Phoenix>
（なんというか‥‥タンジュン
　すぎて、あきれちまうな）
(Nice and easy to figure out!
Even Pearls could see through
that in a heartbeat.)

< >
証拠品《新聞記事》の
データを書きなおした。
Newspaper Clipping updated in
the Court Record.

<Ron>
‥‥でも、
さすがは名探偵ですよね。
But as you might expect,
Detective Atmey found the
disguise...

ボクがバケツに捨てた怪人の衣装、
見つけちゃいましたから。
He truly deserves the
title of "Ace Detective".

<Phoenix>
アイガ探偵が‥‥怪人の衣装を？
（聞いたことなかったな‥‥）
Detective Atmey found the
Mask☆DeMasque disguise?
(Hmm, that's interesting...)

<Ron>
ウチに持って帰っちゃった
みたいですね、探偵さん。
Yes, and I heard that he
brought it home with him.

<Phoenix>
（哀牙探偵‥‥そのとき、
　コイツを手にいれたワケか‥‥）
(So that's it... That's when
Atmey got his hands on this.)

<Ron>
おかげでボク、新しい衣装を
作り直したんですよ。
Thanks to that, I got the
chance to remake my costume.

<Maya>
それはタイヘンでしたねー‥‥
That must have been
really time-consuming, huh?

<Ron>
‥‥その数日後でしたね。
Yes, it took quite a while
to complete. Anyway, a few
days after that...

ボクのウチに、最初の脅迫状が
届いたのは‥‥。
I received the first of the
blackmail letters...

<Maya>
きょ‥‥キョーハクジョー！
B-Blackmail letters!?

<Phoenix>
どど、どういうコトですか！
優作くん！　話して！　ホラ早く！
Wh-What are you talking about?
Hurry! Tell me what you mean!

<Ron>
そそ、そんなに
身を乗り出さないでください‥‥
H-Hey, calm down...!
Don't get so worked up...!




同日　某時刻
怪人☆仮面マスク　アジト
October 13
Mask☆DeMasque's Hideout

<Desirée>
あ！　リューイチくん！
マヨイちゃん！
Oh! Nicky boy!
Maya!

<Phoenix>
まれかさん‥‥
Ms. DeLite...

<Desirée>
アタシ‥‥ユーサクくんを
助けるつもりだったのに！
All I wanted to do was
help my dear Ronnie...!

<Phoenix>
‥‥完全に逆効果でしたね。
Yeah... but I guess it ended
up hurting his case...

<Maya>
そういうコト言わない、
なるほどくん。
Don't say that, Nick!
She doesn't need your help
beating herself up.

<Desirée>
ねえ、リューイチくん。
助けてくれるでしょ？
Hey, Nicky boy! Please!
Please help Ronnie!

ユーサクくん‥‥殺人なんて、
ゼッタイ‥‥！
He's not a killer, I swear!
My Ronnie wouldn't hurt a fly!

<Phoenix>
‥‥とにかく、調べてみます。
...Alright. I'll poke around
and see what I can find out.

<Desirée>
ホントに！
ウレシイっ！
Really! Are you serious!?
Oh, I'm so happy!

‥‥リューイチくんたちが
いてくれて、よかったな。
I knew asking for your help
was the right thing to do.

アタシ‥‥もう、
どうしていいかわからなくて。
I... I don't know what I can
do to help anymore...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥意外にモロいところが
　あったんだな。まれかさん）
(I had no idea Ms. DeLite
had such a vulnerable side.)




<Maya>
これ‥‥仮面マスクだよ！
It's Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
ムネに、テープレコーダーが
ブラさがっているな。
There's a tape recorder
hanging from his neck.

<Maya>
どれどれ。いじってみよう！
Let me see that!

< >
　　　　　‥‥カチ‥‥
...click...

<DeMasque>
わははははははははははははは‥‥
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...

‥‥ゴクロウだったねえ、諸君。
宝冠はいただいて行くよ‥‥
I'll be taking this crown now!
Better luck next time,
gentlemen!

わーははははははははははは‥‥
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、『ほがらかな笑い声
こそ、怪人のイノチだ』‥‥って。
Ronnie used to say that
"a happy laugh is the
lifeblood of a thief".

<Maya>
たしかに、ココロが
洗われるような笑い声ですね。
Well, that certainly is a
happy-sounding laugh alright.

<Desirée>
けっこう、笑うのって
ムズカシイんだよ。
Yes, and laughing isn't
as easy as it sounds.

なんかこう、しらじらしく
なっちゃってねー。
The harder you try, the more
fake it sounds.

<Maya>
うーん。優作さん、
ドリョク家なんだねえ‥‥。
Yeah.
Mr. DeLite really works
hard at his craft, huh?




<Maya>
きゃあ、カワイイ！
これ、気球っていうんだよ！
Oh, that's so cute!
It's called a hot air balloon,
you know!

<Phoenix>
‥‥さすがに知ってるよ。
...Wow!
There's no fooling you!

<Maya>
あたしも
作ってみようかなー、気球。
I want to make my own
balloon now!

なるほどくんも
乗せてあげるからね！
I'll even let you ride in it,
Nick!

<Phoenix>
（気球には、ゴクヒのはずの
　エンブレムがプリントされてる）
(That emblem on the balloon is
supposed to be top-secret.)

（‥‥天杉　優作が仮面マスクで
　あるという証拠だ）
(This could convince the
courts that Ron DeLite is
Mask☆DeMasque...)

（真宵ちゃんにはダマっておこう。
　‥‥コワいから）
(I'd better not tell Maya.
She gets kinda... scary when
it comes to "celebrities"...)




<Phoenix>
天杉　優作は‥‥脅迫状を
受け取っていたんだ。
So Ron received a
blackmail letter, huh?

<Maya>
まれかさんは知ってるのかな？
このコト‥‥
Do you think Ms. DeLite knows
about this?

<Phoenix>
知ってたら、ニコニコ笑ってる
ワケにも行かないだろ。
Well if she did, I don't think
she would've been smiling
like that.

<Maya>
教えてあげたほうが
いいのかな‥‥
I wonder if we should tell
her about it...

<Phoenix>
よけいなコトは
しないほうがいいと思うよ。
I think it'd be smarter if
we didn't.




<Phoenix>
中途ハンパなヘンソウ道具が
ガクに入ってかざられている。
It's a bunch of cheap costume
pieces arranged inside a nice
frame.

<Maya>
つ、つけヒゲだよ
なるほどくん！
L-Look, Nick!
It's a fake beard!

<Phoenix>
厚紙を切りぬいた
仮面もあるぞ‥‥
There's also a mask made
out of cardboard...

<Maya>
ほらほら、なるほどくん。
つけヒゲつけヒゲ！
Here, Nick!
Try on this fake beard!
Come on! Try it on!

<Phoenix>
う、うわ！
ナニするんだよ‥‥
H-Hey!
Cut it out...

<Maya>
ついでにマスクも
かぶるかぶる！
Now put on the mask!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あはははははははは！
怪人なるほどくんだ！
Aha ha ha ha ha ha!
It's Phoenix☆DeMasque!

<Desirée>
気に入ったら
持っていっていいよ。
If you like it, feel free to
take it home with you.

<Phoenix>
いいです！
Thanks, but no thanks!




<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんか、どこかで
　見たことがあるような気がする）
(Hmmm... This thing looks
vaguely familiar.)

<Maya>
あ！　金魚ばちがあるよ。
逆さまだけど。
Oh, I know! It's a fishbowl!
Well, an upside-down one,
anyway...

<Phoenix>
ヘルメットかもしれないよ。
‥‥宇宙人の。
I think it's a helmet.
...An alien helmet.

<Maya>
となりにあるのは、
テープレコーダーかな。
And that looks like a tape
recorder or something next
to it.

<Phoenix>
通信機かもしれないよ。
‥‥宇宙人の。
I think it's a transceiver.
...An alien transceiver.

<Desirée>
あー、それ。優作くんが
持って帰ってきたんだよねー。
Oh, that. Ronnie brought
that home one day.

会社のトモダチにムリ言って、
もらったんだって。
He asked one of his friends
from work if he could have it.

宇宙レンジャーの制服。
優作くん、うれしそうだったなー。
It's a Space Ranger uniform.
I've never seen Ronnie
happier in his whole life.

<Maya>
はあああ‥‥。
あたしもほしくなってきたよ。
Oh, man...
Now I want one, too!

<Phoenix>
（あの事件の警備会社‥‥
　ＫＢ警備だったのか）
(I wonder if KB Security was
in charge of security at the
event from that old case?)




<Phoenix>
ゴチャゴチャと
いろいろ置いてある。
There's a whole bunch of
stuff piled up over here.

<Maya>
こっちの、ゴミ箱にささっている
巻きものはナニかな？
What are these rolls of paper
stuck in the trash can?

《マザリンの宝石強奪
　アルバトロス大作戦の巻》
"Theft of the Mazarin Stone:
The Great Albatross Strategy"

《不死身の女神像強奪
　ナックルボンバー大作戦の巻》
"Theft of the Immortal
Goddess Statue: The Great
Knucklebomber Strategy"

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（警察の人たち、ここは
　捜査したのかな‥‥）
(Did the police even
investigate this place...?)

<Desirée>
あー、警察のヒトなら、
見ていったよ、それ。
The police took a look
at all of that, you know.

<Maya>
え！　何か言ってましたか？
Really!?
Did they say anything?

<Desirée>
“おハナシにならない”だって。
They said it wasn't
important.

<Phoenix>
そうですか‥‥。
Oh?

<Desirée>
しょうがないでしょ。ユーサクくん
シロートなんだからさ。
Don't worry about it,
Nicky boy. After all, my
Ronnie is just an amateur.

<Maya>
アタシは好きだけどな。
“ナックルボンバー”ってヒビキ。
Amateur or not, this is cool!
"Knucklebomber"!
How cool is that!?




<Phoenix>
本がドンとつんである。
かなりあるな。
There are a bunch of books
lying here.

‥‥怪人やら怪盗やらが
カツヤクする小説ばかりだ。
They're all romantic-sounding
novels about famous heists and
fantastic thieves.

<Maya>
しおりやメモがいっぱい
はさんであるよ。
Wow! Look at all the bookmarks
and notes stuck into them!

<Phoenix>
どれどれ。
Let's see here...

《注意：この怪人の笑いかたを
　参考にすること》
"Note: Must remember this
thief's way of laughing.
Very useful."

《注意：やっぱり、予告状は
　怪人としてのエチケット》
"Note: A calling card is an
important part of any good
thief's modus operandi!"

<Desirée>
いつか怪人になるのが
ユメみたいだから。ユーサクくん。
It was always Ronnie's
dream to become a thief.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥もう、とっくに
　ユメをかなえてるのに‥‥）
(Well, I guess you can chalk
that one down as fulfilled...)

<Maya>
なんで優作さん、キチンと
まれかさんに説明しないのかな。
I wonder why Mr. DeLite never
talked to his wife about it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥気がつかない彼女にも
問題があると思うけど。
...Yeah, well I think she
deserves some of the blame
for not bringing it up either.




<Maya>
ぎょ‥‥魚雷があるよ、
なるほどくん！
Nick! It-It's a torpedo!

<Phoenix>
‥‥信じがたいけど、
ホンモノっぽいぞ、コレ。
...It's hard to believe,
but it sure looks real.

<Maya>
まったく‥‥どこから
拾ってくるのかな、こんなの。
Where could he have picked
up something like this?

<Phoenix>
落としモノみたいに言うなよ。
Please don't say that as if
torpedoes are things people
just leave lying around...




<Desirée>
アタシ、こういうヤツが
イチバン、キライなんだよ。
I hate these kinds of people
more than anything!

<Maya>
あの‥‥メイタンテー、ですか？
Umm...
You mean Ace Detectives?

<Desirée>
メイタンテーはユルせるよ。
No, I'm fine with Ace
Detectives.

<Maya>
ああ‥‥じゃあ、やっぱり
カイジン‥‥だから？
Oh... So then you must mean
thieves?

<Desirée>
モンダイなのは、メイタンテー
のフリをしたカイジンであるコト。
No, they're alright, too.
I just hate thieves that
pretend to be Ace Detectives!

アタシ、ヒキョーなオトコだけは
ユルせないんだ！
There's nothing I hate more
than cowardly men!

<Maya>
ところで‥‥、どうして哀牙探偵の
事務所に行ったんですか？
By the way, why did
you go to Detective Atmey's
office anyway?

<Desirée>
いやー。いざ裁判の当日になると、
アタシも急に不安になっちゃって。
Well, as the trial went on,
I started to get more and
more nervous.

自分なりに、真犯人の情報を
集めよう！　って思ってさ。
I went there to try to find
out more about the "real
criminal".

<Maya>
“しんはんにん”‥‥って‥‥
The "real criminal"...?

<Desirée>
仮面マスクに決まってるでしょ。
ユーサクくんじゃないもん。
Yes! Obviously, the real
Mask☆DeMasque is not
my Ronnie, right?

<Maya>
はあ‥‥
Y-Yeah...?

<Desirée>
仮面マスクといえば、探偵の
星威岳ってヒトが詳しい、って‥‥
And Detective Atmey knew
more about Mask☆DeMasque
than anyone else...

テレビの《街のスゴいヤツ》の
コーナーで言ってたから。
They mentioned him on the
"Great People of the Town"
segment on TV.

<Phoenix>
もしかして‥‥ハナシを
聞きに行ったんですか？
So then... you went there
to ask him some questions?

<Desirée>
そうだよ。アタシだって、
ヤルときはヤルからね。
That's right. I'll do whatever
it takes to save my man!

『センセイは、おルスですから！』
と泣きすがる秘書を振りきって、
His secretary said,
"The Ace Detective isn't
in right now!"

探偵さんのアジトに
押し入っちゃったワケ。
But I forced my way past her
and into his hideout.

<Phoenix>
（“あじと”ねえ‥‥）
(I wouldn't exactly call
that office of his a
"hideout"...)

<Desirée>
あのカバンなら、テーブルの上に
ちょこん、って置いてあったよ。
That bag was sitting right
there on top of the table.

<Maya>
あ。きのうもそこに
あったよね、あのカバン。
Oh yeah, we saw that
bag there yesterday, too.

<Desirée>
ホント、ユルせないよ。
ヒトにツミを着せるなんて！
There's nothing lower than
someone who would try to
pin a crime on someone else.




<Desirée>
ね、聞いてよリューイチくん！
Listen carefully, Nicky boy!

ユーサクくん、ぜーったい、
サツジンなんてできないんだから！
My Ronnie would never,
ever kill anyone!
It's just not in him!

<Maya>
‥‥それは、あたしもそう思うよ
なるほどくん。
...I don't think he would
either, Nick.

<Phoenix>
でもなあ。たまに優作くん、
カッとなるだろ。
Yeah, but you have to
admit he's got a bit of
a temper to him.

『死んじゃってくださーーーい！』
みたいなノリで‥‥
It's not that hard to imagine
him just snapping and
screaming, "Please diiiiie!"

<Maya>
そういうコト言わない！
He would never say that!

あの、まれかさん。
サツジンはともかく‥‥
Anyway, Ms. DeLite, he might
not be a killer...

優作さん、まだ、自分のコト
“怪人だ”って言ってますけど‥‥
...but he's still going around
saying that he's a "thief"...

<Desirée>
だからさ。それはユーサクくんの
思いこみであって‥‥
I already told you, that's
just a fantasy for him...

<Phoenix>
いやいや。思いこんでるのは
まれかさんのほうじゃないですか？
Ms. DeLite, I hate to say it,
but you're the one living in
a fantasy world.

<Desirée>
なな、な‥‥ナニ言ってるの、
リューイチくん！
Wh-Wh-What!?
How dare you say that
to me, Nicky boy!

アタシ、ユーサクくんのコトなら
なんでも知ってるんだよ！
I know everything about
my Ronnie! We don't have
any secrets between us!

石橋を叩いてもわたらない‥‥
っていうか、
Ronnie isn't the thief type!
He's so honest that he
wouldn't even sneak a nap!

コワれるまで叩きつづけるほど
弱気な性格なのに‥‥怪人なんて！
He-He's so honest that he
wouldn't even steal a glance!
Thief! Ha! The very idea...!

<Phoenix>
（そもそも‥‥
　フシギだよなあ‥‥）
Hmm... I guess I just don't
get it...

<Maya>
え。何が？
Huh? Get what?

<Phoenix>
こんなにタイプのちがう２人が、
どうして夫婦になったんだろ。
I just can't understand how
they can be so different, and
yet, be such a happy couple!

<Maya>
それはまあ、たしかにねえ‥‥。
Yeah, they sure are different.

<Desirée>
やだなー、リューイチくん。
それはホラ。しょうがないでしょ？
Come on now, Nicky boy! It's
not that mysterious, is it?

もお、ホレちゃったんだもん。
‥‥アタシが。
It was love at first sight!
...For me, anyway.

<Maya>
え！
まま、まれかさんが‥‥？
What!?
F-For you?




<Maya>
‥‥あの。ホレちゃったんですか？
まれかさんが？　優作さんに？
Umm... So was it really
love at first sight when you
first met Mr. DeLite?

<Desirée>
‥‥ユーサクくんはね。
イノチの恩人なんだよ。
Well, maybe not at first
sight, but Ronnie saved
my life.

<Maya>
イノチの‥‥？
Saved your life...?

<Desirée>
ムカシ、つとめてた会社にね。
２人組の強盗が入ったんだ。
I was at work one day
when two robbers suddenly
rushed in.

アタシ、そういうのユルせなくて。
ダンコ、抗議してやったの。
Well, I'm not the kind to just
curl into a little ball in
a corner, so I fought back.

<Phoenix>
ごご、強盗に、ですか？
R-Robbers?

<Desirée>
そしたら、人質にとられちゃって。
コワかったんだよ、ホントに。
Yes, they took me hostage.
I was so frightened.

２人とも、大きなナイフ持ってて。
泣いちゃったもん、アタシ。
They were both carrying
these huge knives and...
I-I broke down into tears.

<Phoenix>
（そりゃそうだろう。
　ぼくですら、まちがいなく泣く）
(Yeah... I would too, if I
were in that situation.)

<Maya>
あ！　も、もしかして‥‥
それを助けてくれたのが‥‥？
Oh! I think I get it!
Did Mr. DeLite come running
to save you?

<Desirée>
そう！　ユーサクくんだったの！
ガードマンの制服でキメてたよ。
Yes! Exactly! I remember
he looked so handsome in
that guard uniform of his!

ナイフを持ったヤツらに向かって、
まず、ガツンとドナリつけたんだ。
He went right up to those two
knife-wielding robbers... and
screamed in their faces!

“やめてくださーーーい！”って。
強盗たちも、ヒルんじゃって。
"PLEASE, STOP IIIIIIIIIIT!"
he screamed. I could see the
robbers' faces turn pale...

<Phoenix>
（あの悲痛なウラ声は、ミョーに
　ココロにつき刺さるからな‥‥）
(That high-pitched shriek of
his does have a surprisingly
strong effect on people...)

<Desirée>
そして、泣きながら両手ふり回して
強盗につかみかかっていったワケ。
Then, crying and swinging his
arms like crazy, he attacked
the two robbers.

‥‥見ず知らずの、このアタシを
助けるために。たったヒトリで。
All by himself...
He came to save me, a total
stranger, all by himself...

自分が刺されるかもしれないのに。
ガクガクふるえながら。
He was so scared that he was
crying and shaking, but he
still risked his life for me.

<Maya>
‥‥はああ。
いいおハナシですねえ‥‥。
...Wow.
That's a great story...

<Desirée>
ああ、この人はイザというとき、
イノチをかけて戦えるヒトだ‥‥
Yes. He may not look it,
but in a tough situation,
there's no one better...

‥‥アタシね、そう思ったんだ。
うれしかったよ。
...That's why I fell in love
with him like I did.

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥ホレちゃうかも
しれませんねー。
*sniff sniff*
Th-That's so romantic...
I'd fall in love too, I guess.

<Maya>
なるほどくん、シッカリたのむよ。
あたしが人質にとられたときは。
Nick, I hope you'll do the
same for me if I ever get
taken hostage...

<Phoenix>
（この子の場合、そういうコトが
　ホントにありそうで、コワい）
(With Maya, that possibility
always seems to loom in the
not so distant future. *gulp*)




<Maya>
まれかさん。《ＫＢ警備》って
ご存じですか？
Ms. DeLite, do you know about
KB Security?

<Desirée>
もちろん。ユーサクくんが
つとめている会社だもん。
Don't be silly, of course
I do. That's where my
Ronnie works.

<Phoenix>
（“つとめている”会社‥‥か）
(So she thinks he still
works there, huh...)

（たしか、ぼくたちが今日、
　聞いたハナシでは‥‥）
(Oh, that's right. According
to what we heard today...)

<Godot>
まさか‥‥
知らねえとは言わせねえぜ。
Come on! Don't tell me
you didn't know it!

天杉　優作はムカシ、
ＫＢ警備会社の社員‥‥
Ron DeLite was once an
employee of KB Security...

プロの警備員だったんだ。
He was a professional
security guard.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥今はもう、やめているはず
　なんだよな‥‥あの会社）
(...But he quit. He doesn't
work there anymore.)

<Maya>
まれかさん‥‥
知らないみたいだね。
It looks like Ms. DeLite
doesn't know...

<Desirée>
ＫＢ警備なら、ウチから２０分
ぐらいかな。バイクで飛ばして。
KB Security is only about
20 minutes away.
By motorcycle, that is.

<Phoenix>
矢張はクルマで３０分、って
言ってましたけど‥‥
Larry told me it takes
30 minutes by car...

<Desirée>
なんてったって、
飛ばすからさ。あたしのバイク。
Well, I have to admit I
tend to fly pretty fast on
my bike.

<Phoenix>
（“飛ばす”って‥‥
　空でも飛ぶのか？）
(To make it to KB Security
that fast, are you sure you
aren't literally flying...?)

<Desirée>
‥‥あ。なんだったら、
乗せていってあげようか。今から。
Why don't I give you a
ride sometime? Or better
yet, how about now?

<Phoenix>
い、いえいえいえ‥‥。そんな！
Um, ahh... N-No...!
I'll pass, th-thanks!

とりあえず、場所だけ
教えてもらえればケッコウです。
Wh-Why don't you just tell
us where it is and we'll go
ourselves.

<Maya>
あーあ。いくじなしだなー、
なるほどくんは。
Ha ha, what a scaredy-cat
you are, Nick!

<Phoenix>
（まれかさんからＫＢ警備の
　場所を教えてもらった）
(Ms. DeLite told us the
location of KB Security.)

<Maya>
よーし。じゃあサッソク
行ってみようか、なるほどくん！
OK. Let's head over
there right away, Nick!




<Desirée>
《倉院のツボ》かあ。
よかったね、戻ってきて。
I'm so happy that you got
your Sacred Urn back.

<Maya>
まれかさんのおかげです！
‥‥ごめんなさい。
Well, I have you to thank
for that, Ms. DeLite!
...A-And I'm sorry.

<Desirée>
‥‥？　なんで、あやまるの？
Huh...?
What are you apologizing for?

<Maya>
だって‥‥ツボを盗んだハンニンは
優作さんだ、って思ったから‥‥
Because I mistakenly blamed
your husband for taking it...

<Desirée>
あはは。だから言ったでしょ。
Ha! I told you, didn't I?

ユーサクくんが
怪人のワケ、ないって。
My Ronnie could never do
such a thing.




<Phoenix>
あの、これなんですけど‥‥
Umm, so what do you know
about this...?

<Maya>
だ、ダメだよなるほどくん！
No!
You can't show her that, Nick!

そのエンブレム、ゴクヒだって
言われたでしょ！
That emblem is top-secret!
Don't you remember!?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥そうだったっけ。
...Doh!
Oops, sorry about that.

（ゴクヒと言われると、よけい
　見せびらかしたくなるよな‥‥）
(But the way she just said
"top-secret" was a worse
giveaway than what I did...)

<Desirée>
あたしも、ゴクヒって言われると
よけい見たくなるよー。
Ooh! When I hear the word
"top-secret", it just piques
my interest like nothing else!




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥これ、なんですけど。
知ってますか？
Umm...
Do you know about this?

<Desirée>
ああ、ユーサクくん宛ての
お手紙ね？
Oh, is that a letter addressed
to my Ronnie?

アタシ、ヒトのものを勝手に
盗み見るの、キライだから。
Sorry, but I hate it when
people poke their noses into
other people's business.

<Maya>
‥‥やっぱり、まれかさんは
知らないみたいだね。
It looks like Ms. DeLite
doesn't know about it...

優作さんが
キョーハクされていたコト‥‥
Which means she has no idea
that her husband was being
blackmailed...




<Desirée>
ユーサクくんのサイフだね、それ。
That's Ronnie's wallet.

<Maya>
事件があった夜、ＫＢ警備の
ビルで見つかったんですけど‥‥
It was found at KB Security on
the night of the murder...

<Desirée>
あの晩は、ユーサクくんと
レストランでゴハン食べて‥‥
Ronnie and I went out to
dinner early that evening...

そのときは、たしかに
あったんだけどなー、それ。
I'm sure he had his wallet
with him then.

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり‥‥優作くんが
　現場で落としたのかな‥‥）
(So it's true then.
He must have dropped it
at the crime scene...)




<Desirée>
あ！　知ってるよ、それ。
Ah! I know what that is!

ユーサクくんの会社の
カードだから。
That's one of those key cards
from Ronnie's company.

‥‥そういえば、ひさしぶりに
見た気がするなあ‥‥。
...Come to think of it, it's
been a long time since
I've seen one.

<Phoenix>
（会社はやめていたみたい
　だからな‥‥優作くん）
(That's probably because Ron
doesn't work there anymore...)




<Desirée>
これが怪人☆仮面マスクかー。
どんなウチに住んでるのかなあ。
So this is Mask☆DeMasque, huh?
I wonder what kind of a house
he lives in.

<Phoenix>
こんなウチ‥‥かもしれませんね。
Who knows... Maybe it's
exactly like this house.

<Desirée>
あはははは。
それ、おもしろいねー。
Ha ha ha, you're so funny
sometimes, Nicky boy.

でも、アタシが怪人なら、もっと
ゴージャスなお屋敷に住みたいな。
But if I was a famous
thief, I'd live in a great
big, gorgeous mansion.

<Phoenix>
‥‥優作くんに伝えておきます。
...I'll be sure to tell
that to your husband.




<Phoenix>
すみません。
これ、なんですけど‥‥
Excuse me, but would you
take a look at this...?

<Desirée>
やー、ゴメン。
アタシ、意外に世間知らずでさー。
Oh, I'm sorry...
I haven't the faintest idea.

ちょっと、わからないな。
そういうの。
I guess I just don't get out
enough.




<Desirée>
リューイチくん、
弁護士なんだよね。
So, Nicky boy, you're a
lawyer, huh?

<Phoenix>
ええ、まあ。
Well, yeah.

<Desirée>
どう？　弁護士って。
スリルがあるんじゃない？
How do you like it?
I bet it's SO exciting!

<Phoenix>
‥‥まあ、たしかに。
不必要なほどスリリングですね。
...Yeah, sometimes.
Actually, a little too
exciting at times.

<Desirée>
‥‥アタシ、大好物
なんだよねー、スリル。
Oooh! I just love a good
thrill.

‥‥ふうん‥‥いいなあ、
リューイチくんは‥‥
Hmm... Nicky boy...
It sounds like you have it
so nice...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥うう‥‥
　いごこち悪いな、どうも）
(Um... This is starting
to get awkward.)




<Desirée>
たいしたもんだよねー、
その若さで家元なんてさ。
That's really amazing!
A "Master" at your age!

<Maya>
い、いえいえ。今の家元は、
あたしのおかあさんなんですけど。
Oh no, you've got it wrong.
It's my mother that's the
current Master!

<Desirée>
あ。そうなんだ。
‥‥ところでさ。なんの家元？
Oh, I see...
So what exactly is she the
master of anyway?

<Maya>
えーと、れいば
Well, you see, it's li--

<Phoenix>
やめとけよ。“霊媒”なんて
言っても、笑われるだけだぞ。
Don't say it, Maya.
If you say "spirit
channeling", she'll laugh.

<Maya>
ううう‥‥さみしいなあ。
Ouch... That hurt.




<Desirée>
あ、この子。
リューイチくんにビンタしてた。
Oh, this girl.
I saw her slap Nicky boy
right across the face.

<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥
（そのおぼえ方はやめてほしいな）
Um, ah, yeah, she did...
(Of all the ways she could
remember Pearls by... Why?)

<Desirée>
かわいいよねー。
今度さ。あたしにも紹介してよ。
She's such a little cutie.
If you could bring her by,
I'd love to meet her.

<Maya>
ええ！　いいですよ。
Sure! Of course!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥また、ひっぱたかれそうな
　気がする‥‥）
(Great... I can just tell I'm
in for a reprise of the
"Hundred Hand Slap"...)

<Maya>
‥‥？
...?




<Desirée>
たよりなさそうに見えるけどねー。
I know he doesn't look it...

これでも、やるときは
ビシッとやるんだよ。
But he can really get things
done when he puts his mind
to it.

<Maya>
へえ！　いつなんですか？
その“やるとき”って。
Really? So when exactly does
he put his mind to it?

<Desirée>
‥‥まあ。
めったにないけど。
...Well.
Not very often, I admit.

‥‥でもね。アタシは
一生、忘れないと思うな。
...But I'll never forget the
first time we met as long
as I live.

<Maya>
ステキな思い出が
あるんだね、まれかさん。
It must be nice to have
such a fond memory
like that...




<Desirée>
ゼッタイ、ユルせないよ、
こんなヤツ。
I'll never forgive this man.

自分のツミを、ユーサクくんに
着せようなんて。
He tried to pin his own
crimes on my Ronnie.

<Maya>
そうですよね！
I don't blame you!

<Desirée>
犯罪者って、みんなそう！
自分勝手で‥‥ヒキョウで！
All criminals are the same!
They're nothing but filthy,
sneaking liars!

アタシ、大っキライ！
I hate their guts!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんとなく、
　わかる気がするな‥‥）
(*gulp*
OK, I think I get it...)

（ユーサクくんが、怪人のコトを
　まれかさんに話してない理由）
(...And I think I can see why
Ron didn't tell her how he
was earning that money.)




<Desirée>
アタシは、バイクとユーサクくんが
いれば、シアワセだなー。
As long as I've got my
motorcycle and my Ronnie,
I'm happy.

<Maya>
うわあ、ステキですね！
Oh! That's so sweet!

<Desirée>
あとは‥‥少しのスリルと、
少しじゃないお金があれば。
Oh, that plus a little
excitement and a little
shopping money.

それで、もうじゅうぶんかな。
...THEN I'm happy.

<Maya>
‥‥意外によくばりだよ、
なるほどくん‥‥
Now she's starting to sound
a bit greedy...
Don't you think, Nick?




<Desirée>
あー、サイフを
届けてくれた、カレだね。
Oh, this is the guy who
delivered Ronnie's wallet.

『やっぱり』が口グセの。
He's got some "issues",
doesn't he?

<Phoenix>
‥‥え。
...Huh?

<Desirée>
しゃべってたら、不自然なほど
『やっぱり』を連呼するから、
Let's just say his flirting
style is pretty obvious.
...Pretty stale too, actually.

名前は忘れちゃったけど、
そのクセだけ、印象に残ってるな。
It's pretty sad when the only
thing you remember about a man
are his lame pick-up lines.

<Phoenix>
（たぶん、自分を売りこもうと
　必死だったんだろうな‥‥矢張）
(What's even more sad is said
man probably believes in those
like they're his life-lines.)

<Maya>
‥‥作戦はシッパイだった
みたいだけどね。
...Looks like he blew it
again, huh?




<Desirée>
こいつ‥‥シャチョーだね、
ユーサクくんの会社の。
Oh, I know him...
This is Ronnie's boss,
the CEO guy.

<Phoenix>
亡くなったんですよ。
ゆうべ、ナニモノかに襲われて。
Well, now he's an ex-boss.
Someone killed him last night.

<Desirée>
‥‥うん。モチロン知ってるよ。
Naturally, I know that.

なんかね。ズルがしこい
ヤツだったな。
He was a pretty sly man,
let me tell you.

<Maya>
そうなんですか‥‥
Oh really...?

<Desirée>
ユーサクくんに《警備チームの
チーフ》っていう肩書きをつけて、
You bet he was.
He made Ronnie "Chief" of
one of the security teams.

さんざん、コキ使われてた
からね。もう、スリ切れるほど。
But that was just so
he could work him like
a slave.

<Maya>
‥‥優作さん、
社長さんにモンクは‥‥？
Did Mr. DeLite ever
have a problem with
Mr. Bullard himself?

<Phoenix>
（言えるワケ、ないよな‥‥）
(Even if he did, you think
she'd ever tell you about
it...?)

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、そういうコト、
あんまりギモンに思わないし。
Well Ronnie isn't the type
to complain about that
kind of thing.

アタシががんばっても、
相手にされなくってさ‥‥
I tried to get him to talk
to me about work, but he
never would.




<Desirée>
イヤなヤツだよね、ホント。
Grrr, I don't like this
man one bit.

最初っから、狙ってたんだ。
ユーサクくんのコト。
He's had it in for my Ronnie
from the very beginning.

‥‥サツジンハンとして、
疑いをかけてたんだよ！
It's his fault that Ronnie is
under suspicion of committing
murder.

<Phoenix>
ぼくは、コーヒーを
かけられましたしね。
Plus, he lobbed a coffee
grenade at me!

<Maya>
かけられっぱなしじゃ
カッコわるいよね‥‥
You looked pretty silly
wearing that mug on your
head like a birthday hat...

よし。明日、アイツに
牛乳ひっかけちゃおうよ！
Oh, I know! We can get him
back tomorrow by returning
fire with a milk grenade!




同日　某時刻
哀牙探偵事務所
October 13
Atmey Detective Agency

<Phoenix>
‥‥ものすごい数の警官が、
ものすごいイキオイで捜査中だ。
Whoa, this place is literally
crawling with cops!

<Maya>
そりゃまあ‥‥仮面マスクの正体が
じつは名探偵だった、なんて‥‥
What did you expect?
Now that they know he was
actually Mask☆DeMasque...

警察にしてみれば、これ以上
マヌケなコトはないもんねー。
This must be incredibly
embarrassing for them,
don't you think?

<Phoenix>
メンツにかけて
捜査をしてる、ってワケか。
Yeah, I guess they're trying
to make up for it by tearing
the place apart.

そういえば‥‥
イトノコ刑事が、いないぞ。
Hey, I just noticed...
Gumshoe is nowhere to be seen.

<Maya>
殺人事件の捜査じゃない？
Well, he is a homicide
detective. He's probably
working on the murder case.

<Phoenix>
でも、きのうまで仮面マスクの
担当だったのに‥‥
But wasn't he in charge of the
Mask☆DeMasque investigation
all the way up to yesterday?

<Maya>
やっぱり、シゲキ的だからね。
サツジンのほうが。
Well, a murder case is a lot
more exciting, isn't it?

“そっちのほうが楽しそうッスー”
‥‥なーんて。
He'd say something like:
"There's nothin' like a good
murder case, pal."

<Phoenix>
（‥‥浮気な刑事さんだな‥‥）
(Points for the quality of the
impression, but I'm not sure
Gumshoe has bloodlust, Maya.)




<Officer>
コラッ！　キミタチッ！
Hey! You guys!

<Maya>
きゃっ！
Eeek!

<Officer>
勝手にさわっちゃイカン！
ワレワレが捜査中だッ！
We're investigating this
place! So keep your hands
to yourselves!

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
フキゲンだよ‥‥警察のヒトたち。
Boy! These policemen sure
are a bunch of sourpusses!

<Phoenix>
そりゃ、名探偵にコケにされて
ゴキゲンってわけにもいかないよ。
Well, Mr. Ace Detective did
make complete and utter
fools out of them...

<Officer>
さあさあ、帰りなさいッ！
ほらほら、今すぐッ！
What's all this now!
Move it along!
The show's over!

<Maya>
ううう‥‥。調べさせて
くれそうにないよ。
Aww...
It doesn't look like they're
going to let us investigate.

<Phoenix>
（今日は、あきらめたほうが
　いいみたいだな‥‥）
(I guess we might as well
call it a day for this place
and go look somewhere else.)

