<Judge>
‥‥そこまで！
That's enough!

本法廷は、これ以上の審議の
必要性を認めません。
This court sees no reason to
further prolong the trial.

これは、きわめて明白な事件です。
疑問の余地はない！
This case is extremely clear.
I see no room for mis-
interpretation of the facts.

< >
そ‥‥そんな‥‥
アタシじゃない！
I-It wasn't me!
I swear it wasn't me!

<Judge>
毒入りのコーヒーを飲んだとき、
テーブルにいたのは被害者だけ‥‥
The evidence and testimony
we have seen and heard are
conclusive!

<Judge>
‥‥すべての証言・証拠が、
それを物語っています！
The victim was alone at his
table when he drank from that
poisoned cup of coffee.

< >
ちがう！　アタシ‥‥見たのに！
本当に‥‥見たのに‥‥
No! You're wrong!
I know what I saw...!
I saw... I saw...!



< >
そうよ！　‥‥もうひとり、いた！
アイツが‥‥アイツが、犯人！
I saw someone else there!
A man. He's the real killer!

< >
‥‥どうして‥‥
だれも信じてくれないの！
Why won't anyone believe me?

<Payne>
どうやら‥‥
勝負あったようですな。
Well...
I'd say that pretty much wraps
this case up, wouldn't you...

‥‥成歩堂くん！
...Mr. Wright!?




<Judge>
それでは‥‥被告人に、
判決を言い渡します。
This court finds the
defendant...

本日は、これにて閉廷！
The court is adjourned.




< >
１月　６日　午前１０時　３分
成歩堂法律事務所
January 6, 10:03 AM
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Maya>
いやあ。正月気分がぬけないねえ
なるほどくん。
Ahh! The start of the new year
always makes me feel like I
can take on the whole world!

<Phoenix>
そうだなあ。
I bet it does, Maya.

<Maya>
そうだ。今年の成歩堂法律事務所の
抱負はズヴァリ！　“正月気分”。
So! I've decided that our
resolution should be...
Zvarri! "Take on the world!"

‥‥コレで行こうよ！
What do you think?

<Phoenix>
どうでもいいけど、
食いすぎじゃないか？　おもち。
Sure, whatever, Maya... But I
think maybe you've had more
than enough mistletoe cake.

<Maya>
いいのいいの。お正月といえば、
おもち食べながらみかん食べて、
Never! You've got to eat a lot
of cake during New Year's!
It's practically a tradition!

おせちをつつきながらテレビ見て、
さらにトランプでババ抜きだから。
Like watching the fireworks on
TV or playing a board game.

<???>
コラアッ！
HEY, PAL!

<Phoenix>
い、イトノコ刑事‥‥
Detective Gumshoe...

<Maya>
あけまして
おめでとうございます！
Happy New Year, Detective!

<Gumshoe>
う‥‥お、おめでとうございます。
コラ、アンタ！
Uh... likewise...
NOW LISTEN UP, WRIGHT!
I WANNA...

<Maya>
今年もよろしくおねがいします！
Here's to another fruitful
year of lawyer-police
cooperation!

<Gumshoe>
う‥‥よ、よろしく‥‥。
いいッスか！　アンタは‥‥
Um... Yeah... Me too...
ALRIGHT, PAL! YOU'VE GOT
SOME EXPLAINING TO...

<Maya>
あ。イトノコさんイトノコさん。
お年玉ちょうだい！
Have you got a holiday
present for me, Detective?

<Gumshoe>
う‥‥じゃ、じゃあこれ。
ケンソン抜きで少ないッスけど。
A what? Well... I, um...
Here, have this. It-It's
really nothing much, but...

<Maya>
やったあ！
Yay! Thanks!

<Gumshoe>
今日はハナシがあるッス！
そこに座るッス！
LOOK, PAL, WE NEED
TO HAVE A TALK.
TAKE A SEAT!

<Maya>
はみちゃんのぶんも。
Hey! What about Pearly?
You haven't forgotten her
present, have you?

<Gumshoe>
う‥‥は、はい‥‥って、
ワザとやってないッス？
Ah... N-No... I mean, yes...
I mean, no...
Are you doing this on purpose?

<Maya>
バレちゃいました？
初わらい、ってヤツですね！
Ha ha, guess I'm busted.
How did you like my first
practical joke of the year?

<Gumshoe>
ハッ！　コレを見ても
笑っていられるッスかッ！
Very funny, pal. Now let's
see how funny you think it is
when I show you this!

<Phoenix>
‥‥雑誌‥‥ですか？
What is it?
A magazine?

<Maya>
えー、なになに。
Hey, I wanna see!

《毒殺事件に有罪判決。
　成歩堂弁護士、惨敗》
"Deadly Poisoning Brings
Guilty Verdict. Defense
Attorney Wright Trounced."

<Phoenix>
ざ、ザンパイ‥‥？
ちょ、ちょっと貸して！
Tr-Trounced!?
Let me see that!

“昨日の裁判での弁護士は、
　まさにシロウト以下で‥‥”
"The defense attorney gave an
almost childishly amateur
performance yesterday..."

‥‥なんだコレ？
What the heck is this!?

<Gumshoe>
アンタのコトッス！
It's a report, pal.
About you!

<Maya>
“有罪判決のセキニンのすべては、
　成歩堂弁護士にある”だって。
Listen to this! "Mr. Wright
must take full responsibility
for the ruling in this case."

<Gumshoe>
どッス！　おぼえがないとは
言わせねッス！
WELL!? And don't tell me you
don't remember anything about
it!

<Phoenix>
お、おぼえがありませんよ！
But I don't remember anything
about it!

だいたい、いつの雑誌ですか？
それ。
When was that issue from
anyway?

<Gumshoe>
えーと。‥‥去年の１２月ッスね。
Umm...
December of last year, which
I guess makes it last month.

<Maya>
古雑誌じゃないですか。
Which makes it old news,
you mean.

<Phoenix>
去年の１２月に、
毒殺事件なんて扱ってませんよ！
But I wasn't involved in a
poisoning case in December!

<Maya>
‥‥どういうことなのかな？
Hmm, so what do you
think this is all about, Nick?

<Gumshoe>
これがアンタじゃないとすると
‥‥考えられるのは、１つッス。
If it wasn't you, pal, then
that leaves only one
possibility...

<Maya>
ま。まさか‥‥‥
No way. You don't mean...

<Phoenix>
に‥‥‥
A pho...

<Maya>
ニセなるほどくん。
A phony Nick!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥初わらいだな、たしかに）
(This must be Gumshoe's idea
of a joke. Guess he's starting
off the year with one, too...)

< >
《雑誌の記事》を
法廷記録にファイルした。
Magazine Clipping added to
the Court Record.

<Gumshoe>
さー、どうしてくれるッス！
SO!? What are you gonna do
about it, pal!?

<Phoenix>
どうする、って言われましても‥‥
What do you mean, what am I
going to do about it?

<Maya>
でも。でも。なるほどくんのせいで
有罪になっちゃったんだよ！
Well, it's your fault that
the judge found the defendant
guilty in this case!

<Phoenix>
ぼ、ぼくのせい‥‥？
My fault!?
How do you figure that?

<Maya>
なるほどくん、最近ちょっと
有名になってきたからねー。
Because THE Phoenix Wright
is super famous now!
Well, maybe only sort of...

<Gumshoe>
チョーシに乗るから、
こういうコトになるッス！
Yeah. See what happens when
you hotshots start getting
too full of yourselves?

<Phoenix>
（ううう‥‥
　ぼくがワルいのか‥‥）
(But I didn't do anything
wrong! ...At least, not that
I can remember...)

<Gumshoe>
キチンとオワビに行くッス！
今からッス！　すぐにッス！
You better make this right,
pal. Now!

そして、裁判をやりなおすッス！
And that means taking the case
back to court. Got it?

<Maya>
“正月気分”で引き受ける、
今年最初の事件になりそうだね！
Sounds like we've got our
first case of the new year!
Let's tackle it with gusto!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥この事件、一度は
有罪判決を受けてるんだぞ。
I don't know... The judge
already issued a guilty
verdict once in this case.

カンタンにひっくり返せるワケ、
ないじゃないか。
It's not going to be easy to
get it overturned.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ザンネンだけど、“正月気分”は
来年の抱負にしようか。
I guess that New Year's
resolution is going to have
to wait until next year.

<Gumshoe>
じゃッ！　自分はこれから、
裁判所のほうに行くッスから！
So you're taking the case,
right!? Good! I'm gonna head
over to the courthouse then.

なんかあったら、ケーサツの
自分のところへ来るッス！
After that, I'll go back to
the precinct. Drop by if you
need something, OK pal!?

<Phoenix>
（たしかに“成歩堂　龍一”の名前
　も、少しは知られてきたようだ）
(I guess people are starting
to know the name, "Phoenix
Wright".)

（依頼人が、その名前を信頼して
　ぼくに弁護を頼んだのなら‥‥）
(If a client entrusted a case
to me based on my
reputation...)

（ぼくにも、セキニンが
　あるのかもしれない）
(I guess I am kind of
responsible.)

（‥‥それにしても‥‥
　ぼくの“ニセモノ”なんて‥‥）
(But why would someone want to
impersonate me?)

（いったい、どんなヤツなんだ？）
(What sort of a guy would do
that?)




<Phoenix>
観葉植物のチャーリーくん。
Charley.
A quite decorative plant.

今は亡くなってしまった所長、
千尋さんの形見‥‥だ。
He's sort of a keepsake...
Something to remember
Mia by.

散らかりほうだいの事務所だけど、
こいつの世話だけは忘れない。
Sure, the office is a mess,
but I never forget to water
this little fella.




<Phoenix>
ムズカシイ法律の本が
あざ笑うように並んでいる。
Difficult-looking legal books
stand in a formidable row.
They mock me.

‥‥そういえば、うっすらと
ホコリをかぶってるな。
...Actually, I've neglected
them for so long that they're
covered in a layer of dust.

たまには‥‥せめて
読むフリだけでもしてみるか。
I guess I should at least
pretend to read them
once in a while.




<Phoenix>
ぼくのデスクだ。
It's my desk.

あまり座る機会がないため、
いやにキチンとかたづいている。
I don't get to use it much, so
it's still super neat and tidy
from when Pearls cleaned it.




<Phoenix>
窓の向かいがわには、
巨大なビルがそびえている。
There is a giant building
just outside the window.

《ホテル・バンドー》
超ゴウカな超一流ホテルだ。
It's the Gatewater Hotel, a
high-class, luxury hotel.

なんでも、となり街の一角を
ゴッソリ買収して、
The chain is getting so rich
that they bought a whole
chunk of the next town over...

超レジャー施設《バンドーランド》
の建設が始まったらしい。
...and started building a huge
theme park. It's going to be
called "Gatewater Land".

‥‥そういえば、あのボーイさん
から年賀状が来てたっけ。
...I wonder if that bellboy is
going to send me a greeting
card this year, too?




<Phoenix>
古い映画のポスターだ。
An old movie poster.

ムカシ千尋さんが見て、
初めて泣いた映画なのだそうだ。
Apparently, this was the first
movie that made Mia cry when
she saw it, a long time ago.

最近、妹の真宵ちゃんが見て、
一晩中泣いていたらしい。
Maya watched it recently, and
said she cried all night, too!

‥‥ということで、最近は
このポスターを張ってある。
...Which, I guess, is why it's
back up on the wall.

今度、ぼくも見てみるか。
I'll have to check it
out one of these days.




<Maya>
さて。どうしようか、これから。
So, what's our first move?

<Phoenix>
どうする、って。
留置所に行って、話を聞いたり‥‥
I guess we go down to the
detention center and talk--

<Maya>
でもさ。相手は、なるほどくんの
せいで有罪になったヒトだよ。
Wait a sec, Nick.
This person's behind
bars because of you.

どんなカオして会えばいいの？
Whoever it is isn't going to
be jumping at the chance to
meet you, right?

<Phoenix>
いやいや！　でも、それは
ニセモノだったワケだろ？
Hey, hey! Let's get one thing
straight. It wasn't me, it was
a fake me that did this!

<Maya>
やっぱり、カオもソックリなのかな
‥‥なるほどくんのニセモノ。
Hmm, I wonder if he looks
exactly like you...
Your phony, Xin Eohp, I mean.

<Phoenix>
（ブキミな話だな‥‥）
(I hope not. *shudder* ...And
what kind of name for an evil
double is Xin Eohp anyway!?)

<Maya>
あ。もしかして、なるほどくん！
Ah! Nick!
I've got it!

<Phoenix>
双子の兄弟なら、いないぞ。
If you're going to ask whether
I've got a twin brother, the
answer is no.

<Maya>
‥‥つまんないの。
...Spoilsport.




<Maya>
今日のイトノコさん、
なんかヘンだったよねー。
Did you notice Gumshoe was
acting weirder than usual, or
was it just me?

<Phoenix>
‥‥なにが？
What do you mean?

<Maya>
ものスゴく
あたふたしてたじゃない。
I mean, he was really
worked up.

初めてムスコさんが生まれた
パパさながらに。
Like a guy who's just found
out he's going to be a dad or
something.

<Phoenix>
そういえば‥‥たしかに。
Yeah, I guess he was acting
kind of strange.

<Maya>
強い思い入れがあるのかな。
なるほどくんに。
Maybe he realized he's got
strong feelings for you, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥きもちわるいコト
言うなよ。
...
Considering how we interact,
I seriously doubt that, Maya...

<Maya>
なるほどくんのせいで
コーフンしてたんじゃなければ‥‥
Well, if he wasn't nervous
because of you...

<Phoenix>
その原因は、
有罪になった依頼人‥‥かな。
...then maybe it's because of
our new guilty client?




<Maya>
まだ持ってたんだ、そのバッジ。
So you've still got that
badge, I see.

<Phoenix>
そ、そりゃそうだろう。
弁護士なんだから。
Huh!?
Well, I'm a lawyer, aren't I?

<Maya>
いやー、こんなに長く
つづくとは思わなかったよ。
Yeah, but I guess I just
didn't think you'd keep on
being one for this long.

あぶなっかしいからねー、
なるほどくんのベンゴ。
You have to admit, you've had
some close brushes with death
because of your job.

<Phoenix>
（それは、真宵ちゃんの霊媒も
　似たようなモノだと思うけど）
(...I fail to see how being a
lawyer is more dangerous than
channeling dead people.)




<Phoenix>
どうかな。これなんだけど。
Do you know anything about
this, Maya?

<Maya>
うーん‥‥
Hmm...

さすがのあたしも、この世のすべて
を知ってるワケじゃないからねー。
Even someone as worldly-wise
as me doesn't know everything
about everything, Nick.

それについては、なんとも
言えないな。さすがのあたしも。
So I, the great Maya, am sad
to say I can't tell you much
about this object.

<Phoenix>
（そこまでキタイしてない）
(A simple yes or no, Maya...
It's not as if you had to give
me a dissertation...)




<Maya>
それにしても、
なるほどくんのニセモノかあ。
I can't believe you've got
an impersonator.

<Phoenix>
メーワクな話だよな。
I can't either. *sigh*

<Maya>
あ。でも、モノマネされる
芸能人は一流だっていうじゃない！
Aww, but look on the bright
side. Only famous stars have
people impersonating them!

<Phoenix>
“モノマネ”じゃなくて
“ニセモノ”だしなあ。
This isn't funny, Maya. It's
not just an impersonation.
This guy stole my identity!

ヒトが有罪になってるんだ。
‥‥シャレにならないよ。
And someone may have been
wrongly convicted as a result.

<Maya>
芸能人になればよかったのにね、
なるほどくん。
...Guess you should've gone
into showbiz, huh, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥それは
　マッタク関係ないと思う）
(...*sigh*
I will never understand how
your mind works, Maya.)




<Maya>
《クリーニング・ボンバー》
‥‥ねえ。
Hmm... "MC Bomber"...

<Phoenix>
それに、《イッセンマン》だぞ。
And don't forget the
"100,000", too.

<Maya>
なんか、どこか引っかかるね。
《クリーニング・ボンバー》。
There's something about that
name, "MC Bomber".

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥
気になる名前だよなあ。
Yeah. It's a pretty unusual
name.

<Maya>
今日び《ボンバー》だもんねえ。
Everyone's worried about
bombs these days, I guess.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そういうイミじゃ
　ないんだけど‥‥）
(I'm not sure that has any
bearing on anything related
to this case...)

<Maya>
とにかく、ちゃんと調べて
みたほうがいいね！
Anyway, we should really look
into this some more!




<Phoenix>
どうなの？　霊媒師の
修行のほうは。
So? How's your spirit medium
training going?

<Maya>
‥‥うん。ちゃんと
打たれてるよ。シャワーに。
Well... I stand under the
rushing waters of the
shower head every day.

<Phoenix>
それは“浴びてる”って
言うんだよ。滝のほうは？
...That's called "taking a
shower". What happened to the
rushing waters of a waterfall?

<Maya>
ちょっと、お休み。
なんかね。ダメなんだ、今。
Well, I'm kind of taking a
break... I'm having a bit of
trouble right now, you know?

<Phoenix>
（１年前の、あの事件から‥‥）
(Last year's incident must
still be on her mind...)

（修行している真宵ちゃんを
　見なくなった）
(I haven't seen Maya train
at all since that time.)

（“迷っている”‥‥千尋さんが
　そう言ってたっけ‥‥）
(I think Mia said that it's
because Maya's at a loss
these days...)




<Maya>
めずらしいよね、
イトノコさん。
Digging up an old case that's
already been ruled on...

有罪が決まった事件を
ほじくり返すなんて。
That's not like Gumshoe,
is it?

<Phoenix>
たしかに。いつも目の前の事件
だけでアップアップしてるのに。
No. He barely manages to stay
on top of the cases in front
of him.

<Maya>
忙しいわ給料は安いわで、
コートもかえないし。
Yeah, he's always busy, and
gets dirt pay. I mean, look at
that dusty old coat he wears!

<Phoenix>
（“替えない”なのか
　“買えない”なのか‥‥？）
(Did you mean he "gets paid
dirt" or do you really think
they pay him in gravel?)




<Phoenix>
‥‥こないだの裁判で、
また助けてもらっちゃったな。
Mia helped me out in court
again last time.

<Maya>
いいね、なるほどくんは
お姉ちゃんに会えて。
It's so cool that you get to
meet my sis like that.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
Yeah...

<Maya>
あたしたち‥‥霊媒中は、
イシキがとぎれちゃうから。
We mediums lose consciousness
when we're channeling, so I
don't get to see my sis...

<Phoenix>
‥‥そういえば、
そうだったね。
...I never really thought
about it that way.

あ！　でも‥‥
千尋さんに会いたかったら、
Hey!
If you want to meet Mia...

春美ちゃんに呼び出して
もらえばいいじゃないか。
...why don't we just have
Pearls call her?

<Maya>
ううん‥‥
それは、できないよ。
No...
I couldn't do that.

はみちゃんに、シンパイ
かけちゃうからね。
I'd be too worried about her.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥真宵ちゃんも、
　いろいろ考えてるんだな）
(I guess Maya's got all sorts
of things to think about, too.)

（‥‥見かけによらず）
(...Despite her immaturity
saying otherwise.)




<Maya>
ケッキョク、まだ思い出せないの？
ゴドー検事のコト。
So you still can't remember
anything about Godot, huh?

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。だから、
ぼくのほうは知らないんだよ！
I already told you. I have
no idea who he is, let alone
why he dislikes me so much.

<Maya>
なんだか、なるほどくんに
恨みでもあるみたいだし。
Well he sure seems to have a
problem with you for some
reason.

気をつけてね。
コーヒー好きはハラ黒いから。
You'd better watch your back,
Nick. Coffee lovers can be
quite bitter.

<Phoenix>
勝手なコト言うなよ。
You're just making that up,
Maya!




<Maya>
マコちゃん‥‥２回目だね。
殺人容疑でつかまるの。
This is Maggey's second time
as a murder suspect, huh?

<Phoenix>
もう、１年以上たつのか。
この前の事件から‥‥
Yeah. The first time was a
little over a year ago...

あのころは、婦人警官の
制服を着ていたっけ。
She was on the police force
back then.

<Maya>
イトノコさんのブカだって
言ってたよね、たしか。
Wasn't she working under
Gumshoe?

‥‥今度も、
ゼッタイ助けてあげようね！
That does it, Nick! We're
gonna get her off the hook
or I'll give up hamburgers!




<Phoenix>
どうかな。このヒトなんだけど。
Do you know anything about
this person?

<Maya>
うーん‥‥
Hmm...

さすがのあたしも、世界中のみんな
とトモダチ、ってワケじゃないし。
Even someone as worldly-wise
as me doesn't know everything
about everyone, Nick.

そのヒトについては、なんとも
言えないな。さすがのあたしも。
So I, the great Maya, am sad
to say I can't tell you much
about this individual.

<Phoenix>
（そこまでキタイしてない）
(A simple yes or no, Maya...
It's not as if you had to give
me a dissertation...)




同日　某時刻
成歩堂法律事務所
January 6
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Phoenix>
やれやれ‥‥本土坊さん、
真宵ちゃんを気に入ったみたいだ。
Poor Maya. It looks like
Mr. Armstrong's really taken
a shine to her.

しかたない。彼女には
しばらく、はたらいてもらうか。
I suppose I'll just have to
let her work at the restaurant
for a while.

‥‥ほとぼりがさめたころ、
吐麗美庵にむかえに行こう。
I'll go pick her up from
Trés Bien once things have
cooled off.




同日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
January 6
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Maya>
うう。ドキドキするねー。
どんなヒトだったんだろ？
This is so nerve-wracking,
waiting to meet our new
client.

なるほどくんにダマされて
有罪にされちゃったの。
I wonder just what kind of
person you tricked and got
found guilty...?

<Phoenix>
ひ、ヒト聞きの悪いこと
言わないでほしいな。
K-Keep it down, Maya!
That kind of talk could ruin
me!

<???>
ああああああッ！
Aaaaaaaah!

成歩堂さん、ヒドいです！
このアタシを見捨てるなんて！
How could you, Mr. Wright!?
How could you do this to me!?

今も独房でひとり、
すすり泣いていたッス！
They put me in solitary!
I haven't been able to stop
crying.

<Phoenix>
き、きみは‥‥たしか‥‥
A-Aren't... you...

<???>
もースズキ、
人間不信になりそうッス！
Yes, I am! I am totally
and utterly let down!

<Maya>
あっ！　も、もしかして、
あなた‥‥
Aah! You're...
Are you...?

<???>
“もしかして”じゃないッスよ！
マコです。須々木　マコ！
Don't pretend you don't
know me! It's me, Maggey,
remember!? Maggey Byrde!

<Phoenix>
須々木　マコって‥‥ああ！
Maggey Byrde... Ah!

<Phoenix>
（須々木　マコ‥‥。以前、
　弁護した婦人警官だ‥‥）
(Maggey Byrde... She's the
policewoman I defended
that one time.)

（たしか、コイビトの警察官を
　殺害した容疑だった）
(She was accused of murdering
her lover. He was a cop, too.)

ど、どうしてこんなところに！
無罪になったはずじゃあ‥‥
What are you doing in here!?
Didn't I get you acquitt--

<Byrde>
うわあ！　よくそんな
コトが言えますね！
Oh, sure! Very funny!

あれだけザツな弁護で
ヒトに有罪、カッ食らわしといて！
After that fifth-rate defense
job, you come in here and
start making jokes!?

<Maya>
ダメだよなるほどくん。
ちゃんと事情を説明しないと！
You better hurry up and tell
her what happened, Nick.

<Byrde>
そ、そうだったんですか‥‥
O-Oh... I see...

<Phoenix>
そ、そうだったのか‥‥
So that's where we stand
right now.

<Maya>
‥‥また、事件に
巻きこまれちゃったんだ‥‥
I'm sorry you've been caught
up in another murder...

<Byrde>
スズキの人生は、まさに不運と
敗北と大番狂わせの見本市ッス。
My whole life has been nothing
but a whirlwind of bad luck
and failures.

<Phoenix>
（この前も、たしか
　そんなコト言ってたな‥‥）
(I vaguely remember her
saying the exact same thing
last time...)

<Byrde>
ヘーキッス！　また１つ、デッカイ
不幸をしょいこんだだけッス。
But I don't mind! What's one
more disaster in my life?

こうして、ホンモノの成歩堂さんも
来てくれたことだし‥‥
At least now the real
Mr. Wright is here with me.

スズキ、ヘコたれません！
I won't let the world keep me
down, sir!




<Byrde>
成歩堂さん‥‥。もう一度、
できるんですか？　‥‥裁判。
Mr. Wright...
Do you think it's possible
to get a retrial?

<Phoenix>
たぶんね。弁護士がいないまま
判決が下されたんだから。
Probably. The court ruled in
the absence of a genuine
defense attorney.

再審理はできると思うよ。
So we should be able to
get a retrial.

<Byrde>
あの‥‥成歩堂さん。
Um... Mr. Wright...?

<Phoenix>
？
?

<Byrde>
今度は‥‥勝てますか？
Do you think we'll win next
time? ...Sir?

<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

<Byrde>
たしかにスズキ、不幸のフルコース
に敗北のデザートつきの人生ッス。
My life has been a full course
meal of bad luck, complete
with defeat for dessert.

<Byrde>
生後６ヶ月のとき、マンションの
９階から落っこちたのを皮切りに、
Since I was 6 months old, when
I fell from the 9th floor of
my apartment building...

ひととおりの乗り物にはひかれ、
ひととおりの食べ物にはあたり、
...I've been hit by all sorts
of vehicles, gotten sick from
all sorts of foods...

だいたいの試験には落第して、
ほとんどの災害をも経験して、
...failed at almost every test
I've taken, experienced almost
every kind of disaster...

殺人の罪を着せられれば、弁護士の
ニセモノをつかまされる始末。
I even landed a phony lawyer
when I had the misfortune of
being accused of murder.

‥‥でも！
But!

それでも、このスズキは
生きているッス！　今も！
I will survive!
Because Maggey Byrde always
lives to fight another day!

だから！　いつか
見つけられるハズッス！
And one day, I'll find it!
Just you wait and see, sir!

‥‥ヒトなみのシアワセをッ！
I'll find that one, single
moment of good luck!

<Maya>
くっそー、
ニセなるほどくんめぇ‥‥
Argh, Xin Eohp is really gonna
pay for this!

<Phoenix>
な、なんでぼくを
ニラむんだよ‥‥
Wh-What are you staring at
me like that for...?

（とはいえ‥‥）
(But Maya's right...)

（ぼくの名前を使って、
　殺人の罪を着せるなんて‥‥）
(Whoever it is that thought it
was a good idea to use my
name...)

（‥‥ユルせるわけがない！）
(...and get an innocent girl
convicted of murder had
better watch out!)

<Maya>
ゼッタイに見つけだそうね！
なるほどくんのニセモノ‥‥
We'll find him! Don't you
worry. We'll get Xin Eohp
for you!

<Byrde>
じゃあ、吐麗美庵の場所を
教えますねッ！
Thank you!
Oh! I'll tell you where
Trés Bien is then!

<Phoenix>
とれび‥‥ああ、事件が
起こったレストランか。
Trés... Ah, right.
The restaurant where the
murder took place.

<Byrde>
はい！　店長によろしく
言っといてください！
Yes, sir.
When you go, please tell
Mr. Armstrong I said hi!

<Maya>
よし！　なるほどくん。
さっそく行ってみようか！
Sure! Alright, Nick! Let's
go check out this restaurant
and its food!

< >



<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

ウエイトレスさんがめずらしい
のだろうか。
I bet they don't get too many
waitresses in here.

ちょっと
そわそわしている。
He looks like he's getting a
bit restless.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile, you're on candid
camera.




<Maya>
マコちゃん。どうしたの？
そのカッコウ‥‥
So, how come you're dressed
like that, Maggey?

去年は、婦人警官の
制服でパリッとキメてたのに。
Last year you looked so sharp
in that police uniform.

<Byrde>
あの事件のおかげで、スズキ、
ケーサツをクビになっちゃって。
Hmph. I was fired after
that... incident last year.

<Maya>
そ、そうなんだ‥‥
Oh. I'm sorry.

<Byrde>
ゼーンゼン、かまいません！
It's OK. I don't mind one bit.

ケーサツのフンイキはまあ、
じゅうぶん楽しみましたから。
I enjoyed being on the force,
but I think it was time for me
to move on.

<Maya>
それで‥‥今は？
So, what do you do now?

<Byrde>
スズキの人生の第２章は、
ウエイトレスさんだったッス！
In the second act of "The Life
of Maggey Byrde", I'm playing
the role of a waitress!

<Maya>
うえいとれす‥‥
A waitress!?

<Byrde>
フランス料理のレストランです！
ちっちゃいけど、カワイイお店で。
Yes. In a French restaurant.
It's a small place, but it's
quite fashionable.

この愛くるしいスマイルと、なやま
しいボディラインのおかげで、
My charming smile and shapely
figure came through for me.

サッソク、採用されたッス！
And the owner, Mr. Armstrong,
hired me straight away, sir!

<Phoenix>
‥‥で、サッソク事件に
巻きこまれたわけだ。
And then you got into this
mess straight away, right?

<Byrde>
う。まあ‥‥。
Yeah, you could put it
that way...




<Byrde>
あのオソロシイ事件は、
先月の３日‥‥
This whole mess started on
the 3rd of last month...

吐麗美庵（とれびあん）で
発生したッス！
And it happened at Trés Bien.

<Maya>
とれびあん‥‥？
"Treh Bee-an"...?

<Byrde>
このスズキが、エガオとメシを
運んでいたレストランです！
Yes. It's a restaurant where
good service and a friendly
smile are always included!

<Maya>
はあ‥‥
Oh...

<Byrde>
テーブルで、２人の男が
コーヒーを飲んでいたッス。
There were two men at the
table, both drinking coffee.

そして‥‥
And then...

<Byrde>
男は、相手のコーヒーに
毒を入れたんです！
One of the men slipped some
poison into the victim's cup!

<Byrde>
被害者は、コーヒーをヒトクチ飲む
なり『ぎゃあ』ってなモンでした！
The victim took just one sip
and was gasping for air!

アタシ‥‥あまりのコトに、キゼツ
して、ぶっ倒れちゃったッス。
I was so shocked, I passed
out.

<Maya>
‥‥ちょっと待って、マコちゃん。
Hey, hold on there, Maggey.

<Byrde>
なんですか？
What?

<Maya>
さっきから“被害者”“被害者”
って言ってるけど‥‥
You keep calling the guy,
"the victim".

知ってるヒトじゃないの？
コロされちゃったヒト。
Didn't you know the guy
who was killed?

<Byrde>
し、知らないッス！
初めて見るカオだったッス！
Not at all!
I'd never even seen the
guy before!

<Maya>
そうなんだ‥‥
Oh...

<Phoenix>
（じゃあ、殺害する
　動機もないワケだよな‥‥）
(So she wouldn't have had a
motive to kill him then, I
guess...)

<Phoenix>
犯人はその、もう１人の男だ。
‥‥見たんだよね？　現場を。
And the other man, the killer.
You saw him, right?

<Byrde>
そのとおりッス！
ウエイトレスは見ていたッス！
Of course!
A good waitress must be
attentive to the clientele.

<Phoenix>
‥‥なのにどうして、
きみが有罪になってるの？
So, you saw the killer, but
you were found guilty of the
crime anyway? How come?

<Byrde>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
成歩堂さんに言われたくないッス！
.........
You tell me, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
ううう‥‥
（ぼくの“ニセモノ”か‥‥）
Ack!
(Guess the answer to my
question is "my phony"...)

（彼女は、そいつを見ている。
　‥‥できれば、情報がほしいな）
(Anyway, she saw the killer.
Better see if I can get a
description of the guy.)




<Maya>
ハンニンを目撃したのに‥‥
どうして、有罪に？
So, if you saw the murderer,
why were you still convicted?

<Byrde>
それが‥‥
ダレも見ていないッス。
Because no one else saw.

<Maya>
見ていない‥‥？
Saw what?

<Byrde>
毒を入れた、もう１人の男。
The other man.
The one who put the poison in
the victim's coffee.

‥‥店長も、レストランのお客も、
みーんな、こう証言したッス。
Everyone testified that way.
Mr. Armstrong, the customer...
Everyone.

『被害者のテーブルには、
　ずっと１人しかいなかった』‥‥
"The victim was sitting alone
at his table the whole time."

<Phoenix>
な‥‥なんだって！
But how's that possible?

<Byrde>
ダレも‥‥。ダレひとり、スズキの
言うことを信じてくれなくて。
I don't know. But nobody, not
one person, would believe me,
sir.

最後の望みをたくした成歩堂さん
にも、キレイにウラ切られて。
Even Phoenix Wright, my one
last hope for a fair trial,
failed me.

あの弁護はないッス！　うちの
おばあちゃんのほうがマシッス。
What a pathetic defense!
My granny could've done a
better job!

<Phoenix>
い、いや！　だからそれは、
ぼくじゃなかったんだから‥‥
Look! That wasn't me, OK?

<Byrde>
‥‥それに。
And then!

<Byrde>
スズキのエプロンのポッケから、
トンでもないモノが出てきたッス。
...They found something a bit
incriminating in my apron
pocket.

<Maya>
な‥‥なに？
What?

<Byrde>
毒薬の小ビン‥‥ッス。
A small bottle... of poison.

<Maya>
ええええええええええッ！
ど、毒が‥‥ポケットから？
WHAT!?
P-Poison!? It was in your
pocket!?

<Byrde>
‥‥被害者が倒れたとき、
スズキもキゼツしちゃったッス。
Well, I passed out when the
victim collapsed.

きっと‥‥そのとき、ハンニンが
ポッケに‥‥
The killer must've slipped
the poison into my pocket
when I was unconscious.

<Phoenix>
だれも、見ていないのか‥‥
その“もう１人の男”を。
And no one else saw this other
guy?

<Byrde>
そッス。『見てない』って。
そんなハズ、ないのに‥‥。
No, sir. That's what everyone
said. But I don't see how they
could've missed him...

< >



<Byrde>
モンダイのあの２人にコーヒーを
運んだの、アタシだったッス。
I was the one who took
the coffee to the two men.

<Phoenix>
お、そうなんだ。‥‥その人たち、
どんな感じだった？
O-Oh...? And what was your
impression of them?

<Byrde>
うーん。最初２人を見たときは、
音楽カンケイの人たちかな、って。
Well... When I first saw them,
I kind of thought they might
be in the music industry.

<Maya>
おんがく‥‥？
In music? How come?

<Byrde>
１人はイヤホンをつけて
ムズカシイ顔をしていたし、
Well, one of them had some
sort of earpiece, and an emo
musician's look about him.

テーブルの上には、見本のＣＤが
置いてあったッス。
And there was a sample CD
on the table, sir.

<Maya>
イヤホンに‥‥見本のＣＤ、かあ。
どんなＣＤだったんですか？
An earpiece and a sample CD,
huh? Did you get a look at the
CD at all?

<Byrde>
サインペンで、ウラ面に
バンドの名前が書いてあったッス。
It had a band's name written
on it.

《クリ》なんとか‥‥って。
きっと、デビュー前ッスね。
I think it was "MC"-something.
They must've been preparing
for their debut, I guess.

<Phoenix>
ふうん‥‥バンドねえ。
売りこみ、だったのかな。
So it was a band's CD.
Maybe a promo disc?

<Maya>
《くりきんとん》かあ‥‥。
Maybe it was "MC Screwdriver"!

<Phoenix>
勝手に名前つけるなよ。
Get serious, Maya.
Would you buy the CD of
a group named that?

<Byrde>
あのバンド名、なんだっけな。
‥‥“クリ”‥‥
Nngh... What was the name
of that group again...?
"MC Hacksaw..."? No... "MC..."

<Maya>
で？　で？　ケッキョク、どんな
ヤツだったんですか！　ハンニン。
And what about the killer?
What did he look like?

<Byrde>
そ‥‥それが。
よくおぼえてないッス。
Well, I, um...
I don't really remember.

被害者と同じく、体格のいい
おニイさんだった、ぐらいしか‥‥
Only that he was a young man.
Well-built like the victim,
really.




<Byrde>
あ、そのバッジ！
‥‥ホンモノッスか？
That badge!
Is it real?

<Phoenix>
ほ、ホンモノだよ！
Of course it's real!

<Byrde>
一度ダマされたニンゲンは、
うたぐり深くなるッス。
That's what they all say.
But I've been duped before.

貸してくださいッ！
Give it to me for a sec!

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥
Ah...!

< >
‥‥かりっ！
...*chomp!*

<Maya>
バッジを噛んでるよ。
She... She bit into it...

<Byrde>
ちょっぴり歯形がついたッス。
And I left a few teeth
marks, too!

<Phoenix>
はあ。
I can see that...

<Byrde>
‥‥それが何をイミするのか
わからないのがツラいところッス。
I just wish I could remember
if that means it's real
or a fake.

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
（ホンモノなのに）
*sigh*
(I said it was real!)

< >



<Phoenix>
そうだ！　コイツのことを
聞いとかないと！
Oh, yeah. I need to ask you
about this...

<Byrde>
あ！　スズキ惨敗の記事ッスね！
Hey! This article's about
my case!

<Phoenix>
この、ぼくのニセモノの
話を聞かせてくれないかな。
Can you tell me anything about
the guy who was pretending to
be me?

<Byrde>
リョーカイッス！
Yes, sir!

あれは、アタシがタイホされた
翌朝のことでした。
It was the morning after I'd
been arrested...

いつものスーツでビシッとキメて、
面会室に来てくれたッス。
I met you in the visitor's
room here. You were wearing
one of your super-sharp suits.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼくが？
Me?

<Byrde>
ええ。成歩堂さんが。
Yes, you, Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
ううう‥‥
Argh...

<Maya>
ね。ね。あたしのニセモノも
いました？
Hey, Maggey! Was my evil
double Ayam here, too?

<Byrde>
そういえば、ニセ真宵さんは
いなかったなあ‥‥。
No. I don't remember a phony
you, Maya.

<Maya>
‥‥ちぇ。
ちょっと、ザンネン。
Oh...
*sigh*
It would've been so cool...

<Byrde>
アットー的なハクリョクで
このスズキを、かきクドいたッス。
Then you got really worked up
and passionate.

『かならずアンタを
　ムザイにしたるわ！』‥‥って。
"I'm gonna get you cleared of
this crime!" you said.

<Phoenix>
それはいいけど‥‥そもそも、
ぼくと初対面じゃないのに‥‥
OK, I get the picture.
But you've met me in person
before...

<Phoenix>
どうして、ニセモノだって
気がつかなかったの？
So how come you didn't realize
that guy wasn't the real me?

<Byrde>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

たしかに、今、思うと
ちょっとヘンだったッス。
I guess, looking back now,
it was a little strange...

<Phoenix>
ちょっと‥‥？
Only a little?

<Byrde>
いつもよりちょっと背が高かったし
ちょっと目つきがワルかったし、
Well, OK, so you were a bit
taller than normal. And you
looked a bit shady.

ちょっと声も割れてたし、
ちょっと関西弁でしゃべってたし、
And your voice was a bit
weird. Oh, and you had this
kind of funny accent. And...

<Phoenix>
‥‥ゼンゼンちがうじゃないか！
So the guy was nothing like
me, then!?

<Byrde>
でも。アタマはギザギザだったし、
ブルーのスーツだったし。
But he had your spiky hair and
blue suit.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(...
Is that all it takes for
someone to imitate me...?)

<Maya>
法廷のヒトたちも‥‥
気がつかなかったの？
How about everyone else in
the courtroom, like the judge
and the observers...?

‥‥裁判長さんとか。
Didn't they realize he was
an imposter?

<Byrde>
みんな、カオに“？”マークが
うかんでましたけど。
Everyone had these big
question marks on their
faces...

なーんか、言い出せない
フンイキだったッス。
But it seemed that no one
wanted to say anything, sir.

<Maya>
ビミョーな話だなあ‥‥
This case just keeps
getting weirder and weirder...

< >



<Byrde>
おッ！　スポーツ新聞ッスか！
Oh! A sports paper.

どれどれ。タソガレ山は
全勝を守ったかな‥‥
Let's see, let's see...
Did Gutsen Brawn manage to
defend his heavyweight title?

<Phoenix>
悪いけど、この新聞‥‥１ヶ月前、
事件当日のものなんだ。
Sorry, Maggey. That paper is
actually a month old... It's
from the day of the murder...

<Maya>
ちなみに、タソガレ山、
きのうハリ倒されてましたよ。
And Gutsen got knocked out
yesterday, I'm afraid.

<Byrde>
うううう‥‥
Oh, no...

<Phoenix>
これ、吐麗美庵のマガジンラックで
見つけたんだけど。
I found this paper in the
magazine rack at Trés Bien.

<Byrde>
え‥‥
それは、オカシイッスね。
Really?
That's strange...

ウチのお店、新聞は
置いてないはずッスけど。
Trés Bien doesn't get
newspapers.

‥‥店長が、キライだから。
Mr. Armstrong says he's not
really fond of them.

<Maya>
じゃあ、お客さんが
忘れていったのかな。
Then maybe one of the
customers left it behind?

<Phoenix>
見てほしいのは、
このラクガキなんだけど‥‥
Anyway, what I want you to
take a look at is this
scribble here.

<Byrde>
あああああッ！
‥‥こ、こ、これッス！
Ah-ha!
That's it, sir!

<Byrde>
《クリーニング・ボンバー》‥‥
あのＣＤに書いてあった名前ッス！
"MC Bomber"!
That was the name that was
written on the CD!

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり‥‥）
(Just as I thought...)

<Maya>
《くりきんとん》じゃ
なかったんだ‥‥
I guess it wasn't
"MC Screwdriver"
after all, huh...

<Byrde>
じゃあ、１０００万円というのは
ヤッパリ‥‥契約金ッスかねえ。
So, that $100,000 must
be a down payment for a
record deal, right?

<Maya>
１０００万円もらえるんなら、
あたしだって歌っちゃうよ！
If someone gave me $100,000,
I'd sing for sure!

《倉院音頭》とか《霊媒おけさ》
とか《マヨイ節》とか！
"The Master of Kurain" or
"The Spirit Song" or even
"Maya's Theme"!

<Phoenix>
それはともかく‥‥、
Um, OK, Maya...

‥‥その見本版のＣＤは、
被害者のテーブルの上にあった。
So, if the sample CD was on
the victim's table...

つまり！　この新聞‥‥、
被害者のものかもしれない！
That means this newspaper
may have belonged to the
victim!

<Maya>
あ‥‥
You're right!

<Phoenix>
（被害者の、事件当日の
　遺留品‥‥か）
(So the victim left this
behind on the day of the
murder, huh...)

<Maya>
もっと、ちゃんと
調べられないかな‥‥？
I think we better step up the
investigation, don't you Nick?

< >



<Maya>
あの‥‥これなんですけど。
Um, Maggey...

<Byrde>
あれ。真宵さん、
アルバイト探してるんですか？
Oh, are you looking for some
part-time work, Maya?

あ！　ウチの店長なら
きっと、やとってくれるッスよ！
Why don't you take a job
at the restaurant? I bet
Mr. Armstrong would hire you.

<Maya>
え。あ、あたしですか？
Really? Me?

<Byrde>
ウエイトレスさん、
けっこう楽しいッスよ。
It's pretty cool being a
waitress, you know.

それに、キッチンには
店長のヒミツがあって。
And in the kitchen, you'll get
to see all of the chef's
greatest secrets!

<Maya>
ヒミツ‥‥？
What secrets...?

<Byrde>
コッソリ見てみるといいッス。
ちょっと、オモシロイから。
You can't make it obvious,
but just spy on him for a bit.
You'll see. It's interesting.

<Maya>
‥‥なんか、急に
やってみたくなってきた。
Wow! I can't wait to get my
apron on now!

< >



<Phoenix>
これなんだけど‥‥
Maggey... About this...

<Byrde>
あれ。成歩堂さんも
アルバイト探してるんですか？
Oh, are you looking for some
part-time work too,
Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
そんなワケないでしょう。
Me? No!

<Byrde>
成歩堂さんならきっと、
やとってくれるッス。ウチの店長。
Because I'm sure Mr. Armstrong
would hire you, sir.

<Phoenix>
え。ぼ、ぼくを‥‥？
Huh? What? Me?

<Byrde>
ウエイトレスさん、
けっこう楽しいッスよ。
It's pretty cool being a
waitress, you know.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥しかも、
　ウエイトレスさんかよ！）
(I couldn't be a "waitress"
even if I tried!)




<Byrde>
たしかに、このスズキ。
ムカシは婦人警官だったッス。
I know I used to be on the
police force, sir.

でも今は、とらわれの身。
なんの情報も入ってこないッス。
But I'm incarcerated, now.
So I can't use my connections
to help you.

今の自分にわかるのは、
レストランのメニューぐらいッス。
All I can help you out with
now is the menu at Trés
Bien, sir...

<Maya>
グチっぽくなっちゃったよ。
マコちゃん。
Aww, don't let it get you
down, Maggey!

< >



<Byrde>
去年は、お世話になりました！
Thanks for your help last
year!

<Maya>
よかったよね！
この前の事件、ムザイになって。
Aw, it was nothing.
I'm glad we got you off the
hook.

<Byrde>
今年もよろしくおねがいします！
I hope you can help me out
this year, too!

<Maya>
‥‥ムザイになるといいね。
今回の事件も。
Yeah, me too.
It'd be sweet if we could get
that verdict overturned.




<Byrde>
あ‥‥イトノコセンパイ！
Oh, Detective Gumshoe!

警官時代は、さんざん
メンドウを見てもらったッス！
He really looked out for me
when I was on the force!

<Phoenix>
最近は会ってないの？
Have you seen him recently?

<Byrde>
ううん‥‥ウチのレストランには
来てくれないッスねー。
No.
He's never been to the
restaurant.

<Maya>
しょうがないかな。
フランス料理だもんね。
Guess he's not a fan of French
cuisine, huh?

イトノコさんの主食は
ソーメンだから。
He's an instant noodle type
of guy, after all.

<Byrde>
とっても、すずしげッスね！
Yeah, he prefers the simple
things in life.

<Phoenix>
（まずしげ、とも言う）
(...Or he's just simply too
poor to afford anything else.)




<Byrde>
スズキ、どんなコトがあっても、
くじけないッス！
No matter what happens,
I never let things get me
down!

<Maya>
いつも前向きだよねー、
マコちゃん。
You're always so positive,
aren't you, Maggey?

<Byrde>
“マコ”という名前は、
“マけないコ”というイミッス！
Macho Maggey Byrde, they
say! The early Byrde catches
the worm! A Byrde in the hand!

<Maya>
え。そうだったんだ。
Wow! All those phrases are
named after you?

<Byrde>
そしてスズキ、どんなコトからも、
逃げないッス！
And I never turn my back on
anything!

<Maya>
いつも強気だしねー、
マコちゃん。
You're always so strong,
aren't you, Maggey?

<Byrde>
“マコ”の名前のもう１つのイミは
“マっコう勝負”ッス！
Macho Maggey Byrde, they say!
I'm a tough old Byrde!

<Maya>
“マっコう勝負”だって、
なるほどくん。
"Tough old byrde", Nick!
Hee hee! Do you get it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥なるほど。
...Yeah, I get it.




<Byrde>
あ‥‥このヒト！
ウチの常連さんッス！
Ah! This man!
He comes into the
restaurant a lot.

<Maya>
知ってるんだ。
So you know him?

<Byrde>
とってもヤサシイ
おじいちゃんッス。
Yes, sir. He's a really nice
old man.

なぜかいつもファーストフードの
割引券を持ち歩いていて‥‥
And he always has all these
coupons for fast-food joints,
for some reason.

アタシが料理を持っていくと、
エプロンに挟もうとするッス。
He tries to put them into my
apron whenever I take his
food to him.

<Maya>
へええ。
Really?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんてアブない
　ジイさんなんだ‥‥）
(Sounds like he's more of a
creepy old man than a nice
one...)

あの事件があった日も
いたんだよね。お店に。
He was there on the day of the
murder too, wasn't he?

<Byrde>
そうらしいッスけど‥‥
スズキは気がつかなかったッス。
That's what I heard.
But I didn't notice him
myself, sir.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥？　そんなに
　広かったか？　あの店‥‥）
(Huh? It's not like it's that
big of a restaurant... is it?)




<Byrde>
店長ッス！
ホンドボーさん。
Oh, so you met the owner,
Mr. Armstrong!

<Phoenix>
なんというか‥‥
個性的なヒトだね。
He's, um...
Oh, how can I put this...
pretty unique, huh?

<Byrde>
キョーレツなオーラを感じるッス！
シェフとしても、ヒトとしても。
He has a really intense aura.
As a chef and as a person.

<Phoenix>
たしかに、感じるなあ。
‥‥キョーレツなアロマを。
Yeah, he has a pretty intense
aroma, too.

<Maya>
あの、店長さんも
見てないんですか？　ハンニン‥‥
So did Mr. Armstrong really
not see the killer...?

<Byrde>
そうみたいッス。
Apparently not.

まあ‥‥店長は、ずっと
キッチンにいましたから‥‥
Well, he's in the kitchen all
the time, so I guess it's
possible that he didn't.




<Byrde>
あ‥‥そのヒト、
亡くなった被害者ッスね。
Ah! That's the victim,
isn't it?

<Phoenix>
たしか、『初めて見た』って
言ってたよね。
That day was the first time
you ever saw this man,
right?

<Byrde>
そッス！　ゼンゼン
知らないヒトッス。
Yes.
I'd never met or seen him
before then.

たまたまアタシが
コーヒー運んだだけッス！
I just happened to be the
waitress who served him his
coffee, sir. That's all!

<Phoenix>
‥‥コンピュータの
プログラマーらしいけど。
It seems he was a computer
programmer.

<Byrde>
もお、そんな！　自分は、
キカイはゼンゼン、ダメッス！
Really?
I'm useless with computers.
Completely hopeless.

“ぷらぐろまー”なんて
知り合い、いないッス！
I don't know any computer
programs.

<Phoenix>
（ビミョーにまちがってるな）
(Did she mean "programmers"?)

でも‥‥法廷では、動機も
立証されたんでしょ？　きみの。
But when you were on trial,
they must've established a
motive for you, right?

<Byrde>
アタシが、何か盗んだとか
盗まないとか‥‥
They said something about me
stealing something. Or was it
that I didn't steal...

もお、自分にはワケのわからない
ハナシだったッス！
Oh, I don't know.
Even I couldn't follow all
the arguments!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ワケがわからないまま、
有罪になっちゃったの？
You couldn't follow the
arguments, but you were still
found guilty?

<Byrde>
ニセ成歩堂さんの説明も、
まるっきりイミ不明だったッス。
Your phony's statements
didn't make a lot of sense
either, sir.

<Phoenix>
（それはきっと、ワザとだな）
‥‥しかたない。自分で調べるか。
(That must've been his plan.)
...Guess I'll have to look
into this myself.




<Byrde>
たしかに、このスズキ。
ムカシは婦人警官だったッス。
I know I used to be on the
police force, sir.

でも今は、とらわれの身。
なんの情報も入ってこないッス。
But I'm incarcerated now.
So I can't use my connections
to help you.

今の自分にわかるのは、前科者と
店の常連さんだけッス。
All I can tell you about now
is info about ex-cons or the
clientele of Trés Bien, sir...

<Maya>
グチっぽくなっちゃったよ。
マコちゃん。
Aww, don't let it get you
down, Maggey!




同日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
January 6
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Phoenix>
‥‥マコちゃんは
取り調べ中らしい。
Looks like they have Maggey
in questioning.

事件のことは
だいたい聞いたと思うけど‥‥
I guess I've asked her pretty
much everything...

もう一度、聞きたくなったら
またあとで来るか‥‥
I'll come back if there's
anything else I need to ask
her later.




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

今は、することがないのだろう。
立ったまま寝ている。
There's nothing for him to do
right now, so he's catching
some vertical z's.




同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 6
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Maya>
うーん、ひさしぶりだなあ。
警察署に来るのも。
It's been ages since we came
down to the precinct, huh,
Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥イトノコ刑事、
いないみたいだ。
Looks like Gumshoe isn't
around.

<Maya>
ヒトをはたらかせておいて、
イイ気なもんだね。
He's got it so easy, leaving
everyone else to do the work!

<Phoenix>
いやいや。裁判所やら何やら、
動き回ってるんじゃないかな。
No, he's out there somewhere.
My bet is on the courthouse.

この事件の再審理をするために。
He's probably trying to
arrange the retrial of this
case.

<Maya>
やれやれ。先に留置所で
ハンニンの話を聞こうか。
Guess that means we should go
to the detention center and
chat with our killer, huh?

<Phoenix>
ハンニンって言うなよ‥‥。
After being convicted without
a fair trial, I'm not sure
killer is the right label...

< >



同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 6
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Phoenix>
‥‥イトノコ刑事、
いないみたいだ。
Looks like Gumshoe isn't
around.

きっと、この事件を
再審理させるために‥‥、
I guess he's still trying to
organize the retrial.

裁判所やら何やら、
動き回っているんだろう。
He's probably at the
courthouse or something.

‥‥また、あとで来てみるか‥‥
I'll catch up with him later.




<Maya>
あ、カワイイ！　これって、
ケーサツのマスコットだよね。
Hey, that's the police
mascot, isn't it?
It's so cute!

<Chief>
“タイホくん”だよ。
That's the "Blue Badger".

<Chief>
ワシが考えて、ワシが作った。
今や、この国の警察のシンボルさ。
It was my idea! I made it! And
now it's the national symbol
of the police force!

<Phoenix>
１ぴき、ふえてますね。
‥‥ピンクのが。
So what's with the pink one?
It's new, right?

<Maya>
“１ぴき”って言わない、
なるほどくん。
She's not an "it", Nick.
She's a "she", right Chief?

<Chief>
それは、新しい仲間の
“タイホちゃん”だよ。
Yup.
Meet the "Pink Badger".

<Maya>
あれ。
名前、おんなじなんですか？
So one's called "Blue", and
the other's called "Pink", but
they're both called "Badger"?

<Chief>
ケッコンしてるからね、
その２人は。
You got it! They're married.

<Maya>
あの。タイホくんとタイホちゃん
‥‥手錠でつながれてますけど。
Um... Mr. & Mrs. Badger seem
to be cuffed together, Chief.

<Chief>
‥‥それが
ケッコンというヤツだからねえ。
You got it! That's marriage
for you!

<Phoenix>
（さすが警察のマスコット‥‥
　重たいな、なんとなく）
(Whoa... A mascot that's
deeper than the deepest of
deep oceans...)




<Phoenix>
いつ来ても置いてあるな
‥‥このマスコット。
No matter what, whenever
I come here, that mascot's
there to greet me.

<Chief>
“タイホくん”だよ。
You got that right.
That's the "Blue Badger".

<Chief>
ワシが考えて、ワシが作った。
今や、この国の警察のシンボルさ。
It was my idea! I made it! And
now it's the national symbol
of the police force!

<Phoenix>
１ぴき、ふえてますね。
‥‥ピンクのが。
So what's with the pink one?
It's new, right?

<Chief>
それは、新しい仲間の
“タイホちゃん”だよ。
Yup.
Meet the "Pink Badger".

<Phoenix>
あれ。
名前、おんなじなんですか？
So one's called "Blue", and
the other's called "Pink", but
they're both called "Badger"?

<Chief>
ケッコンしてるからね、
その２人は。
You got it! They're married.

<Phoenix>
（次に来たときは
　ムスコが生まれてそうだな‥‥）
(So should I expect to see
Baby Badger next time I'm
here...?)




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Detective>
“赤信号　ムシして死ぬな
　ヒトとして死ね”
"Don't die running a red
light. Die the old-fashioned
way -- of old age!"

‥‥キマリだな。ちょっと
ユーモラスなのがいい。
We have a winner!
Inject a bit of humor, that's
the key.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

交通安全キャンペーンの
標語を考えているようだ。
He must be coming up with
slogans for a safety campaign.
...I guess?




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
This must be the chief
of the detectives here.

‥‥パソコンの画面を、
食いいるように見つめている。
He's glued to his computer
screen.

<Chief>
なにぃ‥‥！　怪人☆仮面マスク、
銀行にサッソウと現れて‥‥
WHAT!?
Mask☆DeMasque turned up
at the bank? What's he doing!?

“お手がら！　強盗をタイホ”
　‥‥だと！
"Hands up, you scalawags!"
"You're under arrest!"
Hey! That's our job!

<Phoenix>
（優作くんたち‥‥新しい道を
　歩き出したみたいだな）
(Looks like Ron DeLite's opted
for a new career.)

<Detective>
カチョー！　インターネットで
遊ばないでください！
Quit surfing the net, Chief!

<Chief>
す‥‥スマン。ゴメン。
S-Sorry... I was just, um...

<Phoenix>
（なんか、ピリピリしてるな。
　空気が‥‥）
(Things feel pretty tense in
here...)




<Phoenix>
婦人警官がビシッと
敬礼している。
A poster of a female
police officer...

‥‥と思ったら、制服を着た
アイドルのグラビアだった。
Wait, no. That's the latest
"Babes in Uniform" calendar.
My bad.




<Phoenix>
刑事たちの机がならんでいる。
These are the detectives'
desks.

パソコンに、資料。
‥‥思ったより片づいているな。
There are computers and files
on each one. Funny, they're a
lot tidier than I expected.

たぶん、あまり席にいることが
ないんだろう。
I guess the detectives don't
spend a lot of time at their
desks.




同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 6
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Gumshoe>
どッスか！　見つかったッスか！
ムザイを立証する証拠は！
Well, pal!? Have you found the
evidence yet!? The one that's
gonna find her innocent!?

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。まだ、
始めたばっかりですから。調査。
Um, no. Not yet.
We've only just started our
investigation.

<Gumshoe>
いッスか！　知ってる情報なら、
じゃんじゃんタレ流すッス！
Well, whatever you need to
know, I'll give you the dirt
on it.

今、担当してる事件も
サボりまくりッス！
I'm putting off all my other
cases for now, pal!

<Phoenix>
（そうとうアツくなってるな
　‥‥イトノコ刑事‥‥）
(Gumshoe's really fired up
about this...)

<Gumshoe>
あ！　それから！
Oh, yeah! One more thing!

再審が、正式に決まったッス！
開廷は明日の１０時。
The retrial's been approved.
Court's sitting at 10 AM
tomorrow.

担当は、あのゴドー検事ッス！
And Godot's gonna be the
prosecutor...

<Phoenix>
（うう。アイツか‥‥）
(Oh.
...
Him.)

<Gumshoe>
とにかく！　もし、また
マコクンを有罪にしたら‥‥
Now, listen up, pal!
If Maggey's found guilty
again...

<Phoenix>
ゆ、有罪にしたら？
Y-Yes...?

<Gumshoe>
その‥‥‥
もー、アレッス！　タイホッス！
Um... I'll...
I'll make sure you get locked
up good for it, got it!?




同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 6
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Gumshoe>
お。ちょうどよかったッス！
Hey, you're just in time!

<Phoenix>
なんですか？
What is it, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
アンタからあずかっていた新聞、
ブンセキが終わったッス。
The lab got back to me about
that newspaper you gave me.

<Phoenix>
（ラクガキの筆跡‥‥）
(He must mean the sports paper
with the memo scribbled on
it...)

そ、それで‥‥どうでした？
検査の結果は！
So? What did they say?
Did the analysis turn up
anything?

<Gumshoe>
どうやら‥‥被害者・岡　高夫が
書いたと見て、まちがいないッス。
They said the doodle was
written by the victim, Glen
Elg. No doubt about it.

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり‥‥そうだったのか）
(I expected as much...)

<Gumshoe>
このスポーツ新聞は事件当日、
被害者が店に持ちこんだ‥‥
The victim took the paper with
him to the restaurant on the
day of the murder.

そう考えていいと思うッス。
That's our best interpretation
of the facts at the moment.

< >
証拠品《スポーツ新聞》のデータを
もう一度、ファイルした。
Sports Paper refiled into
the Court Record.

<Gumshoe>
でも‥‥やっぱり、
どこかで聞いたコト、あるッス。
"MC Bomber"...

《クリーニング・ボンバー》‥‥
I get the feeling I've heard
that name somewhere
before...

‥‥ま。とにかく。
Oh, well.
I guess it'll come back to me.

あのレストランで見つけたモノは、
ちゃーんと自分に教えるッスよ。
Don't forget to report back to
me with whatever you find in
the restaurant, OK, pal?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥エラそうだな。でも‥‥）
(Since when did I start taking
orders from Gumshoe...?
Although...)

（なんか、見せるべきモノが
　あるような気もするな‥‥）
(I get the feeling there's
something I need to show
him...)




<Phoenix>
有罪になっちゃったの‥‥
須々木　マコさんだったんですね。
So the guilty party was
Maggey Byrde, huh?

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そッスよ。
Yeah...

<Phoenix>
彼女、もとは婦人警官で‥‥
Back when she was on the
police force...

新人のとき、イトノコ刑事が
メンドウを見てあげたんですよね。
...you were her mentor
when she was a rookie,
right?

<Gumshoe>
まま、まあ。あ、当たらずとも
遠からず、という感じッスね。
Yeah, I kept a close eye on
her. I-I mean, not too close.
You know.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
<Gumshoe>
......
<Phoenix>
.........

<Gumshoe>
な、なんスかァ、その目は！
Hey, what's with the funny
looks, pal?

じじ、自分はベツにアレッス！
そんなんじゃないッス！
I was just her...
It wasn't anything like...

たしかに、マコクンは研修時代、
自分のブカだったッスが‥‥
Look! Sure, I was her boss
when she was doing her
training.

それだけッス！
やましいトコロはないッス！
But that was it.
Nothing happened.

<Phoenix>
（イトノコ刑事、ミョーに必死に
　なってると思ったら‥‥）
(Gumshoe sure is sweating
up a storm over nothing...)

（そういうコトだったのか）
(...Ah, so that's it!
Our big ol' Gumshoe has a
little ol' crush on Maggey!)

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そーゆうコトって
どーゆうコトッスかッ！
I...
I don't like her or anything!

自分は‥‥自分はああアァァァッ！
I...
I was...
Aaaargh!

<Phoenix>
（あとで真宵ちゃんに
　教えてあげないとな）
(Note to self: Gossip with
Maya about this later!)

<Gumshoe>
だ、ダメッス！
ゼッタイ、ヒミツッスよ！
Look, pal! Don't tell anyone,
OK!? You've gotta keep it
a secret, got it!?

<Phoenix>
それはいいですけど‥‥
S-Sure...

ヒトのココロの中を
読まないでもらえますか？
And would you mind not
guessing what I'm thinking all
the time?

<Gumshoe>
アンタの目は、
口よりもモノを言うッス！
Hey, tell your face, pal, not
me. You'd have to be blind not
to see what's on your mind.




<Gumshoe>
捜査といっても、
動いてるのは自分だけッス。
This isn't really a proper
investigation. I'm kind of
working on it by myself.

<Phoenix>
え。そうなんですか‥‥
O-Oh, that's right...

<Gumshoe>
一度は有罪が決まった事件ッス。
証拠はカンペキにそろってるッス。
The judge already ruled on the
case, and all the evidence is
in already.

ひたすら、マコクンの証言だけが
ジジツと食いちがってるッス。
The only problem is with
Maggey's testimony.

<Phoenix>
うう。イヤな感じですね‥‥
Yeah...
Doesn't sound very good
for us, huh?

<Gumshoe>
自分も、明日の手続きに追われて、
事件の資料を見る時間もないッス！
Look, pal. I've got a mountain
of papers on this case to look
over before tomorrow.

ただ‥‥これだけは
言っておきたいッス！
So I'm just gonna say this...

マコクンは、ゼッタイ
ウソはついていないッス！
Maggey Byrde's no liar.

あのコは‥‥あのコは‥‥
She's...
She's...

そそっかしく、思いちがいと
カンちがいがトレードマークの、
OK, so she's a bit out there,
and a bit off base sometimes.

オチャメな婦警さんッス！
But she was a good cop.

<Phoenix>
（ゼンゼン
　たよりにならないじゃないか！）
(That's not exactly
complimentary, you know!)

それにしても‥‥どれぐらい
食いちがってるんですか？
So what do you think really
happened?

マコちゃんの言ってるコトと、
その‥‥ジジツは？
And just how contradictory
is her testimony?




<Gumshoe>
一番キョーレツなのが、
テーブルにいた、人数ッス。
The biggest problem with
Maggey's testimony is the
number of people at the table.

<Phoenix>
ああ‥‥たしかに。
Yeah. My thoughts exactly.

マコちゃんは、被害者の他に
もうヒトリいたと主張してますね。
Maggey still insists there was
another guy sitting with the
victim.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥そッス。しかし‥‥
Right.
But get this...

シェフや、店の客は‥‥
そんなヤツ、見てないッス。
Everyone else in the place
says the guy was alone.
Even the chef.

そして、もう１つ。
ＣＤのモンダイがあるッス。
And then there's that CD...

<Phoenix>
（ＣＤ‥‥か。そういえば
　彼女、言ってたな‥‥）
(CD?
Oh, yeah. She did mention
something about a CD...)

<Byrde>
テーブルの上には、見本のＣＤが
置いてあったッス。
And there was a sample CD
on the table, sir.

<Gumshoe>
でも‥‥そんなＣＤ、
どこにもなかったッス。
But our guys turned that place
upside down. There was no CD.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
What?

<Gumshoe>
被害者のテーブルどころか、
店の中には存在しなかったッス。
Not on the table. Not anywhere
in the whole restaurant, pal.

<Phoenix>
で、でも‥‥被害者は、
イヤホンをしていた、とか‥‥
But didn't Maggey say the
victim was wearing an
earpiece, too?

<Gumshoe>
被害者の岡　高夫のムネには、
小型のラジオが入っていたッス。
Yeah, but that was for the
portable radio in the front
pocket of his hoodie.

<Phoenix>
ラジオ‥‥
A radio? He didn't have
a CD player?

<Gumshoe>
この食いちがいを‥‥アンタの
ニセモノは説明できなかったッス。
You got it. Your phony never
explained that contradiction
at all.

<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥）
(Come to think of it...)

（店長さん、ＣＤのことは
　何も言ってなかったな‥‥）
(The owner of Trés Bien
didn't mention that CD
either.)

（あのヒトも、ナニか
　ヒミツがありそうだよな‥‥）
(I don't know why, but I get
the feeling Mr. Armstrong's
got something to hide...)




<Phoenix>
そういえば‥‥
被害者のことなんですけど。
So, I was wondering...

いったい、どんなヒトなんですか？
Could you fill me in on the
victim?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥岡　高夫（おか　たかお）。
コンピュータ・プログラマーッス。
Glen Elg, he was a computer
programmer.

<Phoenix>
プログラマー‥‥
I see.
A programmer...

<Gumshoe>
小さなコンピュータ会社で
はたらく、フツーのオトコッス。
He was just a regular Joe
working for a small-time
computer firm.

マコクンと、あらゆるイミで
接点はないッス。
Maggey never had any contact
with the guy before that day.

‥‥ただ、１つ。あの日たまたま、
コーヒーを運んだ、という以外は。
...And all she did was take
him his coffee on the day of
the murder, pal.

<Phoenix>
（マコちゃんも“見たことない”
　って言ってたっけな‥‥）
(Yeah, Maggey also claimed to
have never seen the guy
before...)

被害者は、あのレストランを
よく利用していたんですか？
Did the victim go to the
restaurant often?

<Gumshoe>
シェフのハナシでは‥‥
初めての客だったらしいッス。
Not according to the chef.
Said it was the first time
he'd seen the guy.

<Phoenix>
（プログラマー‥‥
　初対面の客、か‥‥）
(A programmer... and a first-
time customer...)

‥‥そんなオトコを殺害する
理由なんて、ないじゃないですか。
What possible reason could
Maggey have had to kill a
guy like that?

<Gumshoe>
自分もそう思うッスが‥‥
That's what I thought.

法廷では、キチンと立証された
らしいッス。‥‥殺害の動機も。
But a motive was still somehow
established in her trial.

<Phoenix>
え！　なんですか？
マコちゃんの“動機”って！
You're kidding!
What was her supposed
"motive"?

<Gumshoe>
すまねッスが‥‥自分も忙しくて、
資料にあたる時間がないッス。
Sorry, pal. I'm real busy.
I haven't even got enough time
to sift through these papers.

自分で調べてほしいッス。
Look into it yourself, OK?

<Phoenix>
（マコちゃんの“動機”か‥‥）
(What could this motive have
been...)




<Phoenix>
なんですか？　あのシェフの
“気になる点”って‥‥
So what exactly is it that
caught your attention about
the chef at Trés Bien?

<Gumshoe>
それが‥‥ちょっと、
言いにくいッス。
It's, um... kind of hard
to say...

あのオッサン、事件にカンケイ
ないかもしれないし‥‥。
The guy's probably not even
connected with the case
anyway...

<Phoenix>
まあまあ。じゃんじゃんタレ流す
ヤクソクじゃないですか。情報。
Hey, come on, Detective.
Didn't you say you'd give me
the dirt on anything?

<Gumshoe>
ビミョーな
個人情報ッスからねえ‥‥。
Well, this sort of stuff is
kinda... unimportant, gossipy
stuff, you know pal?

じゃ、こうするッス！
Look, how about this?

<Gumshoe>
自分のかわりに、ヤツと吐麗美庵を
もっと調べるッス。
You go to Trés Bien and
investigate the place
yourself.

<Gumshoe>
それで、アイツがアヤシイと
いうことになれば‥‥教えるッス。
And if you find out anything
suspicious about the guy...
you report back to me, OK?

<Phoenix>
うう‥‥しかたありませんね。
Um... Don't suppose I get
a choice in this, huh?

（シェフと吐麗美庵の情報は、
　イトノコ刑事に報告するか‥‥）
(Guess I better find out more
about the chef and Trés Bien;
then report back to Gumshoe.)




<Phoenix>
それで‥‥なんですか？
本土坊さんの“ヒミツ”って。
So what's Mr. Armstrong's
secret?

<Gumshoe>
アンタ、吐麗美庵の
ランチは食べたッスか？
You ever had lunch at
Trés Bien, pal?

<Phoenix>
‥‥え、ええ。
Um... Yes...

<Gumshoe>
どうだったッス？
So, how was it?

<Phoenix>
あくまでも、いいイミで
おいしくありませんでした。
To put it nicely... it was
inedible.

<Gumshoe>
ベツに、この自分に
気をつかわなくていいッス。
Hey, don't worry about being
nice around me, pal.

店はキレイだし、ウエイトレスは
マコクンッスが‥‥
You and I both know the reason
that place is so empty is
because of the food.

あの料理のせいで、吐麗美庵は
まったく客が入ってないッス。
I mean, the place is clean,
and he's got a girl like
Maggey as a waitress, so...

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥そうかもしれませんね。
Yeah... I guess it's probably
the food.

<Gumshoe>
トーゼン、あの男は
借金まみれッス。
The real scoop on the guy is
he's up to his ears in debt.

<Phoenix>
‥‥どれぐらい
まみれてるんですか？
Really? How much does he owe?

<Gumshoe>
ヤツの借用書のコピーッス。
およそ、５０００万ッス。
This is a copy of his loan
contract. He's about half a
million in the red.

<Phoenix>
ごご、５０００万‥‥って、
“円”ですか？
H-Half a million?
Are we talking dollars?

<Gumshoe>
そりゃそッス。“ドル”だったら
とんでもないことに。
Yeah. Hey, if it was Sterling,
he'd really be in trouble!

<Phoenix>
す、すみません。あまりの金額に、
アタマと声がウラ返っちゃって。
Sorry. That figure just took
me by surprise.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥どうも、この事件には
“ウラ”がありそうッス。
Yeah, this case is full of
surprises.

そして、その“ウラ”には、
このシェフがカラんでいる‥‥
And I'd be willing to bet
that chef's got something to
do with most of them.

そんな気がするッス！
That's my hunch.

< >
《本土坊の借用書》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Jean's Loan Contract added to
the Court Record.




<Gumshoe>
ホンモノッスか？　それ。
Is that thing real, pal?

<Phoenix>
‥‥見せると
みんなにそう言われます。
Why does everyone keep asking
me that?

<Gumshoe>
どんなヤツッスかねー、
アンタのニセモノ‥‥
I wonder what this phony of
yours is like...

<Phoenix>
マコちゃんを、ワザと
有罪にしたヤツですよ。
He had Maggey found guilty of
murder. Doesn't that tell you?

（なんとかして、
　見つけだしたいな‥‥）
(I've got to track this
creep down!)




<Gumshoe>
自分も、その裁判は
傍聴していないッスが‥‥
I wasn't at the trial myself.

知り合いの刑事に聞いてみたッス。
このときの、アンタの弁護のコト。
But I asked this one detective
I know how your defense was.

<Phoenix>
ど、どんな感じでしたか？
And what did he say?

<Gumshoe>
『あきれてモノも言えないよ』
‥‥と、前置きしてから‥‥
He started off by saying,
"I'm at a complete loss
for words..."

１時間ぐらい聞かされたッス。
アンタの無能ぶりを。
But he must have found some
quick because he went on about
how bad you were for an hour.

<Phoenix>
うう‥‥
But...

<Gumshoe>
どう見ても、ワザと
有罪にしたんじゃないか、って。
He said you sucked so much, it
seemed like you were trying to
get Maggey found guilty!

<Phoenix>
（ワザと‥‥か‥‥）
(It looked like I was
"trying to get Maggey found
guilty"...?)




<Gumshoe>
なんスか？　スポーツ新聞‥‥
What's that?
A sports paper?

<Phoenix>
吐麗美庵のマガジンラックで
見つけたんですよ。
Yeah. I found it in the
magazine rack at Trés Bien.

<Gumshoe>
日付が‥‥事件当日ッスか。
ちょっと、イミありげッス‥‥
It's dated the same day as the
murder. You may be onto
something here.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ホラ。ここに、
ラクガキがありますよね？
And take a look at this.
See this writing here?

<Gumshoe>
“くりーにんぐ・ぼんばー”
‥‥‥‥‥‥はて。
"MC Bomber"...
Hey!

<Phoenix>
どうかしましたか？
What is it?

<Gumshoe>
どこかで聞いたコトがあるッス。
《クリーニング・ボンバー》‥‥
I've heard that name somewhere
before. Yeah, "MC Bomber"...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いつになく、マジメに
　考えこんでいる‥‥）
(Wow, he actually seems to be
thinking for once!)

<Gumshoe>
ダメ。思い出せないッス。
Ack, it's no good.
I can't remember...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いつもどおり、ダメだった）
(...And he goes back to being
the Gumshoe we all know and
love.)

<Gumshoe>
アンタ！　ちょっとこの新聞、
貸してもらえないッスか？
Hey, pal.
I'm gonna borrow this paper
for a bit, OK?

‥‥このラクガキの
筆跡を調べてみたいッス。
I wanna get a handwriting
analysis done on this
scribble.

<Phoenix>
（筆跡‥‥か。それは、
　ぼくも知りたいな‥‥）
(Handwriting, huh?
It'd be good to know more
about that, in any case...)

<Gumshoe>
これは‥‥オモシロイ
手がかりになるかもしれないッス！
Thanks, pal! I bet this'll
turn out to be an interesting
clue!

< >
証拠品《スポーツ新聞》を
イトノコ刑事にあずけた。
Sports Paper given to
Detective Gumshoe.




<Gumshoe>
お。またもらってきたッスか？
ニオイつきの小ビン。
You got one of those aroma
bottles too, huh?

<Phoenix>
それが‥‥この小ビン、
なんのニオイもしないんですよ。
Only this one doesn't smell.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥イミがわかんねッス。
Huh? I don't get you...

<Phoenix>
アロマテラピーのボトルに
まじって、１本だけ、これが。
This was mixed in with all the
other aromatherapy bottles,
but it's not the same.

デザインもゼンゼン
ちがいますよね‥‥？
It doesn't even look the same,
wouldn't you agree?

<Gumshoe>
ニオわない小ビン‥‥
それはかえって、ニオうッス！
A cologne bottle that doesn't
smell, huh? Smells like a
skunk to me, pal!

今度は、ちょっとその小ビン、
貸してもらえないッスか？
Mind letting me borrow that
bottle for a while?

中身をブンセキしてみたいッス。
I wanna send it to the lab
for analysis.

<Phoenix>
（被害者は“毒殺”された。
　‥‥ビンの中身は重要だな）
(The victim was poisoned, so
the contents of this bottle
are pretty important...)

< >
証拠品《小ビン》を
イトノコ刑事にあずけた。
Small Bottle given to
Detective Gumshoe.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥やっぱり‥‥
あのシェフはアヤしいッスね。
I had a hunch there was
something funny about that
chef.

<Phoenix>
本土坊　薫さん‥‥ですか。
You suspect Jean Armstrong?

<Gumshoe>
ジツは‥‥自分は、
ヤツのヒミツをつかんでいるッス。
I've got that guy's number.
I know what his secret is.

<Phoenix>
（そういえば、そんなコトを
　言ってたな‥‥イトノコ刑事）
(That must be the same secret
Gumshoe was talking about
before.)

<Gumshoe>
どうやら、アンタには
話しておいたほうがいいッスね。
I guess I'd better fill you
in on the details.

本土坊のヒミツを‥‥。
About this Armstrong guy's
secret, I mean...




<Gumshoe>
このラクガキは、
おそらく被害者が書いたものッス。
So according to the boys down
at the lab, the doodles were
probably made by the victim.

<Phoenix>
“おそらく”‥‥ですか。
Probably?

<Gumshoe>
サインペンで書かれたサンプルは
鑑定がムズカシイッスから。
Analyzing this kind of writing
is difficult since it's done
with a fiber-tipped pen.

でも、だいじょぶッス！
この自分がタイコ判を押すッス！
But don't worry!
I'll vouch for it.

<Phoenix>
（なんでイトノコ刑事が
　押すんだ？　タイコ判‥‥）
(Why would Gumshoe have to
vouch for it? Can't it stand
on its own?)




<Gumshoe>
５０００万円ッスよ！
It's for half a million
dollars, pal!

１円玉で、えーと‥‥
ざっと５０００万枚ッス！
That's... um... half a million
dollar bills!

<Phoenix>
（今の“えーと”は
　なんだったんだ‥‥？）
(What was the "um" in there
for!?)

今回の事件、そんな
大金がカラんでいるんですか？
Is there really that much
money tied up in this case?

<Gumshoe>
資料を見てないから
知らないッス。
I can't give you an answer on
that, pal. Not without the
case file in front of me.

でも‥‥
But I'll tell you this...

本土坊が、金のためなら
なんでもやる状況にいたコトは、
That Armstrong guy would've
done anything for cash.

やぶさかでないッス。
He was desperate, you know?

<Phoenix>
‥‥よくわからないけど、
なんとなくわかりました。
No, I don't. But I think
I sort of get the picture.




<Gumshoe>
アレ。今日は
いっしょじゃないッスか。
Hey! So how come she's
not with you today?

<Phoenix>
ええ。今、レストランで
はたらいています。
She's working down at the
restaurant right now.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥そッスか。
カナしいッスよね‥‥ビンボーは。
Working, huh?
Yeah, it's tough being broke.
I would know.

<Phoenix>
は‥‥？
Um... OK...?

<Gumshoe>
今度、おいしいソーメンの
ゆで方を教えてあげるッス。
Next time I see her, I'll show
her how to make the world's
best instant noodles.

ビンボーどうし、
強く生きるッス！
We low earners have to stick
together! It's the only way!

<Phoenix>
（なんでアクシュしなくちゃ
　ならないんだ‥‥？）
(Um... Why is he shaking my
hand with such enthusiasm...?)




<Gumshoe>
あいかわらず、元気そうッスね。
You're looking upbeat,
as usual.

<Maya>
イトノコさんも、あいかわらず
つかれたカオしてるッスね！
And you're looking tired
as usual, Detective Gumshoe!

<Gumshoe>
同じニンゲンなのに、
この差はいったい、なんなんス‥‥
Yeah. That's life, huh?
One guy's got it all, and one
guy's got squat.

<Maya>
あれ。ボヤき始めたよ。
Is it just me or did the room
get darker all of a sudden...?

ま。ま。きっと、今年は
イトノコさんの年になりますよ！
You know, Detective. This is
the year of the, um... gum!

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そッスかねえ。
I-It is?

<Maya>
ええ。たぶん。
Yeah.
...I think.

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そッスよね！
Gum, huh? This is gonna
be a great year for this
ol' Gumshoe then, right?

<Maya>
あは。元気になったよ。
Look at that.
He perked up in no time!

<Phoenix>
遊ぶなよ‥‥
Maya...
Don't mess with him like that.




<Phoenix>
面会には、行ってあげましたか？
Have you gone to see
Maggey?

<Gumshoe>
モチロンッス！
ただ‥‥
Of course I have!
But I...

あまりのコトに、なぐさめる
コトバが出て来なかったッス。
I wasn't much good at
consoling her. I'm... I'm not
very good with words.

<Phoenix>
そう‥‥ですよね。
Oh...

<Gumshoe>
思わずうつむいたら、マコクンが
はげましてくれたッス。
Yeah. I guess I must've looked
a bit down. Maggey was really
supportive of me.

‥‥うれしかったッス。
It was great to have someone
to talk to.

<Phoenix>
（何しに行ったんだ、
　この刑事さんは‥‥）
(Did he go for her, or for
himself...?)




<Gumshoe>
‥‥自分が情けないッス。
I'm such a loser.

マコクンを、一人前の刑事に
するのがユメだったのに‥‥
I had high hopes for Maggey.
I was gonna make her the best
detective there ever was.

いつのまにか、殺人の罪を
着せられて、タイホされて‥‥
But then all of a sudden she
was charged with murder and
arrested.

有罪判決が下されるまで、
気がつかなかったなんて！
I never saw it coming. I never
imagined they'd find her
guilty.

‥‥もう、自分が
イヤになったッス。
I hate myself for not being
able to do anything.

<Phoenix>
大丈夫ですよ、イトノコ刑事。
It's OK, Detective Gumshoe.

‥‥まだ、最後のチャンスが
残っています。
We still have a chance to
make this right.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

アンタが、ココロなしか
いいヤツに見えてきたッス。
You know what? You're not
such a bad guy after all, pal.




<Gumshoe>
‥‥ガンコなジイさんッス。
He looks like one of those
grouchy old man types.

<Phoenix>
そうですね。
Yeah.

<Gumshoe>
自分は、ガンコなジイさんは
キライじゃないッス。
It's OK, though. I don't mind
guys like that.

でも、事件の関係者となれば、
ベツッス。
But, if he's involved with
this case somehow, that's
a different story.

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
Um... sure.

<Gumshoe>
あのジイさんから情報を
引きずり出すには‥‥
Here's a tip for you, pal.
If you wanna get information
out of a guy like that...

“弱点”を探し出して、
そこをたたくしかないッスね‥‥
...you're gonna have to find
his weakness and try to get
under his skin.

<Phoenix>
（あのジイさんの
“弱点”‥‥ねえ‥‥）
(His weakness?
I wonder what that might
be...)




<Gumshoe>
吐麗美庵のシェフ、ッスか。
The chef of Trés Bien,
huh?

会うなり『アナタ、カラダが毒素で
パンパンね』なんて言われて‥‥
You know what that chef
said to me? "Oh là là! Your
body is full of la toxins."

このビンをわたされたッス。
And then he gave me this
bottle.

<Phoenix>
なんですか、それ。
What's in it?

<Gumshoe>
ラベルには“ジュニパー”って
書いてあるッス。
I don't know.
The label says, "Juniper".

おフロにちょっと
しのばせろ、と要求されたッス。
I'm under orders to put a few
drops of it in my bath every
day.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥要求されましたか。
Under orders?

<Gumshoe>
じつは、彼女‥‥いや。カレには
ちょっと引っかかる点があるッス。
Yeah. You know, there's
something about that lady...
I mean, guy.

<Phoenix>
ひ、ひかれる点‥‥？
Huh!? You can't stop
thinking about him!?

<Gumshoe>
ちち、チガうッス！　なんであんな
中年オトコにひかれるッスか！
Not like that, pal!
Gimme a break!
He's not my type.

“引っかかる点”ッス！
I mean, I can't stop thinking
that he's involved with this
case somehow!

<Phoenix>
（詳しく聞いたほうがいいな‥‥）
(Sounds like he knows a little
something more about our
charming chef.)




<Gumshoe>
明日、マコクンの再審理を
担当するッス。
That's the guy who's gonna
be the prosecutor in
Maggey's retrial tomorrow.

<Phoenix>
そ、そうなんですか。
O-Oh, really?

<Gumshoe>
他に、もっと大きな事件も
あるのに‥‥
He was working on a bunch of
more important cases at the
moment...

なぜか、アンタと戦うために
キャンセルしてるッス。
...but he canceled them all
just so he could take you
on, pal.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なぜ、そこまでして
　ぼくを倒そうとするんだ‥‥？）
(Why's that guy so
determined to see me fail?)

<Gumshoe>
ホント、人気者ッスねー。
‥‥モチロン、悪いイミで。
You sure attract a lot of
attention, huh? Too bad
it's all the wrong kind.




<Gumshoe>
ムカシ‥‥一度だけ、
尋問を受けたことがあるッス。
She cross-examined me once,
you know.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥千尋さんに、ですか？
What? Mia did?

<Gumshoe>
あれは‥‥名勝負だったッス。
Yeah. That was us. The big
guns locking horns.

証人対弁護士！　アツいアツい
カケヒキが展開されたッス。
Witness versus lawyer!
It was a battle of cunning
tactics and tricks.

<Phoenix>
（証人がカケヒキしちゃ
　マズいだろ‥‥）
(But the witness isn't
supposed to play any
tricks...)

<Gumshoe>
おしいヒトを亡くしたッス‥‥。
I can't believe she's gone...




<Phoenix>
あの。これなんですけど‥‥
What do you make of
this...?

<Gumshoe>
今は‥‥マコクンのコトで
アタマがいっぱいッス。
Sorry, pal.
All I can think about is
Maggey at the moment.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
<Gumshoe>
...
<Phoenix>
......

<Gumshoe>
ちち、ちがうッス！　そういう
イミじゃなくて、自分は‥‥！
N-No! I didn't mean it like
that! I meant...

<Phoenix>
（ムリしなくていいのに‥‥）
(You don't have to explain...
Really...)




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Detective>
“アクセルを　ふめば人生
　早送り”‥‥
"Hitting the gas is like
hitting the fast-forward
button on your life."

‥‥わかりにくいな。
『すぐ死ぬよ』ってコトなんだが。
No. That's too obscure. You
don't really get the "you'll
die before your time" idea.

いっそ、もっとストレートで、
明るく楽しい感じがイイか。
I need something more direct.
Something a bit more light-
hearted.

“スピード出して
　天国へ行こう！”‥‥みたいな。
Something like, "Hitting the
gas is your passport to
paradise!"

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

交通安全キャンペーンの
標語を考えているようだ。
He must be coming up with
slogans for a safety campaign.
...I guess?




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
This must be the chief
of the detectives here.

‥‥パソコンの画面を、
食いいるように見つめている。
He's glued to his computer
screen.

<Chief>
なにぃ‥‥！　毒入りコーヒーの
ウエイトレス、再審が決定‥‥
WHAT!? Poisoned coffee
waitress gets a retrial!?

そういえば、今日のワシの
コーヒー、イヤにニガいな‥‥。
I knew it! I knew there was
something funny about the
taste of this coffee!

ちょっと！　ワシのコーヒー
いれたヒト、手をあげて！
OK! Who brought me this
coffee today? Hands up!

<Phoenix>
（ブカを信用してやれよ！）
(Yeesh! Have a little faith
in your subordinates!)

<Detective>
カチョー！　インターネットで
遊ばないでください！
Quit surfing the net, Chief!

<Chief>
す‥‥スマン。ゴメン。
S-Sorry... I was just, um...

<Phoenix>
（なんか、ピリピリしてるな。
　空気が‥‥）
(Things feel pretty tense in
here...)










