同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 7
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Maya>
イトノコさん、いないね。
Looks like Gumshoe's not here.

<Phoenix>
それより‥‥なんか、
いつもとフンイキがちがうぞ。
Never mind that.
What's going on? It feels
different in here somehow...

<Maya>
あれ。そうかな？
You think?

<Phoenix>
ミョーに殺気立ってるというか‥‥
Yeah.
Everyone seems to be on edge.

<Detective>
何してるんだ！　聞き込みの
人員を、はやくまわしてくれ！
What are you doing!?
Call in the officers for the
briefing, quick!

署のサーバーマシン、
シャットダウンできないのか？
Can't you shut down the
station's server?

課長！　インターネットは
やめてください！
Chief! Quit playing on the
Internet!

<Chief>
いや、しかし、メールトモダチの
サヨコさんがだね。
But my e-mail pen pal,
1337aZnPrInceSz!

<Detective>
また今度にしてください！
はい。スイッチ、切りますよ！
Save it for later!
I'm turning it off NOW!

<Chief>
ぎゃー！　サヨコさん‥‥
Noooo! 1337aZnPrInceeeeeSz!!

<Maya>
‥‥みんな、なんか
イキイキしているね。
Everyone's keeping busy in
here, huh?

<Phoenix>
“バタバタしている”と言った
ほうが正しいんじゃないかな。
Keeping busy? More like
panicking, if you ask me.

（何か、事件が起こったらしいな
　‥‥それも、重大な‥‥）
(Something's going on.
Something big...)




<Maya>
あ、カワイイ！　これって、
ケーサツのマスコットだよね。
Hey, that's the police
mascot, isn't it?
It's so cute!

<Chief>
“タイホくん”だよ。
That's the "Blue Badger".

<Chief>
ワシが考えて、ワシが作った。
今や、この国の警察のシンボルさ。
It was my idea! I made it! And
now it's the national symbol
of the police!

<Phoenix>
１ぴき、ふえてますね。
‥‥ピンクのが。
So what's with the pink one?
It's new, right?

<Maya>
“１ぴき”って言わない、
なるほどくん。
She's not an "it", Nick.
She's a "she"!
Right, Chief!?

<Chief>
それは、新しい仲間の
“タイホちゃん”だよ。
Yup.
Meet the "Pink Badger".

<Maya>
あれ。
名前、おんなじなんですか？
So one's called "Blue", and
the other's called "Pink", but
they're both called "Badger"?

<Chief>
ケッコンしてるからね、
その２人は。
You got it! They're married.

<Maya>
あの。タイホくんとタイホちゃん
‥‥手錠でつながれてますけど。
Um... Mr. & Mrs. Badger seem
to be cuffed together, Chief.

<Chief>
‥‥それが
ケッコンというヤツだからねえ。
You got it! That's marriage
for you!

<Phoenix>
（さすが警察のマスコット‥‥
　重たいな、なんとなく）
(Whoa... A mascot that's
deeper than the deepest of
deep oceans...)




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Detective>
“ひったくり　ひったくられて
　いたみわけ”
"Even pickpockets can have
their pockets picked."

‥‥キマリだな。一見、
標語っぽくないのがイイ。
That's a keeper! Better to go
with something that doesn't
sound too much like a slogan.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

防犯キャンペーンの
標語を考えている‥‥
He must be coming up with
slogans for a crime prevention
campaign...

ようには、とても見えない。
...But I'm not sure even he
knows what kind of crime
he's trying to prevent.




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
This must be the chief
of the detectives here.

‥‥パソコンのスイッチを
切られて、ボーゼンとしている。
He looks lost, now that the
power to his computer has
been cut.

<Chief>
‥‥しかたがない。
気分を変えて、手紙にするか。
Oh, well. I guess I'll just
have to write her a real
letter instead of an email.

<Phoenix>
（捜査しろよ‥‥）
(Alternately, you could write
up some reports...
Just a suggestion.)

<Chief>
『サヨコさん、お元気ですか。
　ぼくは元気です』‥‥と。
"Dear 1337aZnPrInceSz,
How are you? I'm OK! How
was the show last night...?"

<Maya>
‥‥あたし、カチョーに
なりたくなってきたよ。
Wow, what an awesome job!
Maybe I should send in my
resume and become chief!




<Phoenix>
婦人警官がビシッと
敬礼している。
A poster of a female
police officer...

‥‥と思ったら、制服を着た
アイドルのグラビアだった。
Wait, no. That's the latest
"Babes in Uniform" calendar.
My bad.




<Phoenix>
刑事たちの机がならんでいる。
These are the detectives'
desks.

パソコンに、資料。
‥‥思ったより片づいているな。
There are computers and files
on each one. Funny, they're a
lot tidier than I expected.

たぶん、あまり席にいることが
ないんだろう。
I guess the detectives don't
spend a lot of time at their
desks.




同日　某時刻
警察署・刑事課
January 7
Police Station
Criminal Affairs Dept.

<Detective>
署のマシンがパンクしました！
The main server just went
up in smoke!

記者会見の用意はまだか！
総監が見えたぞ！
Why the heck isn't the press
conference set up yet!? The
Superintendent's here already!

<Chief>
ううん。インターネットでも
話題になっているようだな。
Yeah. And there's a problem
with the Internet, too.

<Detective>
だから！　課長、コンピュータを
使わないでください！
I already told you to stop
using your computer, Chief!

<Chief>
いや、しかし今、ワシの王手が‥‥
But I'm watching videos
online! I'm catching up on
my Asian soap operas!

<Detective>
また今度にしてください！
はい。スイッチ、切りますよ！
It's gonna have to wait,
Chief. I'm throwing the
switch!

<Chief>
ぎゃー！　ワシの王手が‥‥
Nooo! Just when Sum Yung-Gai
was about to confess to his
son's hot-to-trot girlfriend!

<Maya>
いやー、
盛り上がってるねえ。
Wow! This place is really
buzzing.

<Phoenix>
何か事件が起こったみたいだな。
‥‥とびきり、ハデなのが。
Something must be going down.
Something really big.

<Gumshoe>
おッ！　アンタたち！
Huh!? What are you doing
here, pal?

<Maya>
あ、イトノコ刑事さん！
Detective Gumshoe!

<Gumshoe>
ダメッスよ。
こんなときに来ちゃあ。
You can't be here right now.

アンタたちまでかり出されるッス。
‥‥聞き込みに。
You'll be roped into the
briefing if you stay.

<Phoenix>
ま、まさか。
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
とにかく、タイヘンな
コトになってるッス！
We've got big problems here
today.

<Maya>
‥‥あの。何があったんですか？
Why? What's going on?

<Gumshoe>
ウイルスッス！　ウイルスッス！
It's a virus!
A virus!!

<Phoenix>
（ウイルス‥‥？）
(A virus?)

<Gumshoe>
コンピュータ・ウイルスが
署内で暴れ狂っているッス！
There's a virus ripping
through the precinct's
computer system.

<Phoenix>
（まいったな‥‥
　いろいろ聞くことがあるのに）
(But I really need to ask
you some questions...)




<Gumshoe>
‥‥あああああッ、そおッスゥッ！
Aaaaargh! I can't believe it!

イチバン重要なコトを
忘れていたッス！
I almost forgot the most
important thing!

<Phoenix>
な、なんですか‥‥？
A-And that is...?

<Gumshoe>
決まってるじゃないッスかッ！
‥‥ベントウッスよ！
You know, the lunchbox!
How did everything go!?

<Phoenix>
ベントウ‥‥？
L-Lunchbox?

<Maya>
あれだよ。ウインナーの‥‥
You remember. The weenies...?

<Byrde>
スズキ、ウインナーは
大ッキライッス！
I hate weenies!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ああ、あれか‥‥）
(Oh, yeah... Those weenies.)

<Gumshoe>
どうだったッスか！
自分のベントウはッ！
So? How did my weenies taste
when they went down the
hatch?

<Maya>
え！　えーと‥‥あの。
‥‥‥‥‥‥おいしかったです。
Huh? Um... Well...
It was... delicious!

<Gumshoe>
そーッスか！　そーッスか！
そりゃ、よかったッス！
Yeah? That's what she said?
Really!?

<Maya>
あ、いや。そういう
イミじゃなくて‥‥
Umm... Well...
Not exactly...

<Gumshoe>
ダイジョーブ！
シンパイ、いらないッス！
Don't worry about it, pal.

そんなコトもあろうかと‥‥
ちゃーんと、作っておいたッス！
I figured something would
happen, so I came prepared.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
な、ナニを‥‥？
Prepared?
What do you mean...?

<Gumshoe>
おかわりの大盛りベントウッス！
I made a jumbo lunchbox!

<Maya>
は‥‥はああ‥‥。
Oh...

<Gumshoe>
じゃ、またコレ。
よろしくたのむッス。
Do me a favor again, huh, pal,
and deliver this?

<Phoenix>
（ズッシリ重いな‥‥
　あらゆるイミで‥‥）
(This sure is a heavy
burden...
In more ways than one...)

<Gumshoe>
マコクンのよろこぶカオが
目に浮かぶッス！
I can just imagine Maggey's
little eyes sparkling with joy
when you bring her that!

<Maya>
また食べるの？　ウインナー‥‥
...Weenies, again, Nick?
Tell me we don't have to
eat all these too...

< >
《イトノコのベントウ》を
ふたたび、真宵ちゃんに持たせた。
Gumshoe's Lunchbox given to
Maya. Again.

<Maya>
もう食べられないよ、あたし。
I really can't eat any more...




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Detective>
“カギしめて　元センしめて
　抱きしめて”‥‥
"Your batteries won't last
forever. Remember that when
you're having fun... in bed."

‥‥キマリだな。さりげなく
火遊びを風刺しているのがイイ。
We have a winner! A little
joke to make people think
about their smoke alarms.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

防火キャンペーンの
標語を考えている‥‥
He must be coming up with
slogans for a fire safety
campaign...

つもりなんだろうな、
あくまでも本人としては。
...I guess?
...Does he even know what he's
trying to get across anymore?




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
This must be the chief
of the detectives here.

‥‥パソコンのスイッチを
切られて、ボーゼンとしている。
He looks lost, now that the
power to his computer has
been cut.

<Chief>
‥‥しかたがない。
気分を変えて、新聞を読むか。
Oh, well. I guess I'll just
have to read the paper now.

<Phoenix>
（捜査しろよ‥‥）
(Alternately, you could read
some reports...
Just a suggestion.)

<Chief>
‥‥って、なんだ！
１ヶ月も前の古新聞じゃないか！
What the heck is this!?
This paper's more than a
month old!

しかも、サインペンでラクガキ
してあるし！
And someone's written all
over it!

こんなもの、ワシの机に置くなッ！
‥‥イヤガラセか？
Who's the clown that put this
on my desk? Well? Speak up!

<Maya>
くしゃくしゃに丸めて
捨てちゃったよ。
He just wadded it up and
chucked it in the trash!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ダイジな証拠品なのに。
But that's an important piece
of evidence!




<Maya>
あの‥‥なんですか？
コンピュータ・ウイルスって。
So what exactly is a computer
virus, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
知らねッス。
I dunno.

<Maya>
え。
What?

<Gumshoe>
自分は、このさわぎに
ただ、オドらされているだけッス。
Look, I just go with the flow,
alright, pal?

<Phoenix>
（あきれた刑事さんだな‥‥）
(And here I thought detectives
were supposed to be somewhat
knowledgeable...)

<Gumshoe>
あー！　なんスか、そのカオ！
じゃーアンタ、知ってるッスか！
What's with that face, pal?
You think you know what a
virus is?

<Maya>
知ってるッスか？　なるほどくん！
Well, Nick?
Do you?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータ・ウイルス、か。
まあ、カンタンなコトなら‥‥。
A computer virus? Sure.
I mean, only in simple terms,
of course.

<Maya>
えッ！　スゴい、なるほどくん！
ものしりハカセだ！
Really? Wow, you know
everything, Professor Nick!

<Gumshoe>
これから、ハカセって呼ぶッス！
Yeah. I'm gonna call you
Dr. Wright from now on!

<Maya>
あ。いいなそれ。
‥‥ね？　ハカセ。
Hey, that sounds pretty cool!
Don't you agree, Dr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（バカにされてるような気がする）
(Why do I get the feeling
they're making fun of me?)

しかたないな。あまり詳しく
ないけど、説明しましょうか？
OK, fine. I'm no expert, but
I can at least explain the
basics to the two of you.




<Phoenix>
“ウイルス”は、コンピュータを
破壊するためのプログラムです。
A virus is a program that
gets inside a computer and
causes damage.

<Gumshoe>
は、ハカイ‥‥って、
ボカーン！　と行くッスか！
Damage? You mean it makes the
machine go "boom" and explode?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちがいます。コワすのは‥‥
そう。コンピュータの中身、かな。
No. The damage is, um...
Well, it's all internal.

<Maya>
中身がボカーン！　って行くの？
So the inside goes "boom",
right?

<Phoenix>
たとえば、警察のコンピュータには
事件のデータが記録されてるだろ？
Imagine all the case data
you've got stored on your
PCs here in the station...

それが、ウイルスプログラムで
ゼンブ、ぱあになるわけ。
A virus could wipe out all
that. That's the kind of
damage I'm talking about.

<Maya>
ひゃあ。コワいねー、ウイルス。
Whoa! That's scary.

<Phoenix>
もっとコワいのは、ウイルスは
伝染する、ってトコロだ。
Yeah. And what's even more
scary is that viruses are
infectious.

<Maya>
でんせん‥‥？
Infectious?

<Phoenix>
コンピュータは、ネットワークで
つながってるコトが多いだろ？
Most computers are connected
together on a network, right?

ウイルスは、それらのマシンを
次々に破壊していくんだよ。
A virus can move from one
machine to another over the
network.

ネットワークを通じて、ウイルスは
自分で勝手に、増えていくわけだ。
So the virus just keeps
spreading faster and faster.

<Gumshoe>
うーん。ホンモノの
伝染病みたいッスねー。
Hmph. Just like a real virus,
huh.

<Maya>
でも、でも！　なんでそんな
プログラムを作るのかな。
But, Nick! Why would anyone
want to make a program like
that?

<Gumshoe>
そッス。せっかく作ったデータを
ぶちコワしたら、イミがないッス！
Yeah. It takes ages to type in
all that data. Why would you
wanna destroy it, pal?

<Phoenix>
いやいや。ウイルスプログラムは、
他人のマシンに送り込むんです。
No. People don't infect their
own machines. They send the
virus to someone else's.

<Maya>
うわ。ヒドいの！
What!? That's horrible!

<Gumshoe>
あー。つまりアレッスか。
Oh, I get it...

アンタが、ゴドー検事にクシャミ
引っかけてカゼをうつす、という。
It's like you sneezing on
Godot so he catches a cold.

<Maya>
そうか！　それでゴドー検事は
法廷をお休み、と。
Right! Then he wouldn't be
able to turn up in court
because he'd be too sick.

‥‥あいかわらずワルだねー、
なるほどくん。
You really shouldn't do stuff
like that, Nick. It's wrong.

<Phoenix>
なんでぼくの話になるんだよ！
Who? What? Where? When and
why did the conversation jump
to talking about me!?

とにかく、それがコンピュータ・
ウイルスだよ。悪いプログラムだ。
Anyway, that's what a computer
virus is. A bad program that
causes damage.

<Gumshoe>
ウイルスプログラムには、いちいち
名前がついているッス。
And all the different viruses
have names, right?

今回、ウチで暴れてるウイルス‥‥
どこかで聞いた名前なんスがねえ。
I kinda feel like I've heard
the name of the virus we
caught somewhere before.

<Phoenix>
（ウイルスプログラムの名前。
　ココロ当たりがあるような‥‥）
(The name of the virus, huh?
I feel like I've heard of it
before, too...)




<Gumshoe>
《クリーニング・ボンバー》の
情報は、以前から流れていたッス。
We already knew about the
MC Bomber virus from a while
back.

警察の上層部に、ナニやら
取引を持ちかけたグループが‥‥
A group of criminals issued a
series of demands to the head
honchos of law enforcement.

『取引に応じなければ、ウイルスを
　バラまくぞ』と脅してきたッス。
They threatened to release
the virus if their demands
weren't met.

<Maya>
ダレですか？　そんなダイタンな
コトをするの。
Who are they?

<Gumshoe>
ウラ社会の大物、らしいッスね。
‥‥自分は知らねッス。
I dunno. Some hotshots from
the criminal underworld would
be my guess.

<Phoenix>
そのウイルスが、送りこまれて
きた、というわけですか‥‥。
And now the virus has been
released, huh...

<Gumshoe>
公共機関のコンピュータが、
バクハツ的に感染して‥‥
Yeah. It's in every computer
in every public office in the
city.

もお、お祭りさわぎッス！
カーニバルッス！
Everyone's going nuts! They're
hopping around like they're
dancing at a carnival!

<Maya>
すごいなあ。なんか、アレ。
“えすえふ”みたいですよねー。
All this stuff with criminals
and viruses... It almost feels
like we're in a sci-fi movie!

<Gumshoe>
かなりウデのいいプログラマーが
作ったウイルスらしいッス。
Apparently the programmer
who made the virus was a
real genius or something.

今、コイツが売りさばかれた
闇ルートを、必死で探してるッス！
The focus right now is on
tracing the route of this
virus on the black market.

<Phoenix>
ウイルスプログラム‥‥って、
“商品”になるんですか？
You mean someone put this
virus up for sale?

<Gumshoe>
そうみたいッス。特に、今回の
ウイルスはよくできてるッスから、
Yeah. And because this one's
so powerful...

“億”単位のカネが
動いていると思われるッス。
...they're estimating its
price tag was in the millions
of dollars, pal.

<Phoenix>
（ウイルスプログラムに、そんな
　価値があったなんて‥‥！）
(In the millions!? A virus
can be worth that much!?)

< >
《クリーニング・ボンバー》の
データを書きなおした。
MC Bomber updated in
the Court Record.




<Gumshoe>
いいッスか。よく聞くッス！
OK, I'm only gonna say this
once, so listen up!

<Maya>
‥‥は、はい！
Y-Yes!

<Gumshoe>
いくらビンボーでも、こういう
ところから借りちゃダメッス！
No matter how poor you get,
never borrow money from a
place like this, you hear?

<Maya>
‥‥は、はい？
Um... OK...?

<Gumshoe>
そういうときは‥‥
ソーメンを食べて、ガマンッス！
If you got money trouble, just
go on a diet of instant
noodles and hang in there!

<Phoenix>
いやいや！　借金じゃなくて、
この会社の情報がほしいんですよ！
Ah, we're not thinking about
borrowing money, Detective!
We want information.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥なんだ。
Oh... Is that all?
Well, let's see...

カリヨーゼは、闇金融の中でも
特にアヤシイ会社ッス。
Tender Lender is considered to
be even fishier than the
average illegal loan shark.

なんか最近、急に
カネに困りだしたらしく‥‥、
And it seems it ran into
trouble just recently.

かなりゴーインな
取り立てをしている、とか。
Those guys have been pretty
heavy-handed, calling in all
their debts.

<Maya>
そうなんですか‥‥
Really?

<Gumshoe>
あの会社には、クビを
つっこまないほうがいいッス。
Don't go poking your nose
around in their business, pal.

彼女にニラまれたら、
ブジじゃすまないッスからねえ。
You'll really regret it if
you upset that lady.

<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりました。
（‥‥って、ちょっと待て！）
Alright, I get the picture.
(Hey, wait a minute!)

（今、なんて言った！
　‥‥“彼女”‥‥？）
(What did he just say!?
"That lady"?)

<Maya>
‥‥ダレのことかな。
Who's this lady he's talking
about, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（詳しく聞いてみるか‥‥。
　“彼女”のこと‥‥）
(We better find out what the
story is with this "lady"...)




<Phoenix>
あまり聞きたくないですけど‥‥
《鹿羽組》というのは？
I'm not sure if I really want
to get involved in this, but
who are the Cadaverinis?

<Gumshoe>
まー、コワい連中ッスな。
Who are they?
A scary bunch of people,
that's who!

<Phoenix>
（刑事のクセに、“コワい”
　ってのも、どうだろう‥‥）
(You're a cop, and you're
scared? What's that about?)

<Gumshoe>
刑事だろうと小学生だろうと、
コワいものはコワいッス！
Trust me, it doesn't matter if
you're a kid or a cop, these
guys are scary.

ウラ社会で絶大な力を持つ、
やっかいなグループッス。
They've got some serious clout
in the criminal underworld.

とにかく連中、ミョーに資金が
あるので、手に負えないッス。
We can't touch them. They've
got too much moola.

<Phoenix>
資金が‥‥？
Moola...?
As in?

<Gumshoe>
街の闇金融業界をひとまとめに
して、かせいでいるとか。
They pretty much control all
the cash on the city's black
market.

<Phoenix>
闇金融‥‥というと、
《カリヨーゼ》も‥‥？
The black market, huh?
And that includes Tender
Lender, I take it?

<Gumshoe>
トーゼン、鹿羽　権太には
アタマが上がらないッス。
Sure. No one stands up to
Bruto Cadaverini.
And I mean, no one!

<Phoenix>
（そうだったのか‥‥）
(Interesting...)

<Maya>
うらみさん、そんなコワい人の
おマゴさんだったんですね‥‥
So Viola's the granddaughter
of some mafia boss then?

<Gumshoe>
鹿羽　権太のマゴ好きは
有名ッス。
Yeah. And everyone knows how
much Bruto loves his little
girl.

たったヒトリのマゴで、
組長の生きがいッス。
She means everything to him.

<Phoenix>
そういえば‥‥
So...

どうして彼女、
《カリヨーゼ》にいるんですか？
How did she end up at
Tender Lender?

<Gumshoe>
さー。そこまでは
知らないッスけど‥‥。
I dunno, pal.

でも、かなりアツアツな
ふたりらしいッス。
But I heard she and the boss
of the Tender Lender are
pretty tight.

<Maya>
あつあつ‥‥
Tight?

<Gumshoe>
マコクンの事件で、関係者の資料に
そう書いてあったッス。
That's what it said in a file
I read related to Maggey's
case.

<Phoenix>
（これは‥‥かなり重要な
　手がかりだな‥‥）
(Sounds like a pretty
important clue.)




<Gumshoe>
まちがいなく、マコクンに
わたしてほしいッス！
Don't forget to give that
to Maggey, OK?

<Maya>
あ‥‥でも、留置所って
差し入れ、いけないんじゃあ‥‥？
But they don't allow presents
for the prisoners in the
detention center, right...?

<Gumshoe>
あれ！　そう言えば
そうだったッスっけ。
Hey, you're right...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

なんにせよ、マコクンに
わたしてほしいッス！
Well, it doesn't matter.
I'm counting on you to get it
to her somehow.

<Phoenix>
（まいったな‥‥）
(I'm a lawyer, not a delivery
boy, Gumshoe...)




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥イトノコ刑事。
これ、なんですけど‥‥
Detective Gumshoe, umm...
about this...

<Gumshoe>
なんスか！　自分は今、
マコクンとウイルスで、アタマが
What!? I'm trying to
concentrate on Maggey and
this virus right now, so I...

うほおほおおおおおおおおおおッ！
Aaaaaaaaaaah!!

これッス！　この、
フザけた名前！　思い出したッス！
This is it! This stupid name!
I remember now!

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり、な‥‥）
(I thought so.
Here it comes...)

<Maya>
ナニよー！　ヒトリでうなずいて
ないで、教えてよー！
Don't just nod to yourself and
keep me in the dark, Nick!
What's going on!?

<Phoenix>
な、泣くなよ！
It's OK, Maya!
You don't have to cry
about it!

<Gumshoe>
スポーツ新聞のラクガキ‥‥
そして、ＣＤ‥‥
The name scribbled on that
sports paper and written on
that CD...

《クリーニング・ボンバー》
‥‥ウイルスの名前ッス！
That's the name of the virus!
"MC Bomber"!

<Maya>
ええええええええええッ！
WHAT!?

<Gumshoe>
今、署内でウワサの
コンピュータ・ウイルスッス！
Yeah! The virus that's just
infected every computer in the
station, pal. It's MC Bomber!

<Phoenix>
もう少し、詳しく
聞かせてもらえますか？
Can you give us any more
details? Please!?




<Gumshoe>
あんまり、ヒトに見せないほうが
いいッスよ、その写真。
I wouldn't go flashing that
photo around if I were you,
pal.

<Maya>
どうしてですか？
Why not?

<Gumshoe>
なにぶん、ウラ社会の
ボスッスからねー。
That guy rules the criminal
underworld.

こっぴどい目にあうッス。
‥‥くわばらくわばら。
You could get yourselves in
serious trouble. I'm talking
say-your-prayers trouble.

<Maya>
イトノコさん、ふるえてるよ。
You're shaking, Detective.

<Phoenix>
意外にヨワムシだな。
Like a leaf...

<Gumshoe>
自分は、その。
‥‥頭脳派ッスから。
I'm just... You know... Kinda
on edge at the moment...
If you know what I mean.




<Gumshoe>
コイツが、ゼニトラッスか‥‥。
Oh, this guy...
The Tiger...

<Maya>
有名なんですか？
Is he famous?

<Gumshoe>
まさに、ゼニを貸すトラ
みたいなオトコッス！
Yeah. This guy's not a loan
shark, you know. Nope.
He's a big loan cat!

<Phoenix>
そのまんまですね。
Hence the name?

<Gumshoe>
返さないと、食われるッス。
‥‥くわばらくわばら。
Don't pay him back, and you'd
better say your prayers,
because he'll eat you alive.

<Maya>
イトノコさん、ふるえてるよ。
You're shaking, Detective.

<Phoenix>
意外にヨワムシだな。
Like a leaf...

<Gumshoe>
自分は、その。
‥‥頭脳派ッスから。
I'm just... You know... kinda
on edge at the moment...
If you know what I mean.




<Gumshoe>
カリヨーゼの従業員ッスね。
That's the girl who works over
at Tender Lender.

‥‥ヘタに近よらないほうが
いいッスよ。これはホントに。
You wanna stay away from her,
OK? I mean it.

<Maya>
たしかに、うらめしげ
ですからねー、このひと‥‥。
She does look kind of
unforgiving, doesn't she?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥そういうコトじゃないッス。
That should be the least
of your worries, pal.

<Phoenix>
（どういうことだ‥‥？）
(What's that supposed to mean?
What could be worse...?)

<Gumshoe>
彼女の名前は、
鹿羽（しかばね）うらみ。
Her name's Viola Cadaverini.

あの、鹿羽　権太（ごんた）の
たったヒトリのマゴにあたるッス。
She's the only granddaughter
of Bruto Cadaverini.

<Maya>
‥‥しかばね　ごんた‥‥？
知ってる？　なるほどくん。
Bruto Cadaverini?
Do you know who that is, Nick?

<Phoenix>
聞いたコトないよ。
Never heard of him.

<Gumshoe>
鹿羽　権太は‥‥
恐怖の《鹿羽組》組長ッス。
Bruto Cadaverini's the boss
of the Cadaverini family.

<Phoenix>
し、しかばねぐみ‥‥
（ゼッタイ、関わりたくないな）
The Cadaverinis?
(That's one scary-sounding
name!)

<Gumshoe>
警察の力ですら、ヤツらを
つぶすのはムズカシイッス。
We can't touch them. They're
way too powerful for the
police.

それでも‥‥、戦うと言うッスか？
But you're thinking of taking
them on, aren't you?

<Phoenix>
だ、ダレもそんなコト
言ってませんよ！
N-No! I don't remember
ever saying I was going to!

（とにかく‥‥少しだけ、
　話を聞いておくか‥‥）
(I better get some more info
out of Gumshoe about this
"family"...)




同日　某時刻
レストラン　吐麗美庵
January 7
Trés Bien

<Maya>
あいかわらず
いないねー、お客さん。
Empty, as usual.

<Phoenix>
ヒルメシどきなのになあ。
Yeah, and it's lunchtime,
too.

<???>
よよ、よしッ！
きたきたきたきたきたアッ！
That's it!
Come on, come on, come on!

<Phoenix>
あれ。この声‥‥
Hey, that sounds like...

<Gumshoe>
そう！　そこで《８》ッス！
カモンッス！
Now just call an "8", pal!
Come on! I know you can!

<Maya>
‥‥なんか、
ひとりでアツくなってるよ。
He's getting really worked
up about something.

<Gumshoe>
うがああああああッ！
ハズしたッスかああッ！
Noooooo!
That's the wrong number!

《８》なら５００円‥‥
ぐううう‥‥クヤシイッ！
Argh! Looks like an "8" would
have only netted me five bucks
anyway! What a rip off!

<Maya>
なに、もだえてるんですか？
イトノコさん。
What's the problem, Detective
Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
あ！　アンタたち‥‥
Huh!? Oh, it's you...

ま、まあその。ははははは。
ちょっとその。ははははは。
I, uh... I was uh... Hah hah!
I was just... Hah hah hah!

ラジオ、聞いてたッス。
I was just listening to the
radio, pal.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ラジオ‥‥？
To the radio?

<Maya>
ああっ！　イトノコさん、
ランチ食べてる！
Hey, Detective Gumshoe's
having lunch here!

<Phoenix>
（おお、ホントだ！
　ニクハチセット‥‥）
(He is! And he's having the
Twin-T set...)

<Gumshoe>
はああああ。
イイコトないッスねー‥‥
Aha ha ha...
What can I say...?




<Gumshoe>
‥‥じゃあ、アンタたち。
自分はそろそろ、署に戻るッス。
Well, I'm gonna head back to
the precinct now.

捜査会議があるッスから。
We've got a big meeting
starting in a bit.

<Maya>
お。マコちゃんの事件ですか？
About Maggey's case, you
mean?

<Gumshoe>
アレは、いちおう決着が
ついたことになってるッス‥‥
No, that's pretty much wrapped
up now...

なんか今、大事件が
起きてるッスから、そっちッス。
There's another big case
going down at the moment, so
she's been pushed aside...

<Maya>
わかりました。
じゃ、さよなら。イトノコさん。
OK. Well, see you later then.

<Gumshoe>
じゃッ！
Bye!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
......

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
.........

は、早く帰ってくださいよ！
Y-You better get going,
Detective, or you'll be late.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥じ、ジツは‥‥
Actually, I, um...

この糸鋸　圭介！
一生のおねがいがあるッス。
I've kinda got a favor to
ask. It's a big one!

<Phoenix>
お、おねがい‥‥？
A favor?

<Gumshoe>
あ、あの‥‥
ま。マコクンに‥‥
Yeah... It's for, um...
Maggey, actually.

マコクンに‥‥、これを
差し入れしてほしいッス。
I was kinda hoping... you'd
give this to her for me.

<Maya>
こ、これは‥‥？
What is it?

<Gumshoe>
ベントウ‥‥ッス。
早起きして作ったッス。
It's a lunchbox.
I got up early so I could
make it.

マコクン‥‥少し、
ヤセたみたいだったッスから。
I've been real worried about
her. She looked like she'd
lost a lot of weight.

<Maya>
イトノコさん‥‥
Detective Gumshoe...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

イヤになるほどギッシリ
つまってますね。ウインナー。
How many weenies are in here!?
There's not a person on earth
who could down this much meat.

<Gumshoe>
自分には、イチバンの
ゴチソウッスから。
You think? I love weenies.
I can't get enough of their
tender juiciness.

おねがいッス！
いっしょうけんめい、作ったッス！
So will you give it to her?
It took me ages to make,
so please say you will, pal!

<Phoenix>
（これは‥‥
　断れないよな、さすがに）
(I can't exactly say no,
can I?)

< >
《イトノコのベントウ》を
真宵ちゃんに持たせた。
Gumshoe's Lunchbox given to
Maya to carry.

<Maya>
食べちゃうかもよ、あたし。
Maybe I'll eat it myself if
I get hungry!

<Gumshoe>
じゃ、その‥‥
くれぐれもヨロシクッス！
Don't forget, OK?
I'm counting on you to give
that to Maggey.

<Phoenix>
（やっと帰っていった‥‥）
(He's finally gone...)




<Maya>
ファッション雑誌ばっかり。
しかも、フランス語だよ。
It's a rack full of fashion
magazines. And they're all in
French.

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃんも、たまには
おしゃれしてみたら？
Why don't you try wearing
something a bit more "chic"
sometime huh, Maya?

<Maya>
そうだなあ。たまには
パリっぽくキメてみようかな‥‥
Yeah. I'd look stunning in
some of those Parisian frocks,
huh?




<Phoenix>
入り口のドアだ。
It's the restaurant's front
entrance.

パネルがぶら下がっていて、
フランス語で何やら書いてある。
There's a sign hanging on the
door written in French.

《営業中》《準備中》の
どちらかだろう。
It probably says "Open" or
"Closed".

どっちかわからないけど。
‥‥フランス語だから。
It must be one or the other,
but I don't know which since I
dunno Jacques about French.

<Maya>
《入口》《出口》のどちらか
かもしれないしね。
It could say "Entrance" or
"Exit", too. Did you think of
that?




<Maya>
なんか、カワイイ小物が
ちんまり並んでるよ。
Look at all the little
trinkets tucked away in here.

<Phoenix>
きっと、店長さんの
シュミなんだろうね。
I bet Mr. Armstrong collected
all of these personally.

ブーケやら、ポプリやら、
ボーンチャイナのカップやら‥‥
Let's see... A bouquet of
flowers, some potpourri, and
look! Fine bone china cups!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

なるほどくん、ナニ人？
I never knew you were so...
cultured.

<Phoenix>
これぐらい、ニッポン人でも
知ってるよ！
Come on, Maya! This is
common knowledge! Any Joe
Schmoe knows this much!




<Maya>
いくらでもお金が出てくる、
魔法のハコがあるよ。
Look, it's one of those
magical boxes that spits
out money.

<Phoenix>
‥‥レジをそう表現するヒトは
初めてだな。
You know, you're the only
person who would ever describe
a cash register in that way!




<Phoenix>
‥‥事件があった
テーブル、だね。
This must be the table where
the murder occurred.

<Maya>
立ち入り禁止の
テープが張ってあるよ‥‥。
I guess so, with all this
police tape all around it.

<Phoenix>
テーブルのシミは‥‥
毒入りのコーヒーかな。
And that stain must be from
the poisoned coffee.

真宵ちゃん。テーブルクロス、
ナメちゃダメだぞ。死ぬから。
Don't go licking the
tablecloth. OK, Maya?

<Maya>
ナメないよ！
あたしをナメないでよね！
Why would I lick it?
I'm not a cat, you know!

<Phoenix>
（お。ウマいコト言うな‥‥）
(Then why can I picture you
doing just that?)




<Phoenix>
キチンとセットされた
テーブルだ。
This table's set nicely.
It just needs a customer.

<Maya>
これかな？　マメのオジさんが
言ってた《花ビン》って。
Hey, Nick. Do you think Old
Seedy was talking about a vase
like this today in court?

<Phoenix>
たしかに、不安定、かつ
とても割れやすそうな花ビンだな。
It does look like it's ready
to fall over any second.
Looks kind of fragile, too.

<Maya>
お客さんが割るごとに
１００万円ずつもらえば、
I bet if Mr. Armstrong charged
10,000 dollars for every vase
a customer broke...

借金なんか、すぐ返せるのにね。
...he'd be able to pay off his
loan really quickly.

<Phoenix>
‥‥暴動が起こるぞ、
そんなコトしたら。
If you hit people with that
kind of bill, Maya, they will
hit you back!




<Phoenix>
窓のそとは、一面の銀世界だ。
Wow! It's a beautiful winter
wonderland out there.

<Maya>
え！　ウソ！
あたし、大好きなんだよ、雪。
Really!?
Cool! I love snow!
Let me see!

‥‥あれ。降ってないじゃない、
雪なんて。
Huh? It's not white.
It's not even snowing.

<Phoenix>
う、ウソに決まってるだろ。
Got ya!
I was just kidding, Maya.

<Maya>
なるほどくんッ！
Nick!

言っていいウソと
悪いウソがあるよッ！
There are lies that are OK
to tell, and lies that
definitely aren't.

<Phoenix>
（悪いウソだったのか‥‥今の）
(...All I did was tell an
itty-bitty white lie about
nonexistent white snow.)




<Phoenix>
テーブルの間に、
仕切りが立っている。
This restaurant has partitions
that separate the tables.

席について見えるのは、
向かい側のテーブルだけ、か。
When you're seated at a table,
you can only see the tables to
your right or left.

<Maya>
ホントだ。おとなりの席、
ゼンゼン見えないよ。
Wow, you really can't see
the table in front or behind
you at all!

相手のコーヒーに毒を入れるには
もってこいだね。
It's the perfect setup for
slipping poison into your
enemy's coffee.




<Gumshoe>
もう、サイアクッス！
This is a nightmare!

自分は‥‥マコクンに
合わせるカオがないッス！
How am I supposed to look
Maggey in the eye now, pal!?

<Maya>
いい調子で追いつめてました
からねー、マコちゃんのこと。
You really drove her into a
corner, you know.

<Gumshoe>
どーして、今日にかぎって
やっつけてくれなかったッスか！
You always blow apart my
testimony! Why, of all days,
didn't you do it today!?

<Phoenix>
す、スミマセン。めずらしく
スキがなかったから‥‥
S-Sorry...
There just weren't any holes
in it... for once!

<Maya>
いつもは、スキだらけで
スカスカなのにね。
Yeah, what happened? Usually,
your testimonies are like
Swiss cheese!

<Gumshoe>
す‥‥スカスカッスか。
S-Swiss cheese...?

<Phoenix>
（まあ‥‥当たり前の
　ハナシなんだよな）
(Would he have preferred,
"crumbly like aged parmesan"?)

（一度は判決が下ってる事件だ。
　そう、スキがあるワケがない）
(Anyway, this case has already
been ruled on. There shouldn't
be any holes left to find.)

<Gumshoe>
あの‥‥マコクン、ナニか
言ってたッスか？　自分のコト。
So... Did Maggey say anything
to you? About me, I mean.

<Maya>
そうですねー‥‥
Well, um...
How did she put it again...?

<Byrde>
イトノコセンパイ、ヒドいッス！
I can't believe Detective
Gumshoe!

もー、キライッス！
カオも見たくないッス！
I hate him, sir! I mean it!
I don't ever want to see him
again!

<Maya>
‥‥とか、なんとか。
Something like that.

<Gumshoe>
う‥‥‥‥
うおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
Wah...
Waaaaaaaaaah!

<Maya>
あ！　イトノコさん！
P-Please! Detective Gumshoe!
I didn't mean...

<Gumshoe>
自分は！　自分はああああああッ！
Why!?
Why is this happening!?

<Maya>
カベにアタマぶつけてる‥‥
He's banging his head against
the wall, Nick!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥カワイソウに）
(Oh, man... Poor Gumshoe...)




<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事。
どうですか？　ニクハチセットは。
So, did you like the Twin-T
set?

<Gumshoe>
こんな高いヒルメシは
生まれてはじめてッス。
I've never paid that much
money for lunch before.

食べてて、あまりのキンチョーに
手がふるえるッス。
I was so nervous, my hands
were shaking.

<Maya>
で？　で？　おアジのほうは‥‥？
So? How did it taste!?

<Gumshoe>
そッスねー。
Well...

さすが２９８０円だけあって、
なんというか‥‥珍味ッス。
For 20 bucks, I guess...
I dunno how to describe it,
really. It was... delicate.

<Maya>
ちんみ‥‥
Delicate?

<Phoenix>
あの。刑事さん。
マズくないんですか？　それ。
You mean you liked it!?
It didn't taste bad to you?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ど、どうしたのかな、
イトノコさん。
What's the matter with him?

<Phoenix>
なにやら、ジッと考えこんでるぞ。
Looks like he's thinking...

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

それッスゥッ！
That's it!

じつはさっきから、この料理に
ふさわしいコトバを探してたッス。
I've been trying to think of
the right word to describe
the taste.

今、わかったッス！
“マズい”だったッス！
I just got it right now...
"Bad"! That's it.
It tasted bad!

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥。
*sigh*

<Gumshoe>
２９８０円も払ったから、その
ジジツを認められなかったッス！
It's kinda hard to admit it
to yourself when you pay 20
bucks though, pal.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥食べ終わってから
　教えてあげればよかったな）
(Maybe he should've found out
about the price AFTER he had
finished eating...)

<Maya>
被害者の岡　高夫さんも、
わざわざ食べに来たのかな。
Maybe that's why Glen Elg came
here.

恐るべきニクハチセットの
ウワサを聞きつけて。
Maybe he heard about the
famous Twin-T set!

<Phoenix>
（“被害者”、か。
　そういえば、今さらだけど‥‥）
(Glen Elg, the victim, huh...
Which reminds me.)

（岡　高夫の情報、ほとんど
　ないんだよな‥‥）
(We still hardly know anything
about the guy.)

<Maya>
せっかくだし、聞いてみる？
イトノコさんに。
Why don't we ask Gumshoe what
he knows, seeing as he's here?




<Maya>
そういえば‥‥ひとりで
大サワギしてましたよね。
So what were you all excited
about earlier?

<Gumshoe>
え。
Huh?

<Phoenix>
あ！　そうそう。
“ラジオを聞いてた”とか。
That's right!
You said you were listening
to the radio or something.

<Gumshoe>
べ、ベツにそんな！
大サワギなんて‥‥
Oh, that? That was nothing!
I-I wasn't excited!

<Maya>
ね。ね。ナニ聞いて
コーフンしてたんですか？
Come on, Detective Gumshoe!
You can tell little ol' me!
What were you listening to?

<Gumshoe>
いや、その‥‥
ラ、《ラジオ体操》ッス。
N-Nothing, really.
It was just the, um...
"Daily Exercise Show"!

<Phoenix>
（な、なんだ！
　サイコ・ロック‥‥？）
(What the...!?
A Psyche-Lock?)

<Gumshoe>
ははは。オイシイッスねー、
オマールえびは！
Hah hah hah! Mmm... This
lunch special's lobster is
great!

<Maya>
イトノコさん、
声がウラがえってるよ‥‥
Then why are there tears
in your eyes...?




<Maya>
ねえねえ、
教えてくださいよー、ラジオ。
Come on, Detective Gumshoe.
You can tell us what you were
listening to on the radio.

<Gumshoe>
いや、だからその。
の、《のどジマン》ッス。
But I already told you.
It was the, um... the...
weather forecast, pal.

<Phoenix>
（さっきは《ラジオ体操》って
　言ってたじゃないか！）
(Didn't you say it was an
exercise program earlier!?)

<Gumshoe>
いやー、それにしても
あれッスねー。はははは。
It was nothing, really.
Hah hah hah!

<Phoenix>
（大したコトじゃないけど‥‥
　かくされると、気になるよな）
(Even if it's nothing, the
fact that he's hiding it makes
me really curious!)




<Gumshoe>
けっこう当たるもんだな、
と思って、買ってみたッス。
I'm usually pretty lucky so
I figured I'd give it a try.

<Phoenix>
宝クジ、ですか。
What's with everyone and
the lottery...?

<Maya>
で？　で？　どうでした？
So? How did it go?

<Gumshoe>
５０円、当たったッス。
I won 50 cents!

ゼンゼン当たらないより、
かえってハラが立ったッス！
It'd be better to win nothing
at all than half a lousy buck!
I was so mad!

<Phoenix>
（キモチはわかるな‥‥）
(Yeah, I know the feeling.)

<Gumshoe>
岡　高夫と同じクジを
買ったッスがねえ‥‥。
I bought the same kind of
ticket as Mr. Elg.

ラジオ番組と連動していて、
なかなかスリリングだったッス。
When they read those results
out on the radio, it really
gets your heart pumping!

クジの抽選のようすを、ナマ放送。
これが燃えるッス。
You know they broadcast it
live when they're picking the
numbers? It's intense, pal!

<Maya>
岡　高夫さんも、それを聞いて
いたんですねー、きっと。
I bet that's what Glen was
listening to on the day he
was killed.

<Phoenix>
ところで‥‥
今、何時ですか？
Yeah.
What time is it now?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥え。
１時半、ちょっとすぎ‥‥ッス。
Uh, it's...
It's just after 1:30.

<Phoenix>
その、宝クジのラジオ番組は、
いつもこの時間に‥‥？
And are the lottery results
always broadcast at the same
time?

<Gumshoe>
そッス。‥‥クジ売り場で
もらったチラシがあるッスよ。
Yeah.
Look, I got this flyer when
I bought the ticket.

< >
《長者ラジオのチラシ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Millionaire Radio Flyer added
to the Court Record.

<Maya>
《長者ラジオ》‥‥かあ。
いいね、“長者”ってヒビキ。
"Millionaire Radio"?
That sounds cool!

なるほどくん！
あたしもやってみたい！
I want to try it, Nick!

<Phoenix>
自分のおこづかいで買えよ。
Then buy a ticket, Maya.
With your own money!




< >
～ラジオ～
-- The Radio --

<Phoenix>
さあ、イトノコ刑事。
‥‥聞かせてもらいましょうか。
Alright, Detective Gumshoe,
tell me the truth. What were
you listening to?

<Gumshoe>
ううう。あらたまって聞かれると、
よけい言いにくいッス‥‥。
No way, pal. Now that you've
made a big thing out of it,
I'm not gonna tell you...

<Phoenix>
すぐ、ラクにしてあげますよ。
We'll see about that, pal.




<Phoenix>
あなたが、ラジオを聴きながら
絶叫していた内容を考えれば‥‥
Considering all the noise you
were making while you were
listening...

だいたいわかりますからね。
聞いていた番組の内容は‥‥！
...it's pretty clear what kind
of radio program it was.
I'd say it was related to...


<Phoenix>
いかがですか！　イトノコ刑事！
Well, Detective Gumshoe!?

<Gumshoe>
そのとおりッス！　さすがッス！
大セイカイッス！　１等賞ッス！
Yeah! That's it, pal!
You got me.
You sure are something!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥と、言いつつ、
　ロックはそのまんま、か）
(Then how come I'm still
seeing the lock?)

（どうやら、シッパイした
　らしいな‥‥）
(Guess I was wrong...)

（ラジオを聞いていたときの
　イトノコ刑事は‥‥）
(Now, what was it he shouting
when he was listening to the
radio...?)

<Gumshoe>
よよ、よしッ！
きたきたきたきたきたアッ！
That's it!
Come on, come on, come on!

そう！　そこで《８》ッス！
カモンッス！
Now just call an "8", pal!
Come on! I know you can!

<Gumshoe>
うがああああああッ！
ハズしたッスかああッ！
Noooooo!
That's the wrong number!

<Phoenix>
（わかりきったコトだ。
　もう一度、やってみよう‥‥）
(It seems so obvious...
I'd better ask him again.)

<Gumshoe>
ま、まだ
あきらめないッスか‥‥
D-Don't tell me you're
not through yet...


<Phoenix>
もしかして、イトノコ刑事‥‥
I'm right, aren't I?

宝くじの当選番号の発表を
聞いていたんじゃないですか？
You were listening to the
lottery results, weren't you?

被害者の岡　高夫にあやかって、
デカいのを当てようとした！
You thought you'd try to win
big, just like Glen Elg did!

<Gumshoe>
あ‥‥
I-It's...

アンタは超能力者ッスゥゥッ！
It's like you can see right
through me!

<Phoenix>
（な、なんだ‥‥？
　もうオシマイかよ！）
(Huh?
I've cracked him already...?)

<Gumshoe>
‥‥だから、かえって
言いだせなかったッスゥゥゥゥ！
That's why I said it was
nothing!




<Gumshoe>
アンタと戦うために、
この再審理を担当しているッス。
Mr. Godot agreed to take this
case just so he could face
you, pal.

他の、もっと大きな事件も
そのためにキャンセルして‥‥
He was working on a bunch of
more important cases, but he
cancelled them all...

<Maya>
あれ。でも、それなら‥‥
Huh? But then...

１ヶ月前の、マコちゃんの
最初の法廷のときは‥‥
...why didn't Mr. Godot
take this case...

どうしてゴドー検事、
出て来なかったんだろ。
...when Maggey's first trial
came up?

<Phoenix>
そういえば、そうだな。
Yeah, that is kinda odd.
I mean, everyone thought the
defense was "Phoenix Wright".

ニセモノとはいえ、担当弁護士は
《成歩堂　龍一》だったのに。
So why didn't he try to fight
"me" then?

<Gumshoe>
ゴドー検事によれば‥‥
Well, according to
Mr. Godot...

『ひとめ見て、ニセモノとわかった
　から、ほっといた』そうッス。
...he knew the guy was a phony
right away, so he didn't want
to bother with the trial.

<Phoenix>
（ほっとかずに、
　裁判長に言ってくれよ！）
(He couldn't be bothered to
tell the judge!?)




<Gumshoe>
ムカシ‥‥一度だけ、
尋問を受けたことがあるッス。
She cross-examined me once,
you know.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥千尋さんに、ですか？
What? Mia did?

<Gumshoe>
あれは‥‥名勝負だったッス。
Yeah. That was us. The big
guns locking horns.

証人対弁護士！　アツいアツい
カケヒキが展開されたッス。
Witness versus lawyer!
It was a battle of cunning
tactics and tricks.

<Phoenix>
（証人がカケヒキしちゃ
　マズいだろ‥‥）
(But the witness isn't
supposed to play any
tricks...)

<Gumshoe>
おしいヒトを亡くしたッス‥‥。
I can't believe she's gone...




<Gumshoe>
あいかわらず、元気そうッスね。
You're looking upbeat,
as usual.

<Maya>
イトノコさんも、あいかわらず
つかれたカオしてるッスね！
And you're looking tired
as usual, Detective Gumshoe!

<Gumshoe>
同じニンゲンなのに、
この差はいったい、なんなんス‥‥
Yeah. That's life, huh?
One guy's got it all, and one
guy's got squat.

<Maya>
あれ。ボヤき始めたよ。
Is it just me or did the room
get darker all of a sudden...?

ま。ま。きっと、今年は
イトノコさんの年になりますよ！
You know, Detective. This is
the year of the, um... gum!

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そッスかねえ。
I-It is?

<Maya>
ええ。たぶん。
Yeah.
...I think.

<Gumshoe>
そ‥‥そッスよね！
Gum, huh? This is gonna
be a great year for this
ol' Gumshoe then, right?

<Maya>
あは。元気になったよ。
Look at that.
He perked up in no time!

<Phoenix>
遊ぶなよ‥‥
Maya...
Don't mess with him like that.




<Gumshoe>
初めて見たッス。あそこまで
しどろもどろな証人。
You know, in all my years,
I've never seen a witness
who was that confused before.

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事が
カスんで見えましたよ。
Yeah, you looked pretty
confused by his testimony.

<Gumshoe>
自分は、ああいうジイさんは
キライじゃないッス。
Nothing against old guys,
I like them and all...

‥‥ただ‥‥
But...

ジイさんは、見たコトを正直に
話しているように見えたッス。
He sounded like he was pretty
sure about what he saw.

<Maya>
そうですよね！
あたしも、そう思いました！
Yeah, that's the impression
I got, too!

<Phoenix>
（じつは、ぼくも
　そんな気がしている）
(Me, three...)

（でも‥‥それならなぜ、あんなに
　ジジツと食いちがうんだ‥‥？）
(But then, why doesn't even a
single part of his testimony
corroborate any of the facts?)




<Gumshoe>
見るからに“オニ刑事”って
感じッスよねー。
I know I look a little rough
around the edges.

じつは最近、ますます
刑事っぽさがアップしてきたッス。
But the truth is, I'm a
lot more "detective-like"
than I used to be.

<Maya>
へええ。どのへんがですか？
Really? Like what part?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥コートの色あいとか。
...Like the color of my coat.

<Maya>
あ！　言われてみれば。
Ah! You're right!

<Phoenix>
（コートの中身のほうは
　どうなんだろう‥‥）
(Yeah, but what about
what's inside the coat...?)




<Gumshoe>
マコくん、今もヒトリ、
独房でむせび泣いてるッスかね。
Maggey's probably crying all
alone right now, huh...

<Maya>
ええ。イトノコさんのせいで。
Yeah, thanks to you.

<Gumshoe>
うおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
ゴメンッス！　スマンッス！
Aaaaaaargh!
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!

<Phoenix>
やめとけよ。ココロのキズに
ワサビをすりこむの。
Maya! Don't torch poor Gumshoe
feelings like they are some
sort of cheap crème brûlée!

<Maya>
マコちゃんに《ホの字》
なんだねー、イトノコさん。
You're really crazy about
Maggey, aren't you?

<Gumshoe>
いや！　ベツに、自分はアレッス！
そういうナニじゃなくて、その！
No! No, no! I'm just...
I'm not...
It's not that I...

<Phoenix>
（ムリしなくていいのに）
(You don't have to hide it,
Gumshoe! It's pretty obvious.)

<Maya>
ううん。ブサイクなんだねー、
イトノコさん。
Yeah, you're way too
plain-looking for Maggey.
Right?

<Gumshoe>
それを言うなら《ブキヨウ》ッス！
I'd arrest you right now
if you weren't so right...




<Gumshoe>
かなりウデのいい
プログラマーだったッス。
This guy was a real
programming genius.

職場じゃ《歩くコンピュータ》
と呼ばれていたらしいッス。
They called him "the walking
computer" at the place where
he worked.

<Maya>
‥‥じゃあ、そもそも
プログラムを作る必要、ないね。
What happens when he crashes
though!? Does he just stop
moving all of a sudden!?

<Phoenix>
（そういうコトじゃない）
(*groan*
He wasn't a computer, Maya!)

<Gumshoe>
とにかく、マコクンと
接点がないのはたしかッス。
Anyway, there's nothing
between Maggey and the
victim.

<Phoenix>
‥‥きのう聞いたハナシと、
あまり変わりませんね。
Yeah. That's what we found out
yesterday, too.

<Maya>
ね。ね。もっと楽しい情報は
ないんですか？
Hey, Detective Gumshoe.
Don't you have any information
that's a bit more fun?

<Gumshoe>
た、楽しい情報、ッスか？
そッスねー‥‥‥‥‥‥
F-Fun?
I, uh...

あ、そッス！　いっそ、
彼の職場に行ってみるッスか？
Oh! I know! So, have you paid
a visit to where Elg worked
yet? You might as well.

<Maya>
岡　高夫さんの‥‥？
His workplace?
Where's that?

<Gumshoe>
たしか‥‥《バグダス》とかいう
コンピュータ会社ッス。
A computer firm called
"Blue Screens, Inc." or
something like that.

<Maya>
なんか、ヤリ手っぽい名前ですね！
おもしろそうだよ、なるほどくん！
Sounds like a real stable
company. This could be fun,
Nick. Let's go!

<Phoenix>
‥‥キカイ、
ニガテなんだよな、ぼく。
Computers aren't really
my thing, Maya.

<Maya>
だいじょうぶ！　“はいてく”なら
真宵ちゃんにまかせて！
We'll be fine! I know all
about that hi-tech stuff.

<Phoenix>
（ホントかよ‥‥）
(I wonder about that...)

<Gumshoe>
このレストランの近くッスから。
行ってみるといいッス！
It's just around the corner
from this joint. You should
take a look.

<Phoenix>
（コンピュータ会社
　《バグダス》‥‥か‥‥）
(A computer firm called
"Blue Screens, Inc." huh...)




<Gumshoe>
バグダスの社長さんッスな。
That lady is the boss of Blue
Screens, Inc., pal.

そッスね‥‥。
特にアヤシイ点はないッス。
Yeah... I figure she's clean.
She got nothing to hide.

なんというか、お人形みたいな
ヒトだったッス。
She seemed kinda like a doll
to me.

いいイミでも、悪いイミでも。
In a good way and a bad way.

‥‥そこが、
ちょっとアヤシイッスかねー。
...
Kinda makes you think she
might be hiding something.




<Gumshoe>
会うなり『アナタ、カラダが毒素で
パンパンね』なんて言われて‥‥
You know what that chef
said to me? "Oh là là! Your
body is full of la toxins."

このビンをわたされたッス。
And then he gave me this
bottle.

<Maya>
ラベルには“ジュニパー”って
書いてありますね。
What's in it?

<Gumshoe>
ゆうべ、おフロにちょっと
しのばせてみたッス。
I don't know.
The label says, "Juniper".

よく眠れたッス。
But I'll tell you what. This
stuff works like a charm. I
slept like a rock last night.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥よかったですね。
O-Oh, really...
That's nice...




<Phoenix>
あの。これなんですけど‥‥
What do you make of
this...?

<Gumshoe>
今は‥‥マコクンのコトで
アタマがいっぱいッス。
Sorry, pal.
All I can think about is
Maggey at the moment.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
<Gumshoe>
...
<Phoenix>
......

<Gumshoe>
ちち、ちがうッス！　そういう
イミじゃなくて、自分は‥‥！
N-No! I didn't mean it like
that! I meant...

<Phoenix>
（ムリしなくていいのに‥‥）
(You don't have to explain...
Really...)




<Gumshoe>
ホンモノッスか？　それ。
Is that thing real, pal?

<Phoenix>
‥‥見せると
みんなにそう言われます。
Why does everyone keep asking
me that?

<Gumshoe>
どんなヤツッスかねー、
アンタのニセモノ‥‥
I wonder what this phony of
yours is like...

<Phoenix>
マコちゃんを、ワザと
有罪にしたヤツですよ。
He had Maggey found guilty of
murder. Doesn't that tell you?

<Gumshoe>
たたきツブすッス！
It tells me the guy is
cruising for a bruising!

<Maya>
アツいねー、イトノコさん。
いろんなイミで。
You're really caring, aren't
you, Detective Gumshoe?
About Maggey, I mean.




<Gumshoe>
自分も、その裁判は
傍聴していないッスが‥‥
I wasn't at the trial myself.

知り合いの刑事に聞いてみたッス。
このときの、アンタの弁護のコト。
But I asked this one detective
I know how your defense was.

<Phoenix>
ど、どんな感じでしたか？
And what did he say?

<Gumshoe>
『あきれてモノも言えないよ』
‥‥と、前置きしてから‥‥
He started off by saying,
"I'm at a complete loss
for words..."

１時間ぐらい聞かされたッス。
アンタの無能ぶりを。
But he must have found some
quick because he went on about
how bad you were for an hour.

<Phoenix>
うう‥‥
But...

<Gumshoe>
どう見ても、ワザと
有罪にしたんじゃないか、って。
He said you sucked so much, it
seemed like you were trying to
get Maggey found guilty!

<Phoenix>
（ワザと‥‥か‥‥）
(It looked like I was
"trying to get Maggey found
guilty"...?)




<Gumshoe>
被害者がラクガキした
スポーツ新聞ッスな。
That's the sports paper the
victim wrote something in,
right?

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
どうかしましたか？
What is it?

<Gumshoe>
やっぱり、どこかで
聞いたことがあるッス。
I know I've heard that name
somewhere before...

<Gumshoe>
“くりーにんぐ・ぼんばー”
しかも、ごく最近。
"MC Bomber"...
Yeah... I heard it real
recently, too...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いつになく、マジメに
　考えこんでいる‥‥）
(Wow, he actually seems to be
thinking for once!)

<Gumshoe>
ダメ。思い出せないッス。
Ack, it's no good.
I can't remember...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いつもどおり、ダメだった）
(...And he goes back to being
the Gumshoe we all know and
love.)




<Gumshoe>
‥‥それについて、
多く語ることはないッス。
I haven't got anything to
say about that, pal.

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

早く、引っこめてもらいたいッス。
Just take it away already,
please?

<Phoenix>
（よっぽどイタかったみたいだな。
　２９８０円は‥‥）
(Spending 20 dollars on this
has got to be killing him
inside...)




<Gumshoe>
５０００万円ッスよ！
It's for half a million
dollars, pal!

１円玉で、えーと‥‥
ざっと５０００万枚ッス！
That's... um... half a million
dollar bills!

<Phoenix>
（今の“えーと”は
　なんだったんだ‥‥？）
(What was the "um" in there
for!?)

今回の事件、そんな
大金がカラんでいるんですか？
Is there really that much
money tied up in this case?

<Gumshoe>
資料を見てないから
知らないッス。
I can't give you an answer on
that, pal. Not without this
case's file in front of me.

でも‥‥
But I'll tell you this...

本土坊が、金のためなら
なんでもやる状況にいたコトは、
That Armstrong guy would've
done anything for cash.

やぶさかでないッス。
He was desperate, you know?

<Phoenix>
‥‥よくわからないけど、
なんとなくわかりました。
No, I don't. But I think
I sort of get the picture.




<Gumshoe>
シアワセ行きの
片道きっぷッスね。
A one-way ticket to
happiness, huh?

<Phoenix>
岡　高夫さん、コレの
せいで死んじゃったんですよ。
Glen Elg died because of this
ticket.

<Gumshoe>
それでも、シアワセ行きの
片道きっぷッス。
Yeah, but it's still a one-way
ticket to happiness, pal.

<Phoenix>
マコちゃん、コレのせいで
殺人の疑いをかけられたんですよ。
And Maggey was found guilty
of murder because of it, too.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
‥‥マコちゃんの話題は
やっぱり、マズいみたいだね。
...Looks like anything about
Maggey is an instant
conversation stopper.

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事のココロの、イチバン
やわらかい部分を直撃するらしい。
Yeah. He's got a real soft
spot for her, and it obviously
hurts when you hit it!




<Gumshoe>
ケッキョク、その袋の
中身は見つかっていないッス。
We never did find the
contents of that bag.

<Maya>
破れたコマクの
おクスリだったんですよね。
It was medicine for Mr. Elg's
ruptured eardrum, right?

<Gumshoe>
岡　高夫の左耳から、クスリが
検出されているッス。
Yeah. We found traces of it
in his left ear canal.

吐麗美庵で使ったのは、
まず、まちがいないッス‥‥
He must've used it while he
was at Trés Bien. We're sure
of that much.




<Gumshoe>
マコクンがつけていた
エプロンッスね。
That's the apron Maggey was
wearing.

‥‥マコクンのカオリが
するッス。
Yeah, it still smells like
her, too.

<Maya>
マコちゃんって、ケチャップの
ニオイがするのかな。
Does this mean Maggey smells
like ketchup?




<Gumshoe>
人気があるみたいッスよ。
このラジオ番組。
Apparently everyone's
listening to this show now.

<Maya>
まあ、やっぱり
ほしいですからねえ。おカネ。
That's because everyone wants
money.

<Gumshoe>
被害者の岡　高夫は、
ギャンブルが大好きだったッス。
They say that the victim, Glen
Elg, was really into gambling.

<Maya>
あたしも大好きッスよ、
ギャンブル。
Yep.
You can't beat gambling!
I love it, too!

ゆうべも、なるほどくんに
トランプで５万円、勝ったし。
I won 500 dollars last night
playing cards with Nick.

<Phoenix>
え！　あれ、ホンキだったの？
Huh? We were playing for
money!?

<Maya>
トーゼンでしょ！
ちゃんと払ってよね！
Of course!
So you'd better pay up!

<Gumshoe>
刑事の前で、ダイタンな
発言をするッスね‥‥
You're a smart one! ...Waiting
for a cop to be present before
asking for the cash!




<Gumshoe>
お。売ってくれるッスか？
このスクーター。
Hey!
Are you putting this up
for sale, pal?

<Phoenix>
ち、ちがいますよ！
N-No!

‥‥って、ほしいんですか？
こんなポンコツ。
Why, would you want a busted
up scooter like this anyway?

<Maya>
サドルなんて、ハトのフン
まみれですよ。
Yeah. Plus, the seat's all
covered in pigeon poop!

<Gumshoe>
ナニにまみれていようと、
走ればモンダイないッス！
Who cares? If it runs, that's
all that matters to me.

<Phoenix>
（ぼくのニセモノが乗っていた
　スクーター‥‥）
(My phony was riding this
bike...)

（あの公園に行けば、また
　あるかもしれないな‥‥）
(Maybe if I head back to the
park, it'll be there again.)




<Phoenix>
どうですか？
これなんですけど‥‥
What do you think about this,
Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
すまねッスが‥‥
Sorry, pal...

事件に関する証拠については、
しゃべれないッス。
I can't discuss anything
connected to the case.

<Maya>
えー。カタいこと
言わないヤクソクじゃないですか！
Hey! I thought you said you
were going to help us out!

<Gumshoe>
‥‥たいした情報がない、
というウラ事情もあるッス。
I can't help you out if I
don't have any info!

<Phoenix>
まあ、裁判で審理されたもの
ばっかりですからね‥‥
Yeah, I suppose the retrial
has only just begun...




同日　某時刻
レストラン　吐麗美庵
January 7
Trés Bien

<Armstrong>
あ‥‥あら。あなたたち。
お待ちしてたわぁ。
Eh, bonjour!
I 'ave been waiting for you
to return.

<Maya>
‥‥本土坊さん‥‥
Mr. Armstrong...

<Phoenix>
ちょうどよかった。ぼくたちも
お話を聞きたいと‥‥
Ah, good timing. I was hoping
to find you here. We'd like to
ask you a few questions...

<???>
こっちには、
話すコトなんかあらへんねや！
Well, he hasn't got anythin'
to say to youse fellas!

<Maya>
あ！　ニセなるほどくん‥‥
Ah! It's Xin Eohp...

<Tigre>
だァれが
なるほどくんじゃいぃぃィィィッ！
Who you callin'
"Zinnee Ooooope"!?

<Maya>
きゃわははわあああああっ！
Aaaaah!

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、テーブルの下に
　かくれちまったぞ‥‥！）
(Come out from under the
table already, Maya!)

<Tigre>
‥‥さ。
わたしてもらおうかい。
OK. Hand it over!

<Phoenix>
な、ナニをですか‥‥？
Wh-What?

<Tigre>
トボけんなや！
診断書よ、診断書ォ‥‥
Youse wanna play games wid
me? I don't recommend dat!
The medical papers! Now!

<Phoenix>
（うらみさんのアレ、か‥‥）
(Uh, oh... I think he wants
Viola Cadaverini's papers
back...)

‥‥これ、ですか。
“１億円”の診断書‥‥
Y-You mean... this?
The million dollar medical
papers?

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥うらみさんは、あなたを
信じていた。
Ms. Cadaverini trusted you.

だから‥‥“あなたを手伝った”
そう言ってましたよ。
That's why she said that
she helped you.

<Tigre>
‥‥クソがッ！　あのバカ女ァ‥‥
Forget about it!
That girl's dumber dan
an eggplant.

しめっぽいのは
ツラだけにしろっちゅうねん！
Youse wanna know what's sad?
I'll tell youse what's sad.
And it ain't only her face.

ホンマ、組長のマゴや思うて
デカいカオしおって‥‥
She thinks she's got power
cuz she's Bruto's little
girl... Now THAT's sad...

<Phoenix>
この診断書はわたせない。
I can't let you have these
papers.

この“１億円”を用意するために、
あなたがナニをやったか‥‥
Tomorrow in court...

明日の法廷で、立証する！
...I'm going to expose what
you did to get the one million
you used to pay this off!

<Tigre>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

アホな弁護士さんやのォ。
Are you crazy or somethin'!?

アンタにわたす気がなくても、
こっちにはカンケイないんや。
I don't care if you wanna
give it to me or not!

なにしろ‥‥こっちは、
２人がかりや。‥‥せやな？
There's two of us here.
You got dat?
Two.

<Armstrong>
ウイ。‥‥そうね。
Err... oui! Oui, oui!

<Phoenix>
ほ‥‥本土坊さん‥‥！
Mr. Armstrong!?

<Armstrong>
ユルして‥‥。ワタシ‥‥
逆らえないのよ‥‥。
Forgive me! Désolé!
I cannot argue wiz 'im!

<Phoenix>
う、うぐ‥‥ッ！
（な‥‥殴られた‥‥！）
U-Urgh!
(...That... really hurt!)

<Tigre>
‥‥じゃあ‥‥
いただくぜ‥‥コイツは。
Is dat all youse got?
I'll be takin' dose papers
now.

本土坊！　‥‥ライター、
持ってこいやッ！
Armstrong! Get that lighter!

<Phoenix>
ま‥‥待て‥‥ッ！
W-Wait...!

<Tigre>
ザンネンやったな‥‥成歩堂。
Don't take it too hard...
...Phoenix Wright.

<Phoenix>
（最後のサイゴで‥‥
　油断、したか‥‥）
(That was so stupid...
I shouldn't... have let my
guard down.)

（あの診断書は‥‥
　決定的な‥‥証‥‥拠‥‥‥）
(Those medical papers were...
vital... evi...dence...)

< >
　　　待つッスぅぅぅぅッ！
Hold it, pal!

<Phoenix>
い‥‥イトノコ刑事‥‥ッ！
D-Detective Gumshoe!?

<Tigre>
け‥‥刑事ィィ‥‥？
D-Detective!?

ダレだろうとカンケイあらへんでェ
コラアアアアアアァァァァッ！
Youse think you gonna stop
me, copper!? Beat it!
Gwaaaaaaaaaaar!

<Gumshoe>
ここここ、恐ェッス‥‥！
イヤ、ガマンッス！
Whoa!
C-Come on, Gumshoe!
Keep it together!

アンタ！　こ、この場は
自分にまかせて、逃げるッス！
You guys! Get outta here!
Leave this guy to me.

<Phoenix>
‥‥で、でも‥‥
B-But...

<Gumshoe>
いいからッ！
これ、持っていくッス！
Go, pal!
And take this!

アンタがいなくて‥‥
ダレがマコクンを助けるッスかッ！
If you get hurt, who'd
look after Maggey, huh!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

わ‥‥わかりました！
おねがいしますッ！
A-Alright!
Thanks, Gumshoe!

<Maya>
あっ、なるほどくん！
置いてかないでよー！
Wait, Nick!
Don't leave me behind!

<Phoenix>
（明日の法廷で‥‥きっと！
　この借りは、返す‥‥！）
(I'll get even with that guy
tomorrow... in court!)

（カリヨーゼには‥‥ずいぶん、
　いろいろ借りてしまったからな）
(Tender Lender is going
down!)


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
             To be continued.


同日　某時刻
吐麗美庵　キッチン
January 7
Trés Bien
Kitchen

<Maya>
‥‥あれ。
Huh?

店長さん、だれかと話してるよ。
Mr. Armstrong's talking to
someone.

<???>
‥‥来月、また来ますから‥‥
I'll be back next month.

<Armstrong>
おま、おま、おま、
お待ちしてるわあ！
Oui! Naturellement!
I will be waiting for you!

<???>
‥‥今度いただけなかったら‥‥
つけますね‥‥火‥‥
If you haven't got it by then,
I'm afraid it might get a
little... hot... around here.

<Armstrong>
い、いやだワ！
ちゃんと用意するから！
Non!
I will 'ave everything ready,
I promise!

<???>
‥‥スキなんです、火を見るの‥‥
ククッ‥‥
I love fire, you know...
I love the way it crackles...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Armstrong>
ノノノ、ノンノンノン！
やめてちょうだい！
Non, non, non!
Stop it! I beg you!

<???>
‥‥ウラ切らないでくださいね‥‥
わたし‥‥いつも、見てます‥‥
Then don't let me down...
I'll be watching you...

<Armstrong>
そ、そんな！
し、し、信じてちょうだいよお。
Mais, non! Z'is is not
necessary! You can trust me,
mademoiselle!

<???>
‥‥しゃべったら‥‥刺しますから
‥‥包丁で‥‥
Talk to anyone... and I'll
drive a knife... right
through your heart.

<Armstrong>
だだ、だいじょうぶよ。
もお、心配屋さんなんだから！
Oh, non! You do not 'ave to
worry. You know, you worry
far too much.

そんなあなたには、これよお。
サンダルウッドの香水‥‥
Maybe z'is will 'elp you
relax. It is la oil of
sandalwood.

<???>
‥‥スキなんです‥‥おさしみ‥‥
ククッ‥‥。
I do love... raw meat...
from time to time...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Armstrong>
きゃああああああっ！
Aaaaah!

<???>
‥‥じゃあ、わたし‥‥
帰りますから‥‥
I'll be taking my leave...
Goodbye... for now!

<Armstrong>
‥‥うううう‥‥。
キモチワルい！
Urgh!
I 'ave la shivers!

シオでも
まいておこうかしらね！
I must rub some of my oil
all over my body before I
become z'e nervous wreck!

そおれ。オーエス、オーエス！
Z'ere. Oh, oui, oui!
Z'at feels good!

<Phoenix>
うぎゃわっ！
Urgh!

<Armstrong>
あ、あらあらあら！
ゴメンナサイ。
Oh là là!
Excusez-moi, monsieur!

<Phoenix>
めめ、目が！　目があああっ！
M-My eyes! My EYES!

<Armstrong>
そんなときは、これ。
サンダルウッドの香水よお。
Your eyes? If you 'ave trouble
wi'z your eyes, you need z'is.
La oil of sandalwood!

<Phoenix>
さっきの
あまりものじゃないですか！
Isn't this just the leftovers
of what you were just using!?




<Maya>
へえ。ちょっと本格的だね。
聞いたことない調味料ばっかり。
Now I know I'm in a French
restaurant. I've never heard
of most of these seasonings.

“オイスター・ソース”とか。
なるほどくん、知ってる？
Hey, Nick!
This container has... oyster
sauce? What's that?

<Phoenix>
（それって、中華料理の
　調味料じゃなかったっけ）
(Isn't that used in Chinese
food...?)

<Maya>
包丁もぎらぎらに
研いであるしねー。
And look at these knives.
They look really sharp!

<Phoenix>
そんな包丁で、みそ汁の
わかめ、切ってみたいな。
I'd like to see how one of
those slices through a
cheesecake.

<Maya>
せっかくだし、もっと刃ごたえが
あるモノを切ろうよ。
A cheesecake? You don't
exactly need a sharp knife
for one of those, Nick.




<Phoenix>
この、宝のハコみたいなのは
なんだろう。
What's this?
It looks like a treasure chest
or something.

<Maya>
うわ、すごい！
小さなビンがギッシリ。
Wow! Look at all these little
bottles!

<Phoenix>
アロマテラピーのオイルか。
床の上にまで、あふれてるぞ‥‥
Oh! They're aromatherapy oils!
He's got so many, they're
overflowing onto the floor...

<Maya>
１００本はあるよ！
おんなじ小ビンが。
Let's see... 1, 2, 3...
...98, 99, 100!
They're all the same, too.




<Maya>
おっきなカガミがあるよ。
Now THIS is one large mirror!

店長さん、ここで
おめかしするんだねー。
I bet this is where he makes
himself look pretty.

<Phoenix>
机の上に、手作りの本があるな。
《クラリス・ホンドボーの寝室》。
There's a book on the dresser.
"Claurice Armstrong's Bedtime
Literature".

<Maya>
いかがわしいタイトルだね。
Not exactly Pulitzer Prize
material, is it?

<Phoenix>
これは‥‥本土坊さんの
詩集みたいだな。
It looks like a collection of
poems he's written.

<Maya>
詩‥‥？　いいねえ。
ちょっと読んでみてよ！
Poems? Cool!
Read one out!

ゆたかな感情をこめて
おねがいね。
And say it in your best French
accent... with intensity! OK?

<Phoenix>
えーと‥‥じゃあ、これ。
タイトルは“ぷらんたん”。
OK, um... Here's one. Ahem!
It's called, "Printemps".

<Phoenix>
『‥‥映画のような２人は
　今まで気がつかなかったコーヒー
"Zee two of zem, like actors
from a film.
Zee coffee still undrunk.

早すぎるささやきは悲しみの日曜日
意味のない朝は心地よいカクテル
"Sweet nothings over too soon,
on zat sad Sunday morning. Zee
foolish cocktail so delicious.

あなたが紅茶を飲みほすのなら
私、ウソをついちゃう‥‥きっと』
"Take zee last sip of your tea
and I know what I will do.
I must lie to you. I must."

<Maya>
‥‥え？　なに？　おわり？
Huh? That's it!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ま、まあ、
こんなもんだよ。詩は。
Yup. That's a poem for you.




<Maya>
お。いいニオイ。
ナベでぐつぐつ言ってるのは‥‥
Mmm. That smells good.
Something's bubbling away
nicely in that pot.

オマールえびとアワビのフリカッセ
バルサミコ酢風味だね。
It must be the lobster and
abalone fricassée with a
balsamic vinaigrette.

<Phoenix>
きのうのランチじゃないか‥‥
Isn't that what I ate
yesterday for lunch?

<Maya>
すっかりアタマに
焼きついちゃったんだもん。
Yeah, I think it's been
permanently burned
into my brain now...

マズい料理の代表選手として。
...as an example of what truly
awful food tastes like.

<Phoenix>
（ホンモノはウマいだろうに。
　‥‥バルサミコ酢風味）
(I bet it'd taste really good
if it was prepared well.
...Balsamy even!)




<Phoenix>
‥‥このレースのカーテンは
なんなんだろう。
What are these lace curtains
for?

<Maya>
でも、なんかこう、
いいムードだねえ。
I don't know. But they give
the place a real homey feel,
don't they?

こんなところに
ぶら下がれるんなら、
Hmm... Lace curtains...

あたし、ナベになっても
いいかも。
You know, if I was a cooking
pot, I'd be perfectly happy to
sit on a shelf under those.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ぼくとしては
　なんと答えればいいんだ‥‥？）
(How do you respond to
something like that!?)




<Phoenix>
それにしても‥‥お客さんが
来ませんね。このレストラン。
You don't exactly have many
customers, do you,
Mr. Armstrong?

<Armstrong>
オー。そおねえ。
ちょうどいいんじゃないかしら。
Non, you are right, monsieur.
But per'aps z'at is la perfect
time for you to visit me, non?

お客サマには、ゆったりと
食事してほしいから。
Now I can give you my
undivided attention, and cook
for you la dish suprême!

<Phoenix>
‥‥強がり、言ってるぞ。
Putting on a brave face, huh?

<Maya>
ううん、女ゴコロだねえ。
That's what girls do, Nick!

<Armstrong>
‥‥でも。おかげでお店は
苦しくなるばかり。
But you are right. Business
is very difficult z'ese days.

やっぱり、吐麗美庵の“吐”の
イメージがワルかったのかしら。
Per'aps ze name is la problem.
People do not understand it.
Z'ey think it is "tray".

“吐息がもれるほどオイシイ”って
いう意味だったのに‥‥。
I just wanted people to think
z'at my restaurant was
exclusive.

<Phoenix>
‥‥グチ、こぼしだしたぞ。
But they think you just serve
fast food on cheap, plastic
trays?

<Maya>
ううん、めめしいねえ。
Nick! That's the kind of thing
that can make a girl cry!

<Phoenix>
‥‥真宵ちゃん。本土坊さんが
オトコだって、忘れかけてない？
Have you forgotten that
Mr. Armstrong is a man, Maya?

<Armstrong>
‥‥でも。このお店は
ワタシのすべてだから。
But z'is restaurant is my
life! It is everything to me!

なんとしても！　守りぬいて
見せちゃうんだから！
I will defend it to la finale!
No one will take it from me!




<Phoenix>
‥‥あの。ダレなんですか？
さっき帰っていった、女の人は。
So, who was that woman you
were just talking to?

<Armstrong>
オー・ラ・ラ‥‥見てたのかしら？
Oh là là!
You saw z'at?

<Phoenix>
え、ええ。すみません。
Ah, well... Yes. Sorry.

<Maya>
なんかこう、
しとやかなヒトでしたよねー。
So? Who was she!? She looked
so polite and graceful.

<Armstrong>
え！　シ、シトヤカ‥‥？
P-Polite!?
G-Graceful!?

<Maya>
おさしみと火事が大好き、とか。
And she likes raw meat and
fires, right?

<???>
‥‥来月、また来ますから‥‥
I'll be back next month.

<Armstrong>
おま、おま、おま、
お待ちしてるわあ！
Oui! Naturellement!
I will be waiting for you!

<???>
‥‥今度いただけなかったら‥‥
つけますね‥‥火‥‥
If you haven't got it by then,
I'm afraid it might get a
little... hot... around here.

<Armstrong>
い、いやだワ！
ちゃんと用意するから！
Non!
I will 'ave everything ready,
I promise!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥このへんの会話を
　考えれば‥‥）
(Now that I think about it...)

（何のハナシをしていたのか、
　なんとなく、わかる気がするな）
Hey, Maya... I think it's
pretty clear what kind of
conversation they were having.

<Maya>
じゃあ。じゃあ。その証拠品、
見せてみようよ！
You think so? Well, then let's
show him that piece of
evidence and see what happens!




<Phoenix>
さっき帰っていった女の人は、
やっぱり‥‥？
The woman who was here
earlier... I take it that
she's... um...

<Armstrong>
‥‥はああ。まったく、どうして
こんなコトになったのかしら‥‥
Why 'as it come to z'is...?
What a tragedy!

気がついたら、借金まみれ。
社会がワルいと思うんだけど。
Suddenly I find myself so deep
in la debt. It is a sign of la
bad, bad world we live in, uh?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥料理のウデが
　ワルいんじゃないかな‥‥）
(No, I'd say it's more of a
sign of la bad, bad culinary
skills...)

<Armstrong>
あの気味のワルいオンナはね。
お察しのとおり、ローン会社の子。
Z'e woman who was 'ere... Z'e
scary woman... She is from la
loan office.

<Phoenix>
ローン会社‥‥５０００万円を
借りているところですか？
Loan office? Is that where
you borrowed half a million
dollars from?

<Armstrong>
え、ええ‥‥。
《カリヨーゼ》っていうんだけど。
Oui.
Tender Lender, it is
called.

<Maya>
なんか、カルいキモチで
借りちゃいたくなる名前ですね。
Catchy name. Just hearing it
makes me wanna borrow some
money.

<Armstrong>
あそこで借りるなら、
１０００円までにしときなさい！
Please! You must not borrow
from z'em. If you must, no
more z'an ten dollars!

<Phoenix>
（そんなの、真宵ちゃんの
　おこづかいじゃないか‥‥）
Ten dollars? Sounds like your
whole monthly stipend, Maya...

<Maya>
いくらなんでも
もう少しあるよ！
Hey! I get a bit more than
that, thank you very much!

<Phoenix>
本土坊さんが５０００万円の
借金をしている会社、か‥‥。
So Tender Lender is the
loan office you borrowed
half a million from, huh?

<Maya>
事件に関係あるのかな？
I wonder if they've got
anything to do with this
case...




<Armstrong>
ワタシ‥‥ナミダでキレイになる
タイプのオンナなのね。
I am a weak woman. When I am
upset, I 'ave to buy something
nice to cheer me up.

<Armstrong>
アイツのおかげで、借金は
５０００万円にふくれあがって、
Thanks to 'im loaning me la
money, I 'ave to pay back 'alf
a million dollars now!

もう、ナニを言われても
逆らえないわ‥‥アイツに。
I am like 'is slave. I 'ave
to do everything z'at 'e
tells me.

<Maya>
あの。“アイツ”‥‥って、
どなたですか？
Um... Who's this he?

<Armstrong>
《ナニワのゼニトラ》‥‥。
La Tiger...

<Maya>
なにわ‥‥
The Tiger?

<Armstrong>
《カリヨーゼ》の社長サン。
そりゃもう、コワいのよお。
Oui. 'E is la manager of z'e
Tender Lender. A terrifying
man! La big city mobster!

大阪弁でドナりつけられると、
３日ぐらい耳鳴りがやまなくて。
When 'e shouts at me, my knees
are trembling and 'is voice is
ringing in my ears for 3 days!

オンボロのスクーターの音が聞こえ
ただけで、ワタシ、泣いちゃうの。
As soon as I 'ear la noise of
z'at battered old scooter 'e
rides, I start to cry!

<Phoenix>
（“大阪弁”に“オンボロの
　スクーター”‥‥？）
(A big city mobster who
rides a battered old
scooter...?)

‥‥もしかして、その男‥‥
ぼくに似てますか？
Um, does this guy resemble
me by any chance?

<Armstrong>
オオ‥‥ノンノンゼンゼン。
もお、ハクリョクがちがうわ。
Oh, non, non, non!
Z'is man 'as a presence! A
most formidable personality!

‥‥あ。でも、そうねえ‥‥
そのトガったアタマは‥‥
Although... Oui, 'e does 'ave
la spikey 'air just like you.

ちょっと、似てるかも。
Oui, z'ere is a resemblance
z'ere, I suppose.

<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥）
(Hmm...)

（行ってみたほうがよさそうだな。
　そのローン会社‥‥）
(Sounds like this loan office
is worth checking out after
all...)

<Armstrong>
《カリヨーゼ》なら、
ビタミン広場の先にあるわあ。
If you want to visit z'e
Tender Lender, it is just
beyond Vitamin Square.

<Maya>
‥‥なるほどくん。
Hey, Nick...

おカネなら、あたしが貸すよ？
３００円までなら。
If you need money, I can loan
you some... As long as it's
less than 3 dollars...

<Phoenix>
（ビタミン広場の先、か‥‥）
Um... Thanks for the offer...
(...Just beyond Vitamin
Square, huh?)




<Armstrong>
モン・デュ！　ステキな
マドモワゼルね‥‥！
Mon dieu!
What beauty!

<Maya>
あ！　あたしの
お姉ちゃんなんですよ！
That's my sister!

<Armstrong>
あらあら。セ・ラ・ヴィ！
そおねえ‥‥
Ah, oui?
Another delight!

アナタにも、お姉さんには
ないミリョクが、きっとあるわ。
But you 'ave a certain
je ne sais quois z'at I do
not sense from your sister.

<Maya>
は、はあ。
I do?

<Armstrong>
だから、ムネを張って
生きていきなさいな。
So throw your 'ead 'igh!
Thrust out your feminine
features!

くじけちゃダメよ！
オーエス！　オーエス！
Do not lose 'eart, ma fille!
You are a woman! A woman
extraordinaire!

<Maya>
‥‥なんで、なぐさめられなきゃ
ならないんだろ。
Do I look like I need cheering
up or something?




<Armstrong>
‥‥オー・ラ・ラ。アナタ、
とってもいいエガオじゃない！
Oh là là!
You 'ave such a pretty smile,
my petite chulip!

<Maya>
え！　そうですか？
Who, me?

<Armstrong>
やっぱり、アタシたち女性は
エガオがダイジよねえ！
Oui. La smile is the most
important thing for us girls,
n'est-ce pas?

<Maya>
そ‥‥そうですよね。
Um... Sure!

<Armstrong>
ウエイトレス向きのカオだと
思うんだけどねえ‥‥。
You 'ave la perfect face for
a waitress, you know.

<Maya>
‥‥すみません。
ユメにやぶれたら、また来ます。
Um, thanks. I guess if things
don't work out someday, then
maybe I'll be back.

<Phoenix>
（ユメ‥‥って、霊媒師か？）
(What things? Is she talking
about her being a spirit
medium...?)




<Armstrong>
そのカオを見せられると、
とってもツラいわあ。
Oh, 'ow it 'urts me to see
z'at poor girl's face!

<Phoenix>
マコちゃんですか‥‥？
Maggey's?

<Armstrong>
超人的に不幸な子だって
聞いてたけど‥‥
I 'eard she was super'umanly
un'appy.

<Maya>
ちょ、ちょうじん‥‥
Superhumanly...?

<Armstrong>
ウチの店に来なければ、
こんな目にはあわなかったわ。
And if she 'adn't come to
work for me, she wouldn't 'ave
got into z'is mess.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥？）
(Huh? I'm missing something
here, aren't I?)

<Armstrong>
ジュ・スイ・デゾレ‥‥
ゴメンなさいね‥‥マコちゃん。
Je suis désolé, Maggey!
Forgive me!




<Armstrong>
‥‥亡くなったカタね。
初めてのお客さんだったわ。
Ah, la dead man. La first
in my restaurant.

<Maya>
え！　記念すべき
お客さん第１号‥‥
No way! You mean, the first
customer you ever had!?

<Armstrong>
そうじゃなくて‥‥
Non, non, non.

吐麗美庵に来たのが
初めてだったの。
It was z'e first time I've 'ad
a dead man in my restaurant.

‥‥オキノドクね。
Such a s'ame to lose a
customer after only 'is
first meal 'ere!




<Armstrong>
あら。このオジさんなら
常連さんよォ。
Ah, z'is old man. 'E is a
regular 'ere.

ウチのジマンのコーヒーと
お冷やが大好きなの。
My specialty of cappuccino and
cold water is one of 'is
favorites.

<Phoenix>
あの事件が起こったときも
いたんですよね？
Was he here at the time of
the incident?

<Armstrong>
そうだったわねェ。
たしかに、いたわ。
Oui. 'E was 'ere.
I am sure of it.

あの事件が起こったときに、ね‥‥
When la incident 'appened,
z'e old man was 'ere.

<Maya>
‥‥？
...?




<Armstrong>
こう見えても、パリのお店で
５年間、みっちり修行したのよォ。
It is 'ard to imagine, I know,
but I was an apprentice for
five years in la gay Paris.

<Maya>
へええ。スゴいですねー！
Wow! In Paris!?

<Armstrong>
そのお店のシェフのヒトコトで、
自分のお店を開く決心をしたの。
It was something la chef z'ere
said to me z'at made me decide
to open my own restaurant.

<Phoenix>
なんて言われたんですか？
What was it?

<Armstrong>
『あと１０年修行が必要だ』って。
Z'at awful man said to me,
"You must train for another
ten years!"

やってられないでしょ？　だから
帰ってきちゃったのよねえ。
Oh! It was such a shock! So
unexpected! But you would 'ave
to be a fool to do z'is, uh?




<Phoenix>
これなんですけど‥‥
Um, about this...

<Armstrong>
フェリシタシオン！
メ‥‥ケスク・セ？
Felicitations!
Mais... qu'est-ce que c'est?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥！
み‥‥、みー・とぅー。
Ack! Um...
Je... Je no comprehend...

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
テキトーに返事しない！
Nick!
Don't just make something up!




<Armstrong>
それがあるかぎり、ワタシ、
ツバサの折れたエンジェルなのね。
So long as z'at paper exists,
I am but a delightful angel
w'iz la broken wings!

<Maya>
えんじぇる‥‥
An angel, huh...?
Doesn't bode well, when you
think about it...

<Armstrong>
毎月まいつき、ギュウギュウに
シボりあげられた上‥‥、
Oui! Z'ey kept 'arassing me
month after month.

‥‥ついには、あんなコトまで
手伝わされちゃって‥‥
In z'e end, I 'ad to give in.
I agreed to 'elp z'em.

<Maya>
“あんなコト”‥‥？
Help them? With what?

<Armstrong>
あ！　借金がなければ、
モチロン断ったわよ！
Mais bien sûr, if I did not
owe z'em la money,
I would 'ave refused.

でも‥‥しかたないじゃないの！
But my 'ands were tied!

<Phoenix>
いったい、ナニを
手伝わされたんですか？
Please! What did you agree to
help them with?

<Armstrong>
そ‥‥それだけは言えないわ！
Non. I-I cannot say!

言っちゃったら、あのオンナに
おさしみにされて‥‥
If I tell you, z'at woman,
she will slice me up...

ワサビじょうゆで食べられちゃう！
...and eat me w'iz la salad
garnish!

<Phoenix>
（“おさしみにされちゃう”
　‥‥か）
(Eww! I hope he doesn't mean
that he'll literally be sliced
up and served with garnish...)

どうやら‥‥さっきの女の人、
借用書と関係があるようですね。
I'm going to guess that woman
has something to do with your
loan contract. Am I right?

<Armstrong>
う‥‥！
Ah!

<Maya>
あの女の人のコト‥‥
聞かせてくださいっ！
Please, Mr. Armstrong, tell
us about that woman!




<Armstrong>
まあ、キレイ！
イヤリングにピッタリね！
Oh, what a beautiful pendant!
It would look stunning on me
w'iz la earrings!

<Maya>
もう、とらないでくださいね！
１個しかありませんから。
Please don't steal it again,
OK? It's one of a kind!

<Armstrong>
うすくスライスすれば
いいじゃない！
I could just 'ave a sliver
of it, non?

<Maya>
ち、チーズみたいに
言わないでください！
I-It's not a block of cheese,
you know!




<Phoenix>
この新聞、被害者が
持ってきたものなんですよ。
This is the paper the victim
brought with him.

<Armstrong>
《クリーニング・ボンバー》
‥‥ねえ。
"MC Bomber"...?
Oui...

<Maya>
心当たり、ありますか？
Does that mean something to
you?

<Armstrong>
さあ‥‥ワタシ、フランス語しか
わからないから。
Non, I only speak French,
mademoiselle.

<Maya>
マガジンラックのウラに
落ちていたんですけど‥‥
But we found it behind your
magazine rack...

<Armstrong>
あらあら。きっと、
捨て忘れてたのね。
Oh, 'ow naughty I am!
I 'aven't cleaned for such a
long time!




<Armstrong>
オー・ラ・ラ！
Oh là là!
So you 'ave eaten my lunch,
oui?

いかがだったかしら？
ウチのランチ。
Tell me, monsieur.
Did you enjoy la lunch I
prepared for you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥個性的で、野性的な味でした。
It was a... unique and...
wild mixture of flavors.

<Maya>
オマールえび、って
あたし、初めて食べました！
That was the first time I ever
had lobster, you know!

<Armstrong>
オマールえび‥‥？
そんなの、使ってないケド‥‥
Lobster?
Z'ere was no lobster in my
lunch...

<Maya>
え！　だって、メニューに
そう書いてありましたよ。
Huh? But, it said, "lobster"
right on the menu.

<Armstrong>
マドモワゼル・マヨイ。
メニューはちゃんと読んで。
Mademoiselle Maya.
Please, you must read la menu
more carefully.

オマールえびとアワビのフリカッセ
バルサミコ酢風味の、“何か”。
It says, "A dish inspired by
lobster and abalone fricassée
with a balsamic vinaigrette."

<Maya>
な、“何か”‥‥ですかあ。
Oh. It's "inspired", is it?

<Armstrong>
最後に“風味”とつけてる
ところがミソなのよお。
Oui. "Inspired" by z'ese
ingredients, but not per'aps
made from z'em, n'est-ce pas?

<Maya>
こりゃ、いっぱい食わされたね、
なるほどくん。
Well, guess that's the way the
cookie crumbles, Nick.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いったい、
　ナニを食わされたんだ！）
(The way the lunch tasted,
it's probably 99% perspiration
and 1% inspiration.)




<Armstrong>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ど、どうかしましたか？
What is it?

<Armstrong>
そのスクーター‥‥
あなたのかしら？
Is z'is your scooter?

<Phoenix>
い、いえ。ビタミン広場で
見かけたんですけど‥‥
No, no! I saw it before in
Vitamin Square, you see...

<Armstrong>
オオ、モン・デュ！
そんなの、見せないでちょうだい！
Mon dieu! Non, non, non!
Take it away!
Do not show z'at to me!

<Phoenix>
（なんだ、この反応は‥‥？）
(Talk about an allergic
reaction...)




<Armstrong>
‥‥あのとき、トナリの
クジに手を出していたら‥‥
If only I 'ad taken z'e right
lottery ticket...

今ごろ、借金とも
お別れだったのにねえ。
I would not 'ave any debts
right now. I would be free!

<Maya>
いいじゃないですか。
１００円、当たったんですから！
Look on the bright side,
Mr. Armstrong. You won
a dollar, right?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥あんまり反省してない
　みたいだな‥‥）
(A lack of remorse for
having stolen something:
Priceless.)




<Armstrong>
たしかに、よく割れるのよお、
ワタシの花ビン。
Ah, it is true. My vases are
broken all z'e time.

事件があった次の日に、
新しいのを買ってきたんだけど、
I bought a new one z'e next
day after la incident.

“捜査中だから”って言われて、
置かせてくれなくて。
But z'ey wouldn't let me put
it on la table because of la
investigation.




<Armstrong>
そんなの見せなくても、
だいじょうぶよお。
Please, monsieur. Z'ere is no
need to show me z'at.

ムッシュ・ナルホドーでしょ。
‥‥ウデの悪い弁護士さん。
You are Mon. Phoenix Wright,
z'e worst defense lawyer in
town.

<Phoenix>
（しっかり、まちがって
　インプットされているな‥‥）
(I'm pretty sure I know how he
formed this completely wrong
impression of me...)

あの‥‥前に会ったときも、
このバッジ、つけてました？
Um, the last time we met, did
I show you this badge?

<Armstrong>
ウイ。こないだも
見せてたでしょ、それ。
Oui. You flashed it to
everyone in la restaurant!

<Maya>
ニセモノも、それを見せるのが
好きみたいだね。
Looks like Xin Eohp is a
bigger fan of flashing stuff
than you are, Nick!




同日　某時刻
吐麗美庵　キッチン
January 7
Trés Bien
Kitchen

<Maya>
あ、あれ。
またいないよ、店長さん。
Looks like Mr. Armstrong's out
again.

<Phoenix>
‥‥開店中のレストランで、
シェフが“いない”って‥‥
But the place is open for
business...

どう考えても
あり得ないぞ、ふつう！
You can't have an open
restaurant without a chef!

<Maya>
あ、あたしに怒られても‥‥。
Hey! It's not my fault, Nick!
Don't take it out on me!

<Phoenix>
（事件が起こってからの、
　数分間‥‥）
(Only a couple of minutes
after the incident
happened...)

（五十嵐さんは店をはなれ、
　本土坊さんは１人きりだった）
(Mr. Kudo left the scene,
leaving Mr. Armstrong here
alone.)

<Maya>
ううん‥‥ハナシを
聞きたいのにねえ。
Argh... Missing when we need
to talk to him the most.

<Phoenix>
（もしかして‥‥ぼくたちから
　逃げてるのか？）
(Maybe he's trying to avoid us
on purpose?)




<Phoenix>
（今はまだ、証拠が
　足りないのかもしれない）
(I don't think I have enough
evidence yet...)

（もう少し調査をして、
　材料を集めてみるか‥‥）
(I should investigate and
gather some more clues
before I try again...)




< >
‥なるほどくん‥
...Mr. Nick...

‥これ以上つづけると、
ココロがこわれてしまいます‥
...If you push yourself
any more, your soul
will shatter...

‥もう一度、冷静になって
考えなおしましょう‥
...Please calm down,
collect your thoughts,
and try again...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥しまった！
　シッパイしすぎたか‥‥）
(Nnrgh! I've made
too many mistakes!)
