< >
午前１時をお知らせします。
The time is 1:00 AM.

ピッ‥‥ピッ‥‥ピッ‥‥
ポーン‥‥
Beep... Beep... Beep...
Beeeeeeep...

刑事さん！
予告の時間をすぎましたぞ！
Detective!
We made it!

ふう‥‥どうやら、
宝石はブジだったようですな。
Whew... What a relief.
Glad the jewel is still safe.

きっと、ワレワレの警備に恐れを
なしたッスね！
Ho ho! You said it, pal.
It musta been our rock solid
security that scared him off!



いちおう、金庫の中を
カクニンしてもらえますかな？
Would you mind opening the
safe just to double check?

あああああああッ！
やられたッスウゥゥゥッ！
Aaaaaaaaaah!
We've been had!

お‥‥オモテだッ！　警官隊！
探照灯をつけろおッ！
O-Out front! Guards!
Turn on the searchlights!

わははははははははははははは‥‥
‥‥ゴクロウだったねえ、諸君！
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...
Better luck next time,
gentlemen!






わははははははははははははは‥‥
それでは、諸君。シツレイするよ！
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...
Excuse me, but I'm afraid I
must be leaving now!

次の満月の夜‥‥また会おう！
わははははははははははははは‥‥
We shall meet again...
When the next moon is full!
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...

わーははははははははははは‥‥
Ahaaaa ha ha ha ha ha ha...




９月１１日　午後　３時２４分
成歩堂法律事務所
October 11, 3:24 PM
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Maya>
ね、ね、なるほどくん！
ちょっと聞いてよ！
Hey, Nick!
Get a load of this!

ほらほら、トイレ掃除なんて
あと、あと！
Hey, are you listening to me!?
You can clean the toilet
later! This is important!

<Phoenix>
‥‥うるさいな。
何をハシャいでるんだよ。
*sigh*
What are you freaking
out about now?

<Maya>
ふふん。
Hee hee.

このあたしに向かって、エラそうな
口をきけるのも、今日かぎりだよ！
Today will be the last time
you talk to me that way!

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
Huh?

<Maya>
あたしたち、
ついにビッグになれるかも！
We're about to hit the
big time!

<Phoenix>
“ビッグ”‥‥？
真宵ちゃんと、ぼくが？
"Big time"? And what do
you mean by "we"? You don't
mean you and me are...?

<Maya>
ナニ言ってるの、なるほどくん。
Ha! Don't be silly.

あたしと‥‥
はみちゃんに決まってるでしょ！
I'm talking about me and
Pearly, of course!

<Pearl>
こんにちは。
おひさしぶりです、なるほどくん。
Hello.
It's a pleasure to see you
again, Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
あ、春美ちゃん。よく来たね。
‥‥何かあったの？
Pearls! You haven't changed
a bit! Wait... What are
you doing here anyway?

<Pearl>
ふふ。なるほどくん、
何も知らないのですね。
Hee hee.
Haven't you heard, Mr. Nick?

ほら、これですっ！
Here! Take a look at this!

<Phoenix>
（なんだ、これ‥‥。ポスター？）
(What's this...?
Some kind of poster?)

<Phoenix>
倉院の里（くらいんのさと）
‥‥って、あの？
Kurain Village...
Isn't that...?

<Maya>
そうだよ。
あたしと、はみちゃんのふるさと。
That's right.
It's our hometown...
Pearly and mine, that is.

<Phoenix>
“秘宝”‥‥なんて、あったっけ？
あんなイナカに。
What's this about "treasures"
from the boonies?

<Maya>
ふっふっふっ‥‥
あたしたちをナメちゃダメだよ。
Ha ha ha. Very funny.
You can laugh all you want...

今夜、ゆっくり見せてあげるから。
But you'll be singing another
tune tonight!

<Phoenix>
こ、こんや‥‥？
Tonight? What about tonight?

<Pearl>
《倉院の里・ひほうてん》は、
来週から始まるのですが‥‥
The "Treasures of Kurain"
exhibit doesn't actually start
until next week, but...

主催者のかたが、トクベツに
招待してくださったのです！
...the promoter sent us some
special VIP entry passes!

<Maya>
だからね。ちょっと今日は
オシャレしてきちゃった！　どう？
That's why I dressed up
extra special today!
What do you think, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（いつもと変わらない‥‥）
(Heh.
Same Maya.
Different Day.)

<Phoenix>
この子は、綾里　真宵
（あやさとまよい）ちゃん。
This young lady here is
Maya Fey...

‥‥ぼくの師匠、
綾里　千尋さんのイモウトさんだ。
The younger sister of
Mia Fey...
...My friend and mentor.

彼女と知り合ったのは‥‥
今から、２年前。
I first met her two
years ago...

‥‥千尋さんが亡くなった、
ある事件がキッカケだった‥‥。
I was working on the case
surrounding Mia's death, and
ever since then...

<Maya>
今は、この法律事務所の
“影の所長”やってます！
I've been the one who's been
keeping this law office afloat
from behind the scenes!

<Phoenix>
‥‥というのは、
世をしのぶ仮の姿で‥‥、
Actually that's just a cover
for her true identity...

じつは、一人前の霊媒師をめざして
修行中の、とても怪しげな女の子。
In reality, she's a spirit
medium, and a bit of a
shady character.

<Maya>
ちょっと！
ナニよ“怪しげ”って！
Hey!
Who are you calling "shady"!?

<Phoenix>
そして、この子は綾里　春美
（あやさとはるみ）ちゃん。
And this little girl is Pearl
Fey, but I usually call her
"Pearls".

真宵ちゃんのイトコで、
これまた霊媒師のタマゴだ。
She's Maya's cousin and a
spirit medium in training
herself.

<Pearl>
ふつつかものですが、
よろしくおねがいいたします！
I know I'm a bit young, but
I want to help in any way I
can, Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
２人のふるさと・倉院の里は、
倉院流霊媒道の総本山。
Kurain Village is the home of
the mysterious Kurain
Channeling Technique.

真宵ちゃんは、その倉院流霊媒道の
家元のムスメにあたるという。
And Maya here is the daughter
of the Kurain School of
Channeling's Master.

‥‥冗談みたいなハナシだが、
決してそうじゃない。
...I know it sounds
ridiculous, but it's no joke.

ぼくはもう、何度もその
トンでもない霊媒のチカラを‥‥
I've seen her power with
my own eyes...
It's the real thing alright.

<Maya>
ホラホラ、なるほどくん。
いいから、さっさと用意する！
Earth to Nick! How long
are you going to make two
gorgeous women like us wait!?

<Pearl>
もうわたくし、待ちきれません。
ひほうてん‥‥楽しみですっ！
Yes, Mr. Nick!
I can't wait any longer!
I want to see the exhibit!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ。つきあうしか
　ないみたいだな‥‥）
(*sigh* Looks like I don't
get a choice here.
Might as well head on out...)

< >
《秘宝展のポスター》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Treasure Exhibit Poster added
to the Court Record.




< >
９月１２日　午前１０時　９分
成歩堂法律事務所
October 12, 10:09 AM
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Maya>
な、な、なるほどくん！
タイヘンだよっ！
N-Nick!
This is terrible!

‥‥もう！　また
トイレ掃除なんかやってるし！
...What the--!?
You're cleaning the
toilet again!?

そんなにトイレ好きだとは
思わなかったよっ！
I never knew you were such
a toilet freak!

<Phoenix>
なんだよ朝っぱらから‥‥
Gimme a break, would you?
My brain just hit the snooze
button for the fifth time...

<Pearl>
あの。わたくし、
テレビつけますから！
Um... I'm going to
turn on the TV!

<Announcer>
‥‥では、先ほどお伝えした
盗難事件の続報です！
...We've got an update on
the recent treasure heist!

警察当局は、犯行の手口などから、
今回の事件の犯人を‥‥
Based on clues found at the
scene of the crime,
authorities have announced...

あの《怪人☆仮面マスク》であると
正式に発表しました！
...that they believe it was 
work of the renowned
phantom thief, Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
‥‥か、“かめんますく”‥‥？
...M-Masque the Mask...?

<Announcer>
高菱屋百貨店には、数日前、
予告状が届いていたらしく‥‥、
According to a spokesperson,
Lordly Tailor received a
threat letter some days ago.

秘宝ばかりを狙う怪人の犯行は、
これで５件目になります！
This is the fifth heist by
this phantom thief, who only
targets rare treasures.

<Phoenix>
‥‥た、“高菱屋百貨店”‥‥？
L-Lordly Tailor...!?

<Maya>
どーよ、なるほどくん！
Well, Nick!?
What are you going to do!?

これでもまだ、
トイレ掃除をしようっての！
Don't you dare go back to
scrubbing the toilet!

<Phoenix>
“秘宝が盗まれた”って
‥‥まさか？
Treasure...? Lordly Tailor...?
You don't think...!?

<Maya>
やられちゃったんだよ！
仮面マスクに！
Yes! Now get up, Nick!
It was stolen!
By Mask☆DeMasque!

あたしたちの秘宝が‥‥
Our most valuable treasure...

あの《倉院のツボ》が、
盗まれちゃったんだよおお！
The Kurain Sacred Urn
was STOLEN!!

<Phoenix>
えええええええええッ！
Whaaat!?




<Phoenix>
その、怪人に盗まれた
《倉院のツボ》ってのは‥‥
Refresh my memory a little...
What's this "Sacred Urn"...?

<Maya>
倉院の里で、イチバン大事な
お宝なんだよ！
It's only the most important
treasure in Kurain Village!
That's all!

ほら！　このポスターにも
デカデカと！
Look! It's right there on
this poster!

<Maya>
このツボにはね。タマシイが
封じこめられているんだよ！
Don't you remember what's
inside? The urn contains
a very important soul!

倉院流霊媒道の創始者、
あの綾里　供子さまのタマシイが！
Namely, the soul of Mystic Ami
Fey, the founder of the
Kurain Channeling Technique!

‥‥ねっ、はみちゃん！
Right, Pearly?

<Pearl>
え！　ええ。そ、そうですともっ！
Ah, yes! Th-That's right!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥あれ？
...
Hold up...

このツボ‥‥。たしか、供子さまの
お名前が書いてあったのに。
I thought that urn had the
name "AMI", written on it...

いつのまにか《子供》になってる。
‥‥はみちゃん、知ってた？
Now it says "I AM"...
Hmm... Any idea how that
happened, Pearly?

<Pearl>
え！　い、いいえ‥‥その。
わたくしは、あの。
Huh!?
Um, I...
W-Well...

ふふ、フシギなコトも
あるものなのですね‥‥
Tee hee... There are some
things best left unsolved,
wouldn't you say, Mr. Nick?

<Phoenix>
（１年前‥‥真宵ちゃんのふるさと
　倉院の里で殺人事件が起こった）
(That's right! One year ago,
there was a murder in Kurain
Village, Maya's hometown.)

（倉院のツボは‥‥その事件で
　重要な手がかりになったんだ）
(The Sacred Urn... It turned
out to be an important clue
in that case.)

< >
《倉院のツボ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Sacred Urn added to the
Court Record.




<Phoenix>
さて。これからどうしようか。
トイレ掃除が終わったら、次は‥‥
OK, the toilet is shinier than
the judge's head, so let's
see what's next...

<Maya>
ナニ言ってんの、なるほどくん！
What's wrong with you, Nick!?

<Phoenix>
な、なんだよ。
What do you mean?

<Maya>
“なんだよ”じゃないで
What do you mean what
do I--

<Pearl>
なるほどくんっ！
Mr. Nick!

イトしい真宵さまの秘宝が
盗まれたのですよ！
Your beloved Mystic Maya's
treasure has been stolen!

なんとも思わないのですかッ！
Doesn't that even bother you!?

<Phoenix>
い、いや、盗まれたツボは
倉院の里の秘宝であって‥‥
But I thought the urn was
the village's treasure, so I
don't see how...

<Pearl>
同じコトですッ！
真宵さまは、家元をつぐお方。
The village IS Mystic Maya!
She's the future Master of the
Kurain School of Channeling!

知らないとは言わせません！
‥‥ええ、言わせませんとも！
You know what I'm talking
about, Mr. Nick!
I won't let you say you don't!

<Phoenix>
そ、それはいいけど‥‥
ぼくにどうしろと？
O-OK OK! I do!
...So what am I supposed
to do about it?

<Pearl>
決まってるではありませんか！
ワルモノをひっとらえるのです！
Isn't it obvious?
Go and find the bad guy
who did this!

<Maya>
そうだそうだ！
倉院のツボ、取り戻してよー！
Yeah!
And get the Sacred Urn back!

<Phoenix>
で、でも。
ぼくは探偵じゃなくて弁護士な
B-But...
I'm not a detective...
I'm a lawyer.

<Pearl>
いーえ、カンケイありません！
That has nothing to do with
this!

殿方ならば！　イトしいヒトの
ために、今こそ立ち上がるのです！
If you're a real gentleman,
you would find it for your
beloved Mystic Maya!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥春美ちゃんの
　思いこみには負けるなあ‥‥）
(Man, oh man... There's no
winning against Pearls's
fairy-tale image of love...)

で‥‥なんて言ったっけ？
そのワルモノの名前。
...So what's the name of this
bad guy again?

<Maya>
怪人☆仮面マスクだよ、
なるほどくん！
Mask☆DeMasque, Nick!
Make a note of it!
Mask☆DeMasque!




<Maya>
いやー、タイヘンだったよねえ。
あたしがタイホされちゃってさ。
Ah, it was terrible!
I was arrested and everything!

<Phoenix>
１年前‥‥倉院の里で
起こった殺人事件。
One year ago...
The murder in Kurain Village.

真宵ちゃんの霊媒儀式の最中、
被害者は殺害された。
A man was killed during one
of Maya's spirit channelings.

このツボは、彼女の無実を
立証する証拠になったんだ‥‥
And this urn wound up being
the key piece of evidence
that proved her innocence.

<Pearl>
あの‥‥なるほどくん。
Umm...
Mr. Nick?

真宵さまには‥‥ナイショに
してもらえますか？
Would you mind not telling
Mystic Maya about that?

あのとき、わたくしが、その。
ツボを割ってしまったコト‥‥
You promised, remember?
You said you wouldn't tell
anyone I broke the urn...

<Phoenix>
ああ、そうだったっけね。
Oh yeah, that's right.

（このツボ‥‥たしかに最初は
《供子》と書いてあったらしい）
(Now I remember. This urn
used to say "AMI" on it...)

（‥‥それを、うっかり
　割っちゃったのが、春美ちゃん）
(Until Pearls accidentally
broke it into a million
pieces.)

（コッソリ修理したんだけど‥‥
　うまく行かなかったそうだ）
(She tried to secretly
fix it... Let's just say it
didn't work out so well.)

<Pearl>
わたくし‥‥工作がニガテで、
漢字も知らないものですから‥‥
Sorry... I'm not so good at
arts and crafts...
Spelling either...

<Phoenix>
‥‥で、その結果できあがったのが
この、ユガんだツボ。
...Anyway, this is how her
gluing project turned out.

破片をムリヤリくっつけたから、
《供子》が《子供》になったとか。
She put the pieces together
wrong and now, instead of
"AMI", it says, "I AM".

‥‥よく、今まで１年間も
バレなかったよなあ。
...I can't believe no one's
noticed this until now, a
whole year later.

<Pearl>
わたくしも、そう思います‥‥。
I can't believe it myself...




<Phoenix>
観葉植物のチャーリーくん。
Charley.
A quite decorative plant.

生前、千尋さんがかわいがっていた
事務所のマスコット。
When she was alive, Mia really
loved it. She even went so
far as to make it our mascot.

‥‥いいよなあ。おまえは
いつも、のんびりしてて。
It must be nice to be a plant,
being able to just sit in the
sun and photosynthesize...

<Maya>
コラ！　なるほどくん！
しみじみしない！
Hey! Nick!
No time for daydreaming!

<Pearl>
ダメですよ！
しみじみしていては。
That's right, Mr. Nick!
No time for daydreaming!

<Phoenix>
（秘宝が出てくるまで、
　平和はないな、こりゃ‥‥）
(Oh man. Until I find that
urn, they're not gonna give
me a second of peace...)




<Phoenix>
ムズカシイ法律の本が
あざ笑うように並んでいる。
Difficult-looking legal books
stand in a formidable row.
They mock me.

‥‥そういえば、うっすらと
ホコリをかぶってるな。
...Actually, I've neglected
them for so long that they're
covered in a layer of dust.

たまにはちょっと
読んでみるか。
Maybe I should actually
try reading them once in
a while.

<Maya>
コラ！　なるほどくん！
よりによって今、読まない！
Hey, Nick!
This is no time for reading!

<Pearl>
あとにしましょう！
なるほどくん！
Yes, Mr. Nick!
You can always read later!

<Phoenix>
（秘宝が出てくるまで、
　平和はないな、こりゃ‥‥）
(I guess I won't be getting
any peace and quiet to even
read until I find that urn...)




<Phoenix>
ぼくのデスクだ。
It's my desk.

あまり座る機会がないため、
ちょっとホコリっぽいな。
I don't get to use it much, so
the dust bunnies are starting
to mount their assault.

‥‥たまには、そうじでも
してみるか。
Maybe I should wipe them out
with a few well-placed swipes
of my cleaning rag...

<Maya>
コラ！　なるほどくん！
ワザとやってるでしょ！
Hey! Nick!
Are you trying to make
me upset!?

<Pearl>
おそうじなら、
わたくしがやりますっ！
Yeah, Mr. Nick! If you're
worried about the cleaning,
please leave it up to me!

<Phoenix>
（秘宝が出てくるまで、
　平和はないな、こりゃ‥‥）
(At least Pearls is good at
cleaning. *sigh* Guess I'd
better go find that urn...)




<Phoenix>
そんなに値打ちモノなの？
このボロっちいツボが。
Is this thing really all that
valuable? It looks kinda...
well... junky, if you ask me.

<Maya>
だって、タマシイ入りだよ！
綾里　供子さまの！
But it's got the soul of
Mystic Ami, the founder of
our channeling technique!

<Phoenix>
売ったら、いくらぐらいに
なるんだろう？
So how much do you think
you could get for it?

<Maya>
“売る”‥‥？
その発想はなかったなあ‥‥。
What!? Sell the Sacred Urn!?
You know, I never thought
about that...

ちょっと、はみちゃん。
メモしといて。
Hey Pearly...
Make a note of that.

“お金のたまる方法、その１０９。
　お宝を売りはらうべし”
"Ways to Save Money, Tip 109:
Sell treasures whenever
possible."

<Pearl>
‥‥うりはらうべし、と。
...Whenever possible, check!

<Phoenix>
（こんなツボ、買う人なんか
　いないと思うけどな‥‥）
(Somehow, I think Maya's
going to be searching for
a buyer for a long time...)




<Phoenix>
‥‥どうかな？　これなんだけど。
So, what do you think about
this?

<Maya>
どうかな？　はみちゃん。
Hmm...
What about it, Pearly?

<Pearl>
いかがなものでしょう？
なるほどくん。
I'm not certain.
What do you think, Mr. Nick?

<Phoenix>
（特に手がかりはなし、と）
(Maybe three heads aren't
better than one...)




<Maya>
かわいいよねー、はみちゃん。
Pearly is such a cutie,
isn't she Nick?

<Phoenix>
そうだなあ。
Yup.

<Maya>
あたしに似て、
おリコウさんだしね。
And she's smart too, just like
yours truly!

“スエはハカセかダイジンか”
‥‥なーんて。
She's got quite a future
ahead of her! I bet she
could be President some day!

<Phoenix>
（霊媒師じゃないのか‥‥？）
(A President that can channel
past Presidents... Hmm... That
just might come in handy...)




<Maya>
あ、お姉ちゃん。
また、会いたいな‥‥。
S-Sis...
*sniffle*
I really miss her...

<Pearl>
千尋さま‥‥エラい弁護士さん
だったのですよね？
Was Mystic Mia...
Was she a really good lawyer?

<Maya>
そうだよ。
なるほどくんの、お師匠さん。
Yeah, she was awesome!
She taught Nick everything
he knows.

<Pearl>
なるほどくん。千尋さまに
負けないよう、修行するのですよ。
You should train hard and try
to make her proud, Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
う、うん。がんばるよ。
Y-Yeah, I'll do my best.

<Pearl>
今度、わたくしといっしょに
滝に打たれましょうよ！
You can join me on my next
trip to a freezing waterfall!

<Phoenix>
（霊媒師の修行と
　いっしょにされてしまった）
(I hate to break it to her,
but I don't think being frozen
to the bone helps in court...)




<Maya>
写真うつり、よくないね。
You're not very photogenic,
are you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Pearl>
会話が終わってしまいましたね！
I guess that's the end
of that conversation!




<Phoenix>
‥‥どうかな？
このヒトなんだけど。
So, what do you think about
this person?

<Maya>
どうかな？　はみちゃん。
Hmm...
What do you think, Pearly?

<Pearl>
いかがなものでしょう？
なるほどくん。
I'm not certain.
What do you think, Mr. Nick?

<Phoenix>
（特に手がかりはなし、と）
(I think the saying I'm
looking for is, "never seen
them before in my life"...)




<Maya>
お。あたしのあげた勾玉だ。
どう？　役に立ってるでしょ？
Oh, hey! It's my Magatama!
So what do you think, Nick?
Isn't it neat?

<Phoenix>
そうだね。なにしろ、人の
ココロのヒミツが見えるからね。
It sure is. Being able to peek
into people's minds is
definitely a nice advantage.

<Maya>
ええッ！　そんなコトが
できるんだ！
What? How do you do that!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥真宵ちゃんがくれたんだぞ、
これ‥‥。
What do you mean?
You gave me this thing...

<Maya>
ま、そうだけど。勾玉に霊力を
こめたのは、はみちゃんだからね。
Well, I knew Pearly put some
sort of spiritual power into
it...

あたし、それでナニができるか
よく知らないんだよね。
But I had no idea that it let
you do something as cool
as that!

<Phoenix>
‥‥たよりない家元だな‥‥。
...Some future leader
you are.

<Maya>
今度、あたしにも見せてね。
ココロのヒミツ。
Next time you use it, let me
know, OK!? I want to see into
people's minds, too!




<Maya>
まだ持ってたんだ、そのバッジ。
So you've still got that
badge, I see.

<Phoenix>
そ、そりゃそうだろう。
弁護士なんだから。
Huh!?
Well, I'm a lawyer, aren't I?

<Maya>
いやー、こんなに長く
つづくとは思わなかったよ。
Yeah, but I guess I just
didn't think you'd keep on
being one for this long.

あぶなっかしいからねー、
なるほどくんのベンゴ。
You have to admit, you've had
some close brushes with death
because of your job.

<Phoenix>
（それは、真宵ちゃんの霊媒も
　似たようなモノだと思うけど）
(...I fail to see how being
a lawyer is more dangerous
than channeling dead people.)




<Maya>
あたしも知らなかったよ、
こんなものがあったなんて。
You know, even I didn't know
this statue existed until a
little while ago.

<Phoenix>
“倉院流・分家の霊場から
　借りてきた”って言ってたな。
Didn't Adrian say it's from a
Fey branch family's training
hall or something?

<Maya>
全国に、たくさんあるんだよ。
倉院流霊媒道の修行場。
Yes, there are actually a lot
of training halls scattered
all over the country.

さみしい山奥に、ひっそりと。
いくつあるか知らないけど。
Hidden away deep
in desolate mountains...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥さみしくなくちゃ
　ダメなのかな、修行場‥‥）
(Why does it always
have to be "desolate"
mountains...?)




<Phoenix>
観葉植物のチャーリーくん。
Charley.
A quite decorative plant.

生前、千尋さんがかわいがっていた
事務所のマスコット。
When she was alive, Mia really
loved it. She even went so
far as to make it our mascot.

どんなにいそがしくても、
こいつの世話だけは忘れない。
No matter how busy I get,
I never forget to water this
little fella.




<Phoenix>
窓の向かいがわには、
巨大なビルがそびえている。
There is a giant building
just outside the window.

《ホテル・バンドー》
超ゴウカな超一流ホテルだ。
It's the Gatewater Hotel, a
high-class, luxury hotel.

なんでも、となり街の一角を
ゴッソリ買収して、
The chain is getting so rich
that they bought a whole
chunk of the next town over...

超レジャー施設《バンドーランド》
の建設が始まったらしい。
...and started building a huge
theme park. It's going to be 
called "Gatewater Land".

‥‥２年前は小さな
ビジネスホテルだったのに。
...And to think that two years
ago, it was just a little
hotel for businessmen.




<Phoenix>
ムズカシイ法律の本が
あざ笑うように並んでいる。
Difficult-looking legal books
stand in a formidable row.
They mock me.

ぜんぶ、千尋さんが
残していったモノだ。
These were all Mia's...

‥‥そういえば、自分で買った本、
ひとつもないな。
Wow, I just realized I didn't
buy a single one of these.




<Phoenix>
ぼくのデスクだ。
It's my desk.

あまり座る機会がないため、
いつもはホコリっぽいんだけど‥‥
I don't get to use it much, so
the dust bunnies are starting
to mount their assault.

今日は、まぶしいほどピカピカだ。
‥‥きっと、春美ちゃんだな。
Hm? Today it's sparkly clean.
I guess Pearls must've wiped
them out for me.




<Phoenix>
古い映画のポスターだ。
An old movie poster.

ムカシ千尋さんが見て、
初めて泣いた映画なのだそうだ。
Apparently, this was the first
movie that made Mia cry when
she saw it, a long time ago.

最近、妹の真宵ちゃんが見て、
一晩中泣いていたらしい。
Maya watched it recently, and
said she cried all night, too!

‥‥ということで、最近は
このポスターを張ってある。
...Which, I guess, is why it's
back up on the wall.

今度、ぼくも見てみるか。
I'll have to check it
out one of these days.




同日　某時刻
成歩堂法律事務所
October 12
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Pearl>
あ‥‥
お、おかえりなさいませ！
Ah... Mr. Nick!
W-Welcome back!

<Phoenix>
ああ、春美ちゃん。
帰っていたんだ。
Oh, hey Pearls.
You're back too, I see.

<Pearl>
わ、わたくし、おだんごを
買っておきましたから！
I, um... I went and bought
us a strawberry cake!

今、お茶をいれますねっ！
I'll go make some tea to
go with it!

<Phoenix>
あ、春美ちゃん‥‥
Hey, uh Pearls...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
気にしてるみたいだね、
留置所のコト‥‥
It looks like she feels really
bad about what happened at
the detention center...

<Pearl>
な‥‥なるほどくん！
わたくし、見そこないましたっ！
M-Mr. Nick...!
I-I was wrong about you...
I shouldn't have trusted you!

わたくし‥‥わたくし‥‥
ゼッタイ、ユルせませんっ！
I-I...
I'll never forgive you...
EVER!

<Pearl>
さあ。お茶がはいりましたよ、
真宵さま！
Mystic Maya!
The tea is ready!

<Maya>
あ‥‥どうもありがと‥‥
Oh... Thanks...

<Pearl>
ささ。なるほどくん。
おだんごをめしあがれ！
Come on, Mr. Nick!
Please have some
of this cake!

<Phoenix>
うん‥‥ありがとう。
あの、春美ちゃん‥‥？
Yeah... Thanks.
Umm, Pearls?

<Pearl>
あ！　わたくし、おトイレ掃除の
途中ですので‥‥！
Oh! Ex-Excuse me...
I was in the middle of
cleaning the toilet...!

<Phoenix>
ちょ、ちょっと待って。
トイレなら、ぼくが今朝‥‥
Hey, it's OK! I just
cleaned it this morning...

<Maya>
行っちゃった‥‥
Too late...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いい機会かもしれない。
　彼女のこと、聞いてみるか‥‥）
(...This might be a good
time for me to ask about her.)




<Maya>
じゃ、なるほどくん！
そろそろ調査に出かけようか。
Well, Nick!
Why don't we go out and
start investigating?

事務所にいても、
手がかりは見つからないからね！
We're not going to learn
anything just sitting around
the office!

<Phoenix>
うん。‥‥でも
その前に、春美ちゃんと‥‥
Yeah, I know...
But... First I want to talk
to Pearls...

<Pearl>
‥‥あの。
...Umm, Mr. Nick?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥
Yeah...?

<Pearl>
わたくし‥‥バカでした。
I... I acted like a baby.

<Phoenix>
春美ちゃん‥‥
Pearls...

<Pearl>
真宵さまが‥‥こんなに
なるほどくんを信じているのに‥‥
I doubted you...
Even though Mystic Maya
trusted you completely...

わたくし、まだまだ
修行がたりません。
I guess I still have a lot
of training to do.

なるほどくん！
Mr. Nick!

<Phoenix>
は、はい！
Y-Yes?

<Pearl>
わたくし‥‥わたくし、
かならずや、おワビをいたします！
I... From the bottom of my
heart, I apologize for what
I said!

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。
とんでもない。ぼくのほうこそ
Aww, it's OK!
I'm the one that should
be apologizing!

<Pearl>
ちょっと、ひとっ走り
行ってきますね！
Well, I'm going out now for a
little bit.

<Phoenix>
え！　ど、どこへ‥‥？
Huh!?
Wh-Where are you going...?

<Pearl>
わたくし、これでも霊媒師の
タマゴのはしくれです！
I may be small, but I
still have a lot of spirit
channeling power!

きっと‥‥ささやかな
証拠を、見つけてみせますとも！
So I'm going to show you
I can be useful too... By
finding some evidence!

<Phoenix>
あ。ちょっと‥‥！
（‥‥走っていってしまった‥‥）
Hey! W-Wait a...!
(Ack! She sure runs fast...)

<Maya>
なるほどくん。‥‥しばらく、
好きにさせてあげようよ。
Nick... Let's back off
and give her some room,
OK?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうだな。
...Yeah.




<Phoenix>
（春美ちゃんと初めて会ったのは、
　今から１年前‥‥）
(I first met Pearls a
year ago...)

（倉院の里で起こった
　殺人事件のときだった）
(It was when that murder
happened at Kurain Village.)

（‥‥思えば、初めて会った
　ときから、彼女は‥‥）
(I still remember what she
said to me when we first
met...)

<Pearl>
あなたがあの、
なるほどくんなのですね。
You...
You're Mr. Nick, right?

あの。
真宵さまの‥‥大切なヒト。
You're...
You're Mystic Maya's...
"special someone"...

<Phoenix>
‥‥真宵ちゃん。前から
フシギに思ってたんだけど‥‥
...Hey, Maya.
I've always thought it was
because she was young, but...

<Maya>
なあに？
But what...?

<Phoenix>
春美ちゃん‥‥なんか、
ゴカイしてるよね。
Pearls... I think she's got
the wrong idea.

真宵ちゃんと、ぼくのコト。
About... you and I.

<Maya>
え！　
あ、ああ‥‥
Huh!?
Err, I...

‥‥あのね。ちょっと、
事情があるんだよ。
...Umm...
There's something you
need to understand...

<Phoenix>
“事情”‥‥？
Wh-What is it?

<Maya>
うん‥‥なんて言うか、
倉院の里の風習‥‥みたいな。
Umm... It's kind of like a
Kurain Village custom...
Sort of.




<Maya>
倉院の里って、男の人が
ほとんどいないんだ。
There are hardly any men
in Kurain Village.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥ぼくが行ったときも、
ゼンゼン見かけなかったよ。
Now that you mention it,
I never actually saw any
men there when I visited.

<Maya>
なるほどくんには‥‥ムカシ、
話したことがあったよね。
I'm pretty sure I told you
about it a long time ago...

あたしたち綾里家の血には、
強い霊力が宿っている、って。
About how spiritual powers run
very strong in the Fey family.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ああ。だから、霊媒師を
めざして修行するんでしょ。
Yeah, you did. And that's why
you're undergoing training to
be a spirit medium, right?

<Maya>
ただ、霊力を受けつぐことが
できるの‥‥女のヒトだけなの。
Yeah... The thing is,
only women can actually
inherit the spiritual power.

だからね。里の社会は自然に、
女性中心になっちゃうんだ。
That's why the whole culture
of Kurain Village kinda
revolves around its women.

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥しかたないだろうね。
特殊な世界だから。
Well, that's understandable...
Nothing wrong with that.

<Maya>
そのせいか‥‥
Yeah, but because of that...

ケッコンしても、
うまくいかない夫婦が多いんだ。
There tends to be a lot of
unsuccessful marriages.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥
Oh?

<Maya>
居場所がなくなっちゃって。
男の人は、みんな里を出ていくの。
Well, men start to feel left
out after a while, and then
they just start leaving.

‥‥女の子が産まれたら、ね。
...Especially if the man has
a daughter.

<Phoenix>
もしかして‥‥春美ちゃんの
お父さんも‥‥？
Are you saying that
Pearls's father...?

<Maya>
‥‥いないんだよ。
里を出て行っちゃったみたい。
...He's gone. He left the
village when she was
very young.

<Phoenix>
そうだったんだ‥‥
Boy, that's tough...

<Maya>
あの子、里の悲しい夫婦の
姿ばっかり見て育っちゃったから。
Yeah, and she grew up seeing
nothing but unhappy marriages
all around her.

だから‥‥そういうことに、
とってもビンカンなの。
That's why she's so
sensitive to things like that.




<Phoenix>
春美ちゃん‥‥真宵ちゃんのこと、
ホントに好きみたいだね。
Pearls seems to love you
a lot.

<Maya>
イトコだからね。たったひとりの。
それに‥‥
Well, it's because I'm her
only cousin. And... well...

ホラ。去年の事件で、はみちゃんの
おかあさんは‥‥
Because of the murder
case last year, Pearly's
mother is...

<Phoenix>
あ、ああ‥‥。
Oh yeah...

（そう‥‥春美ちゃんの母親、
　キミ子さんは、今‥‥）
(I remember now...
Pearls's mother,
Morgan Fey...)

（‥‥刑務所の独房で、
　刑の執行を待っている‥‥）
(She's serving a prison
term in isolation right
now...)

<Maya>
‥‥だからね。もう、あたししか
いないの。あの子の“家族”‥‥
So you see?
I'm the only family Pearly
has right now...

でも‥‥それは、
あたしもおんなじだけどね。
But... It's the same for
me, too.

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん‥‥
Maya...

<Maya>
‥‥あたしのおかあさんも‥‥
My mother's gone, too...




<Phoenix>
やっぱり、おかあさんは、
まだ‥‥？
So your mother's still
missing...?

<Maya>
うん‥‥。どこにいるか
わからないんだ。
Yeah...
And no one has any idea
where she is.

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃんの母親‥‥
　綾里　舞子さん）
(Maya's mother... Misty Fey.)

（倉院流霊媒道の
　“家元”ということだ）
(The current Master of the
Kurain Channeling Technique.)

（今から１７年前、ある事件に
　巻きこまれて以来、行方不明）
(She disappeared 17 years
ago after getting involved in
a certain police case.)

‥‥あの。生きているのは
たしかなの？
...But you're sure she's
still alive, right?

<Maya>
うん‥‥わかるんだ。
あたしたち‥‥霊媒師だからね。
Yeah... I know she is...
It's sort of a spirit medium
thing...

<Phoenix>
もし‥‥このまま、おかあさんが
あらわれなかったら‥‥？
And if your mother doesn't
come back, then what...?

<Maya>
里のオキテでは、
あたしが家元になるのかな。
Then according to the laws
of the village, I'll become
the next Master.

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃんが、家元にねえ‥‥。
Mystic Maya... The Master of
the Kurain Technique... Sounds
like a heavy responsibility.

<Maya>
他にいないからね。綾里本家の
血を受けついでいる霊媒師。
Yeah, but there's no one else
with the blood of the Fey main
family who's a spirit medium.




<Maya>
かなりカンシャしてるよね、
なるほどくんに。
She certainly seems
grateful to you, Nick.

<Phoenix>
タイヘンだったからね。
あの事件は。
Well, she was in a pretty
tight spot during that
terrible ordeal.

ぼくも彼女には
カンシャしてるよ。
Actually, I'm grateful to
her, too.

<Maya>
うう‥‥なんか
ズルいなあ、なるほどくん。
Hmmm...
It sounds like you're
not telling me something.

今度、こっそり見てみようかな。
その事件の記録‥‥。
I'm going to take a good
look at the case file next
chance I get...




<Maya>
ごめんね。はみちゃんが
あんなコト言っちゃって。
I'm sorry that Pearly
said what she did.

<Phoenix>
べ、ベツに、気にしてないよ。
Oh, it's fine...
It-It was nothing...

（あとで、仲なおり
　しておかないとな‥‥）
(I'm going to have to smooth
things over with Pearls later
somehow...)




<Phoenix>
千尋さんがいなかったら、
今のぼくはなかったよ。
If it wasn't for Mia, I
wouldn't be the person
I am today.

<Maya>
ホント、たよりなかったもんねー。
ムカシのなるほどくん。
Yeah, she told me you
used to really be useless.

あまりにたよりなかったから、
今、スゴくたのもしく見えるもん。
Compared to how unreliable
you were then, you actually
seem responsible now.

‥‥じつは、そんなに
変わってないのに。
...Actually, you haven't
changed that much, I guess.

<Phoenix>
（ホメられた‥‥ワケじゃ
　なさそうだな）
(Maya praised me for a change!
...
Hey, wait a second...)




<Maya>
いつからこんなギザギザな
アタマなの？
When did you first get
that porcupine cut?

<Phoenix>
‥‥小さいころから
こんな感じだったけど。
...Um, it's been like this
ever since I was a little kid.

<Maya>
ええッ！　そのヘアスタイル、
天然ものだったんだ！
What!? You mean that's
the way your hair is
naturally!?

あたしはまた、トコヤさんで
『なるほどカットで』‥‥とか、
I thought you had some sort
of special "Phoenix Cut" deal
with the barber.

トクベツ注文してるのかと
思ってたよ。
I mean... You usually only
see hair like that in a
video game.

<Phoenix>
（そんなにヘンかな、
　このアタマ‥‥）
(Is my hair really that
weird-looking?)




<Maya>
‥‥あたしも、もっと
シッカリしないとね。
I'm going to have to
really buckle down and
get serious.

<Phoenix>
倉院流霊媒道・家元の
ムスメだもんな。
Well, you're the future Master
of the Kurain Channeling
Technique, after all.

<Maya>
そうだよ。‥‥それに、
お姉さんがわりだからね。
Yeah...
That, and I have to play the
part of big sister, too.

はみちゃんと、なるほどくんの。
For Pearly... and you, Nick!

<Phoenix>
ぼ、ぼくもかよ。
Wha-?? Do I look like I was
born yesterday!?




<Maya>
倉院のツボ‥‥見つかったと
思ったのになー。
You know, I thought we'd
finally found the urn.

<Phoenix>
優作くんが仮面マスクなら、
ゼンブ解決なのに。
Yeah, if only Ron DeLite were
Mask☆DeMasque, we'd have
figured it all out.

<Maya>
え。優作さん、
仮面マスクじゃないの？
Huh? You mean he's
NOT Mask☆DeMasque?

<Phoenix>
だって、まれかさんは
ちがうって言ってたぞ。
Well, Desirée says he isn't
and I believe her.

<Maya>
ううん‥‥ナゾは深まる
ばかりだねえ。
Hmm... The mystery gets
deeper and deeper.

<Phoenix>
‥‥裁判は明日なんだけどな。
Yeah, and the trial starts
tomorrow... as usual.




<Phoenix>
これ‥‥ホンモノの
仮面マスクが作ったんだよな。
So this was made by
the real Mask☆DeMasque, huh?

<Maya>
イトノコ刑事がタイコ判を
押してたからね。
Yup, Detective Gumshoe
said it was the real thing.

“このエンブレムこそ、
　ホンモノの証拠ッス”って。
"One look at this mark
and you know it's the real
deal, pal."

<Phoenix>
あの刑事のタイコ判は、
三文判よりチカラ不足だけどね。
Yeah, but you do realize whose
deductive reasoning skills
we're talking about, right...?




<Maya>
このカタナ‥‥、
フシギなオーラを感じるね。
This sword...
It has a strange aura
surrounding it.

なんというか、怒りや悲しみが
こめられているみたいな。
It's like it's infused with
a spirit of both anger and
tragedy.

<Phoenix>
クニャッ、て曲げられてるからね。
怒ってるんじゃないか、カタナも。
Well, I'd be mad too if
somebody bent me the
way they bent this sword.

<Maya>
‥‥ま。そんなトコかも
しれないけど。
...
Yeah, I guess that could
be it.




<Phoenix>
どう思う？　これ‥‥
What do you think about this?

<Maya>
うーん‥‥事件に
カンケイありそうだけど‥‥
Hmmm...
It seems like it has something
to do with this case...

ちょっと、あたしには
わからないな。
But I'm not really sure...




<Maya>
また出てきたね、イトノコさん。
Detective Gumshoe's on
this case too, huh.

<Phoenix>
事件といえば、あの刑事だよ。
‥‥グーゼンとは思えないな。
He seems to show up
during all of our cases.
It can't be a coincidence.

<Maya>
ウンメイの赤いイトで
しばりつけられてるんじゃない？
Maybe it's a sign that our
fates are destined to be
woven together for all time!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちょっとイヤだな、それ。
Yeah, that'd be a real
Beauty and the Beast kind of
fairy tale, wouldn't it.




<Maya>
仮面マスクの正体は‥‥
So the real identity of
Mask☆DeMasque is...

優作さん‥‥なんだよね？
...Ron DeLite, right?

<Phoenix>
本人はそう言ってるけどね。
‥‥どうもハッキリしないんだよ。
That's what Mr. DeLite claims.
...But I'm not too convinced
about something he said.

<Maya>
え。‥‥何が？
Huh? About what?

<Phoenix>
倉院のツボだよ。
About the Sacred Urn.

優作くん、どうもツボのこと、
アイマイだろ？
Didn't he sound a little
vague on the subject?

<Maya>
ああ。“なくしちゃった”
とか言ってたっけ。
Yeah, now that you mention it,
he said that he had simply
"lost it", right?

<Phoenix>
（何か、まだヒミツがありそうな
　気がするんだよな‥‥）
(I have this distinct feeling
that he's hiding something.
I just know it...)




<Maya>
いやー、ビックリしたね、
アイガ探偵。
That Detective Atmey
guy really surprised me.

“ズヴァリ！”‥‥だもん。
ちょっとビビっちゃった。
There was this certain
something about the way
he said, "Zvarri!"

<Phoenix>
でも、前回の怪人の犯行で、
エモノを取り戻したんだろ？
Well he did manage to get back
the treasure that the Mask
guy stole last time, right?

しかも、たったひとりで。
And he did it by himself, too.

<Maya>
うん。‥‥その事件で
有名になったからね。
Yeah, I guess.
...That case has certainly
made him famous.

<Phoenix>
となると、やっぱり‥‥
メイタンテーなのかな。
It looks like he does deserve
to be called "Ace Detective"
after all.




<Maya>
カッコイイよねー、まれかさん。
バイクでツッ走るんだよ。
That Desirée sure is cool!
I love that whole motorcycle
thing!

‥‥それも、死のセトギワで。
あたしもやってみようかなー。
The way she laughs in
the face of death...
I want to try it myself!

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん、自転車しか
乗れないだろ？
I thought you only knew
how to ride a bike...

<Maya>
でも、でも！　電動自転車
だからね、いちおう。
Hey! Don't forget, Nick,
that it's an electric bike!

<Phoenix>
‥‥若いんだから、
ちゃんと運動しろよ！
...E-Electric? So young and
already so lazy. Whatever
happened to good old exercise?




同日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
October 12
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Gumshoe>
ウエルカムッス！
よーこそ留置所へ！
Hey, pal!
Welcome to the detention
center!

<Phoenix>
ゴキゲンですね、イトノコ刑事‥‥
You're sure in a happy
mood, aren't you?

<Gumshoe>
そりゃそッス。なにしろ、
あの仮面マスクめを‥‥
Yup.
After all, we got
Mask☆DeMasq--

<Maya>
それより、あの。
‥‥ツボのほうは！
Right, but... Um...
So where's the Sacred Urn?

<Gumshoe>
お。‥‥これは、すまねッス。
よくよく考えてみれば‥‥
Oh... Sorry about that, pal...
I guess I didn't really
think about it before...

アンタはその。
いわば被害者だったッスな。
But you're the "victim"
in this case.

<Maya>
え。
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
ま。とにかく、本人のクチから
ハナシを聞いてほしいッス。
Well, I guess I should let you
guys hear the story straight
from the horse's mouth.

<Maya>
そーだよ、なるほどくん！
You know, he's right, Nick!

<Phoenix>
な、なんだよ。
He is?

<Maya>
よおおおく考えたら、
あたしたちって被害者じゃない！
If you think about it reeeeal
hard, we are the victims!

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥ある種、ね。
Well... I guess so...
In a way...

<???>
あの‥‥
Umm...

<Maya>
いつも殺人事件だから、被害者って
いえば死体だと思ってたケドさ。
I'm so used to thinking of the
victim as a dead person 'cause
we're always on murder cases.

<???>
スミマセン‥‥
Ex-Excuse me...

<Maya>
くっそー。なんとしても、
あたしたちのツボを‥‥
But anyway!
I have to get the
Sacred Urn back!

<???>
ボクのコト、
ムシしないでくださーーーい！
Pleeeeease!
Don't just ignore meeeeee!

‥‥あ。
...Err.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
あの。あなたは？
...
Um, who are you?

<???>
‥‥あ。あ。あの。ぼく。その。
...I, err, umm. I-I-I...

か、か、か。怪人☆仮面マスク？
‥‥なんですけれども。
I-I'm Ma-Ma-Ma...
Mask☆DeMasque...?
...O-OK?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
なんかショボいよ、なるほどくん。
...
Hey, Nick... Doesn't he look
kind of... Well, gangly?

<Ron>
天杉　優作（あますぎゆうさく）
です。仮面マスクでおなじみの。
I'm Ron DeLite...
Th-The famous Mask☆DeMasque.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥イタイタしいな。
　なんとも言えず‥‥）
(...I don't think this guy
could punch his way out
of a wet paper bag.)




<Phoenix>
怪人・仮面マスクなんですか？
‥‥あなたが。
So, you're the
Masque DeMask guy?

<Ron>
は、はい！　そうです！
‥‥‥‥いや。ちがうか。
Y-Yes! You bet!
...
No... Err, that's wrong.

なんていうか、ビミョーだしな。
そのへんは自分でもハッキリしない
You see... it's complicated.
Sort of yes, and sort of no.
If you know what I mean

<Pearl>
え？　ちがうのですか？
Hm? What's wrong?

<Ron>
ちがうって言うか、イチガイには
なんとも言えないのかな？
Well when I say "wrong",
what I really mean to say is
that it's "not right", per se.

そもそも“怪人・”じゃなくて
“怪人☆”だし、そのへんをボクは
You see it's not spelled
"Masque DeMask", it's
actually "Mask☆DeMasque"...

<Maya>
‥‥なんなの、このヒト。
...What's with this guy?

<Phoenix>
（とりあえず、気の弱い
　ヒトであることはたしかだな）
(Well, he's a timid little
weakling, we know that much.)

<Ron>
そ、そんな‥‥あわれむような目で
見ないでくださーーーい！
D-Don't do that...
Don't look at me like that!
I don't need your pityyyyy!

<Phoenix>
（そして‥‥ちょっぴり
　怒りっぽいみたいだ）
(And a major crybaby, too.)

でも‥‥どうして
自首したんですか？
So... Why did you
give yourself up?

<Ron>
そ‥‥それは‥‥その。
Well, you see...
It's because... Well...

<Maya>
アレでしょ！　あまりにも
貴重な秘宝を盗んじゃったから、
I know why!
It's because you stole such
a priceless treasure!

そのツミの重さに
耐えられなくなったんだよ！
And now you're overwhelmed
with guilt. Am I right!?

<Phoenix>
（“貴重な秘宝”‥‥って、
　あのコワれそうなボロツボか？）
("Priceless treasure"?
That broken old urn...?)

<Ron>
あの‥‥おねがいが
あるんですケド‥‥
Umm... I have a little
favor to ask...

<Phoenix>
は、はあ。‥‥なんですか？
Y-Yes? What is it?

<Ron>
まれかちゃんに‥‥
会っていただけませんか？
Could you... go and
talk to Dessie?

<Maya>
‥‥ま、まれかちゃん‥‥？
...D-Dessie?




<Maya>
とりあえず、返してください！
あたしたちのツボ。
Look, we really want our
urn back, so where is it?

<Ron>
スミマセン！　かならず
お返しします！　‥‥‥‥いや。
I'm sorry! I'll give it back!
I really will!
...Err, maybe not.

ダメか。そんな、できもしない
ヤクソクは、ヒトをキズつけるだけ
No, I can't... I can't make
promises I can't keep... I'll
just end up hurting people

<Pearl>
あの‥‥なるほどくん。
Um, Mr. Nick...?

わたくし、聞き取りにくいです。
‥‥特に、後半部分が。
I couldn't hear what he
just said... Especially
the last part.

<Phoenix>
ちょっと‥‥仮面マスクさん。
もっと大きな声でおねがいします。
Um, Mr. DeMasque?
Do you think you could
speak up a little?

<Ron>
は。は。は。は。はい、
わかりました！　‥‥‥‥いや。
Y-Y-Y-Yes, sir!
I will... I promise!
...Err, maybe not.

でも、待てよ。
ボク、もともとホソい声がウリだし
You see, I'm already speaking
in my normal voice, so I
really can't do anything

<Maya>
仮面マスクさん。
ツボなんですけど‥‥
Mr. DeMasque?
About the urn...

<Ron>
は、はい！　そのコトですけど！
‥‥‥‥いや。ムダだよな。
Oh! Yes! The urn!
Right away!
...Err, actually no.

こんなボクが何を言ったって
信じてもらえるワケ、ないし、ボク
I wouldn't mind telling you,
but actually I'm afraid you
wouldn't believe me anyway

<Maya>
もお！　ハッキリしてください！
Enough already!
Just tell it to us straight!

<Ron>
大きな声、
出さないでくださーーーい！
Please...
Please don't yell at meeee!

<Ron>
はあ。はあ。はあ。ボク‥‥ボク。
*huff huff huff*
I... I... I'm sorry...

その、倉院のツボを‥‥
なくしちゃいましたーーーッ！
That urn... I...
I-I lost it!

<Maya>
な‥‥‥‥ナニぃぃぃぃぃッ！
Wh-Wha-What!?




<Phoenix>
あの。さっき、なんて言いました？
“ツボをなくしちゃった”とか‥‥
What did you just say?
Did you say you "lost it"?

<Ron>
その。はい！　いえ。その‥‥
はい！　やっちゃいましたっ！
Yes... Er, no.
Umm... Maybe so.
I mean, yes, I lost it!

<Maya>
ど、どういうコトですか‥‥？
Wh-What do you mean...?

<Ron>
あの‥‥ホラ。
よくあるじゃないですか。
Well, you know...
I lost it, like I said...
These things just happen...

考えごとしてたら、電車の
あみだなに、ニモツを忘れたり。
You're on the train and you
get distracted and you forget
your bag. You know...

<Maya>
あみだなに忘れたんですか！
‥‥あたしたちのツボ！
What!? You forgot our
Sacred Urn on a train!?

<Phoenix>
それ以前に、そのカッコウで
電車に乗ったんですか！
Wait a minute!
You went on the train
dressed like that!?

<Ron>
い、いえいえ！　今のは
“たとえば”のハナシですから。
N-No! I... I...
I was just speaking
hypothetically, that's all.

と、とにかく‥‥
A-Anyway...

すみまっせぇぇぇん！
どっか行っちゃいましたーーーッ！
I'm sooooorry!
I just lost it somewhere!
I don't know where!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（‥‥どうも、ハナシが
　アヤフヤだなあ‥‥）
(This guy's story is more
surreal than a Dali
painting.)

<Maya>
ホントにコレ、怪人なのかな。
Are you really sure this
creep is Mask☆DeMasque?

<Phoenix>
‥‥“コレ”って言うなよ。
Maya, don't call him
a "creep".

（《アヤしいヒト》というイミでは
　じゅうぶん《怪人》だよな‥‥）
(Although I do have to
admit, I understand your
doubts about this guy...)




<Phoenix>
まれかちゃん‥‥というのは？
So who is this Dessie person?

<Ron>
き‥‥。気やすく奥さんの名前を
呼ばないでくださーーーい！
...!
Pleeeease don't talk about my
wife like that!

<Maya>
‥‥ど、どうやら、奥さん
みたいだね。‥‥怪人さんの。
...I-I guess she must
be his wife...

<Ron>
はあ。はあ。はあ‥‥スミマセン。
じ、じつは‥‥
*huff huff huff*
I'm sorry!
The truth is...

みなさんに来てもらったのは、
彼女が“そうしろ”って‥‥
It was my wife that told
me to have you all
come here...

あの。ボクのアジトに
行ってみてもらえますか？
Umm... Do you think you
could go and visit her at
my hideout?

<Phoenix>
‥‥あ、あじと‥‥？
H... Hideout?

<Pearl>
なるほどくん！　“あじと”と
いうのは、いかなる‥‥？
Mr. Nick!
What does he mean
by "hideout"...?

<Ron>
あ。スミマセン。
もちろん、ヒミツ基地のコトです。
Oh, sorry.
Naturally, I meant to say
my "secret base".

<Phoenix>
‥‥ひ、ひみつきち‥‥？
S-Secret Base?

<Ron>
‥‥いわゆる、ボクの自宅です。
《パラッツォ・ペルペペ》３階‥‥
Well, my apartment actually.
Palazzo Pelpepe, 3rd floor...

<Maya>
行ってみようよ！　なるほどくん！
いざ、怪人のアジトへ！
Let's go have a look, Nick!
To Mask☆DeMasque's hideout!

<Phoenix>
（“アジト”というヒビキが
　気に入ったみたいだな‥‥）
(Something tells me she just
likes the sound of the word
"hideout".)




<Phoenix>
‥‥あ、そうだ。
奥さんが、これを‥‥
...Oh, that's right!
Here. This is from your wife.

<Ron>
え！　まれかちゃんが！
‥‥いただきますッ！
Oh? From Dessie!?
Thank you!

< >
手紙を怪人にわたした。
‥‥というか、取られた。
Letter given to Mask☆DeMasque.
...
Actually, more like "taken".

<Ron>
“ユーサクくん、お元気ですか？
　あたしは元気です”‥‥
"My dear Ronnie, how are you?
I'm doing fine..."

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（部屋のスミっこにしゃがみこんで
　一心に読みふけっている‥‥）
(He's clutching onto that
letter so hard, the ink is
going to be squeezed out...)

<Maya>
シアワセそうだねー、怪人さん。
He looks so happy...

<Pearl>
なるほどくんも、真宵さまに
お手紙を出しましょうよ！
You should write a letter
to Mystic Maya too, Mr. Nick!




<Ron>
ホント、おさわがせして
スミマセン。
I'm really sorry I caused
so much trouble.

<Maya>
あやまるぐらいなら、
最初から盗まなきゃいいのに。
If you're so sorry,
then you shouldn't have
stolen it in the first place!

<Ron>
あ‥‥でも。なくしちゃった
だけですから！　‥‥‥‥いや。
B-But... The only thing
I did wrong was lose it!
...Err, that's not right.

おんなじコトだよな。
他の秘宝だって、きっと持ちヌシは
I was wrong either way.
I'm sure the owners of the
other treasures feel the same

<Maya>
‥‥反省してるよ。
...He sure seems sorry.

<Pearl>
ココロのキレイな
怪人さんなのですね‥‥。
Who would have imagined that
such a famous thief would
have such a pure heart...




<Ron>
あ。仮面マスクの
予告状じゃないですか！
Oh! That's Mask☆DeMasque's
calling card!

ちょっとシャレてますよね！
Pretty nice-looking, huh!?

<Maya>
うれしそうだよ、怪人さん。
He looks so happy...

<Ron>
ボク、文章を書くのが
ニガテだから‥‥、
I'm not very good at writing,
you see...

『ビジネス文書の書き方』っていう
本を買って、勉強したんです！
So I bought a book called
"How to Write Business
Letters" and studied hard!

<Phoenix>
（まあ、これもある種、
　“ビジネス”ではあるな‥‥）
(Well, I guess you could
call thievery a type of
business...)




<Phoenix>
どうですか？　これなんですけど。
What do you think about this?

<Ron>
そういうのはボク、ちょっと。
‥‥‥‥いや。
Hmm... I don't really think
I can help you with that.
Err, no, that's not it...

ちょっとちがうか。
“そういうの”って、どういうのか
Well... The thing is...
I don't really know if I can
say one way or the other

<Maya>
よく聞こえないね。
I didn't really catch that.

<Phoenix>
聞くイミもなさそうだよ。
Don't worry, you didn't
miss anything.




<Ron>
キレイですよね！
ボクの奥さんなんですよ！
That's my lovely wife!
Isn't she beautiful?

<Phoenix>
はあ、そうですね‥‥
Yeah, she sure is...

<Pearl>
‥‥じろり。
...
*glare*

<Phoenix>
（春美ちゃんの前では、あまり
　触れたくない話題だな‥‥）
(Whoo boy. The one topic I
didn't want to get into in
front of Pearls...)

<Ron>
でも‥‥。
But...

まれかちゃん、曲がったコトが
キライだから‥‥
Dessie doesn't approve
of my... "interests".

ボク、もう‥‥
キラわれちゃったよなあ。
So I'm afraid she doesn't
like me anymore...

どうすればいいんだろ。
ボクがもっとシッカリやっていれば
What should I do? If I want to
win her back, I'm really going
to have to be super honest

<Phoenix>
（自分の世界に
　閉じこもってしまった‥‥）
(Oh boy, he's gone back into
his own little world again...)




<Ron>
小さいころからのアコガレ
だったんですよ！　怪人。
Ever since I was a little boy,
I've always been interested in
mysterious masked men!

<Phoenix>
ユメがかなったワケですか。
So that's what you wanted
to be when you grew up?

<Ron>
はい！　‥‥‥‥いや。
でも、これでよかったのかな‥‥
Yes!
...Err, no.
Sort of, but not exactly...

こうして、秘宝を盗まれて
悲しむヒトだっているのに、ボクは
I never imagined I'd feel as
bad as I do now about the
treasures being stolen...

<Phoenix>
（ううん‥‥ニンゲンって
　フクザツだよなあ）
(...People sure can be
complicated, can't they.)




<Ron>
そ、そのヒトは‥‥
H-Him...!

<Phoenix>
知ってますよね？　あなたの
“好敵手にしてライヴァル”とか。
Do you know him?
He claims to be your
arch-enemy and rival.

<Ron>
そ‥‥そんなヒト‥‥
Th-That person...

好敵手でもライヴァルでも
ありませーーん！　‥‥‥‥いや。
He... He's not my arch-enemy
OR my rival!
...Well, actually, no.

どうなんだろ。“好敵手”も
“ライヴァル”も同じイミだしなあ
Now that I think about it,
the terms arch-enemy and
rival are the same thing.

<Maya>
いやー、やっぱりカタキどうし、
感情のスレちがいがあるんだねー。
They ARE rivals! Only people
who have it out for each other
would disagree like this!




<Ron>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あの‥‥弁護士さん。
Umm... Mr. Lawyer?

<Phoenix>
はい？
Yes?

<Ron>
まれかちゃんの手紙に
書いてあるんですケド‥‥
In the letter that Dessie
wrote, she said...

“このヒトにベンゴを依頼せよ”
‥‥って。
"Ask this guy to be your
lawyer!"

<Maya>
え‥‥
Huh...?

<Ron>
‥‥あのお。タイヘン
あつかましいんですけど‥‥
Err, umm...
I know this would be
asking a lot, but...

引き受けてもらえませんか？
ボクの裁判、明日なんですケド。
Could you please take my case?
My trial starts tomorrow...

<Maya>
ちょ、ちょっと！　ベンゴなんて、
できるワケないじゃないですか！
Hey, hang on a second!
He can't be your lawyer!

<Phoenix>
どうして？
Why not?

<Maya>
“どうして”じゃないよ！
What do you mean,
"why not"!?

あたしたち、被害者なんだよ？
この怪人さんの！
We're the victims in this
case, right!? Victims of
this DeMasque guy!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥まれかさんによれば、
優作くんは怪人じゃなくて‥‥
Well, yeah...
But according to Desirée,
he didn't do it...

<Pearl>
“そう思いこんでいる、カワイソウ
　なヒト”‥‥というコトでした。
She said, "Poor man, he's
deluded himself into thinking
he did it." Right, Mr. Nick?

<Maya>
ダメだよ！　そんなの、
ウソかもしれないじゃない！
Come on! She could be
lying to protect her husband!

<Phoenix>
そ、そうだな。‥‥‥‥いや。
でも待てよ。むしろここは、やはり
W-Well, that's true.
...Err, no actually not.
Actually it's hard to say

（‥‥って、ウツっちまったぞ！）
(...Oh no, it's spreading!)

<Ron>
お、おねがいします！
お礼は、お好きな秘宝を１つ‥‥
Oh, please!
I'll give you the treasure of
your choice in return...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥さて‥‥どうしよう）
(Hmm... What should I do?)



<Maya>
ダメだよ、なるほどくん！
優作さん、怪人なんだから。
Don't do it, Nick!
He's a thief!

<Pearl>
なるほどくん！　わたくしも
そう思います！
Mr. Nick!
I agree with Mystic Maya!

<Phoenix>
（優作くんのタイド‥‥
　生まれながらにアヤしいからな）
(Well, I admit something
about this guy stinks like
last week's sushi.)

<Phoenix>
（ここは、断るべきかもしれない。
　でも‥‥）
(I guess I really should
say no. But...)

（ぼくが断ったら‥‥彼には
　味方がいなくなってしまう！）
(If I do that, this poor guy
will have nobody on his side!)

<Phoenix>
‥‥いいでしょう。
弁護を引き受けます。
...Well, Mr. DeLite,
I've decided to take
your case.

<Ron>
‥‥ホントですかッ！
Really? You will?


<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりました。
やってみましょう‥‥弁護。
...Well, Mr. DeLite, I've
decided to give it a try.
I'll defend you.

<Ron>
‥‥ホントですかッ！
Really? You will?

<Maya>
なな、ナニ言ってるの
なるほどくん！
Hey! What're you doing, Nick!?

<Pearl>
か‥‥かいじん、なのですよ！
この殿方は！
He... He's a thief!
You can't trust him!

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥怪人かもしれない。
Well, he may be a thief...

でも‥‥どうも、
それだけじゃない気がするんだよ。
But I think there's more to
this case than meets the eye.


<Pearl>
な‥‥なるほどくん！
わたくし、見そこないましたっ！
M-Mr. Nick...!
I-I was wrong about you...
I shouldn't have trusted you!

<Phoenix>
は、春美ちゃん‥‥？
P-Pearls...?

<Pearl>
イトしい真宵さまのカタキを
弁護するなんて‥‥
I can't believe you'd defend
this person after what he
did to Mystic Maya...!

わたくし‥‥わたくし‥‥
ゼッタイ、ユルせませんっ！
I-I...
I'll never forgive you...
EVER!

うわああああああああああああん！
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAHHH!

<Maya>
あ‥‥ちょっと！
はみちゃん！
P-!
Pearly...!
Wait!

<Phoenix>
（まいったな‥‥）
(This is going to be ugly...)

<Maya>
あたし‥‥ちょっと、見てくるね！
I-I'll go after her!

<Ron>
あの‥‥スミマセン。
ボクなんかのために‥‥
Umm... Sorry about that.
I didn't mean to cause any
trouble...

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥
そういうコトになりましたから。
Well... You couldn't have
known she'd react like that.

（‥‥とにかく、
　調査してみるしかないな‥‥）
(I guess I might as well
start investigating...)

あ。真宵ちゃん‥‥
‥‥春美ちゃんは？
Oh, Maya...
Where's Pearls?

<Maya>
事務所に帰ってるって。
あとで、カオ出してあげてね。
She said she's going back
to the office. Go check in on
her later, would you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥真宵ちゃんは‥‥いいの？
And what about you...?
Are you OK with me taking
Mr. DeLite's case...?

<Maya>
ううん‥‥あたしはね。
なるほどくんを信じてるから。
Y-Yeah...
I'm fine, Nick.
I believe in you.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
（泣かせるなあ）
...
*sniffle*
(I think I'm going to cry.)

<Ron>
じゃあ‥‥ボク、取り調べが
ありますから‥‥
Umm... I, err...
I know you have a lot
of work to do...

よろしくおねがいしますね。
I... I really appreciate it.

<Maya>
よし！　いっちょ、やるよ。
なるほどくん！
OK, Nick!
Let's get this show
on the road!




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

怪人を目の前にして、
ややキンチョーぎみに見える。
He looks nervous being this
close to an alleged thief.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile, you're on candid
camera.




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors the
visitor's room.

どうやら今は、
することがないのだろう。
It looks like he doesn't
have much to do right now.

向かい側のカメラに向かって
おもしろいカオをしている。
I can tell because he's
looking at the camera
and making funny faces.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile, you're on candid
camera.

どうやら今は、
監視するものがないのだろう。
The camera doesn't seem to
have a lot to tape right now.

向かい側の看守を
やさしく見守っている。
The only thing it's watching
now is that guard over there.




同日　某時刻
怪人☆仮面マスク　アジト
October 12
Mask☆DeMasque's Hideout

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
なんというか、スゴいね。
...
Wow, check this place out!

<Maya>
ダレがどう見たって、
怪人のアジトだね、こりゃ。
No doubt about it, this is
Mask☆DeMasque's hideout
alright.

<???>
だれー？　ユーサクくん？
Who is it?
Is that you, Ronnie?

<???>
あれー。なに？　アナタたち。
Huh? Who are you people?

<Phoenix>
あ、あの。奥さん‥‥
まれかさん、ですか‥‥？
Err, umm...
Are you Desirée DeLite?

<Desirée>
そうよ。天杉　希華（まれか）
‥‥ああ！
That's right. I'm Desirée.
...
Ah!

アナタたち、アレだね。
弁護士さんと、被害者さん！
Oh!
You must be the lawyer...
and the victim!

<Phoenix>
は、はい。ご主人に言われて、
お話を聞きに来たんですけど‥‥
Y-Yeah, that's us.
Your husband told us that
you wanted us to stop by.

<Maya>
弁護士の成歩堂　龍一と、
被害者の綾里　真宵です！
I'm Maya Fey, and this is
Phoenix Wright, attorney
at law.

<Desirée>
へえー。リューイチくんと
マヨイちゃんかあ。
"Nicky boy" and Maya, huh?

いいトコあるねー。ユーサクくんの
言うこと、聞いてくれるなんてさ。
I can't tell you how grateful
I am that you decided to help
my Ronnie.

<Maya>
いや、まあ‥‥あははは。
Well, um...
Aha ha... You're welcome.

<Phoenix>
（“リューイチくん”てなあ‥‥）
(Did she really call me
"Nicky boy"?)




<Desirée>
ね‥‥。ちょっといいかな、
リューイチくん。
Say... Can I ask you
something, Nicky boy?

<Phoenix>
なんですか？
What is it?

<Desirée>
アタシね。たしかに、
イイカゲンな女だけどさ。
I know I may seem like a
"bad girl" on the outside...

曲がったコトだけは、
ガマンできないんだよねー。
But the one thing I won't
stand for is illegal activity.

<Maya>
そんな感じですよね！
なんか、“アネゴ”みたいな。
I had the feeling you didn't!
You're tough... But I can tell
you've got a good heart.

<Desirée>
だれかが、ユーサクくんを
ワナにかけたんだよ。
Somebody framed my poor
Ronnie, I just know it.

あの‥‥これ。ユーサクくんに
わたしてくれないかな。
Umm...
Could you give this to
Ronnie for me?

<Maya>
お手紙、ですか‥‥？
A letter?

<Desirée>
ユーサクくんにね。
たたかってもらいたいんだ。
Yes, for Ronnie.
I want him to fight back.

<Maya>
まれかさん‥‥
Ms. DeLite...

<Maya>
わかりました！　安心して、
あたしたちにまかせてください！
OK, you've got it!
Just relax and leave
it all to us!

< >
《希華の手紙》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Desirée's Letter added to
the Court Record.




<Maya>
これ‥‥仮面マスクだよ！
It's Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
ムネに、テープレコーダーが
ブラさがっているな。
There's a tape recorder
hanging from his neck.

<Maya>
どれどれ。いじってみよう！
Let me see that!

< >
　　　　　‥‥カチ‥‥
...click...

<DeMasque>
わははははははははははははは‥‥
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...

‥‥ゴクロウだったねえ、諸君。
宝冠はいただいて行くよ‥‥
I'll be taking this crown now!
Better luck next time,
gentlemen!

わーははははははははははは‥‥
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha...

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

これはどういうコトかな、
なるほどくん。
I don't get it...
What's this supposed to
be, Nick?




<Maya>
きゃあ、カワイイ！
これ、気球っていうんだよ！
Oh, that's so cute!
It's called a hot air balloon,
you know!

<Phoenix>
‥‥さすがに知ってるよ。
...Wow!
There's no fooling you!

<Maya>
あたしも
作ってみようかなー、気球。
I want to make my own
balloon now!

なるほどくんも
乗せてあげるからね！
I'll even let you ride in it,
Nick!

<Phoenix>
（気球には、ゴクヒのはずの
　エンブレムがプリントされてる）
(That emblem on the balloon is
supposed to be top-secret.)

（‥‥天杉　優作が仮面マスクで
　あるという証拠だ）
(That's proof enough that
Ron DeLite really is
Mask☆DeMasque.)

（真宵ちゃんにはダマっておこう。
　‥‥コワいから）
(I'd better not tell Maya.
She gets kinda... scary when
it comes to "celebrities"...)




<Maya>
ね、なるほどくん。
イスの上、見てよ！
Hey, Nick!
Look on top of the chair!

<Phoenix>
ああ。封筒と‥‥手紙があるね。
Looks like an envelope...
And a letter.

<Maya>
ほらほら。
ちょっと読んでみようよ。
Well, don't just stand there!
Come on, let's read it!

<Phoenix>
いやいや、マズいだろ、
さすがに。
Maya, you know we
shouldn't do that!

<Maya>
ナニ言ってんの。‥‥ものスゴく
重要な手がかりかもしれないよ！
What are you talking about?
That letter could be an
important clue!

<Phoenix>
ダメだよ。オモシロ半分に
ヒトの手紙を読むなんて。
No way. You can't just go
reading a private letter
because you feel like it.

<Maya>
‥‥ちぇ。オモシロ半分だけど、
もう半分はマジメなのにな。
...Hmph! It's not just because
I "feel like it". It really
could be important!

<Phoenix>
（ハッキリ“手がかりだ”と
　わかれば、話もちがうけど‥‥）
(If I was sure it was a clue,
I guess I wouldn't mind...)




<Phoenix>
中途ハンパなヘンソウ道具が
ガクに入ってかざられている。
It's a bunch of cheap costume
pieces arranged inside a nice
frame.

<Maya>
つ、つけヒゲだよ
なるほどくん！
L-Look, Nick!
It's a fake beard!

<Phoenix>
厚紙を切りぬいた
仮面もあるぞ‥‥
There's also a mask made
out of cardboard...

<Maya>
ほらほら、なるほどくん。
つけヒゲつけヒゲ！
Here, Nick!
Try on this fake beard!
Come on! Try it on!

<Phoenix>
う、うわ！
ナニするんだよ‥‥
H-Hey!
Cut it out...

<Maya>
ついでにマスクも
かぶるかぶる！
Now put on the mask!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あはははははははは！
怪人なるほどくんだ！
Aha ha ha ha ha ha!
It's Phoenix☆DeMasque!

しばらく借りておこうよ。
Let's borrow it for a while.

<Phoenix>
（やだよ！）
(No way! I'm not stealing
from a thief! I have enough
bad karma as is!)




<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんか、どこかで
　見たことがあるような気がする）
(Hmmm... This thing looks
vaguely familiar.)

<Maya>
あ！　金魚ばちがあるよ。
逆さまだけど。
Oh, I know! It's a fishbowl!
Well, an upside-down one,
anyway...

<Phoenix>
ヘルメットかもしれないよ。
‥‥宇宙人の。
I think it's a helmet.
...An alien helmet.

<Maya>
となりにあるのは、
テープレコーダーかな。
And that looks like a tape
recorder or something next
to it.

<Phoenix>
通信機かもしれないよ。
‥‥宇宙人の。
I think it's a transceiver.
...An alien transceiver.

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
Nick...

きちんと現実を見つめて、
オトナになろうよ。
Do you think maybe you
could act like a grown-up
for a little bit?

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃんに意見された）
(Getting lectured by Maya
to be more of an adult.
That's a new low...)




<Phoenix>
ゴチャゴチャと
いろいろ置いてある。
There's a whole bunch of
stuff piled up over here.

<Maya>
み、ミサイルに
ダイナマイトがあるよ！
Duck and cover! It-It's a
missile! Did you know there's
d-dynamite in missiles!?

<Phoenix>
この、不吉な重量感‥‥
お、オモチャだよ。よくできた。
But they're not heavy enough
to be real... Oh wait. They're
just really well-made toys.

<Maya>
こっちの、ゴミ箱にささっている
巻きものはナニかな？
What are these rolls of paper
stuck in the trash can?

《マザリンの宝石強奪
　アルバトロス大作戦の巻》
"Theft of the Mazarin Stone:
The Great Albatross Strategy"

《不死身の女神像強奪
　ナックルボンバー大作戦の巻》
"Theft of the Immortal
Goddess Statue: The Great
Knucklebomber Strategy"

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（警察の人たち、ここは
　捜査したのかな‥‥）
(Did the police even
investigate this place...?)




<Phoenix>
本がドンとつんである。
かなりあるな。
There are a bunch of books
lying here.

‥‥怪人やら怪盗やらが
カツヤクする小説ばかりだ。
They're all romantic-sounding
novels about famous heists and
fantastic thieves.

<Maya>
しおりやメモがいっぱい
はさんであるよ。
Wow! Look at all the bookmarks
and notes stuck into them!

<Phoenix>
どれどれ。
Let's see here...

《注意：この怪人の笑いかたを
　参考にすること》
"Note: Must remember this
thief's way of laughing.
Very useful."

《注意：やっぱり、予告状は
　怪人としてのエチケット》
"Note: A calling card is an
important part of any good
thief's modus operandi!"

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
べ、勉強ネッシンだね。
‥‥優作くん。
W-Wow, Ron really
studied his stuff!




<Maya>
ぎょ‥‥魚雷があるよ、
なるほどくん！
Nick! It-It's a torpedo!

<Phoenix>
‥‥信じがたいけど、
ホンモノっぽいぞ、コレ。
...It's hard to believe,
but it sure looks real.

<Maya>
まったく‥‥どこから
拾ってくるのかな、こんなの。
Where could he have picked
up something like this?

<Phoenix>
落としモノみたいに言うなよ。
Please don't say that
torpedoes are things people
just leave lying around.




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥ご主人ですけど。
Umm, about your husband...

<Desirée>
ふふっ。カワイイでしょ？
ちょっぴり、たよりないけど。
Hee hee, isn't he the cutest?
A bit weak sometimes though...

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちょっぴり、ね。
..."A bit"?

<Desirée>
あのね。テレビでマヨイちゃんの
コト、紹介してたんだよ。
By the way, did you know
they mentioned Maya on TV?

<Maya>
え！　ホントですか！
Huh? Really!?

<Desirée>
ツボの持ち主で、弁護士事務所で
怪しげな修行をしている、って。
They said you own the urn and
that you're doing some shady
training at a law office now.

<Phoenix>
（情報がコンランしているな‥‥）
(Remind me not to watch
that channel's news program.)

<Desirée>
せっかくだから、その弁護士さんに
会ってみよう、って思ったんだ。
After I saw that, I thought it
might be a good idea to meet
the lawyer they mentioned.

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
...I see.

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、思いこみが
はげしくてさー。
My Ronnie... He has a powerful
imagination and gets deluded
easily.

どうしても自首するって
聞かなくて。コマっちゃったよ。
He kept insisting he was going
to surrender to the police.
I didn't know what to do!

『あのツボは、ぼくが
　盗んだんだー！』‥‥なんて。
"It was me! I stole that
urn!" he kept saying!
As if it was even possible!

<Maya>
え‥‥？　で、でも‥‥
ツボは優作さんが‥‥その。
Huh...?
B-But...
Are you saying he didn't?

<Desirée>
あははははは。
そんなワケないじゃない。
Ha ha ha.
Of course he didn't!

どうしてユーサクくんが
そんなもの、盗むの？
Why would my Ronnie ever
do something like that?

<Maya>
だ、だってそれは‥‥その。
アレじゃないですか！
W-Well, you know...
It's a p-priceless treasure!
And-And he's... You know...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんだ？　もしかして、
　知らないのか？　ご主人の正体）
(...Is it possible his own
wife doesn't know his
secret identity?)




<Desirée>
アタシね。スリルがないと
ダメなオンナなんだよねー。
Me? I'm the kind of woman
that needs excitement in
her life!

<Maya>
はああ‥‥すりる、ですか。
Oh... Excitement, huh?

<Desirée>
バイクを飛ばしてるときがね。
アタシ、最高にシアワセだな。
Yes. I'm at my happiest when
I'm racing along with my bike
going at full throttle.

‥‥ホラ。バイクって、つねに
死ぬセトギワでツッ走るじゃない？
Riding a motorcycle is like
putting your life on the line.
You know what I mean?

<Phoenix>
（それは、乗りかたに
　よると思うけど‥‥）
(Well, I think that depends
on how you ride it...)

<Desirée>
タイクツな毎日が
何よりニガテなんだ。アタシ。
I'm the type that can't stand
living a boring, dreary old
life with no action.

<Maya>
でも‥‥優作さん、スリルが
好きそうには見えなかったなあ。
No offense, but your husband,
Ron, doesn't exactly look like
the risk-taking type himself.

<Desirée>
あー、たしかに。彼にスリルを
求めるのはムリだけどね。
You're right about that.
He's definitely not one for
thrills and danger.

でもね。ちゃーんと、
かわりのモノをくれるから。
But I do have to say that he
makes up for it in other ways.

<Phoenix>
かわりのモノ‥‥って？
Other ways...?

<Desirée>
おカネ。‥‥ユーサクくん、
フシギにお金持ちなんだよ。
Yes, money...
Ronnie is incredibly rich...
And super generous.

目玉が飛び出るほど
スピードの出るバイクを買って、
He bought me a bike that's
so fast it would make your
head spin.

目玉が飛び出るほど高い
ショッピングをするのが好き。
And shopping?
I like to shop so much it
makes Ron's head spin.

ユーサクくん、こないだ
ホントに飛びだしてたもん。目玉。
The other day, it actually
happened. His head actually
started to spin.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥かなり燃費のワルい
　奥さんだな‥‥）
(Man, talk about a high
maintenance wife...)

<Maya>
優作さん‥‥そんなお金、
どうやってかせいでるんですか？
So where does Mr. DeLite
get all this money from?

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、警備員なんだよ。
死ぬセトギワではたらいてるから。
Ronnie is a security guard.
They put their lives on the
line, right?

そりゃあ、お金ぐらい
もらわないとねー。がっぽり。
So they get paid tons of
money in return. Tons of it.

<Phoenix>
（ケイビイン‥‥似合わないなあ）
(He's a security guard...?
I think it's my turn for my
head to spin...)




<Phoenix>
ゆうべのコトを
聞かせてもらえますか？
Can you tell us about what
happened last night?

<Desirée>
その事件が起こったの、
何時ごろかな。
Hmm, what time did that
incident take place again?

<Phoenix>
何時だっけ？　真宵ちゃん。
What time was it again, Maya?

<Maya>
イトノコさんの話では、たしか
午前１時３０分‥‥だったよ。
Well, according to Detective
Gumshoe, it was around 1:30
in the morning.

<Desirée>
やー、ゆうべはヤバかったなー。
つかまっちゃってさあ。
Ah, last night was horrible.
I got pulled over!

<Maya>
つつ、つかまった？
P-Pulled over?

<Desirée>
アタシね、夜はいつも
飛ばすことにしてるんだけど。
Yes... I always do my best
flying at night!

<Phoenix>
“飛ばす”‥‥って、
バイクですか、やっぱり。
"Flying"...?
Um, you're talking about
your motorcycle, right?

<Desirée>
追いつかれちゃったんだよねー。
ゆうべは、おまわりさんに。
Yes. Anyway, last night I got
pulled over. By a policeman.

あれはなかなか、アツい
レースだったよ。
I can't believe he caught
up to me! It was a great
chase, let me tell you!

おまわりさん、死にそうな
カオ、してたもん。
When he finally caught me,
the poor man was as white
as a sheet.

帰ってきたら、夜中の３時
すぎてたっけ。
It was about three in the
morning when I finally got
home.

<Phoenix>
（アリバイはバッチリ、か）
(Sounds like she's got
an airtight alibi...)

<Maya>
あの。優作さんのほうは‥‥？
Well, what about Mr. DeLite?

<Desirée>
さー。ゆうべは
いっしょじゃなかったからなあ。
I don't really know...
We weren't together at
that time of the night.

帰ってきたら、
さすがにもう、寝てたけど。
But when I got home, he
was already fast asleep.

<Phoenix>
（こっちはアリバイなし、か‥‥）
(So basically he's
got no alibi...)




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥優作さんは、
怪人☆仮面マスクでは‥‥？
So... When did Ron first
become Mask☆DeMasque?

<Desirée>
ナニ言ってんの、リューイチくん。
そんなワケ、ないじゃない！
What are you talking about?
He's not Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ‥‥。
い、いやいや！　待ってください！
Huh? But...
W-Wait a second!

だって、この部屋は、どう見たって
怪人のアジトふう‥‥
Look around at this room!
This place is obviously
Mask☆DeMasque's hideout...

<Desirée>
逆だよ、ギャク。
No no, you're totally wrong.

ホンモノの怪人が、こんな
バカな部屋に住んでると思う？
A real thief's hideout
wouldn't look like this!

ユーサクくん、気が弱いから。
アコガレが強いんだ。ヒーローに。
It's because Ronnie is so
timid himself that he looks
up to heroic figures.

<Maya>
ひーろー‥‥って、
ワルモノですよ？　仮面マスク。
Heroic figures?
But Mask☆DeMasque is a
bad guy.

<Phoenix>
（“思いこみ”‥‥
　ホントにそうなんだろうか‥‥）
(So he's "deluded", huh...
Could that really be true?)

<Desirée>
だって、彼が盗んだのなら、
持ってるハズだよね？　そのツボ。
Anyway, if he really had
stolen the urn, wouldn't he
still have it?

<Phoenix>
ま、まあ‥‥そうなんですけど。
W-Well, I suppose so...

<Desirée>
ユーサクくんに聞いてみなよ。
‥‥盗んだツボのありか。
Then why don't you ask him
if he has the urn or not?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥たしかに‥‥、どうも
　シックリこないんだよな）
(She has a point. Mr. DeLite
isn't exactly the criminal
type...)

（優作くんの、あのタイド‥‥）
(But something about Ron's
behavior bothers me.)

<Maya>
やっぱり‥‥怪人じゃないかも
しれないね、優作さん。
Maybe it's true...
Maybe Mr. DeLite isn't
Mask☆DeMasque after all.




<Desirée>
たよりなさそうに見えるけどねー。
I know he doesn't look it...

これでも、やるときは
ビシッとやるんだよ。
But he can really get things
done when he puts his mind
to it.

<Maya>
へえ！　いつなんですか？
その“やるとき”って。
Really? So when exactly does
he put his mind to it?

<Desirée>
‥‥まあ。
めったにないけど。
...Well.
Not very often, I admit.

<Phoenix>
（まれかさん‥‥優作くんの
　どこにホレたのかな）
(What exactly does Ms. DeLite
see in her husband anyway?)

<Maya>
きっと、ドラマティックな
出会いがあったんだよ！
Wow, you must've really seen
skyrockets when you first
met to love him so much!

<Phoenix>
“ティック”と来たか‥‥
Skyrockets...?
I didn't know people still
used that word.




<Phoenix>
‥‥あの、まれかさん。
もちろん、知ってますよね？
...Um, Ms. DeLite.
You must know, right?

ご主人‥‥優作さんが、
あの怪人☆仮面マスクだ、って。
About your husband and
Mask☆DeMasque...

<Desirée>
ああ。仮面マスクでしょ？
知ってるよー、モチロン。
Mask☆DeMasque? Of course.
I know all about it.

大ファンだからね、
ユーサクくん。
My husband is his biggest fan.

<Maya>
そうですよねー。
‥‥え？
Yup... Wha...?
...Huh?

<Phoenix>
だいふぁん‥‥？
B-Biggest fan?

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、思いこみが
はげしいからさ。
Yes, and Ronnie can be pretty
delusional sometimes.

こんな騒ぎになっちゃって。
That's how this whole
misunderstanding happened.

<Phoenix>
ちょ、ちょっと待ってください！
“思いこみ”というのは‥‥？
W-Wait a minute!
Did you say "delusional"!?

<Desirée>
それなんだよねー。ホント
コマってるんだ、アタシ。
Yes, that's right.
I just don't know what I'm
going to do with him...

ユーサクくん、自分が仮面マスク
だと思いこんじゃって。
You see, Ronnie actually
believes that HE is
Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
な‥‥<Maya>
なにィィィィィィィッ！
<Phoenix>
WH<Maya>
-WHAAAAT!?

<Maya>
く、詳しく話を聞かせてください！
What are you talking about!?

< >



<Desirée>
たいしたもんだよねー、
その若さで家元なんてさ。
That's really amazing!
A "Master" at your age!

<Maya>
い、いえいえ。今の家元は、
あたしのおかあさんなんですけど。
Oh no, you've got it wrong.
It's my mother that's the
current Master!

<Desirée>
あ。そうなんだ。
‥‥ところでさ。なんの家元？
Oh, I see...
So what exactly is she the
master of anyway?

<Maya>
えーと、れいば
Well, you see, it's li--

<Phoenix>
やめとけよ。“霊媒”なんて
言っても、笑われるだけだぞ。
Don't say it, Maya.
If you say "spirit
channeling", she'll laugh.

<Maya>
ううう‥‥さみしいなあ。
Ouch... That hurt.




<Desirée>
リューイチくん、
弁護士なんだよね。
So, Nicky boy, you're a
lawyer, huh?

<Phoenix>
ええ、まあ。
Well, yeah.

<Desirée>
どう？　弁護士って。
スリルがあるんじゃない？
How do you like it?
I bet it's SO exciting!

<Phoenix>
‥‥まあ、たしかに。
不必要なほどスリリングですね。
...Yeah, sometimes.
Actually, a little too
exciting at times.

<Desirée>
‥‥アタシ、大好物
なんだよねー、スリル。
Oooh! I just love a good
thrill.

‥‥ふうん‥‥いいなあ、
リューイチくんは‥‥
Hmm... Nicky boy...
It sounds like you have it
so nice...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥うう‥‥
　いごこち悪いな、どうも）
(Um... This is starting
to get awkward.)




<Desirée>
アタシは、バイクとユーサクくんが
いれば、シアワセだなー。
As long as I've got my
motorcycle and my Ronnie,
I'm happy.

<Maya>
うわあ、ステキですね！
Oh! That's so sweet!

<Desirée>
あとは‥‥少しのスリルと、
少しじゃないお金があれば。
Oh, that plus a little
excitement and a little
shopping money.

それで、もうじゅうぶんかな。
...THEN I'm happy.

<Maya>
‥‥意外によくばりだよ、
なるほどくん‥‥
Now she's starting to sound
a bit greedy...
Don't you think, Nick?




<Phoenix>
すみません。
これ、なんですけど‥‥
Excuse me, but would you
take a look at this...?

<Desirée>
やー、ゴメン。
アタシ、意外に世間知らずでさー。
Oh, I'm sorry...
I haven't the faintest idea.

ちょっと、わからないな。
そういうの。
I guess I just don't get out
enough.




<Desirée>
やー、なんかシンピ的だよね。
アタシ好きだなー、こういうの。
Ooh! That's so mysterious
looking...
I love old stuff like this!

<Maya>
ホントですか！　あたしたちの
お宝なんですよ！
Really!? That's one of our
most treasured possessions!

今度、あの高菱屋で
秘宝展をやるんです！
There's going to be a whole
exhibit at Lordly Tailor with
these types of things!

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、とても
　うれしそうなカオをしてるぞ）
(Maya looks so happy.
She's lit up like a 1,000
watt bulb.)

<Desirée>
今度、ユーサクくんといっしょに
見に行くね。‥‥その秘宝展。
Terrific! You can count on
Ronnie and me to be there!
Sounds like fun!

<Maya>
え！　そ、そうですね‥‥
あははは。
Huh!
...Oh, err, yeah...
Ha ha ha...

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、とても
　フクザツなカオをしているな）
(Oops, looks like that light
bulb is starting to flicker.)

< >



<Phoenix>
あの、これなんですけど‥‥
Umm, so what do you know
about this...?

<Maya>
だ、ダメだよなるほどくん！
No!
You can't show her that, Nick!

そのエンブレム、ゴクヒだって
言われたでしょ！
That emblem is top-secret!
Don't you remember!?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥そうだったっけ。
...Doh!
Oops, sorry about that.

（ゴクヒと言われると、よけい
　見せびらかしたくなるよな‥‥）
(But the way she just said
"top-secret" was a worse
giveaway than what I did...)

<Desirée>
あたしも、ゴクヒって言われると
よけい見たくなるよー。
Ooh! When I hear the word
"top-secret", it just piques
my interest like nothing else!




<Desirée>
それ、ユーサクくんに
わたしてね。
Could you please give
that to my Ronnie?

ダイジなコトが書いてあるから。
The contents are very
important.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥
　留置所に行ってみるか）
(*sigh* Back to the
detention center I go...)




<Maya>
ね、ね、なるほどくん！
アイガ探偵が言ってたよね！
Hey! Nick!
Remember what
Detective Atmey said!?

<Atmey>
天杉　優作は、仮面マスクとして
犯行を重ねる理由があるのです。
Exactly that. Mr. DeLite had
a very good reason to dress
up and commit those crimes.

彼の部屋に、ミドリ色の封書が
あるはず。
There should be a green
envelope somewhere in
his room.

‥‥調べてみることですな。
...You'll need to go and
investigate.

<Phoenix>
ミドリ色の封書‥‥か。
どうやら、コレみたいだな。
A green envelope, huh...
Looks like this is it.

<Maya>
よおし。読むぞお！
OK! Let's have a look!

《お前の正体を世間に
　公表されたくなければ‥‥》
"If you don't want your
true identity revealed to
the world...

《１２日の午前１時、５００万円を
　用意して、ＫＢ警備会社に来い》
...come to KB Security at
1:00 AM on October 12th
and bring $50,000."

<Maya>
‥‥ごごご、ごひゃくまんえん‥‥
F-F-F-Fifty thousand...!

<Phoenix>
こ‥‥これって‥‥
キョーハクジョー‥‥だよな。
Th-Th... This is a...
B-B-Blackmail letter...

（たしかに‥‥コイツは
　ものスゴい手がかりだ‥‥！）
(It sure looks like a
major clue alright!)

< >
証拠品《脅迫状》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Blackmail Letter added to
the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
天杉　優作は‥‥脅迫状を
受け取っていたんだ。
So Ron received a
blackmail letter, huh?

<Maya>
まれかさんは知ってるのかな？
このコト‥‥
Do you think Ms. DeLite knows
about this?

<Phoenix>
知ってたら、ニコニコ笑ってる
ワケにも行かないだろ。
Well if she did, I don't think
she would've been smiling
like that.

<Maya>
教えてあげたほうが
いいのかな‥‥
I wonder if we should tell
her about it...

<Phoenix>
よけいなコトは
しないほうがいいと思うよ。
I think it'd be smarter if
we didn't.




< >
　　　‥‥ぴんぽーん‥‥
...*ding-dong*...

<Desirée>
あれ、またお客さんかあ。
‥‥ちょっと待っててね。
Oh! Someone's at the door!
I'll be right back. Won't take
but a second, I promise.

<Desirée>
（やー、わざわざアリガト。
　うれしいなー）
(Oh, thank you for coming!
That's so nice of you!)

<???>
（なーに。オレ、困ってる美人を
　見ると、ほっとけなくてさァ）
(When I see a damsel in
distress, I just can't help
myself!)

<Desirée>
（ちょっと上がって行ってよ。
　コーヒーいれたげるから）
(Please, come on in!
I'll make some coffee.)

<???>
（えー、ホントぉ？　じゃ、
　ゴチソウになっちゃおうかなぁ）
(Really? OK, I guess I'll make
myself at home, pretty lady!)

<Phoenix>
（こ、この、ケーハクな声。
　どこかで聞いたような‥‥）
(...Wait a minute.
I know that voice...)

<Desirée>
リューイチくん、ゴメン！
もう１人、お客さんが来ちゃった。
Oh, Nicky boy, I'm so sorry,
but I've got another guest!

<???>
ああああああああッ！
おまえ‥‥おまえ‥‥
Aaaaaaaaaaaah!!
You... You're...

成歩堂じゃねえか！
それに、マヨイちゃんも！
Nick, it's you!
And Maya, too!
What a fluke!

<Maya>
あ‥‥ヤッパリさん。
おひさしぶりです！
Ah...!
Larry!
Long time no see!

<Desirée>
あれェ？　知り合いなの？
リューイチくんたち。
What? You know each other?

<Butz>
りゅ‥‥
“リューイチくん”って‥‥
Ni... "Nicky boy"!?

成歩堂！　この子、
アンタのなんなのさ？
Nick, do you and this girl
have... you know...
something going on?

<Phoenix>
な、“なんなのさ”と言われても
"S-Something"?
If you mean what I thin--

<Butz>
見そこなったぜ、成歩堂！
I underestimated you, Nick!

こんな‥‥美人の人妻に‥‥
ズルいぞおおお成歩堂おおお！
A gorgeous lady like this?
...And married, too?
Way to go, dude!

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり、メンドウな
　コトになっちまった‥‥）
(I knew it. Just when things
can't get any worse, it's
time to cue in the Butz.)

矢張　政志（やはりまさし）。
小学校のころからの‥‥
Larry Butz...
Ever since grade school,
he's been...

親友というか、まあ知り合いだ。
Not exactly a close friend,
but yeah, we know each
other.

<Butz>
水くせェな。オマエの初めての
依頼人じゃねえか！
Hey, man, that wasn't nice!
I was your very first client!

<Phoenix>
“事件のカゲに、ヤッパリ矢張”と
言われつづけて、今年で２５周年。
It's been 25 years since I
first met Larry.

まったくそのとおり。こいつに
関わると、ロクなコトがない。
And what we used to say still
rings true. When something
smells, it's usually the Butz.

<Butz>
‥‥なんだー、そういうワケかい。
ビックリしたぜ。
Hey, come on now!
You're embarrassing me!

やっぱり、人妻はアレよな。
ヤバいって！
And in front of this pretty
little thing here...

<Desirée>
ふーん‥‥シンユーか。
いいね、そういうの。
So you two are old childhood
friends, I see.
That's so sweet!

好きなだけしゃべっててよ。
アタシ、バイク見てくるから。
You two go ahead and catch up
on old times. I'm going to go
check on my bike.

<Butz>
‥‥いい子よなー、マレカちゃん。
で、最近どうよ？　成歩堂。
Nice girl, that Dessie...
So how have ya been, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いそがしいんだけどな‥‥）
(Too busy if you really
want to know...)




<Phone>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
あ、なるほどくん。電話が‥‥
Oh, Nick! Your phone!

<Phone>
‥‥ピッ‥‥
...*beep*...

<Pearl>
も‥‥もしもしっ。
成歩堂さんのお宅でしょうか？
H-Hello?
Is this the Wright residence?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥春美ちゃん！
今、どうしてるの？
Ah! Pearls!
Where are you!?

<Pearl>
そ、それが‥‥高菱屋さんに
行こうと思ったのですが‥‥
I-I thought I'd go to Lordly
Tailor to try to find some
more clues, but...

すっかり、道に
迷ってしまいまして‥‥
...I'm afraid I've gotten lost.

<Maya>
えええッ！　ちょっと貸して、
なるほどくん！
Whaaaat!?
Give me that phone, Nick!

は、はみちゃん！
どこにいるの、今！
P-Pearly!
Where are you right now!?

<Pearl>
あの‥‥歩いていたら、あの方の
事務所についてしまいました。
Um... I was walking along and
I found myself in front of
that person's office.

<Maya>
“あの方”‥‥？
"That person"...? Who!?

<Pearl>
トシのわりに落ちつきのない、
“ズヴァリ！”のオジさまの‥‥
Um, that person who doesn't
act his age and always says,
"Zvarri!" when he's excited...

<Phoenix>
（名探偵・星威岳　哀牙か‥‥）
(Luke Atmey, Ace Detective...)

そこにいるんだよ、春美ちゃん！
今、むかえに行くから！
OK, stay right there!
We're coming to get you!

<Pearl>
は、はい‥‥。
わたくし、心細くて‥‥
A-Alright...
I-I'm a little scared...

<Phone>
‥‥ピッ‥‥
...*beep*...

<Phoenix>
よし！　すぐ行こう、真宵ちゃん！
Alright! Let's go, Maya!

<Butz>
ちょっと待て、成歩堂！
Wait a second, Nick!

<Phoenix>
な、なんだよ。
Wh-What?

<Butz>
今の電話！　カワイイ
女の子の声だったぞ。
That phone call just now...
Sounded like real cutie...

その子‥‥アンタのなんなのさ！
Another one of your, ahem,
..."special friends"?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
まれかさんによろしくな、矢張。
.........
Say goodbye to Ms. DeLite for
me, would you Larry?




<Phoenix>
おまえ、今まで何してたんだ？
たしか、２年ぶりぐらいだよな。
So what have you been up to
this whole time? It's been two
years since I heard from you.

いつのまにか、ファッションの
センスもおかしくなってるし。
And what's with these clothes?
You look... well, weird.

<Butz>
これは、バイト先の制服だッ！
Hey man, that's uncalled for.
This is my uniform, from
my part-time job.

いやー、それにしても２年か。
早いよなァ、時のたつのだけは。
But I can't believe it's been
two years. They say time flies
when you're having fun.

はははははは‥‥‥はは‥‥は。
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥。
Ha ha ha ha... Ah ha... Ha...
...ha?

<Phoenix>
ど、どうした？
Wh-What's wrong?

<Butz>
成歩堂よぉ。‥‥オレ。
もう‥‥オンナなんか信じねぇぞ。
Nick... I gotta tell you.
Women.
...I don't trust 'em anymore.

<Phoenix>
また、フラれたのか？
You got dumped again?

<Butz>
あのマキコを追っかけて、オレ
チベットへ飛んだワケよ、２年前。
Well, you know Bennifer?
I followed her all the way to
Tibet 2 years ago.

そこでオレ、例のコズエと
運命の出会いをしたんだけどサ。
That's where I met the famous
Katty Tom, and my whole life
changed.

<Phoenix>
“あのマキコ”も“例のコズエ”も
聞いたことないぞ。
"Bennifer"? "Katty Tom"?
I never heard of either
of them.

<Butz>
でも、コズエのヤツ‥‥オレより
ハリウッドをとるわ、だってよォ！
Anyway... Dude!
Katty Tom chose Hollywood over
me! Can you believe it?

<Maya>
それは‥‥その。
大ボウケンでしたねえ。
Well, actually...
Anyway, sounds like you
had quite the adventure.

<Butz>
オンナなんか‥‥
オンナなんかあああぁぁぁ！
Women!
They're so... so...
Aaaah!

あ。‥‥とは言っても、
マヨイちゃんだけはベツだから。
Oh...
B-But you're different, Maya.
You're not like the rest.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥まだコリないらしい）
(...Looks like he's still the
same old Larry.)




<Phoenix>
で？　なんでおまえ、
こんなトコロへ来たんだ？
So what are you
doing here anyway?

<Butz>
え‥‥！
Huh...?

オレってホレ、生まれながらの
ナイスガイだろ？
What do you mean by that?
I'm just a natural-born
nice guy, that's all.

‥‥じつは、コレ。ゆうべ、
バイト先で拾っちゃってよ。
Well, actually... I picked
this up last night while
I was working.

<Phoenix>
‥‥サイフ？
ゆうべ、拾ったって‥‥？
...A wallet?
You say you found this
last night?

<Butz>
免許証が入ってたからさァ。
これはもう、届けるだろ。フツー。
Yeah, it had a driver's
license in it, so I figured
I'd just return it myself.

< >
証拠品《天杉　優作のサイフ》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
Ron's Wallet added to
the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちょっと見せてみろよ、
そのサイフの中身。
Hang on... Let me see that
for a minute.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥やっぱり、
まれかさんの写真、か。
...
I knew it.
Dessie's picture is in here.

<Butz>
い、いやあ、女房おもいの
ダンナよなー。
Yeah, I guess he really
digs his wife, huh?

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥ち、ちがうぞ！
成歩堂、そんなんじゃねえって！
...
Hey, Nick... It's not what
you're thinking at all!

<Phoenix>
目的はやっぱり、まれかさんか。
No, I'm pretty sure it is.
You haven't changed a bit.

<Butz>
‥‥いやいや！　やっぱり、
人妻はアレよな。ヤバいって！
Aw, no way man! I mean,
she's a married woman!
That's just bad news!

<Phoenix>
（コリないヤツだな、ホント‥‥）
(He really IS here just to
check out Ms. DeLite...)

<Maya>
あの。“アルバイト先で拾った”
って言ってましたよね？
So you said you found it at
your job, right?

<Butz>
ああ！　オレさ、警備会社で
ガードマンやってるんだぜ！
Yeah! I'm working for a
private security company
as a guard!

ホレちゃうだろ？　思わずさあ！
Chicks just love a guy
in uniform, you know!

<Phoenix>
（ガードマン‥‥。たしかに
　それっぽい制服を着ているな）
(A security guard, huh.
So that's what that uniform
is all about...)




<Phoenix>
おまえがコレを拾ったの
‥‥ゆうべの何時ごろだ？
So what time was it when
you found this last night?

<Butz>
お、なんだよそれ！
いわゆるアリバイってヤツ？
Huh? Why are you asking that!?
Trying to see if I've got
an "alibi"!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ゼンゼンちがうよ！）
(Umm... You're not the one
on the hook for a crime
this time, buddy.)

<Butz>
たしか‥‥１時ごろかな。夜中の。
バイト先の、ビルの１階でさ。
I guess it was around 1:00 in
the morning on the first floor
of our company building.

<Phoenix>
（どうして、優作くんのサイフが
　そんなところに‥‥？）
(What was Mr. DeLite's wallet
doing there...?)

<Butz>
‥‥ベツに、おかしくねえだろ。
...Anyway, there's nothing
weird about that.

あの会社の社員なんだから。
After all, he works there.

<Maya>
しゃ‥‥社員？
優作さんが、ですか‥‥？
He... works there?
You mean... Mr. DeLite?

<Butz>
だってよォ。サイフの中に
コイツが入ってたから。
Sure. Here, take a look at
this. It's right there in
his wallet.

<Maya>
このカードは‥‥？
What's this card?

<Butz>
バイト先の警備会社の
キーカードだよ。
It's a key card for the
security company.

シリアル番号が入ってるから、
まちがいないぜ。
Hey! It's got a serial number
on it right there. There's no
mistake about it.

<Phoenix>
おまえのアルバイト先‥‥
“警備会社”だったよな。
You said you were working
part-time at a "security
company", right?

<Butz>
そうだぜ。‥‥なんだよ、
コワいカオしちゃってさあ！
That's right.
...Wh-Why are you making
that scary face?

<Phoenix>
（なんか、引っかかる‥‥
　“警備会社”‥‥）
("Security company", huh...
Something's not quite secure
about Larry working there...)

（それに、このキーカード‥‥
　詳しい情報がほしいな）
(I need to find out as much as
I can about this key card...)

< >
証拠品《キーカード》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Key Card added to
the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
脅迫状に書いてある《ＫＢ警備》
‥‥おまえ、知ってるんだな！
KB Security, the company
in the blackmail letter!
You know about it!?

<Butz>
なにしろ、バイト先だからなァ。
今もオレ、キンム中だし。
That's where I work, yeah.
In fact, I'm on the job
right now.

<Maya>
あれ。‥‥じゃあ、どうして
ここにいるんですか？
Huh...?
So what are you doing
here then?

<Butz>
はは。社長が今、ルスだから。
チョイと一休み‥‥自主的に。
Well, the boss is away right
now, and you know what mice
do when the cat's away...

<Phoenix>
“一休み”って‥‥
どこにあるんだよ、その会社。
...Yes, yes. *sigh*
Anyway, how far away is this
company?

<Butz>
そうだな‥‥クルマでスッ飛ばして
３０分ぐらい、だったかな。
Lemme see... About 30 minutes
by car, I guess... Well, if
you fly down the road, anyway.

<Phoenix>
このマンション‥‥高菱屋百貨店
の、すぐそばにあるよな。
Hmm. Well, this apartment
building is pretty close to
Lordly Tailor, right?

<Maya>
ＫＢ警備に行って、帰ってきたら
１時間かかっちゃうね。
And it would take roughly an
hour to go from here to KB
Security and back.

<Phoenix>
天杉　優作が、犯行時刻のころ、
ＫＢ警備に行っていたら‥‥？
If Ron DeLite was at
KB Security when the
robbery occurred, then...

<Maya>
あ‥‥
Whoa...!

倉院のツボ、盗めないよ‥‥。
Then he couldn't have
stolen the Sacred Urn!

< >



<Butz>
オマエ、もう２６才だろ。
You're 26 years old, right?

そろそろ、しっかり生き方を
見つめなおしたほうがいいぜ！
Don't you think it's about
time you took a long, hard
look at your life?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

女の子にフラれるために生きてる
アルバイトの警備員に言われると、
Coming from a guy who can
only brag about how many
times he's been rejected...

‥‥逆に重くのしかかるなあ。
そのセリフ。
I find that kind of... ironic.




<Butz>
お！　おぼえてるぜ！
マヨイちゃんのネエちゃんだろ！
Hey, I remember her!
That's Maya's big sister!

<Maya>
わあ！　おぼえてて
くれたんですか！
Wow! You really do remember!

<Butz>
美女よなあ。姉妹そろってさあ！
Yeah, who could forget!
A couple of gorgeous sisters!
Hubba hubba!

<Maya>
ビジョだって、なるほどくん！
You hear that, Nick!
Gorgeous!

<Phoenix>
（そういえば、
　矢張を弁護したとき‥‥）
(Oh yeah... That's right.
When I defended Larry...)

（千尋さん、まだ
　生きていたんだっけな‥‥）
(Mia was still alive...)




<Butz>
しばらく会わないうちに
グッとかわいくなったね！
Wow! You're even cuter than
the last time I saw you.

<Maya>
え！　ホントですか！
Oh, really!?

<Butz>
もお、２年前とはベツジンだぜ。
なあ、成歩堂！
Yeah, you look totally
different than two years ago.
Don't you think, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（近くにいるせいか、あんまり
　変わったようには見えないな）
(Maybe it's 'cause we're
always together, but she looks
pretty much the same to me.)




<Butz>
おッ！　カワイイ‥‥
Oh! What a cutie!

成歩堂！　この子、
アンタのなんなのさ？
Hey, Nick!
So what's the deal between
you and this girl?

<Maya>
あ。あたしのイトコです。
綾里　春美っていうんですよ。
Hey! That's my cousin!
Her name is Pearl Fey.

<Butz>
ハルミちゃん、か‥‥
ザンネンだなあ。
Pearl, huh...
Too bad.

オレ、同じ名前のカノジョは
作らないルールだから。
Never date two girls with the
same name... That's one rule
I can't break.

<Phoenix>
（それ以前に、春美ちゃん
　９才だぞ‥‥）
(...I'd think the fact that
she's only 9 years old would
break some rule somewhere!)




<Butz>
お！　アマいマスクの下に、
セクシー美女の予感！
I just thought of something!
What if it's actually a hot
chick under that costume!

<Phoenix>
いやいや。オトコだよ、中身は。
Forget about it.
It's a guy, trust me.

<Butz>
バカ！　つまんねえモノ
見せるんじゃねえ！
Man! You're killin' my
buzz, dude!

<Maya>
‥‥わかりやすいヒトだね、
ヤッパリさん‥‥。
Boy, talk about someone
who has a one track mind...




<Butz>
いやー、やっぱり
イイよなあ、マレカちゃん。
That Dessie is one
awesome lady alright!

ひさしぶりに、マジで
ホレちまいそうだぜ。
It's been a long time since
I've felt this way... I think
I'm really in love this time!

<Maya>
ひさしぶり、ですかあ‥‥
A long time, huh?

<Butz>
あ！　モチロン、
マヨイちゃんはベツよ！
Yeah! Well, err...
Except for what I feel
for you, Maya!

<Phoenix>
（もう、イミが
　わからないな、コイツは）
(I don't think even HE knows
what he's saying anymore.)




<Butz>
成歩堂、オマエも
見習えよ、このオレをさ！
Even you could learn a few
tricks from me, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥たとえば、どのへんを？
...Yeah? Like what?

<Butz>
見ろよ、オレのアタマ。
上ムキにトガってるだろ？
Look at my hair for example.
It points up straight, right?

なのに、オマエときたら。
いっつも、後ろムキにトガらせて。
But your hair, on the other
hand, points backwards.

ダメだよ、それじゃあ。
オトコなら、トップを目指せ！
That's no good at all, man!
It's defeatist! You gotta aim
high... for the stars!

<Phoenix>
（は‥‥反論できない）
(I... I can't find a
counter-argument
to that...)




<Phoenix>
矢張。このヒトなんだけど‥‥
Larry, what about this
person...?

<Butz>
知らね。
Beats me.

<Phoenix>
（ここまでキョクタンな
　オトコだったかな‥‥）
(What the...? All of a sudden,
he's got nothing to say...?)




<Phoenix>
矢張、これなんだけど。
Hey Larry, what about this?

<Butz>
なんだよ。言いたいことが
あったら、クチで言えよな。
What? If you've got
something to say,
then say it already!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
な、なんだコレ！　脅迫状って！
...
Huh...?
A blackmail letter!?

<Phoenix>
何か、思い当たることでもあるか？
Do you know anything
about this?

<Butz>
な‥‥な、なんで知ってるんだよ！
エミコのことだろ！
Wh-Wha-What?
I don't know anything about
Alexis! And that's the truth!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥は？　ナニ‥‥？
...
Huh? What?

<Butz>
お、お、お、お‥‥オマエ、
トモダチじゃなかったのかよ！
I-I can't believe you'd
do this to me! I thought you
were my friend!

そんな‥‥
ゴヒャクマンエンって、オマエ！
Fifty thousand dollars!
I don't have that kind
of money!

<Phoenix>
い‥‥いやいやいや！　それは
天杉　優作が受け取ったものだぞ。
No, no, you don't understand!
This blackmail letter was
sent to Ron DeLite!

<Butz>
えええッ！
ビックリさせるな！　バカ！
Wheeeew!
Man, you scared me!! I almost
had a heart attack, you idiot!

<Phoenix>
どっちがだ！
Wait, I'm the idiot!?

<Butz>
まぎらわしいぜ。“ＫＢ警備”
なんて書いてあるからよォ。
Man, I was totally confused
because it says, "KB Security"
right on the envelope.

<Maya>
‥‥あの。
それがどうかしましたか？
Um, yeah...
So what?

<Butz>
ＫＢ警備会社って、オレが
バイトしているトコだからさァ。
That's where I've got a
part-time job!
At KB Security!

<Maya>
な‥‥なにィィィィッ！
Wh... Whaaaat!

<Phoenix>
（ＫＢ警備について‥‥
　情報を引きずり出さないと！）
(Sounds like I should really
find out some more about
this KB Security company!)




<Phoenix>
このキーカード、
まちがいなく‥‥？
So you're sure about
this key card?

<Butz>
ああ。そいつはウチの
ビルで使われているカードだぜ。
Yup. That's the key card they
use at the building I work in.

シリアル番号によると‥‥
社長室のカードだな。
According to the serial
number, this one is for
the CEO's office.

部屋に入るときに必要でさ。
使うと、記録が残るんだ。
You need it to get into that
room, and every time you use
that card, it leaves a record.

<Maya>
記録が‥‥残る‥‥？
It leaves a record?

<Butz>
ダレが何時に部屋を出入りしたか、
バッチリってワケ。
Yeah, it tells you
exactly who entered
the room and when.

<Phoenix>
矢張！　その記録だけど‥‥
Larry! I need that data...!

<Butz>
おおっと！　悪いケド、外部の
人間にデータは見せられねえぜ。
Whoa! Slow down, man!
Sorry, but that data is
off limits to outsiders.

クビになったら、まれかちゃんと
遊ぶ計画がパアだ。
If I lost this job, I'd never
have a chance with Dessie...

<Phoenix>
（こういうとき、
　弁護士ってヨワいよな‥‥）
(It's times like these when I
wish lawyers weren't so
powerless...)

< >
証拠品《キーカード》のデータを
書きなおした。
Key Card updated in the
Court Record.




<Phoenix>
矢張。倉院の里の
秘宝なんだけど‥‥
Larry, this is one of
the treasures from
Kurain Village...

<Butz>
バカか、成歩堂！
Be serious, Nick!

オレ、そういうジミなヤツには
まったくキョーミねえの！
I couldn't care less about
mystic mumbo jumbo stuff!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Butz>
あ！　モチロン、
マヨイちゃんはベツだぜ！
Ah!
Of course Maya is a
different story!

<Phoenix>
（このオトコはいったい
　ナニを言ってるのだろう‥‥）
(Talk about your mixed
messages...)




<Phoenix>
まさか‥‥サイフの中身には
手をつけてないだろうな？
You didn't touch anything in
the wallet, did you?

<Butz>
バカなコト
言ってんじゃねえよ！
Hey man, be serious!

オレの狙ってるエモノは
こっちだって！
You know what I was
interested in!

<Phoenix>
（怪人☆仮面マスク、あやうし！
　‥‥だな）
(If Mask☆DeMasque doesn't
look out, he's gonna be the
victim of a robbery himself!)




<Butz>
うおおおおお！
ダレよコレ！　ダレよ成歩堂！
WHOA!
WHO is this! Come on, man,
don't hold out on me!

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。
‥‥知らなきゃいいよ、ベツに。
Forget about it.
It's on a need to know basis
and you don't need to kn--

<Butz>
よくねぇよ、成歩堂！
オマエだって知ってるだろ！
Hey now!
I thought we were pals!

オレ、黒いノースリーブでメガネの
オンナに、めっぽうヨワいんだよ！
I got a MAJOR thing for girls
with black sleeveless shirts
and glasses!

<Phoenix>
そんなの知るかよ！
How do you know that!?

<Butz>
これで、オレンジ色の手帳でも
持っていたら、も。たまんねえぜ！
And if they have an orange-
colored memo pad, I really
lose my cool!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥本当に知らないのか？
　霧緒さんのこと‥‥）
(He has to be making that
up... He can't really know
Adrian... Can he...?)




<Phoenix>
‥‥これについて、
何か思いつくことはないか？
...What about this?
Does anything come to mind?

<Butz>
オレ、警備員だからさあ。
Listen, I'm a security guard.

こんなトコで、アブラ売ってる
ワケにはいかねえのよ。
I'm not here to sell you juicy
bits of info and chew the fat,
man.

<Phoenix>
（２年前はマンジュウを
　売ってたくせに‥‥）
(Funny, you had no qualms
about selling Samurai Dogs
just 2 years ago.)
