同日　某時刻
ビタミン広場
January 7
Vitamin Square

<Maya>
‥‥あれ。
オジさん、いないよ。
Hmm...
I don't see any sign of
Mr. Kudo. Do you?

<Phoenix>
マメを買いに行ってるのかも
しれないね。
Maybe he went to buy another
ton of bird seeds.

なんにしても、あまり
会いたくないな、今は。
I was kind of hoping he
wouldn't be here, anyway.
At least, not for now.

（もう、今日はじゅうぶん
　食らわされたからな。マメなら）
(Besides, any more seeds today
and I'm liable to turn into a
real phoenix!)




<Maya>
フルーティーだよね。
なんていうか。
This place is so fruity!

<Phoenix>
‥‥まあ、いいんじゃないかな。
ぼくもリンゴは大好きだし。
That's not a bad thing.
Besides, I love apples.
They're among my favorites.

<Maya>
あ！　じゃあ、あの
すべり台、もってこいじゃない！
Then that apple slide is
perfect for you!

<Phoenix>
‥‥なにがどう
“もってこい”なんだよ。
...
And what is so "perfect"
about it?

<Maya>
はいはい、なるほどくん。
すべってすべって。
Oh come on. Don't be a stick
in the mud! Slide down it
a few times. Go on! Woo!

<Phoenix>
や、やだよ。
No way!

すべったら、かならず砂まみれに
なるシステムだぞ、あれ。
I'd get covered in sand if I
slid down that slide.
Anyone can see that.

<Maya>
ううん、たしかに。
それがなきゃ、あたしもねえ‥‥
Yeah, you're right.
Otherwise, I'd give it
a try, too.




<Maya>
ハトだ。
Hey, look. Pigeons!

<Phoenix>
たくさんいるね。
Yeah. And heaps of them, too.

<Maya>
ね。知ってる？　ハトって、
平和のシンボルなんだよ！
Did you know that pigeons are
a symbol of peace?

<Phoenix>
そりゃ、白いハトだけだろ。
That's a dove, not a pigeon.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

かわいそうだね、この子たち。
Poor things.

色が白くないだけなのに‥‥
平和になりそこねちゃって。
Just because they're gray
means they can't be symbols
of peace and harmony?

<Phoenix>
な、何もそこまで
しんみりしなくても‥‥
You're over-thinking this one
by just a smidge, Maya.




<Maya>
いやあ、砂場には
燃えたねー、あたしも。
I used to love sandboxes like
you would not believe.

<Phoenix>
燃えた？　砂場遊びに？
Really? You?

<Maya>
ホラ。じしゃくを使って
砂鉄あつめ。
Sure. Finding iron filings in
the sand with a magnet was my
favorite thing to do.

<Phoenix>
サテツ‥‥地味だなあ。
Iron filings?
Wow... That's too exciting
for words.

<Maya>
『砂場じゅうの砂鉄を
　集めきる！』って決意して。
It was my ambition to collect
every single shred of iron in
the sandbox.

<Maya>
あたしも若かったな。
あのころは。
I was such a kid back then!

<Phoenix>
‥‥で、集めきったの？
So, did you manage to get
all the iron?

<Maya>
ううん。
もう少しだったんだけどねえ。
No, I never did.
I think I came close, though.

あ。そういえば、まだ
とってあるよ！　そのときの砂鉄。
Come to think of it, I still
have all the iron filings I
found way back when.

いる？
You want them?

<Phoenix>
いらない。
No.




<Maya>
あのさ。このみかん見てたら
思い出したんだけど。
Looking at this orange
reminds me...

<Phoenix>
‥‥なに？
Of what?

<Maya>
やっぱり、お正月といえば、
おもち食べながらみかん食べて、
That you're supposed to eat
a lot of them to ward off
colds in the winter.

おせちをつつきながらテレビ見て、
さらにトランプでババ抜きだよね。
You can't have fun during the
holidays if you're sick in
bed, you know.

<Phoenix>
マコちゃん助けたら、
みんなでやろうか。
Speaking of fun, if we get
Maggey acquitted, maybe we
can all get together sometime.

<Maya>
でもマコちゃん、ジャンケンすら
勝ったことがない、って‥‥。
OK! ...But what do we play
with someone who's never even
won a game of Tic-Tac-Toe?

<Phoenix>
‥‥じゃ、ルールを変えよう。
How about we change the rules
a bit, then? We could play
Old Maid, and... um...

最後にババ持ってたら勝ち、
ってコトに。
We could say the person who's
left with the old maid at the
end is the winner. How's that?

<Maya>
‥‥《ババ引き》かあ。
いいね、それ！
Not bad... Not bad at all!
We could even rename the
game to "Fair Maiden"!




<Maya>
あれ。これって‥‥
Hey, check this out...

<Phoenix>
近よらないほうがいいよ。
ものすごいコトになるから。
I wouldn't get too close to
that if I were you. Otherwise
you might be in for a shock.

（どうやら‥‥近くに
　ひそんでるらしいな‥‥）
My phony must be lurking
someplace nearby...

（‥‥都会に放たれた
　トラがッ！）
Just imagine! A Tiger, loose
in the city!

<Maya>
ホンモノは、都会に捨てられた
子ネコみたいなのにねえ。
Meanwhile the real Phoenix is
like an abandoned chick, lost
in a vast urban jungle!

<Phoenix>
‥‥え。
Huh?

<Maya>
なるほどくんもがんばって、
早くトラになるんだよ。
Don't worry. Someday, you'll
grow up and become a ferocious
tiger, too! Don't lose hope!

<Phoenix>
（ニセモノを目指すハメになった）
(Why is she trying to pep-talk
me into becoming my phony...?)




同日　某時刻
ビタミン広場
January 7
Vitamin Square

<Maya>
出たッ！　マメのオジさんだ！
ハトにエサやってるよ！
There he is! Old Seedy's back
feeding the pigeons again!

<Kudo>
食らえッ！　食らって飛べッ！
There! Take this!
And this!
And get out of my park!

<Phoenix>
やっぱり、荒れてるな‥‥。
Like I thought, he's really
mad...

下を向いて、目を合わさないように
コッソリ帰ろう。
Come on, Maya. Just keep your
head down and let's sneak
away while we still can...

<Maya>
え。どうして？
おーい、オジさーん！
What? Why?
Hellooo, old man!

<Phoenix>
あ。ま、真宵ちゃん‥‥
What are you doing, Maya!?

<Kudo>
ムッ！　‥‥‥‥プイッ。
Huh!?
...Kah!

<Maya>
あれ。
そっぽ向いちゃった。
Hey, he just turned his back
on us!

<Phoenix>
そりゃまあ。オジさんのプライド、
まるつぶれだからなあ。
I'm not surprised. I bet I
really hurt his pride in
court this morning.

<Maya>
ね、オジさんオジさん。
Hey, Mr. Kudo!

<Kudo>
ぽっぽっぽお！　ハトぽっぽお
‥‥‥‥とぉ！
Hmm, ha-hmm, hmm...
Hmm, pi-pi-pigeon, hmm...
Kah!

<Maya>
お話、聞かせてくださいよー。
Look, we really need to talk
to you, alright?

<Kudo>
オニはーそとォ！
福はーうちィ！
Out with the demons!
In with good fortune!

<Maya>
いたたたたたたたたた。
‥‥あたしもマメ投げられた。
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Seeds... Shell splinters...
Painful...

<Phoenix>
やれやれ。オニあつかいか‥‥。
I always knew you were a
demon, Maya!




<Phoenix>
ど、どうして今日の法廷で
話してくれなかったんですか！
Why didn't you mention this
in court this morning?

<Kudo>
話そうと思ったワイ！
‥‥だのに‥‥
Well, I would have if you'd
given me the chance!

アンタらがよってたかって、
ワシを放り出したではないかッ！
But you all bullied me out of
the courtroom!

<Judge>
‥‥はあ。
証人。ごくろうさまでした。
*sigh* Thank you, Mr. Kudo.
You've certainly earned your
kudos for today.

<Kudo>
ままま、待っていただきたい！
そ、そういうことであれば、その。
WAIT! WAIT A MINUTE!
If that's the case, there's
more! I've got more to say!

‥‥あ、そうだ！
なんなら、あの話を‥‥
Oh, yes!
I remember something else...

<Judge>
法廷係官！
この証人をつまみ出しなさい。
Bailiff!
Escort the witness out of the
courtroom!

<Kudo>
ワルいの、ワシじゃないモン！
アンタらだモン！
It's not my fault!
You're the ones to blame!

<Phoenix>
‥‥先にこっちを話してくれれば
よかったのに‥‥
You could have at least told
us before we got to court.

<Maya>
そんなにダイジなコトなの？
オジさんが電話したこと。
Is it really that important
that Mr. Kudo was the one
who called the police...?

<Phoenix>
（警察が到着するまでの、
　空白の時間‥‥）
(What's important is the
unaccounted time before
the police arrived.)

（店内には、被害者と、
　キゼツしたマコちゃんと‥‥）
(The victim was dead, and
Maggey was unconscious.)

（彼女‥‥いや、彼だけが
　残されていたコトになる！）
(Which leaves that woman...
I mean, that man, alone in the
restaurant!)

オジさんは‥‥追い払われたの
かもしれない。
Mr. Kudo might have been
chased out of the place on
purpose.

<Maya>
“追い払われた”‥‥？
What do you mean?

<Phoenix>
警察が来るまで、
店にいてもらいたくなかった‥‥
Maybe a certain someone didn't
want him in the restaurant.

<Maya>
あ‥‥！
Ah!

<Kudo>
ああ、そうさ！　どうせワシは
ジャマモノだともさ！
Oh, sure! You go ahead and
say I was in the way as usual!

ワシなんか、ハトにまみれて
マメ食ってりゃいいのさ！
I suppose I should've been
getting myself covered in
pigeon poop instead, hmm?

<Phoenix>
（とにかく、ハナシを聞いた
　ほうがいいな‥‥）
(We need to get more
details about what exactly
happened...)

（マコちゃんと‥‥
　あの、店長に！）
(...from Maggey... and from
Mr. Armstrong!)




<Phoenix>
あの。‥‥今日の法廷は、
すみませんでした。
Um... I'm sorry about what
happened in court earlier
today.

<Kudo>
フン！　ケーベツするがいいさ！
どうせワシは、アレさ！
Kah!
Everyone'll be talking about
me behind my back now!

女給さんのおシリに見とれて
ロクにカオもおぼえていない、
A dirty old man who was so
busy looking at the serving
girl's backside...

すけべいなクソ野郎なのさ！
フケツでおぞましい初老の怪物さ！
...that he can't remember her
face! A filthy, depraved
animal!

<Phoenix>
い、いや、そんな‥‥
N-Not at all!

<Kudo>
いいか！　アンタがなんと言おうと
あの女給は入れたんだよ！
Are you listening to me, boy!?
I don't care what you say, I
saw that waitress put it in!

ワカゾウのコーシーに、
なんぞ、白い粉をッ！
She put some white powder into
the young lad's javaccino!

<Maya>
そうなんですか‥‥
We hear you...

<Kudo>
それに！　あのワカゾウは、
イヤホンをブチこんでたんだよ！
And another thing! The young
layabout was wearing an
earpiece!

イカれたメガネをかけた耳にッ！
On the same side as the lens
of his broken spectacles!

<Maya>
うう‥‥ゴメンなさい‥‥。
W-We're really sorry...

<Kudo>
たしかに、花ビンのコトはアレさ。
スットコチョイだったさ！
So I made a little mistake
about the vase. So what!?

でも‥‥ワシは‥‥ワシはぁぁ！
I know what I saw!
I tell you, I tell you, I tell
you!

<Phoenix>
ま、まあまあ、落ちついて‥‥。
OK, OK! Take it easy, please,
Mr. Kudo.

<Kudo>
うるさいワ！　これでも食らえィ！
Don't tell me to take it easy,
you spikey-haired brat!
Take this!




<Maya>
あの‥‥。オジさんて、
職人さんなんですよね！
Um... You said you were
a craftsman, right?

<Kudo>
フン！　このセチがらい世の中、
ワシの居場所なんか、ないワ！
Kah! The modern world casts
honest craftsmen like me
aside in droves!

<Maya>
そ、そんなコトは‥‥
S-Surely it's not that...

<Kudo>
ワシの家は代々、職人だった！
そりゃもう、江戸時代からだ！
I come from a long line of
craftsmen. Right back to the
time of the shoguns!

ワカるか！　生まれた瞬間から
紋章上絵師だった、ワシのキモチ。
Do you hear me!? I didn't
become an embroiderer, I was
BORN one!

<Maya>
‥‥あたしも似たようなモン
なんだけどな。
Actually... I'm kind of in the
same situation myself.

<Kudo>
ワシだって‥‥ワシだって‥‥
I... I...

冷や汗でグズグズになったジイサン
のハナっツラに指をこすりつけて、
I wanted to stick my fingers
up that dribbling old judge's
nose...

耳もとで“異議あり！”と
叫びたおしてみたかったワ！
...and scream right down his
earhole... "Objection!"

<Maya>
‥‥オジさん、弁護士に
なりたかったんだね‥‥。
Oh... So, did you want to
become a lawyer when you
were young...?

<Phoenix>
どうでもいいけど、
グチっぽくなってきたな。
I don't think that's quite it,
Maya. I think he's just in a
bad mood, that's all...

<Kudo>
ワシのグチは、ツナミのごとく
押しよせ、さかまき、飲みこむぞ！
I've got a tsunami of
frustration inside and it's
ready to burst out!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どうしよう。
　長くなりそうだな。‥‥グチ）
(If we let him start rambling
now, we might never shut him
up! What should I do?)



<Phoenix>
あの。ちょっと今はアレなので‥‥
今度、ゆっくり聞かせてください。
Um, actually, we've got places
to go, things to check and
stuff... Maybe another time?

<Kudo>
よおし！　ヤクソクだぞ！
かならず聞きに来るんだからな！
Fine! Whatever! Just don't
forget! I've got a tsunami's
worth of grumbling to do.

<Phoenix>
は、はい。
この子が楽しみにしてますから。
Yes, yes. This girl right here
is really looking forward to
hearing it all. Honest!

<Maya>
なんであたしが！
What!? I never said that!

<Kudo>
ワシの店で待っとるからな！
‥‥持ってけ、このワカゾウがッ！
Come to the place where I
work, then. Here. Bring this
along with you.

<Phoenix>
（マメにまじって、ハンバーガーの
　割引券がとんできた）
(What is this? It's covered in
seeds... A discount coupon
for a burger!?)

<Maya>
よっぽど聞いてほしいんだね。
‥‥グチ。
He really wants someone to
grumble at, huh? ...Although,
it IS a burger joint...




<Phoenix>
（とりあえず、
　聞いてみるか‥‥グチ）
(Guess I better let him
talk...)

お仕事は、ないんですか？
職人さんの。
So, there's not much call for
craftsmen these days, then?

<Kudo>
あたりまえだ！　ワシなんぞ、
使いっ走りがお似あいなのさ！
Of course not, you idiot!
All I'm good for nowadays is
running errands!

<Maya>
“使いっ走り”‥‥？
Errands?

<Kudo>
ダレもカレも、
年寄りをコキ使いおって！
Everyone takes advantage of
the elderly!

“ジイちゃん、とうふ買ってきて”
“イヌのさんぽ、おねがい”
"Buy some bread, gramps!"
"Take the dog for a walk,
granddad!"

“ハトにエサ、やってきて”‥‥
ワシは町の便利屋さんかいッ！
"Feed the pigeons, old man!"
What am I? Some sort of two-
bit community handyman!?

<Maya>
はああ‥‥。
Um, well...

<Kudo>
“とうふ買ってきて”は
リカイできる。しかし‥‥
"Buy some bread", now that I
can understand.

“ハトにエサやってきて”
‥‥これは、なんだ！
But what's the point of
feeding some seedy pigeons!?

アキラカに“どこか行ってきて”
ってコトじゃないかッ！
Why don't people say what they
mean!? "Get lost!" That's what
they're trying to say!

ああ、そうさ！
ワシはジャマモノなのさ！
Oh, yes!
I'm just an inconvenience,
you see!

‥‥ウチでも、メシ屋でもな！
At home... At that
restaurant... I just get in
the way, don't I!?

<Phoenix>
そ、そんなことは‥‥
I-I'm sure you don't.

（ちょっと待てよ‥‥。
　今、なんて言った‥‥？）
(Wait a minute!
What did he just say?)

（ウチでも‥‥
　“メシ屋でも”‥‥？）
(At home and... at that
restaurant?)

メシ屋‥‥‥吐麗美庵で、
たのまれたコトがあるんですか？
Hold up... By "restaurant",
are you talking about
Trés Bien?

その‥‥“使いっ走り”を。
Did you get asked to run an
errand there, too?

<Kudo>
ああ、そうともさ！　あの
ワカゾウが、ぶっ倒れた日にな！
Yes, I did! The very day that
young brat was poisoned.

<Phoenix>
な‥‥
なんですってェェェッ！
WH-WHAT!?




<Phoenix>
事件があった日‥‥吐麗美庵で
何をたのまれたんですか？
So on the day of the incident,
what were you asked to do?

<Kudo>
おお！　よくぞ
聞いてくれたワ！
Glad you asked, boy!
Because I'll tell you what
I was asked to do!

‥‥ワカゾウがぶっ倒れて、
All of a sudden that young lad
slumped over the table...

‥‥女給さんもぶっ倒れて、
The serving girl collapsed...

ワシは花ビンをぶっ倒した。
アタマん中、まっ白だよ。もう。
And I broke that vase.
It all happened so fast, I was
in a bit of a daze, you see.

そこに、あの店長がワシに
叫んだのさ。
Then the owner shouted over
to me.

<Armstrong>
“すみません！　そこのヒト！
　ケーサツを呼んでくださいな！”
"Excusez-moi! You!
Call la police!"

<Kudo>
自分で呼べよ、ケーサツぐらい！
‥‥と、今なら言える。
"Call them yourself!" I should
have said back. But I didn't
think of it at the time.

<Maya>
それで‥‥呼んだんですか？
ケーサツ。
So, did you end up calling
the police?

<Kudo>
まあ‥‥とにかくワシ、
アタマん中、まっ白だったから。
Like I said, I was in a bit of
a daze.

<Phoenix>
警察への通報は‥‥
携帯電話を使ったんですか？
Did you call them on your cell
phone?

<Kudo>
そんなハイカラなモノ、
持ってるワケがなかろうッ！
Kah! Do I look like I'd have
one of those new-fangled
thingamajigs?

店のそとで、公衆電話を
探したワ、モチロン。
I went out looking for a pay
phone, of course!

<Maya>
“探した”‥‥？
You went looking for one...?

<Kudo>
なかなか見つからなくてな。
５分ぐらいムダにしちまった。
I couldn't find one right
away, you know. Wandered
around for 5 minutes or so.

<Maya>
ご、“５分”‥‥？
F-Five minutes...?

<Phoenix>
じゃあ、その５分間、
吐麗美庵には‥‥？
So for five minutes after
the incident happened...

<Kudo>
あの店長が、ひとりで
見張っとったんだろうな。
Yessiree, the owner was at
Trés Bien on his own.




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥ちょっと、
見ていただきたいんですけど‥‥
Um, would you mind taking a
look at this?

<Kudo>
‥‥‥‥‥‥ぷいっ。
...
Kah!

<Phoenix>
あの、すみません。
Excuse me...

<Kudo>
ワシのグチにトコトンつき合うなら
‥‥チラと見てやってもいい。
You let me get a million of my
grumbles off my chest, and
I'll take one quick look.

ワシのグチは、大地震のごとく
ゆらぎ、ふるえ、飲みこむぞ！
I've got an earthquake of
frustration inside and it's
ready to rumble!

<Phoenix>
‥‥やめとこう。
...On second thought,
forget it.

“トコトン”で“チラ”じゃ
ワリに合わない。
A million grumbles for one
quick look doesn't sound like
a good deal... for me.




同日　某時刻
カリヨーゼ
January 7
Tender Lender

<Maya>
‥‥なんか、フツウじゃない
空気がただよってるね。
...This place gives off a
really strange vibe, doesn't
it?

<Phoenix>
どうも、《ナニワのゼニトラ》は
いないみたいだな。
Looks like "The Tiger" isn't
in his lair.

（‥‥ちょっと、
　ホッとしてしまった）
(And that is, as they say,
a very good thing.)

<Viola>
‥‥いらっしゃいませ‥‥
...Welcome...

<Phoenix>
うっ‥‥
*gulp*

（‥‥この、聞いてるだけで
　死にたくなる、暗ぁい声は‥‥）
(Talk about a creepy voice!
It makes your soul want to
shrivel up and die!)

<Viola>
‥‥ご融資の相談、ですよね‥‥
You're here... to discuss a
loan...?

<Phoenix>
え。いや、その‥‥。
Uh, no. Not exactly...

<Viola>
店長は、外出してますから‥‥
おとなしく、お待ちください‥‥
The manager is away at the
moment...
Wait quietly... please...

<Maya>
行っちゃった。
She's gone! Just like that!

<Phoenix>
しかたないな。
また、あとで来るか。
I guess we'll just have to
come back another time.

<Maya>
ね。ね。なるほどくん。
今がチャンスだよ。
But this is the perfect
opportunity, Nick!

なんか、アヤしげなトコだし。
ちょっと調べてみようよ。
This place reeks of suspicion!
Come on, Nick! Let's take
a look around, OK?

<Phoenix>
だ、だいじょうぶかな‥‥。
Do you think it'd be OK...?

<Maya>
ヘーキだって。バレやしない‥‥
Of course! No one will ever
know...

<Viola>
‥‥お茶‥‥
...Coffee...?

<Maya>
ひゃひゃああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Viola>
ここに、置いておきますから‥‥
I'll leave it here for you
to enjoy... Quietly.

<Phoenix>
はは、ハイッ！
ど、ど、どうも。
Y-Yes!
Thank you!

<Viola>
‥‥机には
さわらないでくださいね‥‥
Do not touch the desk...
Please...

<Maya>
なな、なるほどくん！
かかか、帰ろう！
N-N-Nick!
Let's g-get out of here!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(NOW she wants to get out
of here...)




<???>
コォラァアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
アアアアアアアアアアアアアアアア
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa

ッ！
ar!

<Maya>
きゃわわわああああああッ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、デスクの下に
　かくれちまったぞ‥‥！）
(Come out from under the
desk, Maya!)

<The Tiger>
ヒトの事務所、ナニ勝手に
いじくりまわしとるんやワレェッ！
Whad are youse two snoopin'
around in my office for!?

<Phoenix>
い、いえベツに、ぼくは
N-Nothing. W-We were just...

<The Tiger>
うおわあああああああああああッ！
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar!

ワイのお宝ジュータンがコレ、
ハイまみれになっとるやんけェッ！
My precious carpet! Youse got
ash on my rug!

キサマやなッ！
You' gonna wish your ugly
feet never came through
my door!

<Phoenix>
ちち、ちがいますよ！
ぼくたちが来たときには、すでに
I-It wasn't us!
It was already like th--

<The Tiger>
‥‥エエ度胸やなァ、ニイちゃん。
Youse wanna argue with me!?
Is that what you' doin'? You
dink youse can take me on!?

ボテくりこかしまわしてさらにコレ
シバきたおしたろかいワレェェッ！
I'm gonna flatten youse two
into pancakes and turn youse
into my new rugs!

<Maya>
きゃわわわわああああああッ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Viola>
‥‥あら‥‥
...Oh...

‥‥帰っていらしたの‥‥
トラさま‥‥
Don Tigre... You're back...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥この、地の底から聞こえる、
　うらみがましい声は‥‥）
(Ack... That voice... It's
like evil seeping into your
head through your ears...)

<Viola>
ごめんなさい‥‥トラさま‥‥
...I'm sorry... Don Tigre...

‥‥そのハイザラ、わたしが
ひっくり返しましたの‥‥
I knocked over that ashtray
before... and...

<Phoenix>
（うわあ‥‥イノチ知らずだな。
　ドナり倒されるぞ‥‥）
(Eek! Has she got a
death wish, or what!?)

<The Tiger>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あ‥‥そ、そうなんや。
Oh, right.

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

<The Tiger>
う、うらみちゃんなら‥‥ま。
しゃアないな。うん。しゃアない。
F-Forget about it, Violetta.
I-It's noddin'...

<Phoenix>
（なな、なんだなんだなんだ！）
(What, what, what!?)

<The Tiger>
カワイイうらみちゃんのコトや。
なんでも。ゆ、ユルしたるでェ！
I ain't gonna get mad at you.
You' too cute, you hear!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥不公平だ！）
(That's so unfair!)

<Viola>
‥‥わたし、ビスケットを焼いて
待ってましたの‥‥
Here... Have some cookies...
I just baked them...

融資の話をしながら、
濃厚なお茶をいただきましょう‥‥
And you'll need some strong
espresso... while you're
discussing your loan...

<The Tiger>
コラァアアアアアッ！
成歩堂　龍一ィィッ！
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar!
Phoenix Wright!

<Phoenix>
‥‥は、はい！
Y-Yes!?

<The Tiger>
やるのォ‥‥。ついに
ここまで、たどり着いたか‥‥
Youse either crazy or just
plain stupid to chase after
me!

ゴクロウなコトや。わざわざ、
ホンモノが出てくるとはなァ‥‥
I worked so hard, but now
youse gotta come and mess
up my plan...

<Phoenix>
（ぜ、ゼニトラ‥‥
　やっぱり、コイツが‥‥）
(So it was him...
He's my phony...)

<The Tiger>
まあ‥‥。何度やっても
アンタの負けは、動かへんでェ。
Heh, but I don't care.
No one gets in my way!

<Phoenix>
な、なんだと？
‥‥いや、なんですって？
Wh-What?
I mean, e-excuse me?

<The Tiger>
クククク‥‥あんなコムスメ、
ほっておけばいいものを‥‥。
Heh heh heh!
Youse shoulda left de little
girl at home, Wright.

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥
聞きたいことがあるんですけども
Um... I have a few things
I want to ask--

<The Tiger>
おらァアアアアアアァァァァァッ！
Gwoaaaaaaaaaaaaaar!

<Maya>
きゃわわわわああああああッ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<The Tiger>
ワイには聞きたいコトなんかない！
もう、会うこともないで！
No questions! Dis is de
last time we meet!

<Phoenix>
あ！　待てッ！
‥‥いや、待ってください！
Ack! Wait!
P-Please!

<Maya>
‥‥いやー、情けないねー
なるほどくん。
...That was pretty weak, Nick.

<Maya>
声が届かなくなるまで待ってから
“待てッ！”だもんね。
You waited until he was out
of earshot before you shouted
after him.

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃんに
　言われたくないぞ‥‥）
(Like you're one to talk!
I didn't hear you scream,
"Hold it!" either!)

<Viola>
‥‥お茶‥‥
...The espresso...

<Maya>
きゃはああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Viola>
‥‥さらに、ビスケット‥‥
お持ちしました‥‥
...And cookies...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ホント、シンゾウに
　悪いな、このヒト‥‥）
(This woman is definitely not
good for my heart.)

（“うらみちゃん”とか
　呼ばれてたっけ‥‥）
(Now, what was it The Tiger
called her...? "Violetta"?)




<Maya>
なにこれ。
What's this?

<Phoenix>
サンドバッグだよ。
It's a punching bag.

<Maya>
えー！　あたしはヤだな。
こんなバッグ、持ち歩くの。
What!? No way. You wouldn't
catch me walking around with
a bag like that!

<Phoenix>
‥‥“持ち歩く”？
What do you mean, "walking
around"?

<Maya>
デザインはカッコわるいし、
だいいち、重すぎて持てないよ。
The design's gross to start
with, and it's way too heavy
to be practical.

“サンド”っていうワリに、
何も挟んでないしねえ‥‥
And why's it called a
"punching"-bag? Don't people
know messenger bags are in!

やっぱりあたしは、パリっぽく
キメてみたいな。
I knew it. I was right before,
back at Trés Bien. Paris
fashion is more my thing.

<Phoenix>
（どうやら、《ハンドバッグ》の
　仲間だと思ってるらしいな‥‥）
(...I really, really hope
she's pulling my chain on
this one.)




<Phoenix>
“三日坊主”‥‥か。
"Win Through Compromise"...?

<Maya>
あたしのコトじゃないよ。
I wonder what that's supposed
to mean...

<Phoenix>
なんでこんなコトバを
わざわざ、かざってるのかな。
It must mean something if they
took the trouble to frame it
like that.

<Maya>
さあねえ。‥‥あたしのコトじゃ
ないのはたしかだけど。
Yeah well, it still doesn't
make any sense to me...

<Viola>
‥‥それ‥‥
...That...

<Maya>
きゃはわわあああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Viola>
《カリヨーゼ》の
経営理念なんです‥‥
That's Tender Lender's
guiding principle.

<Maya>
けいえいりねん‥‥？
Oh?

<Viola>
『一度つかまえた客は、３日で
　丸ボーズにムシるべし』‥‥
"Compromise the customer
to win."

<Maya>
ど、どうかな？　なるほどくん。
O-Oh, I see...
How about you, Nick...?

<Phoenix>
ぼ、ぼくは今の髪型が
気に入ってるから。
Yeah, umm... Well, as long
as we don't have to compromise
my hair, I'd say we're OK...

（‥‥そんなスローガン、客に
　セツメイするなよ‥‥）
(That's one slogan no business
owner should ever explain to
their customers... *shudder*)




<Phoenix>
まぶしい金のデスクに
ＣＤプレイヤーが置いてある。
There's a CD player on the
desk. But the desk is so loud,
it's a wonder you can hear it.

<Maya>
フタがあいてるよ。‥‥どんな
音楽を聞いてるのかな、ゼニトラ。
The lid's open.
I wonder what kind of music
The Tiger's into.

<Viola>
‥‥飲みましたか‥‥お茶‥‥
Have you finished...
...the coffee?

<Maya>
ひゃひゃあああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
え、ええ、飲みました。
ご、ごちそうさま。
Y-Yes, thanks.
It was... lovely.

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥そうですか‥‥
飲んじゃったんですか‥‥ククッ。
So...
You drank it... all?
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥ぐ。
...
*gulp*

<Viola>
‥‥これ以上、何かさわったら‥‥
もう１ぱい、飲んでもらいます‥‥
...If you touch anything else
that doesn't belong to you...
There's always another cup...

<Phoenix>
（な‥‥ナニが入ってたんだ！
　さっきのお茶！）
(Th-That coffee!
I-It was laced with something!
I'm almost sure of it!)

<Maya>
なな、なるほどくん。
おなかがイタい！　イタいよお！
Nick! My stomach...
It's killing me!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

気のせいかな。
Oh, wait.
Maybe it was just the burger
I ate for breakfast...

<Phoenix>
だ、だといいけど‥‥。
I-I sure hope so...

（とにかく、今のうちに
　ＣＤを見ておくか‥‥）
(We better take a look at
that CD while we're still
alive and have the chance...)

ああああああ‥‥ッ！
What the...!?

<Maya>
な、なに？
やっぱり、ナニワ節‥‥？
What!? It's not the Rocko
soundtrack, is it?
Claw of the Tiger?

<Phoenix>
このＣＤ‥‥どうやら、
サンプルらしいよ。
It's... It's a demo CD...

サインペンでバンドの
名前が書いてある。
The artist's name has been
hand-written on the disc in
pen.

《クリーニング・ボンバー》
‥‥って。
"MC Bomber"...

<Maya>
ええええええッ！
WHAT!?

<Phoenix>
（これが‥‥マコちゃんの
　言っていたＣＤか‥‥！）
(This must be the CD Maggey
told us about!)

<Maya>
き、聞いてみようよ！　きっと、
“ろっけん・ろーる”だよ！
Let's listen to it!
I bet it's heavy metal!

<Phoenix>
ダメだよ！　お茶を飲まされる。
No way! That woman'll make
us drink more coffee if we do!

< >
《クリーニング・ボンバー》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
MC Bomber added to the Court
Record.




<Maya>
うわー、ハイザラが
ひっくり返ってるよ。
Oh, no. Someone's dropped the
ashtray on the floor.

これって、おそうじが
タイヘンなんだよねー。
That's going to be a nightmare
to clean up.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥
ジュータンの上だもんな。
Yeah. It's all over the rug
and everything.

<Maya>
あたしもムカシ、火バチを
ひっくり返してさ。
I accidentally knocked over a
really big space heater once.
Cleaning up was such a pain.

泣きながらハイを
集めたっけ。
It was one of those super
antiques where you have
to burn a ton of charcoal.

<Phoenix>
（火バチなんて、どうやったら
　ひっくり返せるんだ‥‥？）
(How did she manage to knock
one of those over? Aren't they
supposed to be super heavy?)

<Maya>
‥‥おっ！マッチが落ちてたよ。
Oh, hey! There's a book of
matches here, too!

<Phoenix>
へえ。今どき、紙マッチなんて
めずらしいな‥‥‥‥‥‥？
Matches, huh? Places don't
give those out much nowadays.
...Hey, wait a second!

<Maya>
どうしたの？
What is it?

<Phoenix>
この紙マッチ‥‥
《吐麗美庵》って書いてある！
Look what's printed on the
back! It says, "Trés Bien"!

< >
《吐麗美庵のマッチ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Trés Bien Matches added to
the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（このマッチ‥‥
　使えるかもしれないな‥‥）
(These matches could come in
handy. We might be able to
use them...)

<Maya>
そうだね。‥‥事務所のコンロ、
なんか調子ワルいし。
Yeah. The pilot light for the
office boiler keeps going out.

<Phoenix>
‥‥そういうコトじゃ
ないんだ。
Swing and a miss, Maya.
Swing and a miss.




<Maya>
ダルマさんって、エラいよねー。
Let's see...
This round doll thing is
called a "daruma"... I think.

何度コロがしても、
ムクッて起きあがるんだもん。
I figured I'd read a book or
two and be more cultured,
in case you're wondering.

<Phoenix>
こんなデカいダルマでも、
やっぱり起きるのかな。
You mean you aren't making
stuff up for a change?

<Maya>
ほおほお。それはキョーミ深い
モンダイだねー。
Heh. I bet you also didn't
know that no matter what,
he'll always right himself.

ほら。ほら。なるほどくん。
転がす転がす。
Go on, Nick!
Give him a good shove!

<Phoenix>
む、ムチャ言うなよ。
Only if I feel like dying!

<Maya>
こっちには、ショウギの
コマがあるね。《金将》だって。
Now, this yellow thing...
This is a Japanese chess
piece. I think it's a "king"?

ま。あたしは五目ならべしか
知らないけどね。
Not that I'm an expert or
anything... I'm more of a
Reversi person, you know.

<Phoenix>
（それはショウギですら
　ないぞ‥‥）
(Assuming she knows what she's
talking about, these aren't
exactly your typical...)

<Phoenix>
(..."mobster wannabe" items.
They're not... "trophies",
are they...? *gulp*)

<Maya>
‥‥あれ。
Hey...

‥‥なんか、ショウギのコマの
下から、紙キレがのぞいてるね。
There's a piece of paper
sticking out from under here.

<Phoenix>
なんだ、コレ。
‥‥《修理代請求書》か‥‥。
What is it?
...A repair bill?

（自動車の修理をしたらしいな）
(Looks like he did some
repair work on his car...
Does he even have one...?)

バンパーとライトの交換、
１５０万円。‥‥高ェ！
$15,000 to replace a bumper
and a light!? That's insane!

<Maya>
クルマの持ち主は‥‥
《シカバネ組》だって。
The car's registered to...
the "Cadaverinis"?

<Phoenix>
なんだ。ゼニトラじゃ
ないのか。
Huh? So it's not even
The Tiger's car?

（他人のクルマの修理代請求書が、
　どうしてこんなところに‥‥？）
(Why would someone else's
repair bill be in The Tiger's
office...?)

< >
《修理代請求書》を
法廷記録にファイルした。
Repair Bill added to
the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
ものすごいジュータンの上に、
ものすごいデスクが置かれている。
That's one impressive desk on
one impressive rug!

<Maya>
黄金だよ、黄金！　やっぱり
ちがうねー、カガヤキが。
It's solid gold, Nick! Gold!
Just look at that shine! Only
real gold shines like that.

<Phoenix>
デスクにカガヤキが
必要なのかな‥‥。
Would you really want such a
shiny desk, though?

<Maya>
どれどれ。黄金の机の
使いごこちは、どうかな。
I don't know, but let's see
what it's like to sit at a
solid gold desk...

‥‥まっ、
まぶしいよ、なるほどくん！
Wow!
I'm completely dazzled!

<Phoenix>
そりゃ、まあ。黄金だからね。
That's because it's
completely dazzling!

<Maya>
それに、自分のハナの穴が
表面に写って、気が散るよ！
I can see up my nose in the
reflection! That's gotta be
really distracting!

<Phoenix>
（使い勝手はよくないみたいだな。
　‥‥トーゼンだけど）
(So the desk isn't practical.
No surprise there.)




<Maya>
お。パリっぽいコートがあるよ。
オシャレさんだねー。
Hey, look at this
Parisian-style coat!
It's so chic!

<Phoenix>
（ボクサーのガウンに見えるけど
　‥‥気のせいだよな、モチロン）
(Looks more like a pimp
coat to me... Guess I haven't
got an eye for fashion.)

<Maya>
‥‥あれ。
Hey, look at this...

このスーツ、なるほどくんが
着てるのと同じ色だね。
This suit is the same color
as the one you wear, Nick.

<Phoenix>
同じ色の‥‥スーツ‥‥？
Hmm... The same color
as my suit...?

<Maya>
うわああああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
お‥‥大きな声、出すなよ！
Keep your voice down, Maya!

<Maya>
ななな、なるほどくん！
これ‥‥、ちょっと見てよ
N-Nick!
You've got to take a look at
this!

<Viola>
おせんべい‥‥
Some cake...?

<Maya>
きゃわわああああっ！
Aaaaaaaah!

<Viola>
置いておきますから、ここ‥‥
I'll just leave it here for
you...

<Maya>
あああ、あのあのあの！
あの、あたし‥‥！
Uh... yeah... sure...
I, umm... Thanks...

<Viola>
おとなしく待っててくださいね‥‥
でないと、わたし‥‥
Just wait here quietly...
Otherwise...

<Maya>
は、は、はい！
S-S-Sure!

なるほどくん！　ダメだよ
おとなしくしてなきゃ！
Did you hear that, Nick?
Wait quietly, she said!

<Phoenix>
え！　は、はあ。
Y-Yeah! Sure!

<Viola>
‥‥わたし‥‥見てますから‥‥。
I have my eye on you...
Only so I can "take care of
you"... Understand...?

<Maya>
うううう‥‥コワいよお。
Aah! I'm scared, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥で？　さっき、
何か見つけなかった？
...So? What were you getting
so excited about before?

<Maya>
あのね。‥‥スーツのエリに‥‥
Look, on the lapel of this
suit...

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥ッ！　こ、これは‥‥
弁護士バッジ‥‥？
That's...! That's an
attorney's badge!

<Maya>
ゼニトラって、
弁護士なのかな‥‥？
Is The Tiger a lawyer!?

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや！　このバッジ、
ボール紙でできてるじゃないか！
No way! Look at this badge!
It's made of paper!

< >
《紙のバッジ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Paper Badge added to
the Court Record.

<Maya>
なんか、なるほどくんのバッジが
急に安っぽく見えてきたよ。
For some reason, your badge
suddenly looks really cheap
to me, Nick.

<Phoenix>
（ダレか気づけよ！
　こんなヒドいニセモノ‥‥）
(Why doesn't anyone recognize
an obviously fake badge when
they see one...?)




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥。
この会社のことなんですけど。
So... I'm kind of curious
about your company,
Tender Lender...

<Viola>
‥‥カリヨーゼは、
中小企業のミカタ‥‥
...With the warm and friendly
atmosphere you'd expect from
a family-sized business...

良心的な金利と、返済方法‥‥
みなさん、とてもよろこんで‥‥
...a conscientious rate of
interest... and an attractive
repayment policy...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥語尾が聞きとりにくいのが
　ちょっと気になるな）
(Why do I get the feeling this
sentence is not going to end
well...?)

<Viola>
闇金融業界の中で、他よりほんの
少し、明るめのカリヨーゼ‥‥
...we will tenderly lend you
that little bit extra, here at
Tender Lender...

<Maya>
そういえば、ウチの事務所も今、
ちょっと苦しいよね。
Hey, Nick. Things are a bit
tight for Wright and Co. at
the moment, aren't they?

トランプの勝負で、なるほどくん、
あたしに５万円の借りがあるし。
I mean, there's that 500
dollars you owe me from our
card game for starters.

<Maya>
ホラ、なるほどくん。
借りる借りる。
Why don't you take out a
loan?

<Phoenix>
（だだ、だいじょうぶかなあ‥‥）
(Would I like to take out a
loan from a place like this?
Not so much...)

<Viola>
‥‥カリヨーゼは、そんな
アナタのミカタ‥‥ククッ‥‥。
Tender Lender is...
on your side...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
あの。もし返すのが遅れたら、
どうなるんですか？
So, um, let's say I'm late
with my repayment... What
happens then?

<Viola>
‥‥とびきり濃いお茶と‥‥
‥‥‥‥‥を飲んでもらいます‥‥
...We'd give you more
coffee...
...Strong coffee...

<Phoenix>
よそう。借金、踏み倒した
ほうがマシだ。
Um, right...
I think I'd rather skip town!

<Maya>
あたしのお茶も濃いからね！
Hey! Just remember I can
make strong coffee too, Nick!
Strong tea, as well!




<Phoenix>
ええと‥‥事件のことは、
ご存じですか？
So, um, do you know about the
incident we're investigating?

<Viola>
‥‥事件‥‥
What incident...?

<Maya>
レストランで、男の人が
毒のコーヒーを飲んだ、アレです。
Well, a man was poisoned in a
restaurant just near here.
That incident.

<Viola>
‥‥さあ‥‥
Let me see...

‥‥その日は、店長と
お店にいましたから‥‥
I was here that day, with
the manager...

<Phoenix>
店長‥‥って、ゼニトラさんの
ことですか？
The manager being
The Tiger...?

<Viola>
‥‥芝九蔵　虎ノ助（しばくぞう
とらのすけ）‥‥
...Furio Tigre...

<Maya>
し、しばくぞう‥‥
F-Furio...

<Phoenix>
と、とらのすけ‥‥
（《ナニワのゼニトラ》‥‥か）
...T-Tigre?
(So that's where the "Tiger"
thing comes from...)

<Maya>
なるほどくんのニセモノだよ！
もっと、ハナシを聞こうよ！
Xin Eohp's got a real name!
Nick! Hurry up and find out
more about him!




<Viola>
‥‥わたし、もともとカラダが
弱いものですから‥‥
I'm very... frail, you see...

‥‥死んでしまいましたの‥‥
一度。‥‥ククッ。
Just recently, I... died...
Once...
Hee... Hee...

<Maya>
しし、死んだ‥‥？
You d-died!?

<Viola>
‥‥今から、４ヶ月ほど前‥‥
About 4 months ago...

‥‥もう絶望的だろう、って
お医者さまが‥‥
The doctors said to...
abandon all hope...

<Phoenix>
（このヒトが“ゼツボー”って
　言うと、シャレにならないな）
(I guess they were expecting
her to take a boat ride
across the River Styx.)

<Viola>
それなのに‥‥
But Don Tigre...

トラさまが、助けてくれた‥‥
すべてを投げうって‥‥
He saved me.
He gave up everything...

<Maya>
す、“すべてを”‥‥？
Everything!?

<Viola>
うれしかった‥‥それで
トラさまのキモチを知って‥‥
When I found out what he had
done for me, I... was happy...

<Maya>
‥‥ちょっと、想像しにくいね。
ショージキなところ。
No offense, but I'm finding
that a little hard to believe.

<Viola>
このヒトのために、一生、お茶を
いれてあげよう、って‥‥
I decided I'd pay him back...
with my life... by serving him
coffee... and espresso...

<Phoenix>
（だいじょうぶなんだろうな。
　そのお茶は‥‥）
(I still wonder about what's
in her coffee...)

あの‥‥ところで、
そのアタマのホータイは‥‥？
So... is that why you've got
that bandage around your head?

<Viola>
ククッ‥‥。これ、ですか‥‥
Hee... Hee... Hee...
This?




<Phoenix>
そのホータイ‥‥
どうしたんですか？
Um, so what's the story with
the bandage?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

手術のアト、なんです‥‥
They put it on after the
operation...

<Maya>
しゅじゅつ‥‥？
Operation?

<Viola>
ちょっと‥‥致命傷を
負ってしまって‥‥ククッ‥‥。
It's just a little injury...
A little, fatal, injury...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Maya>
ちちち、チメーショー！
A f-f-fatal injury!?

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん、ココロに
　致命傷を負ったみたいだ‥‥）
(Maya just suffered one
herself, by the sound of
it...)

さっき言ってた《一度、死んだ》
と言うのは、そのケガですか。
So, that's the injury you were
talking about before when you
said you had died once?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

<Maya>
ううう‥‥なんか、コワいよ
なるほどくん。
Urgh! She really creeps me
out, Nick!

<Phoenix>
（でも‥‥聞き出さないワケにも
　いかない‥‥！）
(Same here. But we've got to
find out the truth!)




<Viola>
手術を受けました‥‥
とても、ムズカシイ‥‥
It was very complicated...
The operation...

脳の前頭葉部に、
大きな手術を‥‥
They opened up my head...
And performed surgery on my
frontal lobe...

<Maya>
うううう‥‥コワいよお‥‥
Urgh! Just thinking about it
sends shivers down my spine!

<Phoenix>
その原因を作った
《致命傷》ですけど‥‥
So how did you get this "fatal
injury" that left you needing
an operation?

<Viola>
‥‥トラさまと
ヤクソクしてますから‥‥
I made a promise to
Don Tigre...

“ダレにも言わない　ウソついたら
　お茶１００パイ、飲ーます”と。
I said I would never tell...
Cross my heart and hope to
drink 100 cups of espresso...

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
（飲みたくないな、そりゃ‥‥）
Oh.
(That much caffeine would
raise anyone from the dead!)

<Viola>
それに‥‥
Besides...

大切な“思い出”なんです‥‥
It's a very precious memory
to me...

<Phoenix>
お、おもいで‥‥ですか‥‥？
（解除するしかない、な‥‥）
A... A precious memory...?
(I'll never find out what she
means if I can't break her...)




<Viola>
４ヶ月前‥‥交通事故にあって
手術を受けた‥‥
Four months ago... I was in a
traffic accident... That's
why I needed the operation...

わたし‥‥気づいてました‥‥。
たいした手術じゃない、って‥‥
When I woke up... they told
me it was nothing serious...
A simple procedure...

<Maya>
え！　そ、そうだったんですか！
Oh! Really?

<Phoenix>
（まあ、４ヶ月で治ってるぐらい
　だもんな‥‥）
(Well, I guess if she
recovered in 4 months, it
couldn't have been too big...)

<Viola>
手術代は‥‥１億円‥‥
そう聞きました‥‥
They said the operation...
cost one million dollars...

<Maya>
い‥‥い‥‥
いちおくえんンンッッッッ！
A... A...
A million bucks!?

<Viola>
‥‥おじいさまが。トラさまに
払うように、って‥‥
My grandfather ordered
Don Tigre to pay...

‥‥１億円のほとんどは‥‥
“オトシマエ”だった‥‥
One million dollars...
In "compensation"...

<Maya>
なあに？　“オトシマエ”って‥‥
"Compensation", huh...?

<Phoenix>
ウラの社会で、セキニンを
とること、だよ。
It's underworld lingo for
paying money to settle a
score.

‥‥たいてい、タイヘンな
目にあうみたいだね。
Basically, pay or get into
some serious trouble!

（イチオクエン‥‥か）
(But a million bucks!?)

（どうやら、つながったな。
　今回の事件と‥‥）
(This has to be related to
our poisoning case somehow...)




<Viola>
‥‥信じていたかった‥‥
トラさまのコトバ‥‥
I wanted to believe him...
I wanted to trust what
Don Tigre said...

おじいさまは‥‥鹿羽　権太は
いっさい、カンケイない。
He said it had nothing to do
with my grandfather being
Bruto Cadaverini...

“わたしだから”助けてくれた。
　そう思っていたかった‥‥
I wanted to believe he helped
me because he cared about me.
Not about my grandfather...

そうじゃないことは‥‥
はじめから、わかっていたのに。
But I knew...
That wasn't really true...

<Maya>
う、うらみさん‥‥
Wow. I'm so sorry.

<Viola>
トラさま‥‥１億円を払うために、
あんな、ひ‥‥ヒドいコトを‥‥
What he did to get the money
was... It was... evil!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥！
...!

<Viola>
“わたしのためだから”って‥‥
そう、自分に言い聞かせて‥‥
He said it was all for me...
So I...

だから、わたし‥‥
‥‥手伝ってしまった‥‥
I helped him...

<Maya>
て、“手伝った”‥‥？
You helped him?
In what way?

<Viola>
これ‥‥お持ちください。
Here... Take these...

<Phoenix>
（これは‥‥診断書‥‥？）
(What are these? Medical
papers?)

<Viola>
わたし‥‥‥
《鹿羽組》のムスメですから‥‥
I'm Bruto Cadaverini's
granddaughter...

オトシマエ‥‥つけなくては
いけないんですよね‥‥
He had to pay compensation...
He was made an offer... He
simply... couldn't... refuse.

< >
証拠品《うらみの診断書》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Viola's Medical Papers added
to the Court Record.

<Maya>
‥‥かわいそうだね。
うらみさん。
Wow, I feel so bad for Viola.

<Phoenix>
ユルせない。
It's inexcusable!

<Maya>
え‥‥？
Huh?

<Phoenix>
（ぼくには、どうしても
　ユルせないものが、２つある）
(There are two things that
I consider inexcusable.)

（“毒薬”と“ウラぎり”‥‥）
(Poisoning, and betrayal!)

（最もヒキョウで、最も深く
　人をキズつける‥‥）
(Only a coward would hurt
people using either of these
tactics.)

<Maya>
な、なるほどくん‥‥？
Is everything alright, Nick?

<Phoenix>
じゃあ‥‥ぼくたちも、そろそろ
行こうか。
We should get going.

‥‥このお茶を飲んだら。
Right after we finish
our espresso.

<Maya>
そうだね‥‥。
Yeah.

<Phoenix>
（うらみさんに関する証拠は
　もう、いらないな‥‥）
(I won't need to convince
Viola of anything else, so I
guess I can get rid of this.)

< >
《修理代請求書》を
ゴミ箱に捨てた。
Repair Bill thrown into the
trash.




<Phoenix>
ゼニトラ‥‥芝九蔵さんのこと、
聞かせていただけませんか。
Can I ask you about The Tiger,
I mean, Mr. Tigre?

<Viola>
‥‥ビスケット‥‥
...Cookie...?

<Maya>
は、はい？
S-Sure...?

<Viola>
いかがですか‥‥。わたしが
焼いたんですけど‥‥ククッ‥‥。
How do you like my cookies?
I baked them myself...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Maya>
なるほどくん、お先にどうぞ。
Go ahead, Nick!
The honor is all yours!

<Phoenix>
いやいや。真宵ちゃんこそ。
No, no! Ladies first, Maya!

<Viola>
‥‥ククッ。
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
（どうも、よくわからない。
　どうしてゼニトラは‥‥）
(No matter how I look at
this, I just don't get it...)

（こんなコワいヒトと
　いっしょにいるんだろう‥‥？）
(What are The Tiger and this
scary girl doing working
together?)

<Viola>
‥‥わたしたち‥‥
愛しあっていますから‥‥
We... are lovers...

<Phoenix>
（そんな、うらめしげに
　言われてもなあ‥‥）
(That's not exactly coming
across in your tone of
voice...)

<Viola>
イノチの恩人なんです。
トラさま‥‥
And I owe Don Tigre my life...
He's the one who saved me...

<Phoenix>
あの、ゼニトラが‥‥？
The Tiger... saved you...!?

<Viola>
“トラさま”とお呼びください‥‥
でないと、わたし‥‥
Please, address him properly
as "Don Tigre". Otherwise,
I'll have to...

<Phoenix>
とと、トラさまですね、はい！
OK, OK! Don Tigre!
Of course! I'm sorry.

（イノチの恩人、ねえ‥‥
　もう少し、話を聞いてみるか）
(He saved her life?
I'd sure like to know how
that happened.)




<Phoenix>
このヒト‥‥あなたの
おじいさん、なんですか？
This man is your grandfather,
right?

<Viola>
そんな写真‥‥持ち歩かない
ほうがいいです‥‥
Carrying a picture like that
around with you...
You should watch your back...

<Phoenix>
‥‥え。
Th-Thanks for the advice...

<Viola>
‥‥組のヒトが、いつもわたしを
カゲから見てるから‥‥
The family is always watching
me... from the shadows...

<Phoenix>
（く、組のヒト‥‥？）
(The "family"?)

<Maya>
あ、あのダルマの中が
あやしいよ、なるほどくん！
I thought I saw something
suspicious under the corner
of that rug!

<Viola>
ヘタに動くと‥‥
消されますよ‥‥ククッ。
One wrong move and... you
might disappear forever...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥コワい世界だなあ‥‥）
(This feels like Halloween...
Only a whole lot more real...
And a whole lot scarier, too.)




<Phoenix>
あの。これ、なんですけど‥‥。
Um, about this...

<Viola>
‥‥お茶‥‥
おかわり、いれてきますね‥‥。
More coffee...?
You must have more...

<Phoenix>
い、いえいえ！　ケッコウです！
（ノドはカラカラだけどな‥‥）
No! Um, thanks!
I've had enough. Really!
(I'm so thirsty!)

<Viola>
わたし‥‥トラさましか
目に入りませんから‥‥ククッ。
I don't leave the office...
I can't tell you about
anything... except Don Tigre.




< >
～アタマの包帯～
-- The Head Bandage --

<Phoenix>
アタマの包帯‥‥
“手術のアト”なんですよね？
You said that bandage around
your head was from an
operation?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
脳に“致命傷”を負った、とか。
You also said you suffered
a "fatal injury" to the head,
correct?

<Viola>
‥‥ええ‥‥ムズカシイ手術
だったそうです‥‥
Yes...
The operation was very...
difficult, apparently...




<Phoenix>
“致命傷”ということは‥‥
“ケガ”をしたんですよね？
Now, by "fatal injury", you
mean you were hurt very
badly somehow, right?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥ククッ。
...
Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
“ケガ”の原因‥‥。この証拠品と
関係があるんじゃないですか？
Did the injury in question
have something to do with
this?


<Phoenix>
どうですか！
Well!?

<Viola>
おいなりさん‥‥。
Donuts...?

<Phoenix>
は？
Huh?

<Viola>
‥‥わたし、にぎってきたんです。
‥‥おいなりさん‥‥
I baked them myself...
Home-made donuts...

いただきませんか‥‥？
Have one...

<Phoenix>
あの。ナニが入ってるんですか？
Umm, what's inside?

<Viola>
‥‥ごはんと‥‥‥‥‥‥と‥‥。
Jam, and...
...

<Phoenix>
え？　よく聞こえません
でしたけど。
I'm sorry, but I didn't quite
catch that...

<Viola>
‥‥ククッ‥‥。
Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
‥‥い、いりません。
（シッパイみたいだな‥‥）
Um... Thanks, but no thanks...
I think I'll pass.
(I guess that was a flop.)

（彼女がなぜ、アタマに
　それほど大きなケガをしたのか）
(What happened to this woman
for her to have such a huge
bandage around her head?)

（その“原因”をニオわせる
　証拠品、ないかな‥‥？）
(There must be some piece of
evidence that'll prompt her to
tell me what happened...)


<Phoenix>
ここに、自動車の修理代の
請求書があります。
I have here a car repair bill.

当然、考えられるのは‥‥
交通事故、ですよね。
From this, it seems pretty
obvious that this car was
involved in an accident.

<Viola>
‥‥その請求書‥‥
見せてください‥‥
Let me see that...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

修理代の受取人‥‥
《鹿羽組》‥‥ですか‥‥
This bill is made out to the
"Cadaverinis"...?

<Phoenix>
そ、そうですね。
Y-Yes, it is.




<Viola>
わたし‥‥自己紹介した
おぼえ、ないのですけど‥‥
I don't think... I ever
introduced myself...

この《鹿羽組》とわたし‥‥
どういうカンケイなんですか？
Tell me... what do the
"Cadaverinis"... have to do
with me...?

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥自己紹介して
　くれそうなフンイキじゃないな）
(Something tells me she's not
about to say hi and introduce
herself... Alright, then...)

あなたと、《鹿羽組》の
カンケイは‥‥
Your relationship with the
Cadaverinis is very strong...
And this is why.


<Phoenix>
さあ、いかがですか！
So!? What do you have to
say for yourself now!?

<Viola>
たくあん‥‥なんですけど‥‥
Pretzels...
For you...

<Phoenix>
はい？
Huh?

<Viola>
このたくあん‥‥
キレイな黄色でしょう‥‥？
Don't worry about the
little white specks on
the surface...

この色を出すために‥‥
‥‥‥‥‥を入れましたから‥‥。
I just sprinkled a small
quantity of...
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥ケッコウです。
（シッパイか‥‥）
...N-No thanks!
(My evidence must still
be half-baked...)

<Viola>
‥‥《鹿羽組》なんて知りません。
‥‥そもそも、わたし‥‥
I really don't know...
the "Cadaverinis"...
Further...


<Phoenix>
あなたのことは、わかっています。
‥‥鹿羽　うらみさん。
I know exactly who you are,
Viola Cadaverini!

あなたの、そのケガ‥‥
交通事故、だったんですね？
You sustained that injury in
a traffic accident, didn't
you?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Viola>
４ヶ月ほど前のコトでした‥‥
It happened about 4 months
ago...

組のクルマの前に、いきなり
飛び出してきた人がいました‥‥
I was driving in one of our
family's cars... when someone
pulled out in front of me...

<Viola>
オートバイ、だったような‥‥
よく、おぼえていません‥‥
It was a motorbike... or
something like that...
I don't remember it much...

そのオートバイと接触して、
ハンドルを切りそこねて‥‥
Anyway, I swerved to try to
avoid it, but...

‥‥わたし、打ちどころが
悪かったそうです。‥‥異常に。
...I took a blow... to the
head... A bad one.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんか、
　わかる気がするな‥‥）
(Yeah, I can imagine...)

それで‥‥その、飛び出してきた
人は、どうなったんですか？
So what happened to the person
on the bike?

タダじゃすまなかったと
思いますけど‥‥。
I'm guessing they didn't get
away with injuring THE Viola
Cadaverini, right?

<Viola>
‥‥わたし、知りません‥‥
I... don't know...
what happened to them...

‥‥そのまま逃げてしまった、
と聞いています‥‥
They ran away...
Or so I heard...

<Phoenix>
逃げた‥‥
Ran away?

<Viola>
そうでなければ、わたし‥‥
ククッ‥‥。
If they'd stayed, I'd have...
Hee... Hee... Hee...




<Phoenix>
（もしかして‥‥その、
　“逃げた人”というのは‥‥）
(Hmm, is it possible...?
Could the person who committed
the hit and run have been...?)


<Phoenix>
あなたの事故の原因を
作ったのは、もしかして‥‥
The person who caused the
accident that gave you
that injury was--

<Viola>
‥‥もう、いいんです‥‥。
考えたくないから‥‥
No more...
I don't want to... think about
it anymore...

‥‥それより、トマト‥‥
うちの組でとれたんですけど‥‥
Here... try one of these
tomatoes...

わたしが調合した薬が
たっぷりと‥‥ククッ‥‥。
We all picked them together...
as a family... And I added my
own, special, flavoring...

<Phoenix>
た、食べません。
N-No thanks!

（交通事故の原因を作った人物は、
　“オートバイに乗っていた”）
(The person who caused the
accident was riding a
motorbike... Who could it be?)


<Phoenix>
‥‥事故の原因を作ったのは、
このオトコ‥‥じゃないですか？
It was this man, wasn't it?
He was the cause of your
accident.

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

と‥‥トラさまじゃない！
わたし、信じません‥‥
It wasn't Don Tigre!
I refuse to believe it!

<Viola>
相手のオートバイ‥‥
わたしのクルマと接触しました‥‥
We collided... The motorbike,
and my car...

でも、トラさまは‥‥ケガなど
していませんでしょう‥‥？
But Don Tigre isn't injured
at all... is he?




<Phoenix>
（ゼニトラは、鹿羽組の
　クルマに接触したんだ‥‥）
(It was The Tiger who
caused Viola to crash.
I can feel it!)

（ロックが割れたということは‥‥
　彼女もそれを疑っている‥‥！）
(Plus, one of her locks just
broke, so she must suspect
it was him, too...)

‥‥ザンネンですが‥‥
I'm sorry, Ms. Cadaverini...

彼が“交通事故にあった”という
可能性を示す証拠があります！
But I have proof that The
Tiger was involved in a
traffic accident on his bike!


<Phoenix>
これが、その証拠ですッ！
And this is my proof!

<Viola>
‥‥ゆでたまご‥‥
おひとつ、いかがですか‥‥
Hard-boiled eggs...?
Please, try one...

<Phoenix>
た、たまご‥‥？
E-Eggs?

<Viola>
わたしが、大切に育てた
ニワトリがうんだタマゴ‥‥
I raised the chickens these
eggs came from myself...

青いヒヨコをうむように、
トクベツなエサを配合して‥‥
I invented a special diet...
so their chicks would be
blue...

<Phoenix>
ややや、やめときます。
N-No, thanks!




<Phoenix>
‥‥“オートバイ”では
ありませんが‥‥
It's not exactly a motorbike,
but...

芝九蔵さん、スクーターを
乗り回していますよね。
...Mr. Tigre rides around on a
scooter, doesn't he?

前のカバーが、ハデに
コワれています。
And you'll notice that the
front wheel guard is badly
damaged.

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
うらみさん‥‥
Ms. Cadaverini...

ホントは、あなたも
気づいているのでは‥‥？
You know the truth, don't you?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥ククッ‥‥
...
Hee... Hee... Hee...

<Phoenix>
この修理代請求書‥‥支払人の名は
芝九蔵　虎ノ助です。
This repair bill was paid by
Furio Tigre.

《鹿羽組》は、事故のハンニンを、
とっくに見つけていたんですよ。
The Cadaverinis have known for
ages who caused the accident,
haven't they?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥もしかしたら‥‥
そうかもしれない‥‥
It's possible...
Perhaps...

‥‥ココロのスミっこで、
そう思っていました‥‥
Somewhere inside me...
I know that may be true...

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり‥‥）
(I knew it...)

<Viola>
‥‥でも‥‥
But...

トラさまは、わたしの
イノチを助けてくれた‥‥
Don Tigre still saved
my life...

手術はとてもむずかしくて‥‥
おカネがかかりました‥‥
The operation was very
complicated... It was very,
very expensive...

<Phoenix>
いったい、いくらぐらい‥‥？
How much are we talking?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥とても。
とても、たくさん‥‥。
...
Very, very, very expensive...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どうやら、金額は
　言いたくないみたいだな‥‥）
(She seems kind of hesitant
about giving me an actual
figure. I should back off...)

それを支払ったのが‥‥
ゼニトラ、というわけですか。
Well, anyway, it was The Tiger
who paid for it, right?

<Viola>
‥‥なんとか助かってから‥‥
トラさまが、言ってくれました‥‥
After I recovered...
Don Tigre told me...




<Viola>
“うらみちゃんだから”
おカネを出した、って‥‥
He said he paid for the
operation because...
he cared about me...

わたし‥‥それを
信じてますから‥‥。
I... believe him...

<Phoenix>
‥‥本当に‥‥
そうだったんでしょうか。
Really? But do you honestly
believe that to be true?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
もしかしたら‥‥
Do you want to know what
I think...?

芝九蔵さんが手術代を出したのは、
あなたのためではなく‥‥
I think the reason he paid for
the operation wasn't because
of you, but someone else...


<Phoenix>
‥‥あなたには、ショックだと
思います。しかし‥‥！
I know this must be quite a
shock for you, but...

<Viola>
ちゃんちゃんこ‥‥
Overcoat...?

<Phoenix>
は、はい‥‥？
S-Sorry?

<Viola>
わたし、作りました‥‥
‥‥最近、とてもサムいから‥‥
I made it myself...
It's been so... cold lately...

<Phoenix>
（この声を聞いてるほうが
　ココロまで冷えこむぞ‥‥）
(Yeah, just hearing your
voice sends shivers down
my spine!)

<Viola>
どうぞ。着てください。
‥‥‥‥あ‥‥‥‥
Please, try it on...
...
...Oops!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
今の“あ”は、なんですか？
...
What was the "oops" for?

<Viola>
‥‥マチバリ‥‥足りない‥‥
I'm missing a few pins...
I must have left them in the
coat...

<Phoenix>
や、やっぱり
エンリョしておきます！
O-On second thought,
I'm fine, thanks!
Roasty-toasty, that's me!

<Viola>
トラさま‥‥わたしに
言ってくれたんです‥‥
Don Tigre told me, you see...


<Phoenix>
‥‥こんなコト、言っちゃ
いけないのかもしれませんけど‥‥
Perhaps I shouldn't be saying
this, but...

おじいさんの鹿羽　権太さん、
闇金融のボス、なんですよね？
...your grandfather, Bruto
Cadaverini, controls a lot of
"dubious" cash, right?

そして、マゴのあなたを
生きがいにしている。
And you are his beloved pride
and joy.

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
その手術代の金額にも
よりますけど‥‥、
Sure, I don't know exactly
how much the operation cost,
but...

もし、あなたが鹿羽　権太の
マゴでなかったら‥‥
...if you weren't the
granddaughter of
Mr. Cadaverini...

芝九蔵さんは、その
カネを出したでしょうか‥‥？
...do you think Mr. Tigre
would have paid the money?

<Viola>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥いちおくえん‥‥
One million dollars...




<Phoenix>
（今はまだ、証拠が
　足りないのかもしれない）
(I don't think I have enough
evidence yet...)

（もう少し調査をして、
　材料を集めてみるか‥‥）
(I should investigate and
gather some more clues
before I try again...)




< >
‥なるほどくん‥
...Mr. Nick...

‥これ以上つづけると、
ココロがこわれてしまいます‥
...If you push yourself
any more, your soul
will shatter...

‥もう一度、冷静になって
考えなおしましょう‥
...Please calm down,
collect your thoughts,
and try again...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥しまった！
　シッパイしすぎたか‥‥）
(Nnrgh! I've made
too many mistakes!)


