< >
９月１３日　午前　９時３６分
地方裁判所　被告人第４控え室
October 13, 9:36 AM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 4

<Maya>
なっ、なるほどくん！
Hey, Nick!

<Phoenix>
どうした？　何かあったの‥‥？
What is it?
Is something wrong...?

<Maya>
スゴい人気だよ、今日の法廷！
Nah. But did you see all the
people here? It's crazy!

見て、見て！　買っちゃったよ、
怪人☆仮面マスクのブロマイド。
Oh! Look at this!
I bought this Mask☆DeMasque
publicity photo!

<Phoenix>
買った、って‥‥どこで？
You bought that...? Where!?

<Pearl>
裁判所の前に、
屋台がたくさん出ていますよ！
From the little tents in front
of the courthouse. They have
all sorts of things for sale!

<Maya>
あたし、ヨワいんだよねー。
お祭りさわぎ。
You know I'm a sucker for
this kind of stuff!

< >
真宵ちゃんの《ブロマイド》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Mask☆DeMasque Publicity Photo
stuck onto the Court Record.

< >
もお、なんでもいいから、
有罪にしてくださーーーい！
Come on! I'm guilty!
Throw the book at meeeee!

<Pearl>
‥‥あの、キヌを裂くような
殿方のヒメイは‥‥
...Who's screaming like that?

<Ron>
‥‥あ！　成歩堂さん！
いいところに！
...Oh! Mr. Wright!
You made it!

<Phoenix>
なんか、マズいところに
来ちゃったみたいですね‥‥
Yeah, I did. But it doesn't
look like things are going to
get any less ugly for you...

<Ron>
ボク、やっぱりアレなんです！
ハンニンだったんですぅぅぅッ！
Because I did it!!
I'm the criminal! Me! Me!
Meeeeeee!

<Maya>
うううう‥‥また始まったよ。
Ungh... He's at it again.

<Ron>
高菱屋に予告状を出して‥‥
やっちゃいましたーーーっ！
I sent the calling card to
Lordly Tailor! I admit iiiit!!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥カンジンのツボは
持ってないんですよね？
But... You don't have
the Sacred Urn, right?

<Ron>
まあ、そうなんですけど‥‥
Well, that's true, but...

それはそれ、これはこれ
じゃないですか。
That doesn't mean that
I didn't commit the crime.

<Phoenix>
（そんなコトないだろう！）
(Normally, when I say "Of
course you didn't" I'm being
sarcastic, but you... Yikes!)

<Ron>
とにかく、ボク。
ワルモノなワケですから‥‥
Anyway, I admit that
I'm guilty...

今日の裁判、
有罪にしてくださーーーい！
So make sure they
give me a guilty verdict!
Pleeeeease!?

<Desirée>
あ、ユーサクくうん！
グッモオニン！
Oh, there you are Ronnie!
Bonjour, sweetie!

<Ron>
あ！　まま、まれかちゃん！
グッモオニィィン！　‥‥‥いや。
Oh! D-Dessie honey!
B-Bonjour! ...
Well, actually...

どうなんだろ、ここで
わざわざ英語っていうのもなんか
I don't really know why
I should be speaking French
to you at a time like this

<Desirée>
ユーサクくん、アタシにまかせて！
きっと、守ったげるからさ！
Leave it all to me, Ronnie!
I swear I'll protect you!

<Ron>
あ‥‥う、うん‥‥でも。
ボク、なんていうかあの。怪人なの
Ummm, errr... Aaah...
Well, ahh... You see...
Actually the thief is err, me

<Desirée>
いい？　リューイチくん。
Can I tell you something,
Nicky boy?

ユーサクくんの無実は、
このアタシが保証するよ！
I can guarantee that
my Ronnie is innocent!

有罪になんかしたら、
ひきコロしちゃうから！
If he's declared guilty,
I'll be ever so cross with
you!

<Phoenix>
（にこやかに言われても‥‥）
(So why are you smiling
when you say it?)

<Desirée>
じゃ！　アタシ、
ちょっと行くところがあるから。
Well, if you'll excuse me!
I've got some errands
I need to take care of!

よろしくね、リューイチくん！
I'm counting on you,
Nicky boy! Good luck!

<Phoenix>
（天杉　優作が仮面マスクなのか
　‥‥正直なところ、わからない）
(To be honest, I really
don't know whether Ron
is Mask☆DeMasque or not.)

（たしかなコトは、ただ１つ）
(But there's only one thing
I AM sure of.)

（彼は今、《倉院のツボ》を
　持っていない、ということ‥‥）
(He doesn't have the
Sacred Urn right now...)

<Bailiff>
被告人！　そろそろ入廷しなさい！
Mr. DeLite! It's time for you
to enter the courtroom!

<Phoenix>
（今は‥‥まれかさんを
　信じるしかない、な‥‥）
(For the time being,
I guess I'll have to trust
Desirée...)




< >
同日　午前１０時
地方裁判所　第６法廷
October 13, 10:00 AM
District Court
Courtroom No. 6

<Judge>
これより、天杉　優作の
法廷を開廷します。
Court is now in session for
the trial of Mr. Ron DeLite.

<Phoenix>
弁護側、準備完了しています。
The defense is ready, Your
Honor.

<???>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
検察側は？　ジュンビのほうは‥‥
What about the prosecution?
Are you prepared to...

<???>
‥‥くだらねえ。
...What a stupid question!

<Judge>
なな、なんですか！
Wh-What did you say!

<???>
じゃあ、オレから聞こう、裁判長。
アンタはどうなんだ？
Fine. Let me ask you
then, Your Honor.
Are YOU ready?

‥‥できてるのかい？
判決のジュンビは。
Are you ready to pass
judgment?

<Judge>
え！　い、いやいや！
Wh...!
N-No, I... I'm not!

私は、あなたたちのハナシを
聞いてから決めます！
I will pass judgment after
I hear arguments from
both sides.

<???>
‥‥自分にできてないコトを
ヒトに聞いちゃ、いけねえな。
Well, if you're not ready
yourself, you shouldn't
expect others to be.

そいつが‥‥オレのルールだぜ。
That's a rule to live by.

<Judge>
‥‥あの。あなたは‥‥？
...Um, wh-who are you?

<Godot>
ゴドー。
‥‥完全無敗、伝説の検事だ。
I am Godot.
Legendary prosecutor.
I've never lost a case.

<Maya>
あ！　きのう“あいや！”の
探偵さんが言ってた‥‥
Ah!
He's the one that Detective
Atmey was talking about...

<Judge>
‥‥私も、なぜかウワサだけは
聞いたコトがあります。
Yes, your reputation
precedes you.

今まで、どのような事件を
あつかったのですかな？
What kind of cases have
you dealt with so far?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！
そんなもの、ねえさ。
Ha...!
None.

<Judge>
はい‥‥？
What did you say...?

<Godot>
検事席に立つのは、
今日が初めてだぜ。
I've never prosecuted
a case before.

<Judge>
は、初めて？
さきほど“完全無敗”だと‥‥
N-Never?
But you said you've
never lost before.

<Godot>
‥‥どんな検事だって、
最初は無敗さ‥‥
...Exactly. I've never lost.
I've never won before either.

<Judge>
ずいぶん
タイドのデカい新人ですな。
Quite arrogant for a
beginner, aren't you?

<Godot>
‥‥どんな大物だって、
最初は新人さ‥‥
Even the mightiest of
Redwoods begin their lives
as mere saplings.

<Judge>
しかも、なんですか！
法廷内で、仮面なんて‥‥
Yes, but...
A mask? In a court of law?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！
知らねえのかい、裁判長。
Ha...!
Don't you know anything?

ヒトはだれでも‥‥
ココロに仮面をつけてるのさ‥‥
No matter the man, we all
wear masks... Either on our
faces or over our hearts.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Maya>
こりゃホンモノだよ、
なるほどくん‥‥
This guy is the real
deal alright, Nick...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥こんなのばっかりなのか？
　検事って‥‥）
(Why does it seem like
all prosecutors are the
"real deal"...?)

<Godot>
やっと会えたな。
‥‥まるほどう　りゅういち。
So we finally meet...
Mr. Phoenix Trite!

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
...?

<Maya>
な‥‥なるほどくん！
知り合いなの？
N-Nick!
Is he a friend of yours?

<Phoenix>
知り合いはみんな、ぼくを
“なるほどう”って呼ぶよ。
No. I don't have any
friends that call me "Trite".

（あのマスクの下‥‥
　いったい、ダレが‥‥？）
(Just who is this
masked man...?)

<Godot>
オレは、アンタと
戦わなけりゃならねえ。
I've returned from the
depths of Hell...

そのために‥‥
地獄から戻ってきたのさ。
To do battle with you.

<Judge>
それでは、その。後藤検事。
Well then, err,
Prosecutor Gobo.

<Godot>
“ごとう”じゃねえ。
ゴドー‥‥だぜ。
It's not "Gobo".
It's Godot... Your Honor.

<Judge>
とにかく、
冒頭弁論をおねがいします。
In any case, please give
your opening statement.

<Godot>
そんなモノ、
犬にでも食わせちまいな。
Opening statement?
Those things are not fit for
even dogs to consume.

ただ、ひとつだけ。
アンタ。‥‥まるほどう。
I have only one thing to
say before we start.
To you... Mr. Trite.

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんですか？
Wh-What is it?

<Godot>
ヒトには“ウツワのデカさ”
ってモンがあるぜ。
Are you familiar with the
saying, "A chain is only as
strong as its weakest link"?

オレの料理するエモノ‥‥アンタの
サラに、盛りつけられるかな‥‥？
I wonder... how much you can
withstand before you and your
case break in two...?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
それでは、最初の証人の話を
聞くことにしましょう！
Hmm...
Well then, let's hear
from the first witness!

<Gumshoe>
えー、自分は‥‥
Um, my name is...

<Godot>
アンタの名前なんざ、
ダレも聞きたかァねえ。
No one has asked for
your name, witness.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥むぐ。
...Urk.

<Godot>
ダイジなのは、アンタがナニを
知ってるか‥‥それだけだ。
The important thing
is what you know...
That's all.

話してみな。‥‥聞いてやるぜ。
Start talking.
...We're listening.

<Gumshoe>
は‥‥はあ。
Y-Yes, sir.

<Judge>
それでは、証人。
まずは‥‥そうですな。
Alright, witness.
First, let's hear about...

ツボを盗んだという怪人について、
説明していただきましょう。
What you know about the
thief that stole the urn.

<Gumshoe>
リョーカイッス！
Yes, sir!

< >
～仮面マスクの犯行～
-- Mask☆DeMasque's Crimes --

<Gumshoe>
怪人☆仮面マスクは、今から
半年ほど前に現れた、大怪盗ッス。
Mask☆DeMasque is a master
thief that first started his
crime spree 6 months ago.

犯行の前に、かならず予告状を
送ってくる、ナマイキな怪人ッス！
He's so confident that he
sends his calling card before
he even commits the crime!

今度の事件は５回目の犯行で、
やはり高菱屋には予告状が。
This was his fifth heist, and
as usual, he sent a card on
to Lordly Tailor.

ヤツのエモノは、最高の値打ちが
ある美術品にかぎられているッス。
His pattern is to always
go after only the most
precious art pieces.

以上のコトから、仮面マスクの
犯行と断言できるッス！
That's why we're sure it
was Mask☆DeMasque, sir.
It fits his M. O. to a T!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥怪人☆仮面マスク。
ジツはその正体は‥‥
Hmm...
So then the actual identity
of this Mask☆DeMasque is...

ゴドー検事！　あなただった！
なーんて‥‥
M-Mr. Godot!
Y-You!

こここ、コラッ！
審理中ですぞ、ゴドー検事！
W-We're in the middle of a
trial here, Mr. Godot!

<Godot>
‥‥闇よりなお深い暗黒をたたえ、
地獄よりも熱く苦い、コーヒー‥‥
Blacker than a moonless night,
hotter and more bitter than
Hell itself... That is coffee.

オレは、勝手にやらせてもらうぜ。
‥‥そっちも、好きに進めてくれ。
I'm sure you can grant me at
least this much... Your Honor.
Oh, please. Proceed.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
まあ、いいでしょう。
...
Very well.
It's only coffee, after all.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥いいのかよ！）
(What!? You can't be letting
him slide this early in the
trial!)

<Judge>
では、弁護人。
尋問をおねがいします。
Proceed with your cross-
examination, Mr. Wright.

<Maya>
どうするの？　なるほどくん！
Well, Nick?
What are you going to do?

<Phoenix>
とにかく‥‥優作くんの正体が
ハッキリしない以上‥‥、
As long as they haven't
brought up Mr. DeLite's
identity...

“ツボを盗んだのは仮面マスク
ではない”と立証するしかないね。
...all we can do is show that
it wasn't Mask☆DeMasque
who stole the urn.

< >
～仮面マスクの犯行～
-- Mask☆DeMasque's Crimes --




<Gumshoe>
怪人☆仮面マスクは、今から
半年ほど前に現れた、大怪盗ッス。
Mask☆DeMasque is a master
thief that first started his
crime spree 6 months ago.


<Gumshoe>
犯行の前に、かならず予告状を
送ってくる、ナマイキな怪人ッス！
He's so confident that he
sends his calling card before
he even commits the crime!


<Gumshoe>
今度の事件は５回目の犯行で、
やはり高菱屋には予告状が。
This was his fifth heist, and
as usual, he sent a card on
to Lordly Tailor.


<Gumshoe>
ヤツのエモノは、最高の値打ちが
ある美術品にかぎられているッス。
His pattern is to always
go after only the most
precious art pieces.


<Gumshoe>
以上のコトから、仮面マスクの
犯行と断言できるッス！
That's why we're sure it
was Mask☆DeMasque, sir.
It fits his M. O. to a T!


<Maya>
なるほどくん！　やっぱり、
ツボを盗んだのは怪人だよ！
Nick! It definitely looks like
it was Mask☆DeMasque
who stole the urn!

<Phoenix>
でも、優作くんが怪人かどうか‥‥
決定的な証拠はないからね。
But there's no real evidence
either way as to whether Ron
DeLite is Mask☆DeMasque.

<Maya>
そんなあ‥‥
But... But...

<Phoenix>
それに、彼のまわりから
ツボはみつかっていないし。
Also, the urn hasn't turned up
yet, let alone in connection
to Mr. DeLite himself.

<Maya>
仮面マスクがやったに
決まってるのに‥‥
So even though we know it
was Mask☆DeMasque that
did it...

<Phoenix>
（そうじゃないコトを
　立証するんだ‥‥とりあえず！）
(Maybe for the time being,
I should try to show it wasn't
Mask☆DeMasque that did it!)

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
あなたは、最初から
捜査に加わっているんですか？
Have you been involved
in the investigation from
the beginning?

<Gumshoe>
そッス！　自分は、怪人のコトなら
ダレよりも詳しいッス！
Yup!
Nobody knows more about
the thief than me, pal!

‥‥そう！　自分は！　ズヴァリ！
怪人のエスパーッス！
It's true!
I'm a... Zvarri...!
"Author on thieves"!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
えすぱー‥‥って、
超能力者じゃなかったっけ。
An "author"...?
He's written books about
thieves?

<Phoenix>
“エキスパート”のつもり
かもしれないぞ、もしかしたら。
Um, I think he probably
meant to say "authority".

<Gumshoe>
この自分から逃れるとは、
怪人もなかなか、やるッス！
The fact that this guy can
slip through even my fingers
shows how good he is, pal!

<Phoenix>
（イトノコ刑事だから
　逃げられてるんじゃないか？）
(It's easy when those
fingers happen to be
"butter fingers"...)



<Phoenix>
“怪人のコトなら、
　ダレよりも詳しい”‥‥？
So nobody knows more about
the thief than you, huh...?

<Gumshoe>
そッス！　怪人本人と、その
おかあさんの次に詳しいッス！
You got it, pal!
Except maybe for the
thief's mom, that is!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥警察を出し抜いている
人物がいませんでしたか？
But isn't there someone who
knows even more about him
than the police?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥もしかして‥‥あの
“ズヴァリ！”の探偵ッスか？
You don't mean...
"Detective Zvarri", do you?

<Judge>
ふむ。どなたですかな？
その、“図張探偵”というのは？
Hmm... Who is this person?
Zvarri? He sounds German...

<Gumshoe>
星威岳　哀牙ッス。‥‥勝手に
ヒトの名前を作っちゃダメッス。
His name is Luke Atmey, sir.
I guess I shouldn't have made
up such a silly name for him.

<Phoenix>
（なんだよ‥‥たいして有名じゃ
　ないぞ、あの探偵‥‥）
(What the heck?
I guess he's not all
that famous after all...)

<Gumshoe>
たしかにアイツは、前回の犯行で
怪人のエモノを取り返したッス。
Anyway, it's true that he did
manage to retrieve the last
item the thief stole.

<Judge>
‥‥ほお。
ダメですな、アナタは。
...Oh, I see.
It seems you're not the
expert you claim to be.

<Gumshoe>
むぐ‥‥！　たしかに、自分は今、
怪人に、もてあそばれているッス。
...Urk!
I-It looks like the thief is
playing with me, even now!

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
（怪人の“エキスパート”といえば
　あの探偵がいるけど‥‥）
(The real "authority" on the
thief is the other detective.)

（わざわざ聞くほどのコトも
　ないな‥‥）
(I don't need to ask this
one any more questions...)

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
あなたは、その予告状を
すべて見ているんですか？
Have you seen all of these
so-called "calling cards"?

<Gumshoe>
モチロンッス。
‥‥ただ。
Of course I have.
Except...

秘宝展のセキニンシャが
警察に届けなかったせいで‥‥、
The person in charge of the
Treasure Exhibit never brought
their card to the police...

今回の予告状だけは、
犯行後に初めて、見たッス。
So I didn't see this one
until after the crime
occurred.

<Maya>
霧緒さん、アイガ探偵に止められた
から、届けなかったんだよね。
That's because Detective Atmey
stopped Ms. Andrews from
taking it to the police.

<Judge>
その予告状は、
ホンモノだったのですかな？
Was the calling card that
Lordly Tailor received
authentic?

<Gumshoe>
すべての予告状には、
共通のトクチョーがあったッス。
Well, all the cards have one
common, identifying feature.

それらは、一般には
公開されていないッスから‥‥
But we're not releasing
that information to the
general public...

<Judge>
ホンモノと考えて
まちがいないわけですか‥‥。
But you're absolutely certain
that this card is real?

<Phoenix>
（怪人のエンブレムの
　コトだな‥‥）
(Gumshoe can't say it out loud
but I bet he's talking about
Mask☆DeMasque's emblem...)

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
５回目の犯行で‥‥
５回目のシッパイですか。
His fifth heist...
And your fifth screw up, huh?

<Gumshoe>
異議ありッス！
Objection, pal!

自分は、およそ約４回ぐらいほど
シッパイに近いコトをしてるッス！
That ain't fair!
Maybe you could say I
screwed up four times!

しかし！　今回はチガうッス！
予告を知らなかったッスからねえ！
But this last time wasn't my
fault! I didn't know about
the calling card this time!

<Phoenix>
（イバるなよ‥‥）
(You of all people shouldn't
be chuckling about this,
Detective Gumshoe...)

<Gumshoe>
法廷のみなさんに
言っておきたいッス！
I just want everyone here
in the courtroom to know
something!

怪人の予告状を受け取ったら、
クソ探偵なんかに依頼せず、
If you ever get a calling card
from this guy, don't call
some stupid private eye!

気軽に、警察まで
お電話をほしいッス！
Call your local police
right away. Got me?

<Maya>
哀牙探偵のコト、そうとう
目のカタキにしてるみたいだね。
Wow, it looks like he's really
got it in for Detective Atmey.

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
美術品‥‥というと、
たとえば、どんな？
Art pieces?
Like what, for example?

<Gumshoe>
最初のエモノは、あの有名な
《エマノンの涙》ッス。
Well, his first target was the
famous "Tear of Emanon".

<Judge>
それは、なんですかな？
トクベツしょっぱいナミダか‥‥
What's that? Some kind of
especially salty teardrop?

<Gumshoe>
い、いやいや。青いダイヤッス。
ヤツのエモノで、ただ１つの宝石。
N-No, sir.
It's a blue diamond.
A single, rare diamond.

次のエモノは《ボンゴラの宝冠》
‥‥ま、アタマに乗せるモノッス。
Next was the "Crown of
Bongora"... You know, the
thing you put on your head.

その後、《悪魔の左手》
《メジーナ婦人像》とつづくッス。
After that was the "Left Hand
of Hades" and then the
"Portrait of Mejeena", sir.

最後の《婦人像》は、哀牙探偵の
手によって、美術館に戻ったッス。
Detective Atmey retrieved the
"Portrait of Mejeena" and
returned it to the museum.

<Phoenix>
そして‥‥５回目の犯行が
《倉院のツボ》‥‥ですか。
And the target of his fifth
and last robbery was the
"Sacred Urn"... right?

<Judge>
しかし‥‥値打ちのある美術品を
盗んでも、処分に困るのでは‥‥？
But isn't it difficult for him
to dispose of such famous
art pieces...?

<Gumshoe>
おそらく怪人は、地下ルートを
よく知っていると考えられるッス。
Well, we assume he must have
some underworld connections.

<Maya>
優作さん‥‥そんなものに
縁がありそうに見えないよね‥‥
Somehow, Mr. DeLite doesn't
look the type...

<Phoenix>
（“地下”というより“日かげ”
　っていうイメージだよな‥‥）
(Yeah, he's a little too sunny
to be hanging out in the
underworld...)

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
“以上のコト”と言うのは‥‥？
What do you mean when
you say, "it fits his M. O.
to a T"?

<Judge>
あ。私もそれを
聞きたいと思っていました。
I was thinking of asking the
same thing myself.

<Gumshoe>
ううう‥‥ヒトのハナシ、
ちゃんと聞いててほしかったッス。
Ugh...
I wish you would listen
a little more closely, pal.

まずは、予告状ッス。コイツは、
まちがいなくホンモノだったッス。
First of all, there's the
calling card. We're 100%
certain it's authentic.

そして、こちらの警備システムを
読んだかのような手口。
Then there's the fact that
he seemed to know all about
the security system.

さらに、高価な美術品のみを狙う。
‥‥以上、ヤツの犯行の特徴ッス。
And finally, his target was an
art piece. These are all part
of the thief's modus operandi.

<Judge>
今回の犯行も、それらの条件が
当てはまる‥‥と？
And so, since this robbery
seems to fit all those
conditions...?

<Gumshoe>
そッス！　したがって、この事件も
仮面マスクのシワザッス！
That's right! It means that
Mask☆DeMasque is behind it!


<Phoenix>
‥‥ちょっといいですか、
イトノコ刑事。
...Can I ask you a little
something, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
アンタがそう言って“ちょっと”で
すんだコトは一度もないッス。
...Just hearing the "little"
in that question is making me
nervous.

<Phoenix>
『怪人のエモノは、最高の値打ち
モノだけ』‥‥という話でしたね。
You said that he always "goes
after the most precious art
pieces", right?

<Gumshoe>
そッス。
That's right, pal.

<Phoenix>
しかし‥‥今回だけは、
そうではなかった。
But there's one problem...
That's not what he did
in this case.

倉院のツボは、“秘宝”というほど
たいしたシロモノではない！
The supposedly "priceless" urn
doesn't exactly rise to the
level of "precious art"!

<Gumshoe>
なな、なんスと‥‥！
Wh-What do you mean!?

<Maya>
なるほどくん！　そ、それは、
あたしに対するチョーセンなの！
N-Nick! How can you
say such a terrible thing!?

<Phoenix>
いやいや。‥‥金銭的には、だよ。
悪いけど、アレは売れないだろ？
No! I meant from a financial
point of view! I mean, it
wouldn't fetch a good price.

<Judge>
‥‥ゴドー検事、どうなのですか？
あのツボの価値は‥‥
Well, Prosecutor Godot?
What is the value of that urn?

<Godot>
美術鑑定家たちのハナシでは、
ツボに値段はつけられないそうだ。
The appraisers I spoke to
said they couldn't attach
a price to it.

‥‥もちろん、悪いイミで。
And I mean that in the
worst sense.

<Phoenix>
‥‥つまり！
So in other words...

倉院のツボは、仮面マスクが狙う
エモノとして、不自然なのです！
It was not the kind of item
that Mask☆DeMasque would
normally go after!

<Gumshoe>
うぐむッ！
Urk!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥つまり弁護側の
主張は、こういうコトですかな？
Hmm...
If I understand you
correctly, Mr. Wright...

今回の事件‥‥倉院のツボの盗難は
仮面マスクのシワザではない‥‥！
...you're saying that the theft
of the Sacred Urn was not
the work of Mask☆DeMasque...!

<Phoenix>
そ、そういうコト‥‥です。
Y-Yes...
That's what I'm saying.

（ムジュンを指摘したら、自然に
　そうなっちゃったんだけど‥‥）
(Actually all I did was point
out the contradiction. The
argument made itself, but...)

<Judge>
たしかに‥‥まず、そこを
ハッキリさせるべきでしょう。
Well... First of all, we need
to get this issue cleared up.

今回の犯行が、仮面マスクの
シワザか、そうでないか‥‥？
Was this last robbery the work
of Mask☆DeMasque or not?

いかがですかッ、ゴドー検事！
What do you have to say
about this, Mr. Godot?

<Godot>
‥‥このコーヒー‥‥
ゴドー・ブレンド１０７号。
This coffee here...
It's my own special blend.
I call it Godot #107.

刺すような酸味を取るべきか、
からみつく苦味を取るべきか‥‥
I'm trying to decide whether
to cut down on the acidity or
the bitterness...

今、オレに関心があるのは、
それだけだぜ。‥‥まるほどう！
That's the only thing I've got
on my mind right now...
...Mr. Trite!

<Phoenix>
な、なんですか。
Wh-What!?

<Godot>
‥‥アンタもオトコなら、
自分のケツは自分でふくコトだ。
If you're really a man, you
should clean up your own
mess.

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥。悪いけど
イミがわかりません。
Umm...
Sorry, but I don't get
what you mean.

<Godot>
ツボを盗んだのが、もし
怪人の犯行でないとしたら‥‥
If you're saying it wasn't
Mask☆DeMasque that stole
the urn...

その手口をマネた、仮面マスクの
“ニセモノ”ってコトになる。
...then it must be someone
imitating Mask☆DeMasque's
methods... A fake.

<Judge>
に‥‥ニセ☆仮面マスク！
A-A Fake☆DeMasque?

<Maya>
ものスゴくウソっぽいヒビキだね。
‥‥あたしは好きだけど。
Fake☆DeMasque?
That sounds so ridiculous.
...But I like it.

<Godot>
‥‥オレがこのコーヒーの問題に
答えを出す前に、立証してくれよ。
Now, before I decide on
my coffee, I believe some
proof is in order, Mr. Trite.

犯行当夜、高菱屋に現れた怪人が
ニセモノだった、ってな‥‥
Proof that the person who
appeared at Lordly Tailor that
night was actually a fake.

<Judge>
検事のタイドにはちょっとハラが
立ちますが、主張はもっともです。
Hmm... Though I don't approve
of Mr. Godot's behavior, his
point is valid.

弁護人。‥‥よろしいですな！
Mr. Wright.
...We're waiting.




<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥なんとしても
　提示しなくちゃならないようだ）
(It looks like I'm going to
have to prove it...)

（あの晩、高菱屋に現れたのが
　ニセ☆仮面マスクだった証拠！）
(I need proof that the person
at Lordly Tailor that night
was in fact, Fake☆DeMasque!)




<Judge>
‥‥この証拠品が、いったい
ナニを立証しているのですかな？
What is this evidence
supposed to prove?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　どうやら、リッパに
立証しているようだぜ。
Ha...!
Well, it proves someone here
is a fake alright.

‥‥そこの弁護士が
ニセモノだ、ってな‥‥。
...It proves that this
lawyer is a fake.

<Phoenix>
（検事って、みんな
　ウマいコト言うよな‥‥）
(These prosecutors sure know
how to twist the knife...)

<Maya>
感心してる場合じゃないでしょ！
考えなおそうよ！
This is no time to be
impressed!
Think it over again!

ツボを盗んだとき‥‥
怪人、写真を撮られているよね。
When he stole the urn,
his photo was taken, right?

あの怪人に、ニセモノっぽいところ
でもあれば、いいんだけどねえ‥‥
Who knows? Maybe there's
something on there that
shows he's a fake...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥哀牙探偵から
　もらった写真、か‥‥）
(Hmm... Is she talking about
that photo we got from Atmey?)

<Judge>
‥‥そろそろ
よろしいですかな、弁護人。
Are you ready yet,
Mr. Wright?


<Phoenix>
その証拠は、これです。
The proof is right here.

<Judge>
これは‥‥防犯カメラが
撮影した写真‥‥ですか。
This looks like...
a photo taken by a
security camera.

<Phoenix>
この写真には‥‥１カ所、
おかしな部分があります。
But if you look closely...
you'll notice something
peculiar about it.

<Godot>
ほお‥‥それなら、ついでだ。
チョイと教えてくれるかい。
Ha...! Well then, why don't
you go ahead and show
us what it is.




<Godot>
その人差し指で‥‥
“ヘンな部分”とやら、を。
Go on. Use this pointer and
show us just what about this
picture is so "peculiar".


<Phoenix>
それは、ここです！
‥‥おそらく。
It's right here.
...I think.

<Judge>
‥‥そこが“ヘンな部分”
なのですか？
Is that what was so
"peculiar"?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　その人差し指‥‥
示すトコロがちがうようだぜ。
Ha...!
The place that you're
pointing to is all wrong.

<Phoenix>
な‥‥なんだと！
Wh...
What do you mean!

<Godot>
“ヘンな部分”‥‥それは、
アンタ自身のアタマ、ってことサ。
The only thing "peculiar"
in this courtroom...
is on top of your head.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
ヘアスタイルをヒハンされてるよ！
Nick! Are you going to let
him get away with making
fun of your hair!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥おそらく、
　そういうコトじゃない）
(Yes... At least until I know
he can't use his goggles to
fry me or something...)

と、とにかく！　この写真には
ヘンな部分があるハズです！
W-Well anyway!
There is a strange
spot in this photo!

<Godot>
ほお‥‥まだ、ヤル気かい。
それなら、教えてくれよ‥‥　
Ha...! Still haven't given up?
So what is it then?


<Phoenix>
それは、ここです！
‥‥モチロン。
It's right here, of course!

<Judge>
仮面マスク‥‥ですか？
You mean... Mask☆DeMasque?

<Phoenix>
さて。ここに、仮面マスクに関する
資料があります。
I have here a piece of
reference I would like the
court to take a look at.

<Maya>
今朝、あたしが買った
ブロマイドじゃない‥‥
Isn't that the publicity
photo I bought this
morning...?

<Phoenix>
問題は‥‥仮面マスクのムネに
ついている、エンブレムです。
The problem I have with the
security camera photo is the
broach on DeMasque's chest.

<Judge>
えんぶれむ‥‥？
なんですかな、それは。
A Breach? Here!? Bailiff!
Get my steed! We need
to retreat at once!

<Phoenix>
‥‥カタいアップリケ
みたいなモノです。
...A broach, Your Honor.
It's a sort of clasp for
holding one's cape on.

<Judge>
あっぷりけ‥‥ああ！　あの。
A clasp, eh...
Ah! I see now!

<Gumshoe>
たしかに、現場写真のほうの
仮面マスクは‥‥
But the Mask☆DeMasque
in the security camera
photo...

エンブレムがないッス！
Ahh!!
He has no broach!!

<Phoenix>
予告状を見ればわかるとおり、
これは仮面マスクのシンボルです！
That broach is the same as the
emblem on DeMasque's calling
card and serves as his symbol.

しかし‥‥高菱屋に現れた怪人は
それをつけていなかった‥‥
But the thief that broke
into Lordly Tailor wasn't
wearing a broach...

‥‥つまり！　この仮面マスクは、
ニセモノなのです！
In other words, this
"Mask☆DeMasque" is a fake!

<Gumshoe>
ま‥‥
またやられたッスウウゥゥゥゥッ！
...!
I-I've been fooled agaaaaaain!

<Judge>
せ、静粛に！　たしかに‥‥
反論しようがありません。
O-Order!
It's true...
Undeniably true...

イトノコギリ刑事！
あなた‥‥また、こんなミスをッ！
Detective Gumshoe!
How... How could you
have overlooked this!?

<Gumshoe>
す‥‥すまねッス！
自分はまた、こんな‥‥
I-I'm sorry, sir!
I don't know how I...

<Godot>
おいおい‥‥。
Hey now...

‥‥パーティーなら、
オレもまぜてくれよ。
...If you're gonna have
a pity party, invite me, too!

<Judge>
ご‥‥ゴドー検事！
あなたもあなたです！
M-Mr. Godot!
You deserve some blame
in this, too!

こんな大きな
アップリケを見逃すなんて‥‥
How could you have
overlooked such a large
broach...?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　アンタたちが
お探しのシロモノ‥‥
Ha...!
The broach you're
talking about...

ひょっとして、コイツのことかい？
Do you mean this?

<Gumshoe>
あッ‥‥！
Ah...!

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥エンブレム！
Th-That's...!
Mask☆DeMasque's broach!

<Judge>
い、いったい‥‥どこでそれを！
Wh-Where did you find it!?

<Godot>
証拠はさびしがり屋さ。いつだって
現場にかくれてやがる。
Well I've always had a good
nose for evidence... I got it
at the crime scene.

このレディなら、でっかい仏像の
カゲに落ちていたぜ。
It was hidden in the shadow
of a big female Buddha
statue.

<Phoenix>
（“仏像”‥‥
　綾里　供子の像のコトだな）
("Buddha statue"...?
He must mean the Ami Fey
statue.)

<Gumshoe>
な‥‥なんで自分にも
教えてくれなかったッスか！
Wh-Why didn't you
tell me about that, sir!?

<Godot>
‥‥証拠品は、自分のポケットに
しまうことにしてるのさ。
...I always put evidence
away in my pocket.

‥‥ここがイチバン
安全だからな‥‥
...After all, it's the
safest place for crucial
evidence.

<Maya>
くううう‥‥
シビれるねえ、なるほどくん。
Grrr...
This guy is one
cool customer.

<Godot>
シビれるのは早いぜ
‥‥おじょうちゃん。
It's a little early to be
shaken up, isn't it, little
lady?

コイツに、残っていやがったのさ。
‥‥熱いキスマークが。
...That friend of yours left
pretty little hickeys on
there, too.

<Judge>
き‥‥きすまあく？
H-Hickeys?

<Godot>
‥‥ヤケるじゃねえか。
被告人‥‥天杉　優作の指紋さ。
Figuratively speaking,
of course... I'm referring to
Ron DeLite's fingerprints.

<Gumshoe>
な‥‥
Whaaa...?

<Judge>
なんですって！　被告人の指紋が
‥‥エンブレムにッ！
What!?
The defendant's fingerprints
are on the broach!?

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　
Order! Order in the court!

ゴドー検事！
エンブレムを提出してください！
Mr. Godot!
Let's see that broach!

<Godot>
オレのコイビトだ。
‥‥ダイジにあつかってくれよ。
I've grown attached to my
metallic girlfriend here.
...Take good care of her.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥どうも、衣装から
引きちぎられたようですね。
Hmm... She-- I mean, it
appears to have been torn
off some clothing.

エンブレムのウラに、
布の切れはしが残っています。
There's a little bit of cloth
left on the back.

<Godot>
どうやら‥‥あの晩、現場で
タフなファイトがあったようだぜ。
Obviously there must have
been a big struggle that night
at the crime scene.

<Phoenix>
（さ‥‥サイアクの展開だ‥‥）
(Uh oh...
Phoenix, we have a problem...)

< >
証拠品《怪人のエンブレム》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
DeMasque's Broach added
to the Court Record.

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　このゴドー、
ウカツにナメちゃダメさ。
Ha...!
You mess with Godot...

‥‥ヤケドしちゃうぜ！
...and you get burned.

<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥ここまでの流れは
　アイツの計算どおり、か‥‥）
(Grr... He's been playing me
like a violin...)

<Godot>
さて、裁判長。
‥‥そろそろ、次の証人を呼ぶぜ。
Well Judge, I'm about ready
to call my next witness.

<Gumshoe>
え。自分はもう、おしまいッスか。
まだ、ナニも立証してないのに。
Huh? You're done with me?
But I haven't proved anything
yet.

<Godot>
アンタ自身の無能ぶりを立証した。
‥‥それでヨシとしようぜ。
You've proven your own
incompetence.
That's good enough.

<Gumshoe>
ちっともよくないッス！
...That doesn't sound good
at all.

<Judge>
それでは、係官！
次の証人を入廷させなさい！
Bailiff! Bring the next
witness into the courtroom!

<Phoenix>
（いよいよ‥‥
　名探偵さんの登場、か‥‥）
(Finally time for the
Ace Detective to make
his appearance, huh...?)

<Godot>
１秒の時間は、コーヒーの１滴。
さっさと、おっ始めるとするぜ‥‥
One second is one drip
of the coffee pot.
Let's hurry it up.

<Atmey>
‥‥シッ！　ダマって！
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
SHHH! SILENCE!
...

クックックックックッ‥‥
どうやら、見えたようですな。
Hee hee hee hee hee...
Now I see.
It's all becoming clear.

<Judge>
なな、なんですか？
Wh-What's clear?

<Atmey>
‥‥ズヴァリ！
美しきスイリが我にささやく真実。
...Zvarri!
The truth has once again
been elegantly revealed to me!

貴方がたは、裁判長と‥‥おそらく
検事。‥‥それもコーヒー好きの！
What we have here is...
A judge and a prosecutor.
...A coffee maniac, at that!

‥‥ちがいますかな？
...Am I correct?

<Judge>
そ‥‥そりゃま、そうですが。
W-Well, yes. That's right.

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　アンタ、
なかなかやるじゃねえか。
Ha...!
Not bad. Not bad at all.

このゴドーの正体を見抜いたの‥‥
アンタが初めてだぜ。
You're the first person that's
ever been able to penetrate
my secret veil.

<Atmey>
やあれ、検事殿。
自己紹介がおくれたようです。
Well, Sir Prosecutor.
Let me introduce myself.

我が名は星威岳　哀牙。
名探偵という名の、孤高の一番星。
My name is Luke Atmey,
Ace Detective and rising star
illuminating the heavens.

<Maya>
キョーレツなのが
そろっちゃったね‥‥
Boy, these two make
a perfect pair...

<Phoenix>
しかも‥‥ちょっと
気が合いそうだぞ、あのふたり。
They'd either be best friends
or they'd tear each other's
heads off.

<Judge>
あなたは事件当夜、たったヒトリで
警備をしていたそうですね。
I've heard that on the night
of the crime, you were all
alone on security detail.

<Atmey>
‥‥さよう。
...You have heard correctly.

わがマナコは、イトノコギリ刑事
１００人にまさる特別製なのです。
My specially-made monocle is
worth more than a hundred
Detective Gumshoes.

‥‥まあ。あの刑事のマナコが
見えていれば、のハナシですが。
...If Detective Gumshoe was
worth anything, that is.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥
Hmm...

<Phoenix>
（あの探偵がなぜ、たったヒトリで
　警備にあたっていたか‥‥？）
(Why was this guy all
by himself anyway...?)

（何か、理由があるはずだ。
　‥‥かならず！）
(There must be some reason.
I'm sure of it!)

<Judge>
では、その特別製のマナコで
目撃したことを証言してください！
Well then, tell us what this
special monocle of yours
witnessed!

< >
～目撃したこと～
-- What I Witnessed --

<Atmey>
あの晩‥‥日付が変わって、
１時間ほどのこと‥‥。
It was approximately 1 o'clock
in the morning...
just after the date changed.

きゃつめ‥‥宿敵たるライヴァル・
仮面マスクが舞いおりたッ！
That's when my nemesis,
the infamous Mask☆DeMasque,
dancingly descended upon me!

ふり返ろうとした、そのせつな！
ホコリ高きアタマに、一撃がッ！
Just as I began to turn, the
coward struck a fierce blow
upon my noble head!

不覚！　怪人と戦うことすらできず
‥‥我が意識は、ツユと消えたッ！
Darkness swallowed me before
I could land a single strike.
When I awoke, he was gone.

３０分後‥‥非常電話にて
警察に通報を入れたのです！
Thirty minutes later, I used
an emergency phone to notify
the police!

<Judge>
‥‥犯人の姿そのものは
ハッキリ見ていないのですか。
So you didn't get a clear
look at the criminal?

<Atmey>
特別製のマナコは、ナニモノも
見落としたりはしませんぞ。
My specially-made monocle
never misses a thing.

ただし！　目に入らなかったモノは
このかぎりにあらず。
However! That is limited to
things that fall within my
own visual range!

けだし、トーゼンと言えましょう。
But of course, that's only
natural.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥なぜ証人がそこまでムネを
張れるのか、理解に苦しみます。
...I fail to see why the
witness seems so proud of his
performance that evening.

<Atmey>
まあ、ご老人。‥‥これだけは
言っておきましょう。
Well, Sir Old-timer, let me
explain. We are not speaking
of any ordinary thief...

ヤツこそは、我が好敵手にして
ライヴァルたる仮面マスクだった！
...but of the king of thieves!
The great Mask☆DeMasque,
my arch-enemy!

我がケイケンとカン、その他
モロモロがそう告げております。
That is what my instincts
and my years of experience
tell me!

<Judge>
‥‥ふむう‥‥。
では、弁護人。とにかく尋問を。
Hmm...
Very well. Proceed with the
cross-examination, Mr. Wright.

< >
～目撃したこと～
-- What I Witnessed --




<Atmey>
あの晩‥‥日付が変わって、
１時間ほどのこと‥‥。
It was approximately 1 o'clock
in the morning...
just after the date changed.


<Atmey>
きゃつめ‥‥宿敵たるライヴァル・
仮面マスクが舞いおりたッ！
That's when my nemesis,
the infamous Mask☆DeMasque,
dancingly descended upon me!


<Atmey>
ふり返ろうとした、そのせつな！
ホコリ高きアタマに、一撃がッ！
Just as I began to turn, the
coward struck a fierce blow
upon my noble head!


<Atmey>
不覚！　怪人と戦うことすらできず
‥‥我が意識は、ツユと消えたッ！
Darkness swallowed me before
I could land a single strike.
When I awoke, he was gone.


<Atmey>
３０分後‥‥非常電話にて
警察に通報を入れたのです！
Thirty minutes later, I used
an emergency phone to notify
the police!


<Maya>
なんか、アヤしいよねー。
‥‥アイガ探偵。
There's something suspicious
about Detective Atmey...

犯人が入ってきたのに
気がつかないなんて。
How could he not have
noticed when the thief
came in?

<Phoenix>
“戦う前に、キゼツした‥‥”
哀牙探偵はそう言ってるけど‥‥、
Also, he says he was knocked
unconscious before he could
fight back...

‥‥そんなはずはないんだ。
あの証拠品とムジュンしている。
But that can't be right.
It contradicts the evidence.

<Maya>
“あの証拠品”‥‥？
Huh? Which piece...?

<Phoenix>
（モンダイは‥‥どうして、そんな
　あからさまなウソをつくのか？）
(The real question is...
Why would he tell such an
obvious lie?)

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
ということは‥‥１２日の
午前１時ごろ、になりますね？
So that would be one o'clock
on the morning of the 12th,
correct?

<Atmey>
なかなかミゴトな
スイリですな、弁護士殿。
That's an impressive
deduction, Sir Lawyer.

<Phoenix>
あなたは、現場で見張っていた。
‥‥どこにいたんですか？
You were on security duty
that night. Where exactly
were you at the time?

<Atmey>
さよう‥‥。地下倉庫の
コムピュウタのあたり、ですな。
A penetrating question!
I was in the basement
warehouse, near the computer.

<Phoenix>
（コンピュータ‥‥パソコンの
　コトか‥‥）
(Near the computer, huh...)

<Judge>
身をかくしていたワケでは
ないようですね。
So then you weren't trying
to remain hidden, I take it?

<Atmey>
今までの事件では、我はつねに、
身をかくして怪人を待っていた‥‥
Up to this point, I have tried
to remain concealed while
waiting for the thief...

<Phoenix>
（たしか、きのうも
　そんなコトを言ってたな）
(Yeah, he said the same
thing yesterday, too.)

<Maya>
イトノコさんも『現場でヤツを
見たことない』って言ってたね。
Gumshoe also said that he
never saw him at the crime
scene...

<Atmey>
だからこそ！　ゆうべは
あえて、かくれなかったのです！
Precisely! That is precisely
why I chose NOT to hide
last night.

あえて我が身をさらすことで、
プレッシャアを与える作戦ですな。
I knew that by NOT concealing
myself, I would be putting
pressure on the thief.

<Phoenix>
（アッサリ殴られたクセに‥‥）
(Looks like the thief was the
one applying pressure... On
your pidgeony head, that is.)

<Atmey>
とにかく、その時刻‥‥！
In any case!

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
舞いおりた‥‥って、
どこからですか？
"Dancingly descended"...?
From where exactly?

<Atmey>
ま。それは、入り口のドアから
でしょうな、おそらく。
Well... From the entrance,
I suppose. Where else?

<Phoenix>
（“舞い”も“おりる”も
　カンケイないじゃないか！）
(So in actuality, he neither
"danced" nor "descended"!
...Someone please save me.)

あの‥‥。どうして怪人に
気がつかなかったんですか？
Um...
So how is it that you didn't
notice the thief?

<Atmey>
我がマナコは怪人のカゲを求め、
我が耳は怪人の足音を探していた。
My eyes were looking for the
thief's shadow while my ears
listened for his footfalls.

‥‥だのに！　ヤツはその上を
行ったのです！　おそらく‥‥
But even so, the dastardly
criminal managed to sneak
up on me...

怪人め、地味なマントを着て
いいクツをはいていたのでしょう。
It can only be due to his
subtly camouflaged cape
and soft-soled shoes.

<Phoenix>
（アンタ、ホントに
　名探偵なのかよ‥‥）
(...
I hereby dub you
"Ace Dunce".)

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
そのとき、犯人のカオは
見なかったんですか？
You didn't see the
criminal's face when
that happened?

<Atmey>
‥‥それこそは、
“微”にして“妙”ですな。
...Well, that's the difficult
part. How should I put it...

怪人の仮面のマスクは見た
‥‥そうキオクしております。
I saw his mask...
That's all that I can recall.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥ややアイマイですな。
Hmm...
That's not very solid as
far as testimony goes.

<Atmey>
しかし‥‥このとおり、我が
第３のマナコたる防犯キャメラが、
However... Fortunately I had
my third monocle, the security
camera, at the ready.

その姿をシカととらえている。
‥‥じゅうぶんではないですかな？
It captured his image
perfectly... This should be
sufficient, I believe?

<Judge>
たしかに‥‥写真がホンモノで
あれば、モンダイないでしょうな。
Hmm, well, as long as this
photo is authentic, I don't
see a problem here.

いかがですか？　ゴドー検事。
Well, Mr. Godot?
Do you have a problem
with the photo?

<Judge>
‥‥それでは、
証言をつづけてください。
Good. Then let's continue
with the testimony.

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
襲われて、キゼツ‥‥
何もできなかったんですか？
Attacked and knocked
unconscious? And you
weren't able to do a thing?

‥‥名探偵のくせに。
That's certainly some very
impressive detective work.

<Atmey>
あいや、弁護士殿！
貴方‥‥いきなり殴られたことは？
Hmph! Well, Sir Lawyer!
Have you ever been suddenly
struck on the head?

<Phoenix>
え！　あ、ありますけど。
‥‥消火器で。
Huh!?
W-Well... Actually, yes.
By a fire extinguisher.

<Atmey>
その結果、どうなりましたかな？
And what happened?

<Phoenix>
たしか‥‥そのままキゼツして‥‥
...I-I was knocked out.

<Maya>
キオクもなくしちゃったんだよね！
And you lost your memory,
too!

<Atmey>
‥‥さよう。貴方に我を
せめる資格はありませぬな。
You see? You have no
right to look down on me
then, do you?

記憶を保っているぶん、我がアタマ
のほうが優秀とも言えましょう。
The only reason I didn't lose
my memory was because I have
more brains to begin with.

<Phoenix>
（コイツのアタマ‥‥“反省する”
　って回路はないのかよ‥‥）
(He may have brains, but the
wiring to the self-reflection
part seems to be severed...)

<Atmey>
‥‥さて。このようにして、
我が意識はとぎれた。そして‥‥
In any case, that was
how I was knocked senseless.
And then...

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
その“３０分”というのは‥‥？
About this "30 minutes"...

<Atmey>
我が意識が黄泉の世界へと旅立ち、
黄昏の彼岸を彷徨いし、玉響‥‥。
My silver cord was loosened
and my soul fled to the
Golden Halls of Elysium...

<Maya>
‥‥あいかわらず読めないし、
イミもゼンゼンわかんないよ。
As usual, I have no
idea what this guy is
saying.

<Phoenix>
《キゼツしてノビていた》
‥‥たぶん、そういうコトだな。
I think he's saying
that he was out cold.

<Judge>
では‥‥
その３０分間のコトは‥‥？
So... What happened during
these 30 minutes?

<Atmey>
ダレにも知ることのできない‥‥
空白の時間、というワケですな！
No one can say, Your Honor...
That span of time has truly
vanished into the ether!

<Phoenix>
（おまえが言うなよ！）
(Just what is he
going on about!?)


<Phoenix>
‥‥哀牙さん。
...Mr. Atmey.

その特別製のマナコで、
これを見てもらえますか。
Could you take a look at this
with that special monocle
of yours?

<Atmey>
これはしたり！　我が好敵手にして
ライヴァルなる怪人なれば大盗人！
Aha! This belongs to the
criminal mastermind, my
arch-nemesis, Mask☆DeMasque!

かの、仮面マスクめのエムブレム
‥‥ですな。
It is, in point of fact,
Mask☆DeMasque's broach!

<Phoenix>
現場の地下倉庫に落ちていました。
‥‥なぜでしょうね？
It was found on the floor of
the basement warehouse.
I wonder how that happened?

<Atmey>
フッ‥‥カンタンなコト。
ノリづけがアマかったのでしょう。
Ha... Elementary, my dear
lawyer. Obviously it wasn't
glued on well enough.

<Phoenix>
‥‥コイツには、衣装から
引きちぎられたアトがあります。
Not quite. It clearly shows
signs of having been ripped
off a piece of clothing.

<Judge>
引きちぎられた‥‥あっ！
Ripped off...?
Aha!

<Phoenix>
‥‥事件当夜、“怪人”は
何者かと格闘したものと思われる！
...We can only deduce that
the thief struggled with
someone that night!

エンブレムがムシり取られたのは、
そのときしか考えられません。
That's the only thing I can
think of.

そして、犯人と格闘できたのは‥‥
And there's only one person
that was in a position to have
a struggle with the thief.

たった１人で現場を見張っていた
あなたしか、いないのです！
The only person that was on
security duty that night...
You, Detective Atmey!

<Atmey>
‥‥グッ！
...Urk!

<Phoenix>
哀牙探偵！　あなたは怪人と
格闘をしているハズです！
Detective Atmey!
You must have fought with
the thief that night!

なのに、なぜ‥‥
ウソの証言をするのですか？
So, why did you lie in your
testimony to the court?

<Judge>
‥‥証人！　偽証は、
リッパな犯罪ですぞ！
Witness! Giving false
testimony is a serious crime!

<Atmey>
あ、あいや！
‥‥あいや、待たれよ、ご老人。
Err, I... N-No!
W-Wait just a moment,
Sir Old-timer!

<Judge>
私をごインキョみたいに
呼ばないように！
Don't talk to me like I'm
living in a nursing home!

<Atmey>
クックックックックッ‥‥
思い出しましたぞ、裁判長殿。
Hee hee hee he he he...
I just remembered, Your Honor.

最近、多くの事件を抱えているので
‥‥コンランしたようです。
I was just confused because
I've been dealing with so
many cases lately.

<Godot>
デキるオトコは、サバける仕事の
数で決まる‥‥オレの哲学だぜ。
The true measure of a man is
in the amount of work he does.
That's what I always say.

<Maya>
なるほどくん、
いつも１コだよね。シゴト。
Nick, you can only handle
one case at a time...
Isn't that right?

<Phoenix>
うるさいな。
You talk too much.

<Judge>
証人！　つまり、あなたは‥‥
犯人と格闘したと言うのですか？
Witness! So are you now saying
that you and the thief fought?

<Godot>
おっと。おしゃべりは
そこまでだぜ‥‥裁判長。
Hold on.
That's quite enough...
Your Honor.

<Judge>
‥‥お、おしゃべり‥‥
E-Excuse me...?

<Godot>
ダイジなコトは、証言で聞く。
そいつが‥‥オレのルールだぜ。
Save the big questions
for the testimony.
That's one of my rules.

<Atmey>
あいや！　了解しましたぞ。
この哀牙、燃ゆるイノチにかけて。
Indeed! I understand!
I, Luke Atmey, agree
completely!

< >
～犯人との格闘～
-- Fight With The Thief --

<Atmey>
さよう。たしかに、この哀牙が
扉から目をはなしたのは、ジジツ。
Indeed, it's true that I
looked away from the
door for a brief moment.

しかし‥‥、そんなコトで
この名探偵をたばかるのは不可能！
However...
Luke Atmey cannot be so
easily discombobulated!

怪人は、かたわらの武器を手に取り
‥‥我らは、イノチのやりとりを！
Unfortunately, the thief
grabbed a weapon from the side
and... rendered me senseless.

ゼントルメンの武器は、コブシのみ
‥‥それが、アダとなりました。
A true gentleman fights only
with his own fists...
But they were not enough.

ヤツめの一撃がコツンと！
‥‥それで、すべてですな。
His first blow struck true!
Bam!
...And that's all she wrote.

<Judge>
やはり、仮面マスクを
目撃していたワケですか‥‥？
So in the end, you did catch
a glimpse of Mask☆DeMasque?

<Atmey>
さよう。
Correct.

ふり返りザマにやられたのは、
ヤツの３回目の犯行のときでした。
It was during his third crime
that he struck me from
behind.

どうやら、記憶が少々
コンランしてしまったようです。
It seems that my memory
has become a tad jumbled,
so to speak.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥まあたしかに、
よくあるコトですな。
Hmmm...
Well, that's certainly
understandable.

私も、証言がどの事件のものか、
よくわからなくなりますからな。
I, myself, always get confused
about which testimony goes
with which case.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そりゃマズいだろ‥‥）
(Th-That can't be good...)

< >
～犯人との格闘～
-- Fight With The Thief --




<Atmey>
さよう。たしかに、この哀牙が
扉から目をはなしたのは、ジジツ。
Indeed, it's true that I
looked away from the
door for a brief moment.


<Atmey>
しかし‥‥、そんなコトで
この名探偵をたばかるのは不可能！
However...
Luke Atmey cannot be so
easily discombobulated!


<Atmey>
怪人は、かたわらの武器を手に取り
‥‥我らは、イノチのやりとりを！
Unfortunately, the thief
grabbed a weapon from the side
and... rendered me senseless.


<Atmey>
ゼントルメンの武器は、コブシのみ
‥‥それが、アダとなりました。
A true gentleman fights only
with his own fists...
But they were not enough.








<Atmey>
ヤツめの一撃がコツンと！
‥‥それで、すべてですな。
His first blow struck true!
Bam!
...And that's all she wrote.


<Maya>
どうかな？　なるほどくん。
Well what do you think, Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥１つだけ、
ハッキリしているコトがあるよ。
Well, there's one thing that
I'm absolutely sure of now.

<Maya>
え！　なに、なに？
Yeah?
What is it!?

<Phoenix>
アイツは‥‥哀牙探偵は、
まだ、何かをかくそうとしている！
This Luke Atmey guy...
He's definitely hiding
something!

<Maya>
そ、それって‥‥
どういうコトかな？
B-But why?

<Phoenix>
なんとなく‥‥この事件の真相が
見えてきたような気がするよ。
I think I'm starting to
figure out what really
happened that night.

（‥‥あの探偵の“正体”が‥‥）
(...And about the true
nature of this "detective".)

<Atmey>






<Atmey>
背にカベをつけて応戦をしましたが
‥‥我がマユアイに怪人の一撃が！
I put my back to the wall
to fight, but the thief's blow
landed upon my third eye.





<Phoenix>
そもそも、どうして
扉から目をはなしたんですか？
So why did you look away
from the door anyway?

<Atmey>
地下倉庫には、防犯キャメラ以外に
多くのセンサアがしかけてあった。
In addition to the camera,
I had prepared a variety of
other sensors as well.

その１つが、ピピと反応した！
すわ、デエタをカクニンせねばッ！
The alarm on one of those
had gone off, so I had to
check the data.

‥‥我は、コムピュウタのところへ
行ったのです。‥‥そう、華麗に！
That's why I went to the
computer!
...Elegantly, of course!

<Phoenix>
パソコンをいじっていて、
スキができた、ってワケですか‥‥
So you were momentarily
vulnerable when you were
working on the computer?

（どうする？　もう少し、
　聞いてみるか‥‥？）
(What should I do? Should I
ask some more questions...?)




<Phoenix>
（とにかく、哀牙探偵が扉から
　目をはなしたのはジジツらしい）
(Well, we know for sure
that Atmey looked away
from the door.)

（もっと、他のコトを聞いたほうが
　よさそうだな‥‥）
(I think I should ask about
something else now...)

わかりました。あなたは、扉から
目をはなした。‥‥そして？
Alright. So you looked
away from the door.
...And then?

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
その‥‥“センサア”というのは？
What kind of sensors are
you talking about?

<Atmey>
地下倉庫には、ドア以外にも
出入りできる場所がありました。
There are other places in the
basement that someone could
enter and exit from.

エアア・コンディショナアのダクト
に排水口、ネコ用のドアなどなど。
There are air conditioner
ducts, sewer pipes...
And a cat door as well.

すべてに熱感知・赤外線・紫外線・
その他モロモロのセンサアをッ！
I hooked up heat-detecting,
infrared and ultra-violet
sensors to each of them.

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥ご自分で用意された
のですか？
That's a lot of hardware...
Was it all yours?

<Atmey>
機材はすべて、高菱屋百貨店に
用意していただきました。
Lordly Tailor Department Store
was kind enough to provide
the monitoring hardware.

もちろん‥‥この写真を
撮影した防犯キャメラも、ね。
Naturally, the security camera
that took the photo belongs to
them as well.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥つまり、それらの機材に
　細工はできなかったワケか‥‥）
(In other words, he couldn't
have rigged the equipment,
huh...?)

<Atmey>
クックックッ‥‥ウタガイは
晴れましたかな？　弁護士殿。
Hee hee hee hee hee... Has
that cleared up any doubts you
had about me, Sir Lawyer?

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
そのコムピュウタも、高菱屋の
モノだったんですか？
So did that computer
belong to Lordly Tailor
as well?

<Atmey>
さよう。‥‥まあ、デエタを
管理するプログラムは、
Correct.
Well, except for the program
that manages the data.

この哀牙が、ホオムメエドの
味わいで作りあげたモノですがね！
That was specially designed
by me, Luke Atmey!

<Phoenix>
（それなら‥‥哀牙探偵は
　データを自由にイジれたワケだ）
(In that case, he could have
easily manipulated the data.)

<Atmey>
クックックッ‥‥
どうかしましたかな？　弁護士殿。
Hee hee hee hee hee...
What's wrong, Sir Lawyer?

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
あの‥‥なんですか？
“たばかる”って。
Umm...
What does that mean?
"Discombobulated"?

<Judge>
はあ‥‥最近のワカいヒトは
これだからコマります。
Hmm...
Young people these days...
They really irritate me.

うつくしく古いコトバは、
こうして失われていくのですね‥‥
They allow perfectly good old
words to die until everyone
forgets what they mean.

<Phoenix>
スミマセン‥‥。で、
どういうイミなんですか？
Sorry, but what exactly
DOES it mean anyway?

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥ド忘れしました。
なんでしたっけ？
...
Now I've forgotten.
What was I saying?

<Phoenix>
（最近のおジイさんも
　似たようなもんじゃないか！）
(Jeez. It's better than old
people who forget what they
were saying 5 seconds ago!)

<Godot>
‥‥どうやら、結論が出たようだ。
証言をつづけて、かまわねえぜ。
...Well, it looks like we've
cleared that up. You can
go on with your testimony.

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
“かたわらの武器”というのは？
What do you mean by
"weapon from the side"?

<Atmey>
にっくき怪人も、まさかこの哀牙が
現場にいようとは思わなかった！
Naturally, that thief had no
idea that I, Luke Atmey,
was hiding in the area!

倉庫へ通じる扉の近くに立っていた
女人像から、カタナをうばったッ！
He grabbed the sword from
the statue that was standing
by the door to the warehouse.

<Phoenix>
カタナ‥‥って、くねくねと
エダわかれしたヤツですか？
Sword...? You mean the sword
that was all twisted like a
tree branch?

<Atmey>
さよう。‥‥さいわい、刃は
立っていなかったようでしたが。
Correct.
Fortunately for me, the
blade was not sharp.

<Phoenix>
（やはり‥‥七支刀のコトだな）
(OK, so he IS talking about
the Shichishito...)

<Judge>
怪人は、カタナを取った。
それで、証人のほうは‥‥？
So the thief armed himself
with a sword. And what about
yourself, witness?

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
ウデっぷしには
自信があったんですか？
You had that much faith in
your own fighting abilities?

<Atmey>
さよう。我が中学生時代は、
拳闘倶楽部の副主将代理補佐ゆえ。
But of course. In college,
I was the 2nd in-charge of
the boxing club.

<Judge>
‥‥いまひとつ、スゴさが
伝わってきません。
I'm sorry if I fail to find
that appropriately impressive.

<Atmey>
しかしヒキョウなるは、我が怪人
にしてライヴァルたる仮面マスク！
However! My opponent in the
ring this time was my
arch-nemesis, Mask☆DeMasque!

<Phoenix>
（もうメチャクチャだな‥‥）
(This guy is a real
piece of work...)

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
そのときのコト、もう少し
詳しく聞かせてもらえますか？
Can you tell us a little more
about what happened?

<Atmey>
カタナを持っている相手と闘うは、
ハアドでメロウ、そしてヘロウ。
My opponent was both powerful
and vicious. You might say
he was... "powericious".

<Phoenix>
（なんだ“ヘロウ”って‥‥）
("P-Powericious"?)

<Atmey>
トクイの戦法で相手しましたが‥‥
一瞬、ヒカリに目がくらんだッ！
I assumed the "Atmey Fighting
Stance", but a sudden flash of
light blinded me!

そこを、すかさずチェックメエト！
‥‥やられたワケですな。
That of course was checkmate!
My opponent had bested me.

<Phoenix>
（どうする？　もう少し、
　聞いてみるか‥‥？）
(What do I do now?
Should I ask more about
this...?)




<Phoenix>
（とにかく、哀牙探偵がポカリと
　やられたのはジジツみたいだ）
(Well, I guess it's true that
Atmey was knocked senseless
after all.)

（もっと、他のコトを聞いたほうが
　よさそうだな‥‥）
(I'd better ask him about
something else instead...)


<Phoenix>
その、目がくらんだ
“ヒカリ”というのは‥‥？
So what was this flash of
light that blinded you?

<Atmey>
‥‥いわばアレは、ゴオルデン。
女人の像から発したモノでしょう。
...I was bathed in a golden
light that seemed to come
from the statue of the woman.

<Phoenix>
（綾里　供子の像、か‥‥）
(The statue of Ami Fey,
I'm guessing...)

<Maya>
あんまり参考にならなかったね。
Well that wasn't very much
help at all...


<Phoenix>
“トクイの戦法”というのは？
What is this "Atmey
Fighting Style"?

<Atmey>
それこそは、探偵のシイクレット！
‥‥と言いたいところですが‥‥
I'm sorry but that's a trade
secret... I really can't say
any more.

よろしい。教えてしんぜよう。
みなさまも、明日から、ゼヒに。
But, I suppose I can
tell you if I absolutely must.

‥‥カベを背に闘うのです。これで
背後を取られるコトはありませぬ。
The main thing is to put your
back to the wall. That way no
one can get behind you.

<Phoenix>
（カベを‥‥背に？）
(That's it...?
That's the "Atmey Fighting
Style"?)

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥いかがですか、弁護人。
この証言は‥‥？
Hmmm... Well, Mr. Wright?
What about that testimony...?



<Phoenix>
もちろん、重要です！
探偵のシイクレットなワケですし。
Of course it's important!
We've learned a detective's
SECRET technique, after all.

<Judge>
そうですな。夜道で襲われたとき、
私も参考にしましょう。
Yes, indeed... I'll remember
to use it if I ever take a
walk alone late at night.

<Phoenix>
（裁判長‥‥なぜか、ぼくを
　ジッと見つめているぞ‥‥）
(Why the heck is he
eye-balling me like that...?
It's creeping me out...)

<Judge>
‥‥それでは、証人！
...Now then, witness!

今のシイクレットを証言に
加えていただきましょう！
We'll go ahead and add that
secret information to your
official testimony!

<Atmey>



<Phoenix>
‥‥あの。
マユアイ‥‥というのは？
Umm...
Where is this "third eye"
you're talking about?

<Atmey>
さよう‥‥右のマユと左のマユの
ちょうど中央、ちょっと上あたり。
Oh... it's right between my
right and left eyebrows.

‥‥ある種、ヒタイと言いかえても
モンダイないでしょう。
...It's quite invisible to the
unenlightened. You may call
it the forehead, if you like.

<Phoenix>
（じゃあ、
　最初からそっちで言えよ！）
(Why didn't you just say
that in the first place!?)

<Atmey>
やあれ、弁護士殿！　マユアイに
シワがよっておりますぞ！
Sir Lawyer! It looks like the
creases in your own forehead
are getting deeper!

<Maya>
‥‥あの探偵さん、ヒタイを
殴られたの？
So Mr. Atmey got hit on
the forehead then?

<Phoenix>
そう言ってるね。
That's what he says.

<Maya>
ううん‥‥なんか気になるなあ。
Hmm... I've got a funny
feeling about that.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥じつは、ぼくもだ）
(Actually, so do I.)


<Phoenix>
哀牙さん！　あなたの証言は、
バラバラにしてガタガタです。
Detective Atmey!
Your testimony is crumbling
like a house of cards.

<Atmey>
さあれ、弁護士殿！
これはこれは、ユカイしごく。
What fun this is, Sir Lawyer!
It is truly a pleasure to
cross swords with you!

この哀牙に、そのような
ほほえましき挑戦状‥‥
And now, once again, you have
thrown down the gauntlet at
my armored feet...

<Phoenix>
きのう、あなたは
こう言っていたハズです。
I believe this is what you
said yesterday.

<Atmey>
まっこと、ヒキョウなり
仮面マスク！
No, the coward must have
wormed his way in through
somewhere besides the door...

この好敵手の後ろアタマを、
このような危険なもので殴るとは！
Then my arch-nemesis struck me
on the head from behind with
this gruesome item here!

<Judge>
後ろアタマ‥‥
From behind, huh?

<Phoenix>
しかし今、あなたは証言した。
“ヒタイをコツンとやられた”‥‥
But just now you testified
that he struck you on the
forehead...

もし本当に殴られたのなら、
まちがえるコトなど、あり得ない！
I hardly think you could
forget where you were hit
on the head!

<Atmey>
‥‥うぐっ！　どうやら‥‥
やや、ウッカリしていたようです。
...Urk!
It seems...
I-I've made another mistake.

<Phoenix>
‥‥哀牙さん。オカシイのは、
今の証言だけじゃありません。
...Detective Atmey.
That's not the only strange
part of your testimony.

<Judge>
それは‥‥
どういうイミですかな？
Wh-What do you mean
by that?

<Phoenix>
たとえば‥‥
For example...

この予告状を、警察にかくして
いたのが、すでに不自然です！
The very fact that you hid the
calling card from the police
itself is strange!

まるで‥‥警察が警備にあたるのを
恐れていたかのように見えます！
It's almost as if...
You were afraid they were
going to help with security!

<Atmey>
く‥‥うむむ。
U-Urk...!

天才は、いつの世も理解されにくい
‥‥そういうコト、ですかな。
Geniuses such as myself have
always been misunderstood!
How sad...

<Phoenix>
ちがいますよ！
That's wrong!

<Objection!>

<Godot>
‥‥だれしも、まちがいはある。
...To err is human, to
forgive divine.

<Godot>
人間の行動は、リクツだけじゃ
ワリ切れねえのさ。
Humans aren't machines...
They have souls, feelings.

だからこそ‥‥ヒトはヒトとして、
トキめき、キラめくんだぜ‥‥
They live, they die, they
love, they hate... And yes,
they even make mistakes...

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
いやいやいや。これは、そんな
キレイなハナシじゃない！
Hey, hold on!
It-It's not as pretty as that!

<Godot>
じゃあ、どんなハナシだ！
Really?
What is it like then!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

<Godot>
ギモンはトコトン追求する。
そいつが‥‥オレのルールだぜ。
Always chase a riddle down
to the end.
That's one of my rules.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥こいつは‥‥）
(This is it...)

（意外に早くめぐってきた、
　反撃のチャンスかもしれない！）
(This might just be my
chance to turn things
around!)




<Judge>
‥‥成歩堂くん。あなたの
主張を聞かせてください。
...Mr. Wright.
What exactly is it that
you're asserting?

<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりました。
弁護側の主張は‥‥！
Very well, Your Honor.
The defense asserts that...




<Phoenix>
この証人は、じつは‥‥
名探偵などではないのです！
The truth is... this witness
is no Ace Detective at all!

<Atmey>
‥‥では‥‥いったい、
この哀牙は、なんだと？
...So then what exactly
are you saying that I am?

<Phoenix>
ええと‥‥そうですね。
並の探偵、というか。
Uh, umm...
Well, an average detective...?

<Judge>
たいして、変わりませんな。
I hardly see the relevance
of that.

<Maya>
な、何やってんの、なるほどくん！
アイツを追いつめるんでしょ？
Wh-What are you doing, Nick!?
Weren't you going to go
on the attack?

<Phoenix>
そのつもりだったけど‥‥
ぼくのほうが追いつめられてるな。
I was planning on it, but
it looks I'm the one who
got attacked instead.

<Judge>
もっとマジメに考えるように！
Think harder next time!




<Phoenix>
この証人は‥‥星威岳　哀牙の
ニセモノなのですッ！
This witness isn't Luke
Atmey... He's a fake!

<Atmey>
‥‥仮面マスクにつづいて、
この哀牙まで、ニセモノだと‥‥？
...So now it's not just
Mask☆DeMasque.
You're saying I'm a fake, too?

<Phoenix>
名探偵と言われる星威岳　哀牙が、
こんなトボけているはずがない！
An Ace Detective could never
be as forgetful as this guy!

<Godot>
アンタ自身がニセモノだから‥‥
そう見えるんだろうぜ。
Imposters like you are often
suspicious of others as well.

<Judge>
やれやれ。次は、この私が
ニセモノ呼ばわりされそうですな。
Really, this is too much.
Next you'll be calling
me a fake, too!




<Phoenix>
コタエはシンプルです！
すべてのナゾがスッキリする。
The answer is simple!
It's all clear to me now!

この星威岳　哀牙こそが‥‥
怪人☆仮面マスクだったのです！
Detective Luke Atmey's
true identity is actually...
Mask☆DeMasque!

<Atmey>
うぐほほおおッ！
Yeeeeaaargggh!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
弁護人！　どういうことですか！
Order! Order in the court!
Mr. Wright! What is the
meaning of this!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥哀牙探偵には、
不自然な点が多すぎました。
There are too many unnatural
parts to Mr. Atmey's story.

犯行現場では“かくれている”
ため、だれも彼の姿を見ていない。
He says he was "hiding" at the
crime scenes, which is why no
one ever saw him there.

それなのに、いつのまにか
イトノコ刑事と警察を出し抜いて、
And then, in his last case,
he manages to outperform
Detective Gumshoe and...

前回の事件では、怪人の盗みだした
エモノを、取り戻している‥‥
...the entire police force to
"miraculously" retrieve the
stolen treasure.

<Atmey>
そ、それは‥‥
Th-That's because...

現場の状況や怪人の犯行データから
その手口をカンペキにスイリして、
I analyzed the crime scene
data and made an exquisitely
elegant deduction.

警察の見落としているポイントに、
あらかじめ、先回りを‥‥
I picked up clues that the
police overlooked in order
to arrive at a...

<Phoenix>
ちがうでしょう、哀牙探偵。
コタエは、もっとシンプルだった！
Oh, please! The explanation
is far simpler than that,
"Detective Atmey"!

あなた自身が、
怪人☆仮面マスクだったのです。
The truth is that you
are, in fact, Mask☆DeMasque.

<Atmey>
ぐはらあッ！
Gurk...!

<Judge>
し‥‥しかし、弁護人！
この写真には‥‥怪人の姿が！
B-But Mr. Wright!
Th-This photo! It clearly
shows Mask☆DeMasque!

これを撮影したカメラは、
高菱屋のものです！
This security camera belongs
to Lordly Tailor Department
Store!

細工など、できないハズでは‥‥
He shouldn't have been
able to manipulate it...

<Phoenix>
細工なんて、必要ありません！
He didn't need to
manipulate it!

星威岳　哀牙は、“探偵”として
地下倉庫を警備するフリをして‥‥
He gained access to the
warehouse under the pretense
of providing "security"...

“怪人”として、ただ
ツボを盗めばよかったのです！
Then he simply dressed as
the "thief" and stole the urn.

<Judge>
なんと‥‥名探偵が‥‥大怪盗！
So... the Ace Detective is
actually an Ace Thief!

そうなのですか！　証人ッ！
Is this true, witness!?

<Atmey>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

うふ‥‥‥‥
Aha...

あーっはっはっはっはっはっはっ
はっはっはっはっはっはっはっは！
Hee hee hee ha ha ha
Aha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ho ho ho hee hee hee!

仮面マスクの手口はまさに、天才！
名探偵・星威岳　哀牙こそがッ！
DeMasque's M. O. is pure
genius! And so am I, Luke
Atmey, Ace Detective!!

‥‥その正体に、ふさわしいのかも
しれませんな、みなみなさまがた！
You're very clever to have
come to such a conclusion!
I am impressed, Sir Lawyer!

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですとォォ！
Wh-Whaaaaat!?

まさか‥‥証人！
認めるのですか‥‥ッ！
Witness! You...
You're admitting it!?

<Maya>
な‥‥なるほどくん！
N-Nick! Now's your chance!

<Phoenix>
よし‥‥このまま、
一気にキメちゃおう！
Yes! Time to put the last
nail in this guy's coffin!

星威岳　哀牙さん！
あなたを、怪人として‥‥
Detective Atmey!
When you assumed the
thief's identity--

<Objection!>

<Godot>
ゴドー・ブレンド１０２号。
‥‥オレのオゴリだぜ。
Godot Blend #102...
...My personal favorite.

<Judge>
ご‥‥ゴドー検事ッ！
M-Mr. Godot!

<Godot>
名探偵イコール、怪人‥‥
絵空ゴトはキレイに見えるモンだ。
"The Ace Detective is actually
an Ace Thief!" I smell a
best-selling novel!

だけどな‥‥。現実はそんなに、
キレイじゃねえのサ。
There's only one problem...
It simply isn't true.

<Judge>
し、しかし！
この弁護人の主張には、スジが‥‥
B-But Mr. Godot!
Mr. Wright has made some
very strong points and I...

<Godot>
‥‥たしかに、スジだらけで
ゴリゴリしてるようだぜ。
I will admit my opponent
has woven a compelling
narrative out of whole cloth.

どうやら‥‥おイタがすぎた
みたいだな、弁護士さん‥‥
But it is, in fact, nothing
more than a patchwork quilt.
Mr. Trite...

この探偵が、怪人。それなら‥‥
証拠を見せてくれよ。
If this detective really is
the thief, then show us the
proof of your claim.

そのコーヒーのようにカンペキで
‥‥そして、熱いヤツをッ！
But it had better be as hot...
and as perfect as the coffee
dripping down your face!

<Judge>
弁護人！　いつまでも
ボーゼンとしていないで‥‥
Well, Mr. Wright!?
Don't just stand there!

決定的な証拠を
提示してもらえますかな！
This court would like to
see this decisive proof
you have! Quickly!

<Phoenix>
え！　そ、そうですね‥‥
（ちょっと、急ぎすぎたか‥‥？）
Huh!?
Oh! Y-Yes, of course!
(Wh-What's the big rush...?)

<Maya>
だ、大丈夫なの、なるほどくん？
Are you alright, Nick?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥哀牙探偵は今、
　かなり弱っている‥‥）
(Atmey looks pretty
rattled right now...)

（できれば、ここで勝負を
　キメてしまいたい）
(I'd like to finish this right
now if I can.)

（それだけの証拠を‥‥
　ぼくは、持っているのか？）
(But can I really do it?)

哀牙探偵こそが仮面マスクである
という、決定的な証拠は‥‥！
The decisive evidence that
proves Mr. Luke Atmey is in
fact Mask☆DeMasque...



<Phoenix>
‥‥もちろん、弁護側には
決定的な証拠があります！
As usual, the defense
comes prepared,
Your Honor!

<Judge>
わかりました。‥‥それでは、
提示していただきましょう。
Very well then...
Let's see what you've got.

この証人・星威岳　哀牙が、
仮面マスクであるという証拠を！
Please present proof that
Mask☆DeMasque is actually
Mr. Luke Atmey!




<Phoenix>
これが‥‥その証拠ですッ！
Here's your proof!

<Judge>
‥‥いかがですか、ゴドー検事。
What do you think,
Mr. Godot?

<Godot>
どうやら‥‥弁護士さんはまだ、
目がさめてないらしいぜ。
It looks to me like
Mr. Trite is still a
mite sleepy.

ゴドー・ブレンドをもうイッパイ、
いっとくかい？　‥‥弁護士さん。
Perhaps he'd like a big mug of
my special Godot blend? Well?

<Phoenix>
い、いえいえ。ケッコウです！
N-No thanks, I'm fine!
Really!

（どうする‥‥？　ここで判断を
　まちがうと、おしまいだ！）
(What do I do now?
Another mistake like that
and I'm through!)

（決定的な証拠がないかぎり、
　深追いはイノチ取りだけど‥‥）
(Without some decisive
evidence, I could be risking
everything...)



<Phoenix>
証拠は‥‥証拠は‥‥‥‥！
‥‥まだ、ありません。
Proof?
Of course I... I...
...I've got nothing.

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　そうだ。
Ha...!
Just what I thought.

オトコは、ミジメなときでも
カオを上げなきゃいけねえ。
A man has to hold his head
up high no matter how bad
things get, after all.

<Phoenix>
‥‥うううう‥‥
Uuugh...

<Judge>
‥‥そうですか。
I see...

証拠さえあれば、“あるいは”と
思ったのですが‥‥
I thought perhaps you had
some evidence to back up
your assertion...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ダメだ！　ここで攻撃を
　やめてしまったら‥‥）
(This is no good! I've
got to stay on the attack!)

（二度とコイツを怪人として
　告発するチャンスはなくなる！）
(I'll never get another chance
to prove that this guy is the
thief!)

<Maya>
なるほどくん‥‥がんばって！
もう一度、考えようよ！
Don't give up, Nick!
Think harder and try again!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ダメだ‥‥
やっぱり‥‥まだ、早すぎたんだ。
It's no good...
I'm just not ready yet...

<Maya>
そ、そんな‥‥！
あたしたち、負けちゃうの‥‥？
B-But... Are you going to just
give up and let us lose this?

<Atmey>
‥‥どうやら、弁護士殿。
ツメをあやまったようですな‥‥
So, you've come to your
senses, have you Sir Lawyer?

<Phoenix>
う‥‥むむむ‥‥
（い、言い返せない‥‥）
I... Unnngh...
(Argh! I can't think of a
counter-attack at all...)

<Judge>
この証人のウタガイは、これで
晴れたようです。
It seems the cloud of
suspicion surrounding this
witness has lifted.

それでは、ゴドー検事。
まだ他に、何か証言を‥‥
Mr. Godot.
If you have anything further
to add, then--

<Hold it!>

<Judge>
あ‥‥あ‥‥あなたは‥‥
Wh... Wh-Who...

‥‥ダレですか？
...Who are you?

<Desirée>
どうでもいいでしょ、
そんなの。
That doesn't really matter
right now, does it?

<Phoenix>
ま、まれかさん！
‥‥どうして、ここへ！
Ms. DeLite!
What are you doing here?

<Desirée>
リューイチくん！
Nicky boy!

アナタたちが探してるの‥‥
コレじゃないかな！
The thing you've been
looking for...
I think I found it!

<Judge>
それは‥‥カバン、ですか。
You mean... that bag!?

<Desirée>
問題は、このカバンの中身よ。
‥‥どう？
No, not the bag!
What's in the bag!
...Well?

<Judge>
そ‥‥それは‥‥
Th-That's...

<Maya>
《倉院のツボ》だよッ！
なるほどくん！
The Sacred Urn!!
Nick! It's the urn!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
‥‥あなた！　おじょうさん！
Order! Order! Order!
...You! Madame...!

そのツボ‥‥いったい、
どこで見つけたのですかッ！
That urn...
Where did you find it!?

<Desirée>
聞いておどろかないでよ。
You'll never believe it...

あのエラそうな名探偵、
星威岳　哀牙サンの事務所よっ！
It was in the office of
Mr. Fancy Pants Ace Detective!
...Luke Atmey!

<Ron>
（まれかちゃーん、サイコーだあ）
Oh, Dessie! You're the best!

< >
証拠品《倉院のツボ》の
データを書きなおした。
Sacred Urn updated in the
Court Record.

<Phoenix>
‥‥さあ！
いかがですか、哀牙さん！
Well?
How do you explain
that one, Mr. Atmey!?

<Atmey>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
今度こそ、言い逃れはできない！
あなたこそが‥‥
Even you are going to have
a hard time weaseling out
of this one!

<Objection!>

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　なさけねえ‥‥
Ha...!
Pathetic...

<Judge>
ご、ゴドー検事‥‥？
Mr. Godot...?
Do you have something
you wish to say?

<Godot>
ムカシ、男は背中で語ったもんだ。
それが、今じゃあ‥‥
Yes, Your Honor...
It simply amazes me how
quickly times change...

男のコトバを受け止められるヤツは
いねえ。これも時代だな‥‥
In the old days, a man was
to be taken at his word.
It's truly sad...

<Judge>
ま、まさか‥‥
まだ認めないつもりですか！
You're still denying that
Mr. Atmey was involved!?

<Godot>
モンダイは、ツボを持ってきた
ネエちゃんだ。
Before casting aspersions at
Detective Atmey, consider the
young lady here.

アンタ‥‥たしか、
天杉　優作のカミさん、だったな。
Your name is Desirée...
Desirée DeLite.
Is that correct?

<Desirée>
だ、だから？　それがなんなの？
Y-Yes! What about it?

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　泣かせるじゃねえか。
Ha...!
How charming...

ダンナを助けるために‥‥
こんなコトまでするとはよォ！
The lengths that a woman is
willing to go to save her
husband is truly inspiring.

<Desirée>
な‥‥何よ、それ！
Wh-What are you insinuating!?

<Godot>
犯人のカミさんなら、どこからでも
ツボを“発見”できる。
As the wife of the criminal,
you could have "discovered"
that stolen urn anywhere.

モチロン、
探偵の事務所からでも‥‥なァ。
Including the office of
the good detective here.

ツボは見つかった。
‥‥だからなんだ？
So you found the urn.
What does that prove?

モンダイは‥‥ソイツがどこに
あったのか‥‥だぜ。
It certainly doesn't prove
where the urn was before
you "found" it.

<Desirée>
このツボ‥‥アイツの事務所から
持ってきたのよ！
What...?
I just brought it here from
the detective's office!

<Godot>
‥‥この街には‥‥
悲しいウソがあふれてやがる。
Please Madame...
This town is already filled to
the brim with lies.

もう、これ以上は必要ねえぜ。
‥‥おネエちゃん。
Any more could only compound
the tragedy we have been
witness to.

<Desirée>
ちがう！　アタシ‥‥そんな
汚いコト、していない！
You're wrong!
I would never...!
I would never do such a thing!

<Phoenix>
ま、まれかさん‥‥
Ms. DeLite...

<Desirée>
助けて！　リューイチくんなら
‥‥証明してくれるよね！
Please, Nicky boy! You've
got to help me talk some
sense into these people!




<Phoenix>
（何か‥‥
　方法があるに、ちがいない！）
(There must be some way!)

（あのツボが、哀牙探偵事務所に
　あったことを立証するには‥‥）
(I've got to prove that urn
was actually in the Atmey
Detective Agency...)




<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Godot>
どうした？　しゃべるのが
シゴトじゃなかったのか‥‥？
What's wrong?
Isn't it your job to come
up with something to say...?

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
立証なんて、カンタンじゃない！
Nick! Come on!
It should be easy to prove!

だって‥‥あたしたち、
調べたんだよ。あのバッグ！
After all, we checked out
that bag, didn't we?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ああ。
たしかに、おぼえてるよ。
You're right.
I remember doing that.

中に入っていたのは‥‥カタくて、
丸くて‥‥つるつるしていた。
Whatever was in there,
it was hard and round...
And smooth, too.

<Maya>
さわった感じ、どう考えても
ツボじゃないの、それ！
Yes! It must have been the
urn! It must have!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥ぼくは
それを、見ていないんだ。
But... I never actually
saw it with my own eyes.

<Maya>
え‥‥
...?

<Phoenix>
見ようとしたところで、
哀牙が帰ってきた。だから‥‥
Atmey walked in just when
I was about to have a look
at it...

中身が本当にツボだったか‥‥
ぼくたちには証言できない。
So even if it was the urn in
there, I can't testify that
it was.

<Maya>
そんなああッ！
Ack! You're right!!

<Godot>
クッ‥‥！　
見なおしたぜ、まるほどう。
Ha...!
It looks like I was wrong
about you, Mr. Trite.

ウソにあふれた街で‥‥今、
小さな真実の灯がともりやがった。
In this town overflowing with
lies, there's still a single
flickering candle of truth.

<Desirée>
‥‥リューイチくん‥‥！
Nicky boy...!

<Phoenix>
（たしかにぼくは、あのツボを
　見てはいない‥‥）
(Well, it's true that I never
actually saw the urn...)

（だけど‥‥他の方向から、
　立証できるはずだ‥‥！）
(But maybe I can still testify
about it from another angle!)

<Judge>
‥‥いかがですかな、弁護人。
あきらめますか‥‥？
What about it, Mr. Wright?
Have you given up yet...?


<Phoenix>
‥‥今は‥‥
まだ、立証はできません。
I can't prove anything yet.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
But Nick!

<Judge>
‥‥どうやら‥‥
ここまでのようですな。
Very well...
It looks like that's all then.

<Godot>
そう‥‥このツボこそ、
決定的な証拠だからな‥‥。
Exactly...
And this urn is all the proof
I need to make my case...

<Phoenix>
決定的な‥‥証拠？
What?

<Godot>
まだ、わからねえみたいだな。
‥‥いいか、まるほどう。
You still don't get it, huh?
Listen closely, Mr. Trite.

このツボは、怪人☆仮面マスクが
盗んだモノだ。
This is the urn that
Mask☆DeMasque stole, right?

それを今、被告人のカミさんが
持って、ノコノコ出てきたんだ。
Now the wife of the accused
comes strolling in here with
the very same urn, correct?

さあて‥‥怪人は、ダレだ？
Now, who would you
think is the thief?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥っ！
Ah...!

<Desirée>
ダメ！　アタシ、
そんなつもりじゃあ‥‥
No! That's wrong!
That's not why I've got it...

<Maya>
な‥‥なるほどくん！
ダメだよ！　コレじゃあ‥‥
N-Nick!
Y-You can't let him do this...

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥ここはもう、
　１つしか方法はない！）
(Hmm, this isn't good...
There has to be another
way around this...)

裁判長！　もう一度だけ‥‥
考えさせてくださいッ！
Your Honor! Please let me
think it over one more time!

<Judge>
‥‥弁護人。あなたもそろそろ
おぼえてもいいころです。
Mr. Wright.
It's high time that you
learn your lesson.

いいかげんな発言は、
イノチ取りになるということを！
The courtroom is no place
for poorly thought-out or
rash declarations!

<Phoenix>
（今度こそ‥‥シッパイは
　ユルされないぞ‥‥）
(I have to be careful...
He won't be so nice next
time...)


<Phoenix>
そのツボが、どこにあったか‥‥
立証することは、可能です。
I can prove where
the urn was...

‥‥ツボに残った
“指紋”によって！
...by the fingerprints on it!

<Judge>
指紋‥‥ですか‥‥
Fingerprints, eh...

<Atmey>
あいやッ！
Oh come now!

あいや、弁護士殿。これぞ笑止！
よりによって、指紋とは！
Now you're really making
me laugh, Sir Lawyer!
Fingerprints indeed!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Atmey>
よいですかな？
May I go on?
Good.

ツボに、この哀牙の指紋が残って
いるのは、しごくトーゼンですぞ。
Now, it would be perfectly
understandable if my
fingerprints were on the urn.

なにしろ、ツボを警備していた
のは、この哀牙なのです！
After all, it was I who was
guarding the urn in the first
place!

そもそも、我はこうして、
手袋をハメておる。
In any case, I am always in
the habit of wearing gloves
as you can see.

ザンネンながら、我が指紋は、
証拠にはなりますまい。
So unfortunately, my
fingerprints wouldn't be
evidence of anything.

<Judge>
‥‥いかがですかな？　この証人の
指紋は、イミがないようですが。
What about it, Mr. Wright?
This witness's fingerprints
would mean nothing anyway.

<Maya>
ど‥‥どうするの？
なるほどくん！
N-Nick, what are you going
to do now?

<Phoenix>
（ここまで来て‥‥
　あとには引けない！）
(I've come too far to turn
back now!)

（哀牙探偵が、あのツボを事務所に
　持ちこんだのは、きのう‥‥）
(Atmey must have brought
the urn back to his office
yesterday...)

（そこで指紋をつけた人物が
　ひとり、いるじゃないか‥‥！）
(And there, I'm sure
someone must have left
their fingerprints on it...!)




<Phoenix>
ツボには‥‥この人物の指紋が
残っているはずです！
The defense proposes that
the fingerprints of this
person should be on the urn!




<Godot>
‥‥いいコトを教えてやるよ。
Let me give you an
important piece of advice.

ゲームってのは‥‥最後まで
冷静だったほうが勝つんだぜ。
The one who keeps a cool
head all the way until the
game's end is the winner.

<Judge>
もっといいコトを教えて
あげましょう、成歩堂くん。
Let me give you an even
more important piece of
advice, Mr. Wright...

‥‥少なくとも、そのコタエでは
勝てませんぜ。
You are not going to win
this game with that answer.

<Maya>
なな、なんか裁判長まで
カッコよくなってきたよ‥‥
Wow... Even the judge is
making cool, snappy remarks
now...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ぼくが
　まちがっていたのか‥‥？）
(D-Does that mean
I was wrong again?)

（ツボは‥‥きのう、あのバッグに
　入れられて、事務所に置かれた）
(Hmm... The urn was put in
that bag and carried to the
detective's office yesterday.)

（だから、ぼくが
　探すべきなのは‥‥）
(That means the person I
should be fingering is...)

（きのう、あの事務所で
　ツボに指紋をつけた人物‥‥！）
(...the person who left their
prints on the urn yesterday at
the Atmey Detective Agency!)

<Maya>
そんなヒト‥‥ホントに
いるのかなあ‥‥？
Do you really think there's
someone that could fit
the bill?



<Judge>
‥‥さて。
どうしますかな？　弁護人。
Well, Mr. Wright?
What have you decided to do?

<Phoenix>
すみません‥‥もう一度、
最初から考えなおしてみます。
Forgive me, Your Honor.
I've decided to think the
whole thing over again.


<Judge>
‥‥さて。
どうしますかな？　弁護人。
Well, Mr. Wright?
What have you decided?

<Phoenix>
裁判長！　もう一度だけ、
おねがいします。
Your Honor!
Please give me just one
more chance!





<Judge>
そこまで！
That's enough!

本法廷は、これ以上の審議の
必要性を認めません。
This court sees no reason to
further prolong this trial.

さらに、被告に対する判決を
決める時間も、必要としません。
Nor is there any need for
more time to decide the case
against the defendant.

これは、きわめて明白な事件です。
疑問の余地はない！
This case is extremely clear.
I see no room for mis-
interpretation of the facts.

被告人、天杉　優作に
たった今、判決を言いわたします！
This court finds the
defendant, Ron DeLite...

被告人はこれより身柄を
司直に預けるものとし、
The accused will surrender
to the court immediately...

１ヶ月以内に、高等裁判所において
通常裁判を受けることとします。
...to be held pending trial at
a higher court within a
month from today's date.

では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
That is all.
The court is adjourned!




