< >
１０月２０日　午前１０時
地方裁判所　第４法廷
October 20, 10:00 AM
District Court
Courtroom No. 4

<Judge>
これより、荷星　三郎の
法廷を開廷します。
Court is now in session for
the trial of Mr. Will Powers.

<Edgeworth>
検察側、
準備完了しております。
The prosecution is ready,
Your Honor.

<Phoenix>
弁護側も、
準備完了しています。
The defense is ready,
Your Honor.

<Judge>
今日は、審理の最終日になります。
Today will be the final
day of this trial.

検察側、弁護側とも、決定的な
証拠の提出をするように。
I hope both the prosecution
and the defense will be able
to present decisive evidence.

では、御剣検事。
‥‥冒頭弁論をおねがいします。
Very well, Mr. Edgeworth.
Your opening statement.

<Edgeworth>
昨日の法廷で、弁護人によって
新しい説が提示された。
In yesterday's session, the
defense presented us with
a new theory for this case.

殺人現場は、実は
第２スタジオだった、という。
He claims that the scene
of the crime was, in fact,
Studio Two.

本日は、実際にコテージにいた
人間を証人として呼び、
Today, I will call on people
present in the Studio Two
trailer that day.

その事実関係をハッキリさせたい。
From their testimonies, the
truth will become clear.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥わかりました。
Hmm... very well!

<Phoenix>
（御剣のヤツ‥‥今日はちょっと、
　ひかえめだな‥‥）
(Edgeworth seems a bit
on edge today...)

<Judge>
では、
証人を呼んでいただきましょう。
You may call your first
witness, Mr. Edgeworth.

<Edgeworth>
事件当日、第２スタジオの
コテージで会議をしていた、
The prosecution calls Ms.
Dee Vasquez to the stand.

姫神　サクラプロデューサーを。
Ms. Dee Vasquez is a producer
who was present in the Studio
Two trailer that day.

<Edgeworth>
証人。
‥‥名前と、職業を。
Will the witness state her
name and occupation?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

姫神　サクラ。
英都撮影所のプロデューサー。
Dee Vasquez.
I am a producer for
Global Studios.

<Edgeworth>
証人は、事件当日、
第２スタジオのコテージで‥‥
On the day of the murder,
you were in the trailer in
Studio Two...

<Vasquez>
‥‥そんなことは、みんな
知ってるでしょ。
As everyone here knows,
yes?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥？
...?

<Vasquez>
よけいなことはキライ。
I dislike needless banter.

どうしてもやりたいなら、
アタクシぬきでやりなさい。
If you must pontificate, do
it when I'm not here.

<Edgeworth>
むぐぐ。
Mrrph!

<Judge>
で、では、証人。
V-very well, Ms. Vasquez.

事件当日のことを、
《証言》してください。
Please give the court your
testimony concerning the
day of the murder.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
このヒトがハンニンなんだよね！
Nick! I know she did it!
Make her pay!

<Phoenix>
ああ。‥‥そうさ！
R-right!

（ゼッタイ、シッポを
　つかんでやるぞ‥‥）
(If she's guilty, I'll
catch her with her pants
down... So to speak.)

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
-- The Day of the Murder --

<Vasquez>
‥‥正午の少し前、第２スタジオの
コテージに入ったわ。
I entered the trailer, oh,
a little before noon.

会議が始まったのは、正午。
終わったのは４時。
The meeting began at 12:00
sharp. It ended at 4:00.

それから、リハーサルがあるから
第１スタジオへ。
There was to be a rehearsal
afterwards, so we went to
Studio One...

‥‥‥‥そう、つかれてたから、
宇在に運ばせたわ。
I was fatigued, so I
had Sal take me.

会議の休憩は、
２時３０分から１５分間だった。
At 2:30, we took a 15-minute
break in the meeting.

宇在といっしょに、コテージの前で
ホネつきステーキを食べていたわ。
Sal and I ate t-bone steaks
on the table in front of the
trailer.

第１スタジオに行って、そこで
イブクロの死体を見つけたわけ。
We found Hammer's body
later, when we all went
to Studio One.

<Vasquez>
‥‥そんなところね。
That's all.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

証言で、１つだけ
気になったことがあります。
I have a question about
one part of your testimony.

“つかれていたから、宇在に
運ばせた”‥‥というのは？
You were "fatigued" so you 
had Sal "take" you...?

<Vasquez>
クルマ。
The van.

<Judge>
‥‥は？
Hmm?

<Vasquez>
ライトバンがあったでしょ？
第２スタジオ。
There's a van at Studio Two.

<Vasquez>
あれ、宇在に運転させたの。
I had him take me in that.

‥‥サルマゲどんのクビも
あって、あぶなかったし。
I thought it might be risky
to walk, what with that
monkey's head toppling over.

< >
《ライトバン》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Van added to the
Court Record.

<Judge>
な、なるほど‥‥。
I... I see!

では、弁護人。
《尋問》‥‥を。
Very well. Mr. Wright,
your cross-examination.

<Maya>
最後の勝負だよ。
‥‥がんばって！
This is the final battle,
Nick! Let's do it!

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
-- The Day of the Murder --




<Vasquez>
‥正午の少し前に、第２スタジオの
コテージに入ったわ。
I entered the trailer, oh,
a little before noon.


<Vasquez>
会議が始まったのは、正午。
終わったのは４時。
The meeting began at 12:00
sharp. It ended at 4:00.


<Vasquez>
それから、リハーサルがあるから
第１スタジオへ。
There was to be a rehearsal
afterwards, so we went to
Studio One.


<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥そう、つかれてたから、
宇在に運ばせたわ。
I was fatigued, so I
had Sal take me.


<Vasquez>
会議の休憩は、
２時３０分から１５分間だった。
At 2:30, we took a 15-minute
break in the meeting.


<Vasquez>
宇在といっしょに、コテージの前で
ホネつきステーキを食べていたわ。
Sal and I ate t-bone steaks
on the table in front of the
trailer.


<Maya>
なるほどくん。‥‥どう？
Well, Nick? Find anything?

<Phoenix>
もう少し、たくさんしゃべって
くれるとありがたいんだけど‥‥。
I kind of wish she'd
said a little more...

<Maya>
相手はヤリ手プロデューサー
だもんね‥‥。
It's hard. I think she's
pretty used to being the boss.

でも、きっとどこかに
ムジュンがあるはずだよ！
But I'm sure you'll find some
kind of contradiction in what
she said... somewhere!

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
お１人で？
By yourself?

<Vasquez>
そう。
Yes.

<Phoenix>
スタッフエリアには
カオを出さなかったんですか。
And you didn't stop in
at the Employee Area?

<Vasquez>
そう。
No.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

会話、はずみませんね。
Are you always this... terse?

<Vasquez>
そう？
Yes.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Oh dear...)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
そのあいだ、席を立った人は
いませんか？
Did no one leave during
the meeting?

<Vasquez>
いないわ。
No one.

‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

も、もっとしゃべりましょうよ。
C-come on... let's talk
a bit more about that.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
証人は、おしゃべりをしに来た
ワケではない！
The witness did not come
here to engage in idle
conversation!

証言のジャマをしないでもらおう！
Stop interrupting the
testimony.

<Vasquez>
アナタもよ、検事さん。
The same could be said to
you, Mr. Edgeworth.

ムヤミに机をたたかないで。
‥‥耳ざわりだから。
And please stop banging
on your little desk. It
hurts my ears.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥うぐ。
Mmph!

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
それは、何時ごろですか？
And when exactly was that?

<Vasquez>
わすれたわ。
I've forgotten.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
お、思い出そうという気は
ないんですか。
Maybe you could try
remembering?

<Vasquez>
ないわ。
No.

<Edgeworth>
会議が４時に終わり、リハーサルは
５時からだった。
The meeting ended at 4:00,
and the rehearsal was
scheduled for 5:00...

おそらく、そのあいだだろう。
I would think it was
between those times.

<Phoenix>
（“おそらく”も何も、
　そんなのアタリマエだろうが！）
(You "would think"!? C'mon,
all you did was state the
obvious, Edgeworth!)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
ちょっと待ってください！
Hold on!

“宇在に運ばせた”‥‥って、
どういう意味ですか？
You had Sal "take" you?
What does that mean!?

<Vasquez>
‥‥さっき、言ったわ。
It means what I just said.

ライトバン、運転させたの。
‥‥宇在に。
I had Sal take me in
the Studio Two van.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そういえば、
　そんなこと、言ってたっけ‥‥）
(Oh... oh, right.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
その時間は、何を‥‥？
And what were you doing
during that time...?

<Vasquez>
机をたたかないで。
Don't hit your desk.

‥‥うるさいわ。
It irritates me.

<Edgeworth>
そうだぞ！　弁護人‥‥！
あ。
Yeah! Mr. Wright...!

<Edgeworth>
Oops.

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

休憩した時間は‥‥１５分。
It was a 15 minute break...

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
それを証明してくれる人は
いますか！
Do you have someone who
can verify this?

<Vasquez>
‥‥宇在。
Sal.

<Phoenix>
い、いや。
‥‥その他の人たちは？
N-no...
I mean someone else?

<Vasquez>
じゅうぶんでしょ。
１人いれば。
One person is enough.

<Phoenix>
（休憩時間のあいだに
　事件が起こったとすれば‥‥）
(If she committed murder
during that break...)

（当然、ステーキなど
　食べているヒマはない‥‥）
(She wouldn't have had time
to eat a t-bone steak!)

（“ステーキを食べていなかった”
　という証拠はないかな‥‥？）
(If I had some evidence that
proved she didn't eat that
steak...)


<Phoenix>
思ったとおり、そう来ましたね。
Hah! As I thought!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
“ホネつきステーキを
食べていた”‥‥。
You claim you ate a t-bone
steak!

しかし、それはおかしいんです！
But I say you did not!

<Judge>
ど‥‥どういうことですか？
W-what's this, now,
Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
これを見てください。
Look at this.

<Judge>
皿‥‥ですか。
It's... a plate?

<Phoenix>
これは、スタッフエリアの
テーブルにあった皿です。
This plate was on the table
in the employee room.

ごらんのように、
大きなホネが残っている。
As you can see, a large
bone has been left behind.

<Edgeworth>
当然だろう。
‥‥ホネつきステーキなんだから。
Mr. Wright. Need I remind
you it was a T-BONE STEAK!?

<Phoenix>
そう。‥‥当然です。
Exactly my point!

しかし。
‥‥思い出してください。
Remember, if you will...

コテージの外にあった、
テーブルの上を‥‥。
Ms. Vasquez and Mr. Manella
ate at a table outside the
trailer.

このテーブルの皿の上には‥‥
Yet there were no bones left
on the plates!

ホネは残っていない！
The plates were bare!

<Vasquez>
‥‥！
!

<Phoenix>
姫神さん！
Ms. Vasquez?

もし、ホネつきステーキを
食べたのなら、
Tell me, how can a person
eat a t-bone steak...

当然ですが、ホネが残ります。
and not leave the bone?




<Phoenix>
つまり、あなたは‥‥
I think I know how!




<Phoenix>
ホネもいっしょに食べたんです！
You ate the bone, too!

<Maya>
どうしてそうなるの、
なるほどくん‥‥。
Um, Nick... are you sure?

さすがのあたしも、ホネは
残すよ！
I mean, I love steak, but
even I don't eat the bone!

<Phoenix>
ぼくだって残すよ！
Hey, I don't eat it either!

<Judge>
成歩堂くん！
Mr. Wright!

‥‥私も、ホネは残しますよ。
I, too, leave the bone.

<Phoenix>
も、もう一度、おねがいします。
Um, can I try that again?


<Phoenix>
あなたが食べたステーキには、
ホネがなかったのです！
Elementary! You were eating
a boneless steak!

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥。
...

だとしたら、
Mr. Wright, say you
are right...

そんな、指をつきつけて
言うほどのこともありませんね。
What would that prove?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

そうですね。
Um, right, Your Honor.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick!

姫神さんの証言を思い出して！
Remember her testimony?

<Vasquez>
“宇在といっしょに、
ホネつきステーキを食べていたわ”
She said she ate a "t-bone
steak"!

<Maya>
ハッキリ“ホネつき”って
言ってたじゃない！
She said "bone"!

<Phoenix>
そのとおり。
‥‥真宵ちゃんをためしたのさ。
Correct!
I was... testing you!

<Maya>
ウソだぁ。
Yeah, sure, Nick.

<Phoenix>
すみません。
‥‥もう一度おねがいします。
Sorry...
Can I try that one more time?

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥。
...


<Phoenix>
あなたは休憩時間中、
ステーキは食べなかったのです！
You didn't eat any steak
during that break!

きっとステーキは、焼却炉にでも
捨ててしまったのでしょう！
You took your steak and
threw it somewhere... like
that incinerator!

<Vasquez>
！
!

<Vasquez>
...

<Judge>
で、では‥‥、
I... I see!

姫神さんは休憩中、
何をしていたと‥‥？
Then what was Ms. Vasquez
doing during her break?

<Phoenix>
決まっているじゃないですか！
Isn't it obvious, Your Honor?



<Phoenix>
宇在カントクを
いじめていたんですよ！
She was picking on
Mr. Manella!

<Judge>
‥‥弁護人。
たまにあなたは、
Mr. Wright...

ホンキだかジョウダンだか
わからないことを言いますね。
Sometimes this court finds it
hard to tell whether you are
joking or being serious.

<Phoenix>
ええ。
Oh...?

<Judge>
できれば、
ホンキだけにしてください。
I would prefer it if you
remained serious!

<Phoenix>
はあ。
そうします‥‥、できれば。
Y-yes, Your Honor.
I'll do my best.




<Phoenix>
もちろん、トノサマンに
会っていたんですよ！
She was meeting with
the Steel Samurai!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！
Order!

ま、まさか‥‥！
A-are you saying...!?

<Phoenix>
そのとおりです。
Yes, Your Honor!

<Phoenix>
ステーキを食べるため、
コテージを出た姫神さんは‥‥
As Ms. Vasquez left the
trailer to eat her steak...

トノサマンに出くわしたのです！
She ran into the
Steel Samurai!

そしてあなたは、彼を‥‥
And then you did it.

<Phoenix>
殺害したのです。
‥‥その手でッ！
You killed him with
your own hands!

<Vasquez>
！！
!!!

<Judge>
べ‥‥弁護人！
M-Mr. Wright!

そ、その発言は、問題が‥‥
I-isn't that a little
presumptuous!?

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
どういうことだ！
成歩堂、キミは‥‥
What kind of stunt are you
trying to pull, Wright!?

<Vasquez>
かまわないわ。
Let him claim what he wants....

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。

アタクシがやった、と？
You say I did it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥はい。
Yes.

<Vasquez>
‥‥おもしろいわ。
Fascinating!

ひさしぶりに、タイクツを
わすれられそうね‥‥。
And here I was worrying that
today would be as boring
as all the rest.

‥‥‥‥。
...

いいわ。
Very well.

これから、アナタとアタクシの
チエくらべと行きましょう。
Let us have a battle
of wits, you and I.

<Phoenix>
（受けて立つぞ‥‥！）
(Any day, Vasquez!)

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
‥‥しっかりね！
Good luck, Nick!

<Vasquez>
そうね‥‥。
Let's see...

たしか、凶器は
トノサマン・スピアーだったわね。
What was that murder weapon
again? Oh yes, the "Samurai
Spear."

<Phoenix>
‥‥はい。
Yes...?

<Vasquez>
アタクシ、見たとおり
かよわい女よ。
I am, as you can see,
a woman of petite stature.

こんなアタクシが、重いスピアーを
自由にあつかえると思って？
How could I possibly use that
heavy spear as a weapon?




<Phoenix>
不可能ではないでしょう！
It's not impossible!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
不可能ではないかもしれない。
しかし、問題はそんなコトではなく
Well, maybe it's not
impossible, but--

<Vasquez>
おだまりなさい。
Silence.

‥‥アタクシが話してるの。
I'm speaking.

<Edgeworth>
ぐむむ。
Mmmph!

<Vasquez>
被害者は、胸を正面から
刺されているわ。
The victim was stabbed
through the chest from
the front, yes?

つまり、被害者は犯人に
気づいていた、ということでしょ。
I believe this would indicate
that the victim was aware of
the killer's presence.

トノサマンの着ぐるみは、
軽く、動きやすくできてるわ。
Now, the Steel Samurai
costume is quite light
and mobile.

腕力も、走る速さも、すべて
負けているアタクシが、
Compared to the victim, I am
weaker and slower...

被害者とマトモに戦って、
勝てるわけがない。
I couldn't possibly
win such a fight!

しかも、写真が示しているとおり、
Not to mention, there is
proof I did not have the
spear!

そのスピアーは、
被害者自身が持ってきたものよ。
The photograph of the Steel
Samurai shows that the victim
himself was holding it!

アタクシが、彼からそれを
チカラずくで奪ったとでも言うの？
Or do you mean to suggest
that I could have wrested
it away from him?

<Edgeworth>
そ‥‥そうだぞ！　成歩堂！
Y-yeah! Take that, Wright!

それでも“やった”と言うなら、
その証拠を見せたまえッ！
If you still think she did
it, show us proof!

<Phoenix>
う‥‥うううん‥‥。
Umm... er... 

<Maya>
ねえ‥‥なるほどくん。
Hey, Nick.

トノサマン・スピアーのデータを
ちょっと見てみて。
Look at the data we have
on that Samurai Spear in
the Court Record.

‥‥気になること、ない‥‥？
Isn't there something in
there that gets to you...?

<Phoenix>
トノサマン・スピアーのデータ？
Something odd about the
Samurai Spear...?

‥‥‥‥。
...

あっ！
Wait!

<Judge>
どうしましたか？　弁護人？
Something the matter,
Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
す、すみません。
S-sorry, Your Honor.

さっきの発言を取り消します。
I'd like to take back
my previous claim.

<Judge>
‥‥しかたありませんね。
Very well, I won't hold
you to your claim.

しかし、ペナルティは受けて
もらいます。
But I'm afraid I will have
to penalize you.




<Phoenix>
（ひゃあ‥‥）
(Ugh...)

<Edgeworth>
“発言を取り消す”‥‥？
どういうことだ。
What's this?
You're taking back your claim?

<Phoenix>
とにかく、話をもどしましょう。
Let's backtrack for
a moment.

“証人がトノサマン・スピアーを
使うことができたかどうか？”
I want to consider whether
the witness could have used
the Samurai Spear or not!


<Phoenix>
‥‥まあ、あなたでなくても、
あれを武器にして戦うのは、
I think you would have
a great deal of difficulty
using that as a weapon.

フツーなら、ムリでしょうね。
Pretty much anyone would.

<Vasquez>
‥‥フッ。
Hah.

わかってるじゃない。
You see?

<Phoenix>
でも。
Yes...


<Phoenix>
‥‥それは、わかりません。
I don't know.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
“わからない”だと！
‥‥そんなイイカゲンなこと‥‥
You "don't know"!?
What kind of a lawyer
are you!?

<Vasquez>
アタクシが話してるの。
‥‥ジャマしないで。
Quiet. I'm speaking.

<Edgeworth>
むむむ。
M-m-mmph!

<Vasquez>
“わからない”ですって？
そんなイイカゲンなこと‥‥
You "don't know"!?
What kind of a lawyer...

<Phoenix>
トノサマン・スピアーで、あなたが
戦えたかどうか‥‥。
I don't know whether
you could have fought
with the Samurai Spear...




<Phoenix>
そんなことは、このさい
関係ないんですよ‥‥。
However, that has no
bearing on this case!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

どういうこと？
Meaning?

<Phoenix>
凶器は、トノサマン・スピアーでは
なかったんですからね。
The Samurai Spear was
not the murder weapon!

<Vasquez>
なッ！
What!?

<Judge>
な、何を言い出すのですか！
What is the meaning of this!?

スピアーは、死体のそばに
ころがっていたのですぞ！
The spear was found lying
next to the victim's body!

<Phoenix>
証拠をお見せしましょう。
I have proof, Your Honor.




<Phoenix>
トノサマン・スピアーが
凶器ではないという証拠を‥‥！
I can prove that the 
Samurai Spear was not
used as the murder weapon!


<Judge>
違いますね、それは。
Wrong, Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
‥‥まだ、何も言ってませんよ。
But I haven't said
anything yet...?

<Judge>
慣れてきましたからね。
あやしいフンイキを感じます。
I know you well enough by now
to know when you're going to
present the wrong evidence.

<Maya>
あたしも感じる。
‥‥綾里家の霊力で。
I can sense it too, with
my Fey blood...

<Phoenix>
（ようするに、この証拠品は
　違う、ということだな）
(Okay, okay, so I picked the
wrong evidence! Enough with
all the sensing!)

<Phoenix>
わかりました。
‥‥本当の証拠をお見せします。
Right.
Okay, here's the real
evidence, Your Honor.


<Phoenix>
証拠は、言うまでもなく
こいつですよ。
I present my proof: the
so-called "murder weapon"!

<Edgeworth>
凶器‥‥そのものだとッ！
B-but, that IS the
murder weapon!

<Phoenix>
いいですか。
Not so fast.

午前中の打ち合わせで、
このスピアーは一度、折れている！
Remember that this spear
broke during the morning
action scene run-through?

折れたスピアーを修理したのは
‥‥オバチャンです。
But, someone fixed the
spear.

<Phoenix>
It was the security lady!

ガムテープでね。
She fixed it with duct tape!

<Phoenix>
そんなもので、
Now tell me, how is it
possible...

ぶあつい着ぐるみをつけた被害者の
胸を、刺せるわけがない！
for someone to stab a man
who is wearing a thick costume
with this!? Through the chest!

<Judge>
せ、静粛に‥‥！
O-order! Order!

<Edgeworth>
弁護人！　どういうことだ！
Mr. Wright! What are you
driving at!?

自分が何を言ってるか‥‥
Think about what you're--

<Vasquez>
おだまりッ！
Silence!

アタクシをムシしないこと。
I'm the one testifying here
and I will be heard!

<Edgeworth>
うむむ‥‥。
Mmmph...!

<Vasquez>
どういうことかしら？
Are you quite sane?

<Vasquez>
自分が何を言ってるか、
わかってるの？
Are you even aware of what
you're saying?

<Vasquez>
トノサマン・スピアーが
凶器じゃないというなら、
If the Samurai Spear was
not the murder weapon,
then pray tell what was!?

いったい、衣袋は
どうやって殺されたと言うの？
How was Hammer killed?




<Judge>
どうですか？　イブクロさんを
殺害した凶器を、提示できますか？
Well, Mr. Wright? Can you 
tell us what weapon was
used to kill Mr. Hammer?



<Phoenix>
もちろんできません。
Of course I can't.

<Judge>
も、“もちろん”‥‥？
"O-of course"!?

<Edgeworth>
なんだそのタイドは！
Can the antics, Wright!

<Judge>
わからないにしても、
もう少し言い方があるでしょう！
I have to agree, Mr. Wright.
At least pretend that you
think you might know!

<Phoenix>
（しまった‥‥思ったことを
　そのまま言ってしまった‥‥）
(Urk. Note to self: think
before speaking.)

（オトナの世界は、
　気をつかうよなあ‥‥）
(Tough crowd...)


<Phoenix>
できなければ、こんなコトは
言いません。
Would I make a claim like
that if I couldn't tell you
what the weapon was?

<Judge>
いつもながら、ウサンくさいほどの
自信ですね‥‥。
I'm afraid your confidence
can sometimes be unfounded,
Mr. Wright...




<Judge>
では、示していただきましょう。
イブクロさんを殺害した凶器を。
Very well, let's see this
murder weapon, then.


<Maya>
おねがいッ！　なるほどくん！
Nick!

もう一度、考えなおして！
Think about this some
more!

<Phoenix>
え？　なんで？
Huh? Think?

<Maya>
だって‥‥。
Please!

そんなものが凶器なワケ、
ないじゃない‥‥。
How could that possibly
have been the murder weapon!?

<Phoenix>
（それもそうか‥‥）
(Hmm. She has a point.)

<Judge>
どうしましたか？
Something the matter?

<Phoenix>
いえっ。べつに。
‥‥なんでもありませんよ。
N-no, Your Honor.
Nothing!


<Phoenix>
‥‥この写真を見てください。
Look at this photo.

<Judge>
な‥‥なんですか、これは‥‥。
W-what is this?

‥‥階段の上にいるのは‥‥
い、衣袋　武志ですか‥‥！
Why, that's Jack Hammer
standing at the top of
the stairs!

<Judge>
せ、静粛に！　静粛に！
O-order! Order!

さわぎがおさまらなければ、
審理を中止しますぞ！
If I cannot have order this
trial will be suspended!

弁護人！
Mr. Wright!

どういうことですか
これは！
What is this all about!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥今から５年前。
This photograph is from
five years ago.

英都撮影所で、
不幸な事故がありました。
There was an unfortunate
accident at Global Studios.

見てのとおりの事故が、ね。
This is a photo of that
very accident.

このことは、いっさい
外部には知らされなかった。
Not a word of this was
leaked to the outside.

英都だけのヒミツだったのです。
It was a close-kept
secret at the studios.

<Edgeworth>
それが、今回の事件と
なんの関係があるというのだ！
What does this have to
do with the current case!?

<Phoenix>
御剣検事‥‥。
Mr. Edgeworth...

‥‥まだ、わかりませんか？
You still can't see it?

階段から転落して、鉄柵で
胸を刺された、この男を見て‥‥。
See the fallen man in this
photo? See how the fencepost
pierced him through the chest?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥あ、ああッ！
Wh... what!?

な‥‥なんということだ‥‥。
Are you saying...!?

<Phoenix>
この事故があったのは、今から
５年前でした。
Yes.

それと同じコトが‥‥
What happened five years
ago...

<Phoenix>
ふたたび、起こったのです！
has happened again!

<Vasquez>
！！
!!!

<Judge>
成歩堂くん！
‥‥つづけなさい！
Mr. Wright!
Continue!

<Phoenix>
事件のあった日の、
午後２時３０分！
It's 2:30 PM on the day
of the murder!

姫神　サクラは、コテージのそとで
イブクロさんと会ったのです！
Ms. Dee Vasquez meets
Jack Hammer outside
the Studio Two trailer!

そして彼女は、
Then she did it!

故意か事故かはわかりませんが、
イブクロさんを‥‥
She pushed Mr. Hammer off
the stairs onto the fence!

つきおとしたのです！
‥‥鉄柵の上に。
Just like Mr. Hammer had
himself done five years ago!

５年前、イブクロさん自身が
そうしたように‥‥。
Though whether she did it
on purpose or by accident,
I cannot say.

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Edgeworth>
つまり、被害者は‥‥
衣袋　武志は‥‥、
I-in other words...
th-the victim, Mr. Hammer...

自分が人を死なせてしまった、
そのやり方で、
He died in the same way
that he caused another
man to die...

今度は、自らのイノチを
落とした、というワケかッ！
five years ago!

<Phoenix>
‥‥そういうことになりますね。
Precisely.

<Phoenix>
Ironic, isn't it?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

フ‥‥フッ。
よくできた話。
Hoh hoh.
Very creative, Mr. Wright.

その、出まかせの才能‥‥。
ウチの脚本家としてほしいわね。
I could use a man like you
on my script writing staff.

<Phoenix>
何か、反論がありますか？
You deny that what
I say is true?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

‥‥いい？
Mr. Wright.

アナタの言うとおり、衣袋が
コテージで死んだとしましょう。
Let's say, for the sake of
argument, that Hammer died
at the trailer as you say.

でも実際は、死体は
第１スタジオで見つかったのよ。
Yet, the body was found
at Studio One, was it not?

アクダイカーンの着ぐるみの
中からね。
And in the Evil Magistrate's
costume, no less.

<Vasquez>
死体を第１スタジオに運んで、
着ぐるみの中に入れる‥‥、
Are you then claiming that
I carried the body to
Studio One...

そんなの、休憩時間の１５分じゃ
ゼッタイに不可能よ。
And returned to the trailer,
all in the space of 
a 15 minute break?

いったい私は、どうやって
死体を始末できたと言うの？
How could I have
disposed of the body!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Edgeworth>
コテージでは、２時３０分から
１５分だけ、休憩をとった。
The break in the meeting
at the trailer lasted 15
minutes, from 2:30 to 2:45.

その間に、衣袋　武志を階段から
つきおとして殺害して、
Could Jack Hammer have been
pushed off the stairs to
his death...

第１スタジオに運んで、
着ぐるみの中に入れる‥‥。
then carried to Studio One
and placed inside his
costume?

たしかに、時間的にムリが
あるな‥‥。
There wasn't enough time!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥たしかに。
Hmm... indeed.




<Judge>
いかがですか？　弁護人。
‥‥死体の問題については？
Well, Mr. Wright?
How could she have dealt
with the body?




<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥時間的に、
１５分じゃムリですね‥‥。
15 minutes is kind of
a short amount of time...

<Vasquez>
そうでしょ。
You see?

ムリなことは、できない。
Even I cannot do
the impossible.

だから、アタクシは‥‥
Therefore, Mr. Wright.

犯人じゃない。
‥‥よろしいかしら？
I didn't do it.
Agreed?

<Phoenix>
よろしくありません。
Not agreed!

<Vasquez>
‥‥？
?


<Phoenix>
や‥‥やれば
できるんじゃないですか？
You'd be surprised!
I bet she could do it!

ニンゲンて、死んだ気になれば、
思ったよりも、やるもんですよ。
When people think their
life depends on it, they
can do amazing things!

<Judge>
ここでニンゲンを語られても
困ります。
Mr. Wright, this is not
an episode of "That's
Incredible."

<Edgeworth>
“１５分ですべてのことができた”
というならば‥‥
If you claim she did
everything in 15 minutes...

<Phoenix>
（“その証拠を出せ”ってか？）
(Let me guess:
"Show Me Proof!")

<Edgeworth>
そのとおり！
‥‥証拠を出してもらおう！
Correct!
Show me proof!

<Phoenix>
（そんなの、ムリに
　決まってるだろう‥‥）
(How am I supposed to
do that...?)

<Edgeworth>
ならば、テキトーなことは
言わないでもらいたい！
Then I won't have you making
unsubstantiated claims!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥‥‥）
(...)

（なんでさっきから、ぼくの
　考えていることがわかるんだ？）
(Wait a second, how does
he know what I'm thinking!?)

<Edgeworth>
ハッ‥‥！
Hah!

その冷や汗の感じで、なんとなく
わかるのだよ。
I need only look at the cold
sweat running down your face
to know what you're thinking!

<Judge>
弁護人。‥‥もう一度、
考えなおしてください。
Mr. Wright. Perhaps you'd
like to reconsider your claim?


<Phoenix>
死体を運び出す方法が‥‥
他にもあったら、どうでしょうか。
What if she had another way
to carry the body, other than
with her own hands?

<Vasquez>
‥‥どういうこと？
For instance?

<Phoenix>
何も、ムリにすべてを
１５分におさめることはない。
Actually, for that matter,
there was no need for her
to do the deed in 15 minutes!

あなたには、死体を運び出す
方法が、１つだけあったのです。
And there was a way for
you to carry that body.

<Vasquez>
！！
!!!

い‥‥いいわ。
聞かせてもらいましょう？
I-interesting!
Let's hear it then.

<Judge>
では、弁護人。
Mr. Wright?




<Judge>
示してもらいましょう。
‥‥死体を運んだ方法を。
Please show us how
she carried the body.


<Phoenix>
姫神　サクラは、これを使って
死体を現場に運んだのです！
Dee Vasquez used this to
carry the body to Studio One!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Judge>
‥‥成歩堂くん。
Mr. Wright...

<Phoenix>
はい。
Your Honor?

<Judge>
そんなもので、
死体を運べますか？
Mr. Wright, how can you
carry a dead body with that?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ううん‥‥。
Umm...

<Judge>
もう一度、考えてもらいましょう。
Please rethink your statement.


<Phoenix>
姫神さん。
Ms. Vasquez.

あなたは、死体を第１スタジオに
運んだのです。
You carried the body
to Studio One.

この、ライトバンに乗せて。
And you used the studio
van to do it!

<Vasquez>
！！
!!!

<Phoenix>
あなたはさっき、
こう証言しましたね‥‥。
Recall your testimony...

<Vasquez>
会議のあと、リハーサルがあるから
第１スタジオへ。
There was to be a rehearsal
afterwards, so we went to
Studio One.

つかれてたから、宇在に
運ばせたわ。
I was fatigued,
so I had Sal take me.

ライトバンがあったでしょ？
‥‥宇在に運転させたの。
There was a van there, right?
I had Sal drive me.

<Phoenix>
あなたは、ライトバンに死体を
乗せて第１スタジオへ行ったんだ！
You used the van to carry
the body to Studio One!

そして、みんなが集まる前に、
死体を着ぐるみに入れたんです！
Then, before everyone else
got there, you put the body
into the Magistrate costume!

<Vasquez>
‥‥ッ！
...!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
ちょっと待て！
Hold on, Wright!

ライトバンを運転したのは、
宇在カントクだったはずだ！
Don't forget, it was Sal
Manella that drove the van!

弁護人は、宇在カントクが
共犯だったと言うのか！
Are you suggesting that 
Mr. Manella was a conspirator?



<Phoenix>
もちろん違います！
Of course he wasn't!

<Edgeworth>
ハッ！
Hah!

宇在の目を盗んで死体を
ライトバンに乗せて、
So, without Mr. Manella
noticing anything, she put
the body in the van...

宇在の目を盗んで着ぐるみに
入れた‥‥
Then managed to put the body
into the costume...?

ホンキで
そう主張するつもりかッ！
Are you seriously suggesting
that is possible!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

ホンキなワケ、
ないじゃないですか。
Of course I'm not serious.

<Edgeworth>
は‥‥はぅぅッ！
Ha... hah!?

<Phoenix>
ジョークですよ。
‥‥この場をなごませる。
I was kidding. To, er,
lighten up the proceedings.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥な、な‥‥
Li..light... 

なごむかッ！
Lighten!?
Y-you can't lighten up
a murder!

<Judge>
弁護人。
Mr. Wright.

主張するときは、つねに
ホンキでおねがいします。
The court requests you refrain
from making claims in jest.

<Phoenix>
は、はい‥‥。
Y-yes, Your Honor.




<Phoenix>
トーゼン、宇在カントクは
共犯です！
Of course, Sal Manella has
to have been a conspirator!

死体をライトバンに積み込むのも、
着ぐるみに入れるのも、
The body had to be placed in
the van, and put into the
costume.

姫神さん１人では、
ムリですからね！
There's no way Ms. Vasquez
could have done that alone!

それに、トノサマンの着ぐるみも
始末させたんじゃないですか？
Also, don't forget that
they had to dispose of the
Steel Samurai costume.

イブクロさんの血が
ついていますからね！
They had to... because it
was covered in Mr. Hammer's
blood!

おそらく、あの小さな焼却炉で
焼いたのでしょう‥‥。
They probably burned it
in that small incinerator.

どうですか！　姫神さん！
Well, Ms. Vasquez!

‥‥まだ、つづけますか？
Shall I continue?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

もう、ケッコウ。
No need.

アナタ‥‥見かけ以上に
やるわね。
You're smarter than
you look, Mr. Wright.

フッ‥‥。
Hmph.

アタクシの負け。
‥‥楽しかったわ。
I lose. You win.
It... was fun.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やった‥‥）
(I... win!?)

‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

< >
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥あの。
Umm...

それで？
So... what happens next?

<Vasquez>
？
?

<Phoenix>
“？”じゃありませんよ。
Don't "?" me!

何か、言うことはないんですか？
Don't you have anything
to say!?

<Vasquez>
何を言えばいいの？
What would you like me to say?

<Phoenix>
え？
Huh?

“負けましたわ”とかなんとか。
"I lost"?
Something like that!

<Vasquez>
それならさっき、言ったわ。
I just said that.

<Phoenix>
つ、つまり！
W-wait, so you mean...

姫神　サクラさん！
‥‥あなたですね？
Dee Vasquez!
So, it was you?

衣袋　武志を殺害したのは！
You killed Jack Hammer!

‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

< >
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Vasquez>
わからないわ。
Who can say?

<Phoenix>
は？
Huh?

<Vasquez>
なんでそうなるのかしら？
Are you sure I did?

いい？
Mr. Wright...

アタクシ、あなたとチエくらべを
したのよ。
We just engaged in
a battle of wits.

その結果、たしかにアタクシ、
犯行は可能だったみたい。
And the result of that battle?
You proved the possibility
that I murdered Hammer.

<Phoenix>
そのとおりです！
R-right!

<Vasquez>
‥‥でも、それはあくまで
可能性の話。
But... that is only
a possibility.

証拠となれば、またベツよ。
Proof is another thing
altogether.

決定的な証拠、ないじゃない。
You lack decisive proof,
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
‥‥な、な、な、な、な、な、な、
な、な、な、な、な、な、な‥‥
Wha... wha... wha... wha...

なんですってェェェェェェェェェ！
WHAAAAAAAAAT!?

<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛に！
Order!

御剣検事‥‥
どう思われますか？
Mr. Edgeworth,
your thoughts?

<Edgeworth>
う‥‥ううむ‥‥、むむむ。
Umm... uhh... mmmph.

も、もちろん、証人の
言うとおりである‥‥！
O-of course, it's as
the witness says!

‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

たしかに、きわめてアヤシイが、
証拠となると‥‥‥ない‥‥。
Certainly, it does seem very
likely she did it... but, uh,
there's no proof!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥！）
(...!)

（御剣のヤツが‥‥迷っている！）
(Edgeworth isn't sure!)

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

どうしたのかしら？
Well?

アタクシは今日、
証人としてここに来たのよ。
I came here as a witness
today.

質問がなければ、もう帰るわ。
If you've no more questions,
I'll be leaving.




<Phoenix>
（く‥‥くそっ！
　‥‥どうする‥‥！）
(Urk! What do I do now!?)




<Phoenix>
姫神さん！
‥‥あなたがやったんだ！
Ms. Vasquez!
You did it!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

それは質問じゃないわ。
That wasn't a question.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

あなたがやったんですか？
Um, did you do it?

<Vasquez>
いいえ。
No.

<Judge>
弁護人。
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
Y-yes, Your Honor?

<Judge>
どうも、その質問には、
意味がないようですね‥‥。
I'm not sure that question
helped this court get any
closer to a verdict.


<Phoenix>
も、もう一度、《証言》を
おねがいします！
I... I'd like you to
testify again!

<Judge>
もう一度、ですか‥‥？
Testify... again?

<Vasquez>
あきらめの悪い男‥‥。
Know when to give up,
Mr. Wright.

いいかしら。
Think about it.

アタクシ、もう一度証言
することになっても、
Even if I were to testify
again, what's the point?

さっきとまったく同じ
ことしか言わないわよ。
I can only say what I said
before. The truth, Mr. Wright.

それこそ、ヒトコトももらさず、
カンペキに同じことをね。
I've already said all
there is to say.

そうしたらアナタ、どうするの？
What would happen if
I said it again?

<Phoenix>
うむむむ‥‥
Uh...

<Vasquez>
同じ質問をして、同じ答えを
聞いて‥‥。
You'd ask the same questions,
get the same answers.

時間のムダよ。
A waste of time.

<Phoenix>



<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Judge>
どうしましたか？　弁護人。
Yes, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
‥‥机を叩いているあいだに
質問を考えようと思いましたが、
I was hoping I'd come up
with a question while pounding
on my desk.

何も浮かびませんでした。
I didn't.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥。
...

それは、ごくろうさまでした。
You have my sympathies.




<Phoenix>
（‥‥く‥‥くそ！）
(Damn... damn!)

（今度こそ、これまでか‥‥）
(To come so far, only
to fail...)

<Judge>
では、質問もないようなので‥‥、
As it seems there are
no further questions...

これで姫神さんに対する
質問を終了します！
I would like to end the
cross-examination of the
witness, Ms. Vasquez.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Judge>
どうしました？　御剣検事。
Yes, Mr. Edgeworth?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥イギをとなえるあいだに
何か質問を考えようと思ったが、
I was hoping to come up
with a question while I was
objecting, Your Honor...

思い浮かばなかった。
I didn't.

<Judge>
そうですか。
‥‥では、今度こそ
I see...
Very well.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
お待ちいただこうッ！
Your Honor!

証人！　もう一度、《証言》を！
I request that the
witness testify again!

<Vasquez>
アナタ、たしか検事でしょ？
You are the prosecutor,
are you not?

なんでそんなにしつこく
アタクシを‥‥？
Why are you badgering me?
I'm your witness!

<Edgeworth>
とにかく、もう一度だけ、
証人の話を聞きたい！
I... I just want to hear
your testimony again.

<Vasquez>
どういうことなの？
裁判長。
Does this make any sense
to you, Your Honor?

さっきと同じこと、
またくり返すのかしら？
I don't see that we have
anything to gain by repeating
the last several minutes.

<Judge>
御剣検事。
Mr. Edgeworth...

同じことを証言してもらう
わけには行きません。
I, too, see little point in
making Ms. Vasquez repeat
herself.

いったい、何を
証言してもらうのですか？
What exactly did you want
her to testify about?

<Edgeworth>
う‥‥うむぅ‥‥それは‥‥
Mmmph! Well, yes, um...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そ、そうだな。
ええと‥‥そのぅ‥‥。
Indeed!
Verily, I say...
Ergo!

死体を発見してからあとの
ことを、お聞きしたい！
I want to hear about what
happened... after they found
the body!

<Judge>
死体を見つけてから、あと‥‥？
After they found the body...?

わかりました。
Very well.

では、証人。
‥‥《証言》をおねがいします。
The witness will testify
to the court concerning
this matter.

<Vasquez>
‥‥ふぅ。
Hmph.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick!

どうして、御剣検事が‥‥？
Why did Edgeworth...?

<Phoenix>
‥‥さあね。
Who knows?

あいつにも、わかったんだろ？
‥‥誰が犯人か。
He probably realized she
did it, too.

<Maya>
でも、でも！
But... but!

“ヒコクニンをみんなユーザイに
するのが、オレのるーるだ”って、
Wasn't he the one that said
he always gets a guilty
verdict...?

エラそうに言ってたのに‥‥。
After all that...

<Phoenix>
（ミツルギ‥‥）
(Edgeworth...)

< >
～死体を見つけたあとのこと～
-- After Finding the Body --

<Vasquez>
死体を見つけたときは、
宇在や警備員の大場がいたわ。
I was with Sal and Oldbag,
the security lady, when we
found the body.

スタッフの子もいたし。
いなかったのは、荷星だけ。
The assistant was there, too.
Only Powers was absent.

すぐに警察を呼んだわ。
荷星もおくれてやってきて。
I immediately called the
police. Then Powers showed
up.

<Vasquez>
警備員の大場が大さわぎだった。
“こいつが犯人だ”って。
The security lady, Oldbag,
was quite agitated. Pointing
at Powers, saying "he did it!"

アタクシは、その場にいなかった
ことにしてもらって、
I asked to be left out
of the proceedings.

いったんコテージに、台本や
演出ノートを取りにもどったわ。
I went back to the trailer
to get my script and direction
notes.

そしてその日は、
そのまま帰ったわね。
Then I went home.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

この証言に、とくに問題が
あるとは思えませんが‥‥。
I see no issues raised
by this testimony...

成歩堂くん。
‥‥《尋問》を。
Mr. Wright,
your cross-examination.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
あとひと押しだよ！
Okay, Nick, we're
close, real close!

あの人、強がっては
いるけど、
She may be acting
tough now...

なるほどくん、もう
追いつめているんだから。
But if you put her on the
spot she's sure to falter!

最後のカギを見つけたら、
きっと勝てるよ！
Find the key you need
and twist the truth out
of her, Nick!

<Phoenix>
‥‥うん！
Right!

< >
～死体を見つけたあとのこと～
-- After Finding the Body --




<Vasquez>
死体を見つけたときは、
宇在や警備員の大場がいたわ。
I was with Sal and Oldbag,
the security lady, when we
found the body.


<Vasquez>
スタッフの子もいたし。
いなかったのは、荷星だけ。
The assistant was there, too.
Only Powers was absent.


<Vasquez>
すぐに警察を呼んだわ。
荷星もおくれてやってきて。
I immediately called the
police. Then Powers showed
up.


<Vasquez>
警備員の大場が大さわぎだった。
“こいつが犯人だ”って。
The security lady, Oldbag,
was quite agitated. Pointing
at Powers, saying "he did it!"


<Vasquez>
アタクシは、その場にいなかった
ことにしてもらって、
I asked to be left out
of the proceedings.


<Vasquez>
いったんコテージに、台本や
演出ノートを取りにもどったわ。
I went back to the trailer
to get my script and direction
notes.


<Vasquez>
そしてその日は、
そのまま帰ったわね。
Then I went home.

ケガした衣袋にアクションはムリ
だから、持って行かなかったの。
I knew that Hammer was injured
and couldn't do any action
scenes, so I left them behind.


<Maya>
ここで“何か”を
見つけられなかったら、
You have to find something
to peg this on her here...

今までのことがみんな、
ムダになっちゃうんだよ。
Or everything we've done
till now will have been
wasted!

なるほどくんを信じてる！
だから、なるほどくんも‥‥。
I believe in you, Nick!
Go get 'em!

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
それは、何時ごろの
ことでしたか？
What time was that?

<Vasquez>
リハーサルの集合時間は
５時だったから、
We were to meet at 5:00
for the rehearsal.

そのころだったと思うけど。
So I'd say it was then.

<Phoenix>
あなたと宇在カントクは、
何時にスタジオへ？
When exactly did you
and Mr. Manella arrive
at the studio?

<Vasquez>
その１０分ぐらい前かしら？
About 10 minutes before.

死体を着ぐるみに詰めたり
なんかは、しなかったわよ。
I wasn't stuffing any bodies
into costumes, mind you.

<Phoenix>
（うーん‥‥）
(Hmm...)



<Phoenix>
姫神さんがスタジオについたとき、
他のスタッフのみなさんは？
Where were the other employees
when you got to the studio?

<Vasquez>
まだ、いなかったわ。
They weren't there yet.

<Phoenix>
それならば！
Well!?

宇在カントクに手伝わせて、
死体を着ぐるみに‥‥
Then you could have put
Hammer in that costume,
with Sal Manella's help!

<Vasquez>
お待ちなさいな。
Oh?

だから、さっき言ったでしょ。
What did I just say?

“死体を着ぐるみに詰めたり
なんかは、しなかった”って。
Did I not just say "I wasn't
stuffing any bodies into
any costumes"...?

ヒトの話は、よく聞くものよ、
ボク。
You should try to listen
to what people are saying,
boy.

<Phoenix>
（ボ‥‥ボク）
(B-boy!?)

<Judge>
証人。
‥‥つづけてください。
The witness will continue
her testimony.

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
（やめておこう‥‥）
(I'd better leave
this one be.)

（こっちの手など、きっと
　お見とおしだろうからな‥‥）
(I'm sure she'd see through
anything I had to throw
at her, anyway.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
荷星さん‥‥
ヒルネしてたんですよね？
Mr. Powers was taking
a nap, correct?

<Vasquez>
本人はそう言ってるわね。
So he says.

<Phoenix>
誰も、呼びに
行かなかったんですか？
Did no one go to call him?

<Vasquez>
‥‥死体。
Remember...

<Phoenix>
は？
Remember... what?

<Vasquez>
死体を前にして、そんな
冷静でいられるわけないでしょ。
There was a dead body lying
in front of us. Yet you
expect me to be calm?

<Phoenix>
（“殺人犯だ”って言われても
　そんなに冷静なクセに‥‥）
(You certainly seemed 
calm enough when I accused
you of murder!)

（よく言うよ‥‥）
(*sigh*)



<Phoenix>
ちょっと待ってください！
‥‥それは逆じゃないでしょうか。
Wait a second!
Wouldn't that be the
other way around!?

<Vasquez>
‥‥逆？
The other way around?

<Phoenix>
殺人が起こって、１人だけ
いない人間がいたんですよ。
You discovered a murdered
body, and one person was 
missing, right?

探しませんか？　ふつう。
Wouldn't you normally go
looking for the missing
person!?

<Judge>
‥‥ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

そのとおりですね。
I have to agree with
the defense on this one.

‥‥いかがですか？　証人？
Well, Ms. Vasquez?

<Vasquez>
フン。
Hmph.

そりゃ、リクツはそうかもね。
Logically speaking, perhaps.

でも、実際にアタクシたち、
それどころじゃなかったの。
But no one there was thinking
very logically, I assure you.

それに。
Also.

荷星は、トノサマンの着ぐるみを
着ないと、イマイチ目立たなくて。
Without his Steel Samurai
costume, Powers doesn't really
stand out.

よくロケバスに置いていかれたり
していたわ。
We often left him on the
bus when shooting at location.
No one noticed he was missing.

<Phoenix>
（カワイソウな荷星さん‥‥）
(Poor Powers...)

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
それじゃあ、しょうがないですね。
Hmm...
Well, I suppose that
explains that.

では、証人。‥‥つづきを。
Very well, Ms. Vasquez.
You may continue.

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
（やめておこう‥‥）
(I'll hold off.)

（こっちの手など、きっと
　お見とおしだろうからな‥‥）
(She'd just blow off anything
I had to say, anyway.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
そのあいだ、みなさんは
何を‥‥？
What was everyone else
doing at that time?

<Vasquez>
誰も、ヒトコトもクチを
きかなかったわ。
No one said a thing.

重い、重いチンモク‥‥。
It was silent.
Completely silent.

‥‥そこに、やっと起きた
荷星がやってきたわ。
So we stood there until Powers
finally arrived on the scene.

“オクレちゃった！
ゆるしてオクレ！”
"Sorry! Sorry I'm late!"

‥‥って言いながら。
その場がさらに凍りついたわね。
Then... silence.
Dead silence.

<Phoenix>
‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

< >
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Vasquez>
‥‥こんな感じにね。
Silent.

<Maya>
ね、ね、なるほどくん。
Hey... Hey, Nick.

‥‥どうしてかな？
けっこう、おもしろいのに。
Why's everyone so
quiet?

重いフンイキも
なごみそうなもんだけどね。
Someone should do something
to lighten things up!

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
（オオバ‥‥って、あの
　オバチャンだよな‥‥）
(Oldbag... the security lady.)

オバチャンは、どうして
荷星さんを‥‥？
Why did the security lady
think Powers had done it?

<Vasquez>
彼がスタジオに向かうのを
見たから、と言ってた。
She said because she saw
him going toward the studio.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ああ、トノサマンの
　ことか‥‥）
(Right... the Steel Samurai.)



<Phoenix>
刑事は、オバチャンの証言だけで
荷星さんを逮捕したんですか？
Did the detective arrest
Mr. Powers based solely on
the security lady's word?

<Vasquez>
さあ‥‥。
Perhaps not.

あとで聞いた話では、
She seems to have also
given the detective that
photograph...

彼女、写真を刑事に
わたしたみたい‥‥。
Of course, I heard all
this after the fact.

<Phoenix>
（例の、ゲートのカメラが撮った
　写真だな‥‥）
(That photograph... meaning
the one taken by the
security camera.)

<Vasquez>
まあ彼女、衣袋のことになると、
見さかいがなくなるから。
She's not known for exhibiting
the best sense of judgment
when it comes to Hammer.

<Phoenix>
（ううん‥‥とくに手がかりに
　なりそうなことはないなあ‥‥）
(Hmm. I don't think there's
anything in there I can use.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
（やめておこう‥‥）
(I'll hold back, I think.)

（こっちの手など、きっと
　お見とおしだろうからな‥‥）
(I'm sure she's already 
anticipated anything I
could throw at her.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
“いなかったことに”‥‥？
You "asked to be left out"?

<Vasquez>
そう。
Yes.

他の人は、取り調べを
受けたみたいだけど。
It seems that everyone
else was questioned.

アタクシ、ああいうの、
キライだから。
And I'm really not fond
of that sort of thing.

<Phoenix>
なんで、そんな自分勝手な
ことを‥‥？
But, you can't just decide
who the police will and
won't question!

<Vasquez>
英都撮影所の人間は、
思いやりがあってね。
Thankfully, the studio
thinks otherwise.

会議をしていたアタクシたちが
犯人のハズはないからって、
They were nice enough to
understand that, since we
were in a meeting...

かばってくれたの。
There was no way we could
have been involved. Thus,
they covered for us.

<Phoenix>
（よく言うよ‥‥）
(Covered for you...
or covered it up for you?)

（会議に出ていたのは、
　エラいさんに、スポンサー‥‥）
(There must have been a lot
riding on it, with all those
bigwigs at the meeting...)

（どうせ、例の“プロ”でも
　使ったんだろう‥‥）
(I'm sure her "professionals"
helped convince everyone they
didn't require questioning.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
台本や演出ノート‥‥？
The script and your
direction notes?

<Vasquez>
大事なものよ。
‥‥盗まれちゃまずいわ。
Yes, they're quite
valuable. It wouldn't
do to have them stolen.

<Phoenix>
まあ、それはそうですね。
No, I guess not.



<Phoenix>
（やめておこう‥‥）
(I'll hold back, I think.)

（こっちの手など、きっと
　お見とおしだろうからな‥‥）
(I'm sure she's already
anticipated anything I
could throw at her.)

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
ちょっと待ってくださいよ。
Wait a second!

そもそも第１スタジオには、
リハーサルのために来たはずです。
I thought you came to 
Studio One for a rehearsal!

なんで台本やノートを
持っていなかったんですか？
Why didn't you bring your
script and notes!?

<Vasquez>
リハーサルなんか、できないって
思っていたから。
Well, I was under the
impression that we wouldn't
be able to rehearse anything.

<Phoenix>
どうしてです？
Why?

<Vasquez>
‥‥殺人があったでしょ、
なんにしても。
There was a murder,
after all!

リハーサルなんか
できるわけがないわ。
Who could think of
rehearsing after that!

<Phoenix>
（まあ、そりゃそうか‥‥）
(Oh, yeah, I guess...)

<Judge>
‥‥ふむう。
Hmm...

では、証人、
証言をつづけてください。
Very well. Ms. Vasquez,
please continue...

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
証人ッ！
Your Honor!!!

今の発言には、問題がある！
I have an objection to the
witness's last statement!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんだって‥‥？）
(Huh...!?)

<Edgeworth>
よろしいか。
Think!

“リハーサルがないと思ったから
台本を持っていかなかった”‥‥
Ms. Vasquez said she didn't
bring the script because there
wouldn't be a rehearsal.

それではまるで‥‥、
Don't you see what
that means?

コテージを出る前から、すでに
死体があると知っていたようだ！
She would have had to know
about the murder before
going to Studio One!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛にッ！
Order! Order!

御剣検事！
Mr. Edgeworth!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Judge>
今の発言ですが‥‥、
What you have just said...

たしかに、指摘のとおりです。
is a reasonable observation.

しかし‥‥。検察側の人間の
とる行動とは思えません。
However, I find it hard to
understand why the prosecution
would make such a move!

まるで‥‥そう、弁護人では
ないですか！
Or are you thinking of a
career change to defense!?

<Edgeworth>
...

ご心配いただくのは
ありがたいが‥‥
I... appreciate the concern,
Your Honor.

私のとるべき行動を
決めるのは、私だ。
I will stand by my statement,
however, regardless of how
the court sees my role here.

さあ、証人。
‥‥答えていただきたいッ！
Now, Ms. Vasquez...

<Edgeworth>
Do you have an explanation?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ミツルギに‥‥
　助けられた‥‥？）
(I can't believe Edgeworth
is helping me!)

<Vasquez>
フン‥‥。
Hmph.

検事は弁護士とグル、ってわけ？
So the prosecution is in
cahoots with the defense?
What kind of court is this?

‥‥まあ、いいわ。
No matter.

アタクシ、そういう意味で
言ったのではなくてよ。
I think you misunderstood me.

リハーサルがないと思ったのは、
それなりの理由があるわ。
I had a perfectly good reason
to believe there would be
no rehearsal.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

‥‥では、証言を修正して
もらいましょう。
Very well, the witness will
change her testimony to
reflect this reason.

<Vasquez>



<Phoenix>
取り調べは受けなかった
わけですか？
So you weren't questioned?

<Vasquez>
そうね。
That's correct.

アタクシ、そういうの、
キライだから。
I find these things...
distasteful.



<Phoenix>
この裁判のはじめのころ、
あなた方、コテージ組は、
Thinking back to when we
first began this trial...

撮影所には、いなかったことに
なっていましたよね‥‥？
We were under the impression
that there was no one in 
the trailer at all.

<Vasquez>
そうね。
I suppose.

<Phoenix>
どうしてですか？
Why is that?

<Vasquez>
だって、アタクシたち、
ずっと会議をしてたのよ。
Well, we were in a meeting
the whole afternoon.

わざわざ、警察に話すのも
メンドウじゃない。
What's the point of talking
about that to the police?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ツミのイシキみたいな
　ものは、まったくないみたいだ）
(She has got to be the least
guilt-ridden guilty person
I've ever met...)


<Phoenix>
（やめておこう‥‥）
(I'll hold back for now.)

（こっちの手など、きっと
(I'm sure she's anticipated
anything I had to say...)

　お見とおしだろうからな‥‥）
 


<Phoenix>
どうしてケガのこと、
知っているんですか？
How did you know about
the injury?

<Vasquez>
ど、どうして、って。
H-how did I know!?

‥‥宇在よ。
Sal.

アイツから聞いたわ。
He told me.

<Phoenix>
（宇在カントクか‥‥）
(Sal the director...
Hmm...)

<Maya>
ちょ、ちょっと、なるほどくん！

<Maya>
今の証言‥‥よく聞いて！
なんか、ヘンだよ。

<Phoenix>
（‥‥何か、見落としたか‥‥？）


<Phoenix>
“ケガをした、イブクロさん”‥‥
You "knew that Hammer
was injured"...?

ちょっと待ってください！
Don't you think that's
a little funny?

ケガをしたのは、
トノサマンの方‥‥
I mean, it was the Steel
Samurai who was injured!

荷星　三郎なんですよ！
It was Will Powers!

<Vasquez>
な‥‥、なんだって！
Wh... what!?

<Judge>
成歩堂くん！
‥‥どういうことですか！
Mr. Wright!
Explain yourself!

<Phoenix>
たしかに、イブクロさんは
足を引きずっていた！
Yes, Mr. Hammer is dragging
his leg in this photo.

しかし、それはあくまで、荷星さん
のフリをするためだった！
But that's because he was
pretending to be Mr. Powers!

<Vasquez>
ど‥‥どういうこと？
P-pretending...?

<Phoenix>
午前中の打ち合わせで、
たしかにケガ人が出ました。
One person was injured in the
run-through that morning.

しかし、それは荷星さんであって、
イブクロさんではない！
That person was Mr. Powers,
not Mr. Hammer!

<Phoenix>
なぜあなたは、ケガをしたのが
イブクロさんだと思ったんですか！
Now, why did you think it was
Mr. Hammer who was injured?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

う‥‥宇在。
宇在に聞いたんだよ！
I-I already said it
was Sal who told me!

そ、そうだ！
アイツがカン違いしたのさ！
Th-that's right!
He must have gotten it wrong.

<Phoenix>
それはあり得ません。
I think not.

宇在カントクは、打ち合わせに
参加していました。
Mr. Manella was at the
run-through that morning.

だから、荷星さんの足のケガの
ことは、よく知っています！
He would have known it was
Mr. Powers who was injured.
He saw it happen!

彼が間違えるはずはない！
Why would he tell you
the wrong person?




<Phoenix>
姫神さん！　‥‥あなたは、
Ms. Vasquez!



<Phoenix>
聞き間違いを
したんじゃないですか？
You must have heard
Mr. Manella wrong!

宇在カントクは“荷星さんがケガを
した”と言ったのに、
Even though he said
Mr. Powers was injured...

あなたはそれを“イブクロさん”と
カン違いしたのです！
You thought he was talking
about Mr. Hammer!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

言われてみれば‥‥。
Now that you mention it...

そんな気もするわね。
Yes, I believe you're right.

‥‥きっと、
そうだったんでしょう。
I'm sure that's what happened.

<Phoenix>
そうですとも。
Yeah!

‥‥‥‥。
...

<Maya>
なるほどくん‥‥
Nick!

それじゃあ、あのヒトを
追い詰められないよ！
You're supposed to be putting
her on the spot, not helping
her out!

<Phoenix>
‥‥たしかに。
話題がなくなっちまったよ。
Oh, right...
I kind of talked myself out
of that one, didn't I?

<Maya>
早く！　やりなおして！
Quick! Start over!


<Phoenix>
あなたは、実際に‥‥、
Actually, you didn't hear
anything from Mr. Manella.

足を引きずっている
イブクロさんを見たんです！
You saw Mr. Hammer limping
with your own eyes!

<Judge>
しかし‥‥。
Yes, but...

ケガをしたのは、
荷星　三郎のはずですが‥‥？
Wasn't it Mr. Powers who
was injured...?

<Phoenix>
ここで、
思い出してほしいんです。
Yes, but remember!

イブクロさんも、足を
引きずっていたじゃないですか。
Mr. Hammer was dragging
his leg, too!

荷星さんのフリをするために！
He was pretending to be
Mr. Powers!

<Judge>
あっ！
Aah!

<Phoenix>
それは、いつだったか‥‥？
And when was he
doing this...?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥それは‥‥。
Well...

トノサマンの着ぐるみを着て
第２スタジオへ向かい‥‥、
It would have been after he
put on the Steel Samurai
costume...

そして、
殺害されるまでのあいだだ‥‥。
and went to Studio Two.
Where he was murdered!

<Phoenix>
そのとおり！
Exactly!

姫神さん！
Ms. Vasquez!

あなたは、足をひきずった
トノサマンと会ったのです！
You met him, didn't you?
You saw the Steel Samurai
limping!

トノサマンの着ぐるみには、
イブクロさんが入っていた！
And Mr. Hammer was in
that Steel Samurai suit!

<Phoenix>
だからこそ、あなたは‥‥
That's why you were confused!

“イブクロさんがケガをした”
と、カン違いしたのです！
That's why you thought it
was Mr. Hammer who had been
injured that morning!

<Vasquez>
‥‥！！
...!!!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
Order! Order!
I will have order!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥証人！
Witness!

何か反論は？
Can you refute this claim?

<Vasquez>
う‥‥うぐ‥‥！
Hrrmmmm... hmph!

‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（今度こそ、反論なんか
　できるわけがないさ！）
(Yeah, let's see you sneak
out of this one, Vasquez!)

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

じゃあ‥‥
Very well!

じゃあ、
聞かせてもらおうじゃないの！
I have a question for you!

<Phoenix>
（うう‥‥）
(Urk...)

（真犯人というものは、
　どうしてこうシツコイんだ‥‥）
(Why are the real killers
always so... persistent?)

<Vasquez>
アタクシが衣袋の死を望む、
その理由はなんなのさ？
Why in the world would
I want Mr. Hammer dead?

落ちぶれていたとはいえ、
スターだったんだよ。
Yes, he'd fallen on hard
times, but he was a star!

アイツが死んだって、アタクシには
なんのトクもないじゃないか！
I had nothing to gain
from his death! Nothing!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

“動機”‥‥というヤツですな。
Yes, you would need a motive.

たしかに。彼女がなぜ
被害者を殺害したのか‥‥？
Why would she have killed
the victim?

その理由は、まだアキラカに
されていませんな‥‥。
If there is a reason,
it is unclear to this court.

いかがですか？　弁護人。
Does the defense have anything
to say on the matter?

ズバリ、動機を証明する
ことはできますか？
In other words, can you 
prove she had a motive?



<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick, no!

ここで“できない”って
言っちゃったら‥‥
Saying you can't prove it
now would be admitting
defeat!

あのヒト、逃げきっちゃうよ！
She'll get away!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥ムリだよ！
そんな証拠は‥‥。
But... but what proof
could I possibly have!?

<Maya>
ムリでもなんでも、
ここは勝負しかないって！
I don't care if it's
impossible, you still
have to fight this one!

<Phoenix>
うううう‥‥。
Ugh...




<Phoenix>
わかりました。
Okay.

証拠品をお見せしましょう。
I have proof, and
I'll show it to you!




<Phoenix>
この事件の“動機”を
物語る証拠品は‥‥
I present to the court
evidence as to Ms. Vasquez's
motive in this murder.


<Phoenix>
これだぁ！‥‥真宵ちゃん。
Psst, Maya, look.
This is it.

<Maya>
...!

<Maya>
な、なんであたしに見せるの？
Why... are you showing
that to me, Nick?

<Maya>
And why are you whispering?

<Phoenix>
ちょっと、実験。
I was just testing it
out on you.

<Maya>
ふーん‥‥。
Huh.

シッパイみたいだよ。
‥‥ジッケン‥‥。
Well, I'm afraid your
test results are negative.

<Judge>
弁護人！
Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
は、はいッ！
Y-yes, Your Honor!

<Judge>
早くしてください！
Hurry up with it!

こういうのは、テンポが大事です！
We have a certain tempo
we have to maintain here!

<Phoenix>
は‥‥はあ‥‥。
Yes... yes, Your Honor.

では、今度こそ
お見せしましょう‥‥。
Right. Here goes!


<Phoenix>
証拠は、これです！
This is my proof!

<Judge>
‥‥これは‥‥
さっきの写真、ですか‥‥？
This is... the photo
from before?

<Phoenix>
これが、今回の事件の“動機”
を物語っているのです！
This photo reveals the
motive in this murder!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Phoenix>
そうですね？　姫神さん！
I'm right, aren't I,
Ms. Vasquez?

<Vasquez>
う‥‥ううう‥‥！
Hrrrrrrm... hmph!

<Phoenix>
５年前、スターダムの頂点に
立っていたイブクロさんは、
Five years ago, Mr. Hammer
was at the height of his fame.

姫神　サクラのチカラで、
事故をもみ消してもらった。
With Dee Vasquez's help, a
terrible accident was swept
under the carpet...

‥‥今回の事件は、
Ladies and gentlemen,
the case currently up 
for trial...

そのときから、
始まっていたんです。
It began on that day,
five years ago!

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
ヒニクなことに、イブクロさんは
この事故をキッカケに、
Ironically enough, that
accident precipitated
Mr. Hammer's fall...

スターの座から転落することに
なってしまいました。
His fall from stardom!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥ツミの意識が
あったのだろうな‥‥。
His guilt weighed him
down, no doubt.

<Phoenix>
しかし。
However!

姫神　サクラは、そんな
イブクロさんを利用した。
You, Dee Vasquez, used
Mr. Hammer.

格安のギャラで、イブクロさんを
さんざんコキ使ったのです。
You made him work for you
for petty change!

<Vasquez>
‥‥フン。
Hmph.

<Edgeworth>
では、今回のアクダイカーン
の役も‥‥？
Bringing us to the present
day... and Mr. Hammer's last
role as the Evil Magistrate!

<Phoenix>
イブクロさんにしてみれば、
クツジョクだったでしょうね。
Yes! Undoubtedly, it was
a constant source of shame
for the ex-star...

<Edgeworth>
うむう‥‥。
Hmm...

<Judge>
ちょっと待ってください、
成歩堂くん。
One moment, Mr. Wright.

‥‥さっきからあなたは、
イブクロさんの話ばかりしている。
We are talking about motives,
here... yet you have only
talked about Mr. Hammer.

これではまるで‥‥、
It almost seems as if...

<Judge>
イブクロさんが、姫神　サクラを
殺害したように聞こえます。
As if it was Mr. Hammer who
had killed Dee Vasquez, not
the other way around!

<Judge>
‥‥しかし。
姫神さんの方はどうなんですか？
What motive would Ms. Vasquez
have?

<Vasquez>
そ‥‥そうさ。
Y-yes, that's right.

あんたの話によれば、
According to what you say...

アタクシにとって、イブクロは
いい金ヅルじゃないか。
I would have had no reason to
kill Hammer. He was a good
source of income for me!

そんなツゴウのいいオトコ、
アタクシは手ばなしたくないね！
And I never get rid of useful
men. It's a policy of mine.

<Judge>
‥‥弁護人。
Mr. Wright?




<Judge>
彼女の動機を教えてください。
Please explain Ms. Vasquez's
motive for murder.



<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりました。
Okay...




<Phoenix>
では、姫神さんの動機を示す
証拠品をお見せしましょう。
Allow me to present to the
court evidence proving
Ms. Vasquez's motive!


<Phoenix>
その証拠は、これですよ！
This is my proof!

<Judge>
それが、姫神さんの動機を物語る
証拠品ですか？
And... this tells us why
Ms. Vasquez wanted to kill
Mr. Hammer?

<Vasquez>
弁護士の狂気を物語る証拠品
じゃない？
I'd say all it proves is that
the defense attorney has
completely lost his marbles.

<Phoenix>
（うまいコト言いやがって‥‥）
(Urk!)

<Judge>
弁護人！
‥‥シッカリしてください！
Mr. Wright!
The court requests that you
find your marbles immediately.

これは、ペナルティを
受けていただきます！
And, I'm afraid I have to
penalize your for this
waste of the court's time.




<Maya>
なるほどくん！
‥‥あとイッポなんだよぉ！
Nick! We're so close!

おねがいだから、よく考えてよぉ！
Think this one through,
please!

<Judge>
弁護人。
‥‥もう一度聞きますよ。
Mr. Wright,
I'll ask you again.


<Phoenix>
彼女に、動機なんかありません。
She had no motive, Your Honor.

<Judge>
な、なんですって！
What's that now!?

<Phoenix>
彼女はただ、階段からつきおとした
だけなんです。
It was Mr. Hammer who was
out for blood!

殺意をもっておそいかかってきた
イブクロさんを、ね！
All Ms. Vasquez did was
push him off the stairs...
in self defense!

<Edgeworth>
な、なんだと！
What's that now!?

<Phoenix>
カンタンなことです。
It's simple!

殺意があったのは、
イブクロさんの方だったんですよ！
Mr. Hammer was intending
to kill Ms. Vasquez!

<Edgeworth>
な‥‥‥‥
Wha-!?

<Edgeworth>
なんだってェ！！
WHAT!?

<Phoenix>
いいですか！
Your Honor!

衣袋　武志は、睡眠薬で
荷星さんを眠らせた！
Jack Hammer drugged 
Mr. Powers with sleeping
pills!

衣袋　武志は、楽屋にしのびこみ、
着ぐるみを盗んだ！
Jack Hammer snuck into the
dressing room and stole
the Steel Samurai costume!

衣袋　武志は、それを着て
オバチャンの目をごまかした！
Jack Hammer wore the costume
to fool the security lady
into thinking he was Powers!

そして衣袋　武志は、
コテージへ向かった！
Then Jack Hammer made
his way to the trailer!

　　いったい、なんのために！
And for what purpose, you ask?

<Phoenix>
自分をさんざん利用した、
姫神　サクラを殺害するためです！
To kill Dee Vasquez, who had
so cruelly taken advantage
of him all those years!

<Phoenix>
あなたがやったんですね？
So, you did do it, didn't you?

<Vasquez>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥そうよ。
... Yes.

　　犯人は、このアタクシよ。
I am guilty.

　　　このアタクシが‥‥。
It was me...

< >
“イシャだ！　早くしろ！”
"Someone call an ambulance!"

“‥‥す、すごい血だ‥‥。
もう、手おくれじゃあ‥‥？”
"Th-there's blood everywhere!
We're too late!"

“あっ！　ひ、姫神さん！”
"Aah! Ms. Vasquez!"

< >
“これはいったい‥‥？
どうしたの！　何があったの！”
"What...?
What happened here!?"

< >
“‥‥タクミさんが、コテージの
階段から落ちて‥‥”
"Manuel fell from the 
trailer stairs...!"

< >
“タ‥‥‥‥タクミくんが！”
"Manuel! Manuel!"

< >
“姫神さん！　おちついて！”
"Ms. Vasquez, please, try
to remain calm..."

< >
“ウ‥‥ウソよ！
い、いったいどうして‥‥”
"No...! No!
How could this...?"

< >
“事故だったんですよ”
"It was an accident..."

“イブクロさんの
アクションシーンで‥‥”
"Mr. Hammer was doing
an action scene and..."

< >
“タクミくん！　タクミくーん！”
"No! Manuel! Manuel!!!"

< >
“さ、さわっちゃダメです！
姫神さん！”
"D-don't touch him!
Ms. Vasquez!"

< >
“いやああああああああああっ！”
"Nooooooooooooo!"

“死なないで‥‥　おねがい‥‥”
"Please... please don't die."

“おねがい‥‥”
"Please..."

<Vasquez>
おめでとう。成歩堂くん。
Congratulations, Mr. Wright.

‥‥アタクシの、負けね。
I lose... again.

<Judge>
御剣検事。
‥‥姫神　サクラは‥‥？
Mr. Edgeworth...
Where's Dee Vasquez?

<Edgeworth>
控え室に‥‥。
‥‥冷静なものだ‥‥。
In the waiting lobby,
Your Honor. As calm and
collected as ever...

<Judge>
‥‥そうですか。
I see...

成歩堂くん。
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
はい。
Yes, Your Honor?

<Judge>
‥‥どうやらまた、奇跡が
起こったようですね。
It appears you have brought
about yet another miracle.

<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥。
I... thank you, Your Honor.

<Edgeworth>
それは違う、裁判長。
I think not, Your Honor.

荷星　三郎は、無実だった。
Will Powers was innocent.

だから、それが証明された。
‥‥あたりまえのことだ。
That he should be found
so is only natural...
not a miracle.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥そうですね。
そのとおりです。
Yes.
Yes, you're right.

では。
Very well.

荷星　三郎に対する判決を
言い渡しましょう。
This court finds the
defendant, Mr. Will Powers...

<Judge>
では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
That is all.
The court is adjourned!




< >
１０月２０日　午後１時１２分
地方裁判所　被告人第３控え室
October 20, 1:12 PM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 3

<Will>
もう、なんと言えばいいのか‥‥。
I... I don't know 
what to say!

ホント、おせわになりました！
Thank you so much!

<Phoenix>
よかったですね。
I'm just glad you're okay.

<Will>
はい。
‥‥ただ‥‥。
Yes... but... it's sad.

イブクロさん。ボクの
着ぐるみを盗んだってコトは、
I know now that Mr. Hammer
stole my costume.

姫神プロデューサーを殺害して、
そのツミを、
It's bad enough that he
wanted to kill Ms. Vasquez...

着ぐるみごと、ボクに着せようと
したんでしょうね‥‥。
But to think that he
tried to frame me for the
murder!

それだけが‥‥カナシイです。
It makes me sad...

成歩堂さん！　どうして！
Tell me why, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
‥‥は、はい？
H-huh?

<Will>
教えてください！
Tell me!

どうして、イブクロさんは、
ボクにツミを‥‥？
Why did Mr. Hammer
want to blame me...?



<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりました。
ぼくの考えを言いましょう。
Well, this is what
I think.

イブクロさんがあなたに
ツミを着せようとしたのは‥‥
Mr. Hammer wanted to put
the blame on you because...


<Will>
‥‥‥‥。
...

え？　ど、どういうことですか？
S-sorry?
What does that mean?

<Phoenix>
どういうことかな？　真宵ちゃん。
Yeah, what does that mean,
Maya?

<Maya>
‥‥なるほどくん。
Um, Nick? You know that
problem of yours?

また、やっちゃったね。
That problem where you present
evidence that makes no sense?
You're doing it again.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ‥‥）
(Oh...)

<Will>
‥‥？
...?


<Phoenix>
それはあなたが“トノサマン”
だからですよ。
It's because you were
the Steel Samurai.

<Will>
‥‥どういうことですか？
Because I was the
Steel Samurai?

<Phoenix>
イブクロさんは、かつては
大スターだった。
Mr. Hammer was a big star,
once.

なのに今は、子供番組の、
しかも悪役です。
But he was reduced to acting
in a kids' show... and as
the villain, to boot!

子供たちは、トノサマンが
大好きです。
The kids love the Steel
Samurai.

だから、彼はあなたを
ニクんでしまったんでしょう。
And so, he hated you.

<Will>
や‥‥やっぱり、ですか‥‥。
I... I think I understand.

ヒトコト、言ってくれれば。
H-he could have just told me.

いつでも、かわって
あげましたのに‥‥。
I would have changed places
with him any time!

<Phoenix>
（そういう問題じゃ
　ないと思うけど‥‥）
(I think you're missing the
point...)

<Will>
‥‥‥‥
...

ありがとうございます。
Thank you.

これで、この事件とも
キッチリお別れできそうです。
I'm just glad it's
all over.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥よかったな‥‥）
(So am I... so am I...)


<Phoenix>
‥‥それは、今となっては
知りようもないですね。
I guess we'll never know.

<Will>
そ、そうですよね‥‥。
Y-yes, of course.

<Phoenix>
（ふう‥‥。なんとか
　ごまかしたかな‥‥）
(Whew... I'm not sure I wanted
to go down that road.)




<Maya>
おめでとうございます！
ニボサブさん！
Congratulations, WP!

<Will>
いやっ、ははは。
Oh? Oh!
Heh heh.

みなさんのおかげで、
トノサマンをつづけられます！
Thanks to you, I'll be
able to don the Steel
Samurai outfit once more!

うう‥‥早くあの汗くさい
着ぐるみを‥‥。
I can't wait to get back
into that sweaty costume
and...

‥‥‥‥？
...?

どうかしましたか？
Is... something wrong?

<Maya>
い、いいえ！
なんでも‥‥
N-no! O-of course not...

あっ！
Aah!

な、なるほどくん！
‥‥御剣検事が‥‥！
N-Nick!
Edgeworth!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

成歩堂。‥‥なにか言え。
Say something, Wright.

ニガテなのだ‥‥セケン話。
I'm not good at small talk.

<Phoenix>
え？
Huh?

あ、ああ。
What?

‥‥‥‥
...

ザンネンだったな！　御剣！
Umm... that was too bad,
Edgeworth!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥い、いきなりそれか。
You don't waste any
time gloating, do you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ありがとう。
No... I really want to
thank you.

きみの協力がなければ、
姫神に逃げられるところだったよ。
Vasquez would have gotten
away if you hadn't stepped in.

<Will>
あ‥‥恐縮です。
‥‥ニボシと申します。
Ah, uh, pleased to meet
you. I'm Powers. *sniff*

<Edgeworth>
‥‥む。ミツルギと申します。
Ah, er, Edgeworth.

いつも、テレビでごカツヤクを
ハイケンしております。
I'm a big fan of your
work, Mr. Powers.

<Phoenix>
（ウソつけ！）
(Liar!)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

成歩堂。
Wright.

私たちは、こうしてふたたび
出会ってしまった。
I must say, I hadn't expected
to meet you again after all
these years.

<Maya>
‥‥“ふたたび”‥‥？
Meet "again"...?

<Edgeworth>
しかし。
However.

出会うべきではなかった。
In retrospect, it would have
been better had we not met.

おかげで私の中に、よけいな
感情がよみがえった。
Thanks to you, I am saddled
with unnecessary... feelings.

<Phoenix>
よけいな感情‥‥？
Unnecessary feelings?

<Edgeworth>
“不安”‥‥そして“迷い”だ。
Yes. Unease... and
uncertainty.

<Phoenix>
それは、よけいな感情じゃ
ないだろう？
Aren't those kind of
necessary?

<Edgeworth>
私にとってはジャマなものだ。
They only serve to get
in my way.

いいか。
‥‥成歩堂　龍一。
You listen to me,
Phoenix Wright.

もう二度と、私の目の前に
現れないでほしい。
Don't ever show your
face in front of me again.

‥‥それだけ、言いに来た。
That's what I came here
to tell you.

<Will>
あのぉ、成歩堂さん？
Umm... Mr. Wright?

今のカタ、おトモダチなんですか？
Is... this guy your friend?

<Maya>
そんな！　トモダチなわけ、
ないじゃないですか！
What? Friends?
As if!

テキですよ、テキ！
‥‥ねっ！　なるほどくん！
They're rivals! Rivals!
Right, Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥今はね。
For now we are... I guess.

<Maya>
ええーっ！
Huh!?

なんでそう、思わせぶりなこと
言うかなぁ。
Why do I get the feeling
I'm missing something?

教えてよー！
C'mon, Nick! Tell me!
What's the deal with you
and Edgeworth?

<Phoenix>
‥‥こうして、この事件は、
ついに幕を下ろした。
And so the curtain closes
on another trial...

ぼくが法廷でぶちまけた
イブクロさんの“事故”は、
I caused quite a stir by
revealing that accident
from five years ago.

大きく世間をさわがせることに
なった。
It was the talk of the town.

しかしその結果、英都撮影所は
ふたたび方針を変えて、
Thankfully, Global Studios
rethought its programming
change.

子供のためのシリーズは、
つづけられることになった‥‥。
They went back to making
kids' shows again.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick!

今日だよ、新番組！
‥‥いっしょに見るんだからね！
This is it! The new show
starts today! You're going
to watch it with me, right?

<Phoenix>
（しかし‥‥）
(I'll admit, I was kind
of surprised...)

（ホンキでやるとは
　思わなかったよ‥‥）
(I didn't think they'd
seriously go through
with it...)

<Maya>
なるほどくんも買うんだよ！
トレーディング・カード。
You have to buy trading
cards too, okay!

九太くんやスタッフの子と
トレードするんだから！
We have to trade with
Cody and that assistant!

<Phoenix>
はいはい。
‥‥わかったよ。
Fine, fine.
I'll do it.

<Maya>
でも、よかったね。
ニボサブさん、また主役だって！
Isn't it great that WP
gets to play the lead again?

今度こそ、カオ、出るかなあ？
I wonder if they'll show
his real face this time...

<Phoenix>
‥‥ううん‥‥。
I dunno...

‥‥ますます出ないと思うよ。
I don't think the world
is ready for the real
Will Powers...


　　　　　　　　　　　　　おわり
                      THE END


<Judge>
そこまで！
That's enough!

本法廷は、これ以上の審議の
必要性を認めません。
This court sees no reason to
further prolong the trial.

<Phoenix>
（し、しまった‥‥）
(Uh oh...)

<Judge>
被告人、荷星　三郎に
判決を言い渡します！
This court finds the
defendant, Mr. Will Powers...

被告人はこれより身柄を
司直に預けるものとし、
The accused will surrender
to the court immediately,

１ヶ月以内に、高等裁判所において
通常裁判を受けることとします。
to be held pending trial at
a higher court within a
month from today's date.

では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
That is all.
The court is adjourned!

