< >
２月２３日　某時刻
証拠保管室前／警備室
February 23
Evidence Room Entrance
Guard Station

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんだ。この、きわめて
シュミ性の強い空間は‥‥
What's with the decor in
this place? It's very...
eccentric.

<Ema>
パンフレットによると、
《保管室前・警備室》ですけど。
According to the pamphlet,
this is the guard station
for the evidence room.

<Phoenix>
じゃあ、あのドアの向こうが
証拠保管室‥‥“殺人現場”か。
So, beyond that door is the
evidence room... the scene
of the crime?

<Ema>
そういうことになりますね。
‥‥‥‥‥うううう‥‥‥‥‥
It sure seems that way...
Oh. Ohhh...

<Phoenix>
ど。どうしたの？
What's wrong?

<Ema>
ヨコのサボテンくんの存在感に圧倒
されて、考えがまとまりません！
It's those cacti! They're
so prickly... so imposing!
It's hard to think straight.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(If you can't handle the
cacti, stay out of the
desert...)

そもそも、警備室なのに、
どうして警備のヒトがいないんだ！
What I want to know is, if
this is a guard station,
where is the guard?

<Ema>
“警備のヒト”‥‥
だいたい、想像はつきますね。
I have a feeling I know who
this guard is already...







<Ema>
かなり、チクチクしますね。
‥‥ホンモノかな、コレ。
Yipes, that sure is
prickly. It must be
the real deal.

<Phoenix>
このデカいのが１コあれば、
じゅうぶんだと思うけど。
I would think just one big
one would be sufficient.

<Ema>
この、サボテン。
‥‥お姉ちゃん、みたいですね。
This cactus... is a lot
like my sister, actually.

<Phoenix>
と、ともえさん‥‥？
M-Ms. Skye?

<Ema>
冷たくてカタいカラをかぶって、
さらにトゲで身を守って‥‥
Encased in a cold, rigid
shell, with thorns pointing
in every direction...

お姉ちゃん、そっくり。
Just like her.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
悪いけど、どう見ても
ともえさんには似てないよ。
You know, I've been looking at
this cactus a while now, and
I don't see the resemblance.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あたしも、フンイキで
言っちゃいました。
It's more an attitude thing
than a physical similarity.







<Phoenix>
証拠保管室の映像が
映し出されているみたいだ。
It looks like there's a video
feed from the evidence room
here.

<Ema>
モニターの下に、
ランプが光ってますよ。
There's a light blinking
below the monitor.

《録画中》‥‥って
書いてあります！
It says "Recording"!

このパソコンで、出入りするヒトを
チェックしてたみたいですね！
I bet we could use this
computer to check on who
went in and out of here!







<Ema>
警備員さんの服が
つるしてあります！
There's a security guard
uniform hanging here.

<Phoenix>
“制服”じゃないコトは
たしかだね。
It looks more like a costume
than a uniform, honestly.

<Ema>
カワのジャンパーに、
カワのズボンに、カワの‥‥
A leather jacket, leather
pants, a leather...

あれ。これ、なんでしたっけ！
What was that called again?

パンチ‥‥ピンチ‥‥ペンチ‥‥
あ、ポンチ！
A punchy? A paunchy? 
A pinchy? I know! A poochy!

ううん‥‥今ひとつ
ピンと来ないなあ‥‥
Hmm...
Wait, maybe that wasn't it.

<Phoenix>
（“ポンチョ”だけど、もう少し
　ダマっておこう‥‥）
(It's a "poncho," but I think
I'll keep that information to
myself for the time being.)







<Ema>
こんなところに、
投げナワがありますよ。
Look, on the floor,
a lasso!

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんか、“ワナ”っぽい
ムードがただよってるなあ。
Hmm... looks like it's set up
to trap something.

<Ema>
ワナっぽい‥‥ねえ‥‥
あ！　できました！
A trap, here?
Wait, I know!

《“ワナげ”な投げナワ》
‥‥逆から読んでも同じです！
Maybe someone was trying to
catch a wild bull in here...
But the lasso missed!

<Phoenix>
‥‥そりゃ、スゴイね。
You sure have an active
imagination.







<Phoenix>
このドアの向こうが
《証拠保管室》だね。
The evidence room is
beyond that door.

<Ema>
さあ、ハリきって行きましょう！
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
Let's just walk in!
...

開かない。
It won't open.

<Phoenix>
そりゃ、そうだろうね。
You thought it'd be open?

（現場を調べるには、
　だれかの協力が必要だな‥‥）
(I think we'd need someone's
permission to go in there
first...)




<Phoenix>
このドアの向こうが
《証拠保管室》だね。
The evidence room is
beyond that door.

<Ema>
ガント局長さんに
ＩＤカードも借りてきたし。
And we have the ID card
from Chief Gant!

さあ、ハリきって行きましょう！
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
Let's just walk in!
...

開かない。
It won't open.

<Phoenix>
あ！　カード端末の
電源がオフになってるぞ。
Ah hah! The card reader is
turned off, see?

<Ema>
もう！　警備のヒト、
ちゃんとシゴトしましょうよ！
What is that security
guard thinking?







<Ema>
わあ。西部のサルーンみたい！
この、スイングドア。
This swinging door makes
the place look like some
kind of saloon!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥クギで打ちつけてあるぞ。
入れないよ、これじゃ。
But look, it's nailed shut.
You can't get in that way.

<Ema>
だってホラ。ここから入ったら、
サボテンが倒れてきて‥‥
Of course not! If you went
in through here...

チクッ、てなりますから。
The cactus would fall over.
Ouch!

<Phoenix>
‥‥“チクッ”じゃ
すまないぞ、きっと。
I'd say it'd be more of
an "Yeeeeaargh," myself.




<???>
おやおや‥‥バンビーナが
ごきげんナナメのようだよ。
Howdy, pardners. Well, well,
what's made my bambina's
skies so gray?

<Phoenix>
ざ、罪門さん！
（やっぱり、このヒトか‥‥）
O-Officer Marshall!
(Somehow, I knew...)

<Marshall>
なんだい？　その“やっぱり、
このヒトか‥‥”みたいな目は。
What's that "somehow I knew"
look for?

‥‥お察しのとおり。
ここはオレのサルーンさ。
As you may have surmised,
this here's my saloon.

<Ema>
あの‥‥あたしたち、
現場を調査したいんですけど。
Um... we're here to
investigate the crime
scene.

<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ほお‥‥そのムネのカード。
新世界へのティケットかい。
Yeehaw! That card you got
there on your chest.

<Marshall>
That's better than a sheriff's
badge in these parts.

<Ema>
てぃけっと‥‥
Y-yeehaw?

<Marshall>
いいさ。サツジン現場で
開拓者気分を味わってくることさ。
Well, what ya standin' there
for? Get along, little dogies.
The crime scene's a waiting!

< >
ピッ
*beep*

<Phoenix>
（カードリーダーの
　電源がもどったみたいだな）
(Looks like the card reader's
on again.)

‥‥ついでに、お話を
聞かせていただけますか？
While we're here, I was 
wondering if we could
ask you some questions?

<Marshall>
悪いがカウボーイ。
キミたちの相手をする気はないさ。
Sorry, cowboy, but I got
no mind to tangle with
you hombres.

<Phoenix>
やっぱり‥‥忙しいんですか？
You're... busy, then?

<Marshall>
そんなコトは言ってないだろう？
Did I say that?

“相手をする気はない”‥‥
それだけのことさ。
I only said I didn't wish
to speak with you.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Actually, you said you had
"no mind to tangle with us
hombres.")




<Ema>
かなり、チクチクしますね。
‥‥ホンモノかな、コレ。
This cactus sure is prickly.
It must be real.

<Marshall>
ビリーに近づかないほうがいい。
‥‥ケガ、するぜ。
Best keep your distance
from Billy there. You're
liable to get hurt.

<Phoenix>
びりー‥‥
このサボテンのコトですか？
Billy...
The cactus has a name?

<Ema>
左ウデに、カウボーイハットを
かぶってますね。ビリー。
Billy, you're wearing your
cowboy hat on your hand.

<Marshall>
ああ‥‥、そのカウスキンの
ローハイドかい。
Ah, my rawhide cow skin
10-gallon hat!

買ったばかりだったんだけど。
ビリーが気に入ったみたいでね。
I just picked that up, but
Billy took a fancy to it.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥トゲに引っかかって
　とれなくなったみたいだな）
(Looks like it got stuck
on the thorns and he 
couldn't get it off.)




<Ema>
ずいぶんいっぱい
モニターがありますね！
You sure have a lot of
monitors in here!

<Marshall>
証拠保管室は、ゼンブで
８つ、あるからね。
There's eight cameras in
the evidence room in all.

１部屋に１つ、防犯カメラが
設置されているのさ。
One for each section.

<Ema>
へえ‥‥。事件があった保管室の
モニターは、どれですか？
Which monitor shows the
section where the crime
took place?

<Marshall>
そいつは‥‥“神のみぞ知る”
ってヤツだな。
Why do cattle sit before 
the rains come?
It's not for man to know.

<Ema>
‥‥警備員シッカクですね、
罪門さん。
Unless you're the security
guard responsible!




<Ema>
カワのジャンパーに、
カワのズボンに、カワの‥‥
A leather jacket, leather
pants, and a leather...

<Marshall>
ズボンじゃないさ。チャップスに
‥‥そっちは、ポンチョだね。
Those aren't pants, those
are chaps. And that's a 
poncho up there.

<Ema>
あ、それ！　ポンチョ！
Ah hah! A poncho!

‥‥カッコいいけど、
名前はかわいらしいですね。
It sure looks cool, but the
name is a little silly.




<Ema>
こんなところに、
投げナワがありますよ。
Look, on the floor,
it's a lasso.

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんか、“ワナ”っぽい
ムードがただよってるなあ。
Hmm... looks like it's set up
to trap something.

<Marshall>
さっき、デカいウシを
ひっとらえたぜ‥‥そのワナで。
I just roped me a steer
with this here lasso.

<Ema>
え！
What!?

<Marshall>
“もーッス！”“もーッス！”
‥‥しきりに、鳴いてたっけな。
It was a' bellowing
"moo, pal! moo!"

<Phoenix>
（イトノコ刑事か‥‥）
(Detective Gumshoe,
I presume...)




<Phoenix>
このドアの向こうが
《証拠保管室》だね。
The evidence room is
beyond that door.

<Marshall>
カードリーダーの電源は
入れておいたぜ。
I turned on the card reader.

せいぜい、楽しんでくることさ、
カウボーイ！
Go have yourself a ball,
pardners!

<Ema>
このＩＤカード、
あたしが借りたんですからね！
And I have the ID card!
A real ID card!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥早いトコ、現場を
　調べたほうがいいかな‥‥）
(Let's get this investigation
started already...)




<Ema>
わあ。西部のサルーンみたい！
この、スイングドア。
Look at this swinging door!
Just a like a wild west
saloon!

<Marshall>
おっと‥‥。
今日はもう、閉店だぜ。
Ah...
Sorry, pardner, but we're
closed for the day.

<Phoenix>
‥‥え。
Huh?

<Marshall>
早く帰ってくれねえかい、
アンタたち。
Y'all get along home now!

<Ema>
お店のマスター気取りですね、
罪門さん。
I think Officer Marshall
really wanted to be a wild
west bartender.

<Marshall>
‥‥一度、このセリフが
言ってみたくてね。
I always wanted to say that.




<Ema>
この先に、あたしたちの
新世界が広がっているワケですね！
Beyond that door, a whole
new world awaits us!

<Phoenix>
‥‥殺人現場の証拠保管室、だね。
Right, the evidence room where
the murder took place...

<Ema>
新世界へのティケットなら、
ここにありますし。
And our ticket to this new
world is right here.

<Phoenix>
‥‥局長さんから借りた
お客さん用のＩＤ、だね。
The visitor's ID we borrowed
from the Chief of Police
I'm guessing...

<Ema>
さあ。いざ！
このサルーンを出発しましょう！
Right! Let's leave this saloon
behind us in the dust!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥罪門巡査から、よくない
　影響をモロに受けているな‥‥）
(She's definitely the
impressionable type...)




<Ema>
‥‥あの。おハナシを
うかがいたいんですけど‥‥
Um, I was wondering if we
could talk to you...

<Marshall>
悪いが、バンビーナ。
Sorry, bambina.

オレは今、タンブル・ウィードと
ともに、荒野をかけめぐってるよ。
But I'm off to roam the
lands, like a tumbleweed
on the wide prairie.

ガンスリンガーが、マスケットに
弾丸をこめるよう、祈りながらね。
Like a gunslinger loading
his six-shooter, I say a
little prayer.

‥ぐぎゅるるぐぐ‥‥ぅぅ‥‥う‥
GRROOOOORRK

<Ema>
‥‥で。ケッキョク、どういう
コトですか？　成歩堂さん！
What was that all about,
Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
ハラをすかせて、しゃべる気分じゃ
ない。‥‥そういうコト、かな。
I think he was just too
hungry to talk.

<Ema>
それ‥‥、最後の“音”だけで
キメつけてませんか？
You're just saying that
because his stomach was
growling!

<Ema>
You have no idea what he
was talking about either!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とにかく、
　なんとかしないとな‥‥）
(Well, in any case, we need
to get cracking on this 
investigation, pronto!)




<Ema>
罪門さん。証拠保管室の
警備を担当してるんですよね？
Officer Marshall, you're in
charge of security for the
evidence room, right?

<Marshall>
ダレにでもできる、ありがたい
シゴトさ。‥‥よく知ってるね。
You got good eyes, pardner.
It's an easy job, and I'm
grateful for it.

<Phoenix>
留置所の、原灰巡査から
教えてもらいました。
Actually, Officer Meekins at
the detention center told us.

<Marshall>
ああ‥‥あの、
カワイソウなボウヤか。
Ah, that poor little dogie?

２回に１回は、自分の名前を
“灰原”と書きまちがえる‥‥
Poor guy, I keep getting his
name wrong and calling him
"Meekly."

<Phoenix>
彼は‥‥こんなコトも
教えてくれました。
He told us something.

事件があったとき、あなたは
警備室にいなかった‥‥と。
He said that, when the
stabbing occurred...
you weren't at your station.

<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
こんなコト、言っちゃマズいが。
...
Well, maybe I shouldn't be
telling you this...

今から、２年前。
捜査官からハズれてから‥‥
But since I got demoted from
detective two years ago...

見た目ほど、ヤル気マンマン
ってワケじゃないんだよ。
Well, it might not look it, 
but I lost my fire for the
job, you know?

<Ema>
あの‥‥何をしてたんですか？
事件が起こった、５時１５分ごろ。
So... what were you doing
around 5:15 when the murder
took place?

<Marshall>
さあね‥‥。ジップ・コチーズ号で
街道をギャロップで流してたかな。
Well...

<Marshall>
I reckon I was galloping down
the highway on the back of
my steed, Zippy.

<Ema>
‥‥名馬にまたがって
高速道路を走っていた、と。
Note: he was riding down the
highway on his horse named
"Zippy."

<Marshall>
とりあえず、ここには
ニンゲンは必要ないのさ。
There's no need for people
here, anyhow.

最新のキカイたちが、キチンと
見張ってくれるらしいからね。
These newfangled machines
do a bang-up job of keeping
an eye on the place.

<Phoenix>
最新のキカイ‥‥
“防犯システム”ですか。
You mean the security
camera system?

<Marshall>
キカイ‥‥か。
I don't take to machines
much.

ステーキのヨコの、ゆでた
ブロッコリーの次にニガテだよ。
Kinda like that stewed 
broccoli they sneak in next
to your steak, you know?




<Ema>
おキョウさんから聞きました。
Ms. Starr told us something...

罪門さん‥‥２年前まで
捜査官だったんだ、って。
She said that you were a
detective until two years
ago.

<Marshall>
“事件現場のブッシュワッカー”
‥‥荒野にうずめたユメのアトさ。
It was always my dream to be
a rawhide wrangler on the
scene of the crime...

<Marshall>
That's all gone now...
Like a drinking hole
in a prairie fire.

<Ema>
今も、調べてるんですよね。
ＳＬ９号事件‥‥おキョウさんと。
You're still investigating
the SL-9 Incident with
Ms. Starr, aren't you?

<Marshall>
‥‥あれは、オレの事件だった。
That was my case...

記録の上では《解決》している。
お得意のイカサマポーカーさ。
It's all "solved" on the 
record books. But it smells
like a bad game of poker.

しかし。オレはナットクできない。
‥‥それだけのコト、だよ。
I can't let it go...

<Marshall>
That's all there is to it.

<Ema>
あの。どんな事件だったんですか？
《ＳＬ９号事件》って。
What kind of case was it,
anyway?

名前だけ、よく聞くんですけど‥‥
ダレも教えてくれないんです。
We've heard the name so
many times, but no one tells
us what actually happened.

<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

知らないほうがいいコトも
あるよ、バンビーナ。
There are some things you're
better off not knowing, 
Bambina.

それに‥‥あの事件は、２日前。
今度こそ、完全に死んじまった。
Anyway, that case is
officially dead as of
two days ago.

<Phoenix>
“２日前”‥‥
事件があった日、ですか？
Two days ago... the day
of our case!

<Marshall>
そう‥‥
《証拠品の申し送り》さ。
That's right...
The evidence transferals.

<Phoenix>
（御剣も言ってたな
　‥‥《申し送り》）
(Edgeworth was talking about
the transferals, too.)




<Marshall>
オレが知っているキカイは
とりあえず、２つさ。
I know what maybe two of
the machines in here do.

<Ema>
と、“とりあえず”‥‥？
O-only two of them?
There must be a dozen!

<Marshall>
言っただろ、バンビーナ。
オレにとってキカイは‥‥
Like I said, bambina,
Me and machines, well...

ステーキのヨコの、ゆでた
カリフラワーの次にニガテなのさ。
I like them about as much
as I like stewed cauliflower
with my steaks.

まず。わかりやすいのは
《防犯カメラ》だろう。
The easiest ones to understand
are these here security
cameras.

<Phoenix>
（ハラバイ巡査も言ってたな）
(Those are the ones that
Officer Meekins mentioned.)

<Marshall>
数時間ごとに、異常がなければ
消去されちまうらしいけどね。
If nothing happens, the
tapes are automatically
erased every few hours.

<Ema>
そのカメラに、映ってたんですか？
原灰巡査と‥‥多田敷捜査官が。
And Officer Meekins and
Detective Goodman, are they
on one of those tapes?

<Marshall>
‥‥たぶんね。
I reckon they might be.

<Phoenix>
（セキニンシャが
　“たぶん”はないだろう‥‥）
(You're the security guard
and you "reckon"!?)

<Marshall>
そして、もう１つ。
One more thing.

証拠保管室に入るときには、
ＩＤカードが必要なんだよ。
When you go into the evidence
room... You need an ID card.

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥ドアのワキに
　カードリーダーがあるな）
(Thus the card reader by
the door.)

<Marshall>
ＩＤカードを使うと、記録が残る。
ありがちだが‥‥わかりやすいさ。
The card reader leaves a
record of every ID card
passed through.

<Phoenix>
（これが、ＩＤの使用記録‥‥）
(So this is the ID card
record...)

<Ema>
あ‥‥‥あれ！
見たことがあるナンバーが‥‥
Hey! I've seen that somewhere
before!

<Marshall>
おっと‥‥！　これ以上は
見せられないな、バンビーナ。
Sorry, Bambina. I can't
show you more than that.

<Ema>
え。
Huh?

<Marshall>
コイツが事件にカンケイするか‥‥
オレは聞かされてないからね。
I haven't heard whether this
is related to the case, yet.

<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　今の記録。
見おぼえのあるナンバーが‥‥
Mr. Wright! I saw a number
on that record just now!
I've seen that number before!

<Phoenix>
（使用記録と事件との“カンケイ”
　‥‥つきつけてやるんだ！）
(Maybe there's some way I can
prove that record is tied
to the stabbing.)




<Phoenix>
すみませんけど‥‥そもそも、
《申し送り》って、なんですか？
Sorry, but could you explain
what this whole "transferal"
thing is about?

<Marshall>
保管室には、解決した事件の
証拠品だけが眠っている。
We keep only evidence from
solved cases in this room.

それぞれの担当捜査官の管理で、
２年間。ここに保管されるのさ。
They're kept here under the
presiding detective's
supervision for two years.

万が一、解決がまちがっていた場合
‥‥再捜査のためにね。
So we can re-investigate them
if it turns out there was
a mistake, see?

<Phoenix>
じゃあ、２年たった証拠品は
どうなるんですか？
So, what happens to the
evidence after two years?

<Marshall>
警視庁の地下倉庫で、
永久に眠ることになる。
It goes to sleep forever 
in the underground vault
at the Police Station.

それが、《申し送り》ってヤツさ。
‥‥年に一度、２月に行われる。
That's what we call
"transferal."
We do it every February.

<Ema>
そう、だったんですか‥‥
I see now...

<Marshall>
《申し送り》は‥‥そう。
事件の“葬式”とも言えるよ。
"Transferal" is like a 
funeral for old cases.

解決から、２年が経過したとき。
その事件は完全に終わって、死ぬ。
Two years after a case is
solved... it's closed
forever. Dead.

もう、追跡捜査をすることは
できない。‥‥永久に。
Never to be reopened again.
Never to be reinvestigated.

<Phoenix>
（そして‥‥《ＳＬ９号事件》は
　２日前、死んだワケか‥‥）
(And that happened to SL-9
two days ago...)










<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
.........

‥‥このニオイ。
テキサスを思い出すぜ。
That smell...
Ah! Reminds me of Texas!

<Ema>
罪門さん‥‥
テキサスのヒトだったんですか！
So, Officer Marshall...
You're from Texas?

<Marshall>
こないだテレビで見たさ。
‥‥ベイビイからの差し入れかい？
No, I just saw a special on
television the other day.
Is this from my baby?

<Ema>
え、ええ。おキョウさんから‥‥
Uh, yeah, Ms. Starr...

<Marshall>
こ‥‥コイツは‥‥ッ！
Wh-what's this!?

<Ema>
ど、どうしました？
What? What's wrong?

<Marshall>
‥‥フィレ・ステーキ弁当‥‥！
そうか！　そういうコトかッ！
A filet steak lunch!
I see... I see!

<Ema>
‥‥どういうイミがあるのかな、
あのお弁当。
I don't see.
I wonder what it means?

< >
罪門巡査に
《ステーキ弁当》をわたした。
Steak Lunch given to
Officer Marshall.

<Marshall>
オーライ、バンビーナ。
アンタの勝ちだ。
Alright, bambina.
You win.

なんでもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ。
聞いてごくごくごくごくごくごく。
Ask mmph mmph munch munch
Anything mmph munch smack.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どうやら‥‥）
(Finally, it seems like...)

<Ema>
ハナシをしてくれる気に
なったみたいですね！
He's willing to talk!




<Marshall>
‥‥ムカシ、テキサスの保安官は、
証拠品なんか信じなかった。
The sheriffs back in the 
wild west didn't place much
faith in evidence.

信じたのは‥‥自分の
ウデっぷしだけ、だったのさ。
About the only thing they 
trusted was their shooting
hand.

<Ema>
あの。ここは“ムカシ”じゃないし
“テキサス”でもないですけど‥‥
Um... this is neither "Wild"
nor "West" here...

<Marshall>
ハッ！　それとコレとは、
ハナシがちがうんじゃないかな？
Ah hah! But that and this
are two different things
entirely!

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
ダメ。イミがわかりません。
...
I... guess so? Huh?
I'm lost.

<Phoenix>
（決定的にカンケイがある証拠品
　以外、見せてもムダみたいだ）
(Looks like we need some
evidence to get anywhere
with this guy.)







<Ema>
これ、見てください！
被害者のＩＤカードなんですけど。
See this? This is the
victim's ID card.

<Marshall>
ああ。‥‥たしか、現場の
地下駐車場に落ちていたな。
Ah, the one that was on the
ground in the parking lot?

<Phoenix>
コイツの番号なんですけど‥‥
《５８４２１８９》です。
The number on this is...
"5842189."

<Ema>
罪門さん！　さっきの記録‥‥
ＩＤの使用記録を見せてください！
Officer Marshall!
Show us the ID number on that
ID card record!

<Ema>
この、４番目のナンバー‥‥
カンゼンに一致します！
Look, the fourth number!
It's a perfect match!

<Phoenix>
使用された時刻は、５時１４分。
事件が起こった時間‥‥だ！
It was used at... 5:14.
Right before the stabbing!

<Marshall>
しかし！　ＩＤカードは、この世に
１枚しか存在しないはずだぜ！
What's more, there's only
one of them cards in the
world!

<Ema>
やっぱり‥‥事件があった時間、
多田敷さんは証拠保管室に‥‥
So, when the incident
occurred, Detective Goodman
was in the evidence room!

<Phoenix>
（でも、待てよ‥‥
　原灰巡査は、こう言っていた！）
(But wait, what did Officer
Meekins say?)

<Meekins>
保管室に入った本官は、ＩＤカード
の提示を求めたであります！
Sir, I entered the evidence
room, and asked the man to
display his ID card!

<Phoenix>
それで‥‥ＩＤの提示を求められた
多田敷捜査官は？　どうしました？
So you asked Detective Goodman
to show his ID card. What
did he do?

<Meekins>
なんとッ！　いきなり、本官に
ナイフを向けたであります！
That's the thing! Suddenly
he pointed a knife at me!

<Phoenix>
（そのとき、彼がＩＤカードを
　持っていたのならば‥‥）
(If he had his ID card
then...)

（原灰巡査に切りかかる必要
　なんか、なかったハズだ‥‥）
(Why would he have pointed
a knife at Officer Meekins?)

<Marshall>
‥‥オーライ、カウボーイ。
アンタの勝ちさ。
Alright, compadre,
you win.

この記録‥‥アンタに
わたしたほうがよさそうだ。
I guess I can give you
this ID card record.

< >
証拠品《ＩＤカード使用記録》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
ID Card Record added
to the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（このリスト‥‥）
(I've got an idea...)

（ＩＤを持っていそうな人物に
　見せてみたほうがいいな）
(Maybe I should show this
list to other people with
IDs here...)




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
証拠保管室／第３号庫
February 23
Evidence Room
Sector Three

<Phoenix>
（静かだな‥‥
　捜査は終わってるみたいだ）
(It's quiet... the
investigation must
be over here.)

<Ema>
証拠保管室‥‥かあ。
ホント、お墓みたいですね。
So this is the evidence room?
It really is kind of like
a graveyard.

<Phoenix>
“お墓”というより‥‥
“死体置き場”だよ。このムード。
Graveyards are supposed to
have grass and trees.
This feels more like a morgue.

<Ema>
ここ、こ。怖がらせようとしても
む。ムダですからね。
N-nice try, M-Mr. Wright.
Y-you can't scare me!

<Ema>
きゃああああああああああああッ！
Eeeeeeek!

<Gumshoe>
ほほほおおおおおおおおおおいッ！
Whoooooah!

<Ema>
ご、ごめんなさい。
悪霊かと思ったんです。
S-sorry, I thought you
were a ghost!

<Gumshoe>
‥‥悪霊に、いきなり
ビンタはどうかと思うッス。
I wouldn't recommend going
around smacking ghosts on
the head, pal.

とにかく‥‥ホントッスね？
さっきのハナシは！
So, is it true 
what I heard?

<Gant>
‥‥ボクさ。そんなね。
ケチなオトコじゃないワケ。
Wrighto, please, do I look
like a selfish man?

ダレにたのまれても、
５０００円までなら貸すし。
Heck, if anyone asked me
"sir, can I borrow $50?"
I'd give them $50, no problem.

‥‥ぜんぜんモンダイないよ。
好きに調べてくれていいから。
So, go ahead! Investigate
that room to your heart's
desire! Knock yourself out!

<Phoenix>
え、ええ‥‥ホントですよ。
Yeah, it's true.

<Gumshoe>
巌徒局長殿が‥‥
So, Chief of Police Gant...

５０００円も貸してくれるッ！
この自分がたのんでもッ！
will loan anyone 50 bucks?
Even me!?

<Ema>
‥‥そっちですか。
Oh, so that's what you were
talking about...

<Gumshoe>
今日は自分、捜査班長を
任命されていたッス。
Actually, I was put in
charge of the investigation
for today.

<Phoenix>
１日だけですか。
Just for today?

<Ema>
“１日班長さん”ですね。
Boss for a day...

<Gumshoe>
しかし、これからはッ！
アンタが１日班長ッス！
But guess what!? You got
permission from the Chief...
So now you're boss for a day!

<Phoenix>
（うれしくないヒビキだな）
(Gee, thanks.)

<Gumshoe>
とりあえず、これ。
持っておくといいッス。
First of all, you'll
want to have this.

< >
証拠品《証拠保管室の上面図》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
Evidence Room Floor Plans
added to the Court Record.




<Gumshoe>
‥‥おッ！
もう、こんな時間ッスか。
Hey, pal, look at the time!!

<Phoenix>
あれ。何か用事でもあるんですか？
Was there something you
needed to be going to?

<Gumshoe>
そろそろ、御剣検事の査問会が
終わるッス。
It's just that Mr. Edgeworth's
inquiry committee should be
letting out soon.

自分、今日の捜査の報告書を
わたしてくるッス！
I'm going to go give them
my report for the day.

何かの助けになるかも‥‥
It might help, you know...

<Ema>
ほ、報告書、って‥‥
その、チラシですか？
R-report? You mean the note
written on the back of
that flyer?

<Phoenix>
しかも、ウラに《異常なしッス》
しか、書いてありませんけど。
The one that says nothing but
"No problems"!?

<Gumshoe>
御剣検事なら！　こんな報告書すら
役に立ててくれるハズッス！
Hey, it's Mr. Edgeworth
we're talking about! I'm sure
he can use a report like this.

自分、信じてるッス！
I believe in him!

<Phoenix>
（アツ苦しい信頼を寄せられる
　立場も、キノドクなもんだな）
(Who needs enemies when you've
got friends like Detective
Gumshoe...)

<Gumshoe>
‥‥じゃっ！
ひとっ走り、行ってくるッス！
I'm off, pal!
Later!

<Phoenix>
（御剣‥‥ぼくも、話を聞いて
　おいたほうがいいかな）
(I should probably see what
Edgeworth has to say, too.)




<Ema>
さっき入ってきたドア、ですね。
That's the door we
just came in through.

<Phoenix>
出るときは、いらないみたいだ。
‥‥ＩＤカード。
Looks like you don't need
an ID card to get out.

<Ema>
罪門さんが電源を切ったら
どうなっちゃうんでしょうね。
I wonder what would happen
if Officer Marshall cut the
power while we were inside?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（そのへん、ちゃんと考えてる
　のかな、あのヒト）
(Let's hope he remembers
we're in here.)




<Ema>
うわ。おっきなガラクタが
つみ上げられてますよ！
Wow! Look at this big pile
of junk in the corner!

<Phoenix>
これは‥‥クルマのドア、だね。
That looks like...
a car door.

<Ema>
ドアのフレームに
手錠がついてますよ。
There's a pair of handcuffs
attached to the frame.

<Phoenix>
‥‥タイホした怪盗に
逃げられたのかな。
Maybe the guy they caught
was some sort of escape artist
and he got away.

<Ema>
こっちはアレですね。
現場検証用のヒト型。
Hey, that's one of those
human profiles for range
testing.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ヒタイを
キレイに撃ち抜かれてるな。
He's been shot square in the
forehead.

<Ema>
成歩堂さんも、撃ち抜かれない
ように、気をつけてくださいね。
Better him than us.







<Phoenix>
‥‥何か、ハミ出してるね。
There's something sticking
out of here.

<Ema>
シャツ‥‥かな。
何かの証拠品でしょうか。
Looks like a shirt.
I guess it must be evidence
for some case.

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事ですか、コレ。
I wonder if Detective Gumshoe
put this here.

<Gumshoe>
ヒトを“だらしないヤツ”みたいに
言わないでほしいッス。
There you go, pal, making me
out to be some kinda slob!

自分の保管庫は、そこじゃ
ないッスから。‥‥とは言え。
I'm not responsible for
the evidence here.
That said...

おそらく、これは‥‥最近。
開けられた保管庫ッスね。
I bet that evidence locker was
opened recently.

<Ema>
どうしてわかるんですか？
How do you know?

<Gumshoe>
こんなふうにしたら、
証拠品がイタむッスからね。
If you leave things hanging
out like that, the evidence
gets dirty or ripped.

見回りの巡査がチェックして、
担当の捜査官が注意されるッス。
The guard checks on that kind
of stuff and notifies the
detective responsible.

‥‥まったく、
うるさくてかなわないッス！
How many times have I had
him breathing down my neck
about some silly evidence...

<Ema>
‥‥イトノコ刑事さん、いつも
注意されてるみたいですね。
Sounds like Detective Gumshoe
leaves evidence hanging out
a lot, too.

<Phoenix>
きっと、コートの下では、シャツが
ズボンからハミ出てるんだろうね。
I bet he doesn't tuck in
his shirt under that trench
coat, either.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥カゲグチなら、聞こえない
トコでやってほしいッス。
If you're going to talk behind
someone's back, don't do it
right in front of them, pal!




<Phoenix>
白い布がハミ出てるね。
‥‥シャツかな。
A piece of white cloth is
sticking out... looks like
a shirt.

<Ema>
ちゃんとしまっておかないと
シワになっちゃいますよ！
You'd better tidy it up
or it will get wrinkled!

<Phoenix>
ぼくをニラまないで
くれるかな。
Hey, don't look at me!
I didn't leave it hanging
out like that!




<Ema>
この中に、パンパンに詰まってる
ワケですね。ユメと、証拠品が。
This place is stuffed with
evidence... stuffed with
dreams.

<Phoenix>
ユメはどうかと思うけどね。
I'm not so sure about the
dreams.

<Ema>
えいっ！
Mmph!

開かない。
It won't open.

<Phoenix>
そりゃ、そうだろうなあ。
I guess I should have known.

<Gumshoe>
まあ。最新式のセキュリティで
守られているッスからねえ。
Hey, pal, our security
is high-tech around here!







<Phoenix>
‥‥なんか、こまごまとした
キカイが、ホコリをかぶってるね。
Some sort of bulky equipment
is gathering dust here.

<Ema>
かわいそうなほど
ボロっちいツリザオがあります。
What a sorry looking
fishing pole that is.

<Gumshoe>
あ、それ！　自分のッス。
Ah! That's my personal pole!

‥‥あいかわらず、
使ったことないッス。
I never did get around
to using it...

<Phoenix>
あれ！　これ、どこかで
見たような‥‥
Wait, I've seen that
somewhere before...

<Gumshoe>
あ、それ！　金属探知機ッスよ！
Right, pal. That's that
metal detector!

ホレ。ひょうたん湖の事件を
解決にみちびいた‥‥
The one that led to the
solving of that case out
on Gourd Lake, remember?

<Phoenix>
ああ！　なつかしいですね。
Oh, right! Wow, that feels
like it was ages ago.

そして、これは‥‥
見たコトないですね。
And... hmm, I don't think
I've seen this one before.

<Gumshoe>
あ、それ！　電波探知機ッス。
Oh, that! That's a
radiolocator!

近い将来、なんらかの事件を
解決にみちびくかもしれないッス。
I'm sure it will come
in handy in solving some
case sooner or later.

<Phoenix>
（このチャチなハコが‥‥？）
(That cheap-looking box?)

<Gumshoe>
人間とキカイは、見た目じゃない！
‥‥“マゴコロ”ッス！
You can't judge a person
or a machine by their cover!
You gotta look at their heart!




<Ema>
うらぶれたガラクタたちが、
やつれ果て、打ちひしがれてます！
A pile of junk lies 
battered, worn and forsaken!

<Phoenix>
‥‥わざわざ、そこまで
言わなくてもいいんじゃないかな。
Aren't you being a little
dramatic?

ツリザオに、金属探知機。
これは‥‥知らないな。
Looks like a fishing pole...
and a metal detector.
Not sure what this one is.

<Ema>
やるせなくホコリをかぶって、
ウツロな目でこっちを見てます！
They cast a withering gaze
in our direction that screams,
"dust me!"

<Phoenix>
‥‥だから、わざわざ文学的に
表現しなくていいよ。
Can't junk just be plain
old junk?







<Ema>
ここだけ、開いてる‥‥
インジケータがついたままです！
Look, this one's open!
And there's a indicator
tag stuck on it still!

<Gumshoe>
そこが、多田敷刑事の
証拠保管庫ッス。
That locker is coded with
Detective Goodman's
fingerprint.

<Phoenix>
（被害者の‥‥保管庫！）
(Detective Goodman's locker!)

<Ema>
いいんですか？　開けっぱなしで。
Are you sure it's okay to
leave it open like that?

<Gumshoe>
一度閉めちゃうと、
開けるのがタイヘンッスから。
Well, it'd be hard to get
it open again if we closed it.

<Phoenix>
（中身は、カラ。‥‥さすがに
　どこかへ移されたようだな‥‥）
(It's empty... they must have
taken the contents elsewhere.)




<Ema>
多田敷捜査官の保管庫ですね。
中身はカラッポです。
Detective Goodman's evidence
locker. It's empty.

<Phoenix>
保管庫を開けられるのは、
多田敷さん本人だけ‥‥
Only Detective Goodman himself
can open this locker.

<Ema>
つまり、このナイフを持ち出した
のも、多田敷さん、ってコトかあ。
So, the person who took out
this knife had to have been
Detective Goodman.

<Phoenix>
（なぜ、それがマフラーに包まれて
　マフラーから出てきたんだ？）
(And why was it wrapped in
the "scarf" muffler stuck
inside the "car" muffler?)




<Phoenix>
こ‥‥これは‥‥血痕！
Wh-what's this...!?
Blood!

<Ema>
カスれてますけど、
アキラカに、手のアトですッ！
It's a little worn...
but there's definitely a
handprint here!

<Phoenix>
ふき消そうとして
残ってしまったみたいだな‥‥
It looks like someone tried
to wipe it off.

<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　この部屋‥‥
Mr. Wright!

他にも、血痕が
残っているかもしれません！
What if there are other
bloodstains left in the room!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥あのクスリを使って、
　よく調べたほうがいいな）
(We should use her testing
fluid to check it out.)







<Ema>
こんなところに、手袋が
‥‥かたっぽだけ。
Someone left a glove here...
but only one.

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事ですか、コレ。
Detective Gumshoe, maybe?

<Gumshoe>
ヒトを“うっかり屋”みたいに
言わないでほしいッス。
There you go, pal, making me
out to be some kind of absent-
minded detective!

ソイツも‥‥
“例の事件”の証拠品ッスね。
That's evidence from "the"
case, you know.

<Phoenix>
《ＳＬ９号事件》ですか‥‥
（たしかに、タグがついてるな）
You mean SL-9?
(It does have a tag on it...)

< >
証拠品《ゴム手袋》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Rubber Glove added
to the Court Record.




<Ema>
きのう、初めて見ました。
この、黄色いテープ。
That yellow crime scene
tape! You know, yesterday was
my first time seeing that!

群衆をかきわけて、これを
くぐるのがユメだったんですけど。
It was always my dream to
push through the crowd and
just step over the tape!

２日連続で出くわすと、ちょっと
ヘコんじゃいますね！
It's a little daunting
to encounter it again
so soon!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そうは見えないけど）
(I think maybe you're 
overreacting a little...)







<Ema>
‥‥ハデに割れたみたいですね。
何か、大きなものが。
Wow, someone must have broken
something big to make all
these pieces.

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事ですか、コレ。
Detective Gumshoe, perhaps?

<Gumshoe>
ヒトを“いたずらっ子”みたいに
言わないでほしいッス。
There you go, pal, making me
out to be some kind of
hooligan!

どうやら‥‥“例の事件”の
証拠品みたいッスね。
That's apparently from
"the" case.

<Ema>
例の事件‥‥？
"The" case?

<Gumshoe>
《ＳＬ９号事件》ッス。
カケラの１枚に、小さなシールが。
The SL-9 Incident, pal.
See the sticker on one of
the pieces there?

<Phoenix>
（《ＳＬ９号事件》の証拠品が
　また出てきたか‥‥）
(Another piece of SL-9
evidence...)



<Phoenix>
（‥‥やめておこう。
　時間がもったいない‥‥）
(Let's not waste too much 
time with this now.)

<Ema>
あとで、ちゃんと
調べてみましょうね。
We can check it out later.




<Phoenix>
このカケラを組み合わせると、
こんなツボになるワケだね。
If you put these pieces
together, it makes a jar.

<Ema>
‥‥気になる点が、
２つほどありますね。
There are two things
that bother me.

１つは‥‥
なぜ、カケラが足りないのか？
One: why are some of the
pieces missing?

そして、もう１つは‥‥
ちょっと不安定すぎます！
Two: doesn't it seem a
little unstable!?

そりゃ、割れますよ！
No wonder it broke!

<Phoenix>
‥‥今度、ツボを作ることが
あったら、気をつけるよ。
I'll make sure to remember
that next time I make a jar.







<Ema>
なんでこんなところに、
ペンキとノコギリが‥‥
What is a saw and paint
doing here?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥ムカシから。
Since the dawn of time...

ゲージュツはいつも、
《迫害》との戦いだったッス。
True art has always been
a war against oppression.

<Ema>
ゲージュツ？　そういえば‥‥
このペンキ、水色と黄色ですね。
True art...?
I noticed that there's 
blue and yellow paint here.

<Phoenix>
もしかして‥‥ここで
生まれたんですか？　タイホくん。
Perhaps we're witnessing the
birthplace of the Blue Badger?

<Gumshoe>
まあ‥‥自分にとっては、
アトリエ？　みたいなモノッスね。
Well...
You might say this is my
studio...

<Phoenix>
（いいのか‥‥？）
(Here? In the evidence room!?)




<Ema>
青いペンキと黄色いペンキが
ありますね。
There's blue and yellow 
paint here.

これだけあれば、成歩堂さんの
絵、描けますよ、あたし。
This is all I'd need to 
paint a portrait of you,
Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
いちおう、ネクタイも
してるんだけどな、ぼく。
I am wearing a red necktie,
you know...




<Ema>
１日班長さん、なんですよね？
刑事さん。
So, Detective Gumshoe,
you're boss for the day?

<Gumshoe>
そッスよ！　メーヨな任務ッス！
That's right! It's an honor!

なんせ、警察局内で発生した
サツジン事件ッスからねえ‥‥
After all, the murder took
place right here, in the
Police Department!

<Ema>
それにしては‥‥
ヒトリぽっちじゃないですか。
But, if you're boss...
why are you all alone!?

他のヒトたちは‥‥？
Where are your underlings?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

きのうの捜査をもとに、明日の
法廷のジュンビをしているッス。
They're using our findings
from yesterday's investigation
to prepare for the trial.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥つまり。今日もハズされて
　るのか。捜査班から‥‥）
(In other words, Detective
Gumshoe got kicked out of
the investigation again...)

<Gumshoe>
でも自分、メゲないッス！
I'm adamant, though!

担当捜査官の座をモギとって、
この事件を眠らせてみせるッス！
I'm going to take control
and put this case to rest!

‥‥自分の証拠保管庫にッ！
And in my own evidence
locker, pal!

<Phoenix>
イトノコさんの保管庫も
あるんですか？　ここに。
You have a locker in here,
too, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
ハッハッ。そりゃそッス。
自分は‥‥刑事、ッスからねえ。
Hah hah, of course!
I am a detective, after all.

自分にしか開けられない保管庫を、
バッチリもらってるッス。
They gave me a locker that
only I can open, pal!

<Ema>
“自分にしか”開けられない‥‥？
"Only you can open"...?




<Gumshoe>
自分は‥‥御剣検事を
信じているッス。何があっても。
I'll always believe in
Mr. Edgeworth, no matter
what happens.

<Ema>
そういえば‥‥今、査問会に
出頭しているそうですね。
So... Mr. Edgeworth is
with the inquiry committee
now, right?

<Gumshoe>
今日の法廷の失態について、
セキニンを追求されてるハズッス。
They're trying to figure out
who's responsible for the
mess-up in court today.

<Phoenix>
‥‥そう、ですか‥‥
I see...

<Gumshoe>
コイツは‥‥“ウンメイ”
というヤツかもしれないッス。
I guess this is what
you call "fate."

御剣検事は‥‥まだ。あの事件から
逃れるコトはできないッス。
Mr. Edgeworth just can't
get away from that case...

<Phoenix>
“あの事件”‥‥？
That case...?

<Gumshoe>
あれ。聞いてないッスか？
‥‥《ＳＬ９号事件》ッスよ。
Yeah, that case!
The SL-9 Incident, of course!

御剣検事にとっては‥‥
あれが“始まり”だったッス。
That was the beginning
of the end for Mr. Edgeworth.

<Phoenix>
（もう少し、詳しく
　聞き出せないかな‥‥）
(Maybe we can get him to tell
us more about the case...)




<Gumshoe>
ここは、見た目以上に
“ハイテク”ッスからねー。
This place is more high-
tech than you might think.

保管庫は、それぞれの捜査官しか
開けられないようになってるッス。
Every locker is fixed so that
only one detective can
open it.

<Phoenix>
この、ＩＤカードを使うんですか？
Using this ID card?

<Gumshoe>
ＩＤカードは、なくすことが
あるッスからねー。
Well, that's the thing, pal.
ID cards can be lost.

自分、今年に入ってから
もう３枚目ッス。
Why, I'm on my third card
since entering the force
already.

<Ema>
落としすぎです。
That sounds like a lot.

<Gumshoe>
ま。そんな自分でも、右手を
落とすことはできないッスから。
Yes, but even I can't lose
my own right hand!

<Ema>
“みぎて”‥‥あ！
“指紋”‥‥ですか？
"Right hand"...? Oh!
You mean, your fingerprint?

<Gumshoe>
そッス！　保管庫は、指紋による
ロックで守られているッス！
Exactly, pal! The lock for
each locker is coded with a
fingerprint!

<Gumshoe>
自分が開けられるのは、
あの保管庫だけッス。
And that's the only locker
we can open.

<Ema>
でも‥‥そんなスゴいシカケが
あるようには見えませんね。
Funny, they look like
normal lockers...

<Gumshoe>
さすが、最新型ッス。‥‥なんと！
取っ手にヒミツがあるッス！
These are the latest
model! There's a trick
to the handles, see?

<Ema>
とって‥‥
The handles?

<Gumshoe>
ウラに、センサーがついてるッス。
登録されていない指紋だと‥‥
On the other side of the
handles is a sensor, and if
the wrong person touches it...

<Ema>
電気ショック！　ですね。
Bzzzap! You get a shock!

<Gumshoe>
そんなコトされたら自分、
毎日が黒こげッス。
If that's what happened,
my hand would be black
and smoking every day!

とにかく、パッと見た感じが
あまりに自然なシカケなので‥‥
In any case, the locks
aren't that obvious.

捜査官の中には、指紋のロックを
知らない連中もいるみたいッスね。
There's even some people in
the force that don't know
about the fingerprint locks!

< >
証拠品《証拠保管庫》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Evidence Locker added to
the Court Record.




<Gumshoe>
‥‥かなり、
凶悪な事件だったらしいッス。
Now that was a bloody,
violent case.

<Phoenix>
凶悪‥‥というと、
殺人事件ですか？
Violent... so it was a
murder?

<Gumshoe>
連続殺人事件ッス。
A serial killing!

<Phoenix>
（“連続”‥‥扱いたくないな、
　そんなオソロシイ事件‥‥）
(A serial killing... Maybe
I don't want to get involved
in this after all.)

<Gumshoe>
ハンニンはミスを犯して、
御剣検事が立件に成功したッス。
But the killer made a mistake,
and Mr. Edgeworth built his
case around that to nab him.

<Ema>
それが‥‥今から
２年前のコトだったんですね。
And this was two years ago?

<Gumshoe>
御剣検事は名を上げて‥‥
同時に、黒い疑惑に包まれたッス。
That put Mr. Edgeworth right
in the spotlight...
and started the rumor-mill.

<Phoenix>
（証拠品の“ねつ造”か‥‥）
Rumors...
(About forged evidence?)

<Gumshoe>
おとといの《申し送り》で、
完全にカタがつくはずだったッス。
It was supposed to be
all cleaned up with the
"transferal" the other day.

ケッキョク‥‥それが、最後の
シゴトになっちまったッスね。
It was the last job he
ever did...

‥‥多田敷刑事の。
Detective Goodman, that is.

<Ema>
え‥‥
どういうコトですか？
Huh?
What do you mean?

<Gumshoe>
《ＳＬ９号事件》の担当捜査官は、
被害者の多田敷　道夫だったッス。
Detective Goodman was the
detective in charge of the
SL-9 Incident, see.

<Ema>
じゃ、じゃあ‥‥あの、
飛び出しナイフは‥‥
So, so...
That switchblade knife...

<Phoenix>
被害者自身が、証拠保管庫から
取りだしたもの、なのか‥‥？
The victim took the
knife out of the evidence
locker himself?




<Phoenix>
刑事さん。ほら、これ。
弁護士がつけるバッジですよ。
Detective... here's my
attorney's badge.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥アンタ、会うたびに
見せるッスね、それ。
You show that to me every
time we meet, pal.

男はだまって警察手帳ッス！
Real men show their police
badge. 'Nuff said!

<Ema>
いいなあ。あたしも
早くほしいな、身分証明‥‥
I wish I had a badge...
Even an ID card would be nice...




<Gumshoe>
事件の被害者・多田敷刑事の
ＩＤカードッス。
That's the victim, Detective
Goodman's ID card.

今日び、なんでもカードに暗証番号
‥‥気が休まるヒマがないッス。
These days, everything's 
cards and secret numbers.
I can never relax!

<Phoenix>
それは、イトノコ刑事が
ぽろぽろ落とすからですよ。
That's only because you
always lose your card.

<Gumshoe>
暗証番号もぽろぽろ忘れるッス。
‥‥自分がコワくなるッス。
I always forget my secret
number, too. Scary, huh?

ダレが見たって、自分は自分！
それでいいじゃないッスかッ！
My face should be ID enough!
What's the world coming to!?

<Phoenix>
（開きなおった‥‥）
(Detective Gumshoe, rebel
against the system.)




<Gumshoe>
御剣検事のクルマに、
御剣検事のナイフ‥‥
Found in Mr. Edgeworth's car,
stabbed with Mr. Edgeworth's
knife, huh...

どうして宝月主席検事殿は、
そんなコトをしたッスかねえ‥‥
What would drive Chief
Prosecutor Skye to do
such a thing?

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Gumshoe>
あ。あやや。も、モチロン！
ハンニンは、ベツのニンゲンッス！
W-wait, I didn't mean...
I mean, sure, of course
someone else really did it!

そのハンニンは、まるで‥‥
Someone who must have, um...

御剣検事に、ウラミでも
あるみたいッスねえ‥‥
Someone who must have a 
grudge against Mr. Edgeworth!




<Gumshoe>
お、それ！
Hey, that's it!

御剣検事がもらった
《検事・オブ・ザ・イヤー》ッス！
That's the "King of
Prosecutors" award that Mr.
Edgeworth got recently!

<Phoenix>
授賞式、イトノコ刑事も
出席していたんですか？
Were you at the awards
ceremony, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
そりゃそッス！
自分ももらったッスよ。努力賞。
Of course, pal!
I got an award for diligence,
myself.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥おめでとうございます。
Ah... congratulations.

<Ema>
それにしても、
なんで《盾》なんですか？
I was wondering, why is the
award a shield?

‥‥しかも、割れてるし。
And... why is it broken?

<Gumshoe>
それはモチロン、
ちゃーんと理由があるッス。
Oh, there's a reason.

ええと‥‥‥‥‥‥
また、今度教えてあげるッス。
Erm...
I'll tell you what it
is later.

<Phoenix>
（忘れたらしいな、どうやら）
(Apparently, he's forgotten.)




<Gumshoe>
この写真を、おキョウさんが‥‥
That's the photo that
Ms. Starr took.

<Phoenix>
何か、ココロ当たりありますか？
Anything you can tell us
about it?

<Gumshoe>
スゴいヒトッス。おキョウさんは。
‥‥この自分、１６才の冬‥‥
That Ms. Starr is quite
the lady.

<Gumshoe>
Why, I remember
it was winter... I was 16.

あの事件をしゃべらされたのは、
あのヒトが最初で‥‥最後ッス。
She was the only one who
ever got me to talk about
what happened. 

<Ema>
１６才‥‥あたしと同い年だ。
何があったんだろ。
16... that's how old I am
now! I wonder what happened?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥イトノコ刑事も、
　ムカシは高校生だったんだな）
(I wonder if Detective Gumshoe
wore a trench coat in high
school, too.)




<Gumshoe>
あるイミ‥‥自分の代表作、ッス。
せいいっぱい、やってみたッス。
This is my crowning 
achievement, my masterpiece,
you might say.

それなのに‥‥ゲージュツは
やっぱり、リカイされにくいッス。
But... art is always
misunderstood, pal.

<Ema>
げーじゅつ‥‥
Art...?

<Gumshoe>
授賞式当日も、彼はホコらしげに
おどっていたッスが‥‥
He was dancing proudly
on the day of the awards
ceremony...

式典が終わって、関係者の
出入りが多くなって‥‥
But there were a lot of people
coming and going after the
ceremony...

一時的に、どこかに
持っていかれちゃったッス。
So they took the Blue Badger
away for a while!

<Phoenix>
あれ。そうなんですか。
Really? Why?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥“みっともない”から。
連中、そんなコト言ってたッス。
Oh, they said it was
"shameful" or something like
that.

“みっともない”ッスと！
自分が、いっしょうけんめい‥‥
"Shameful"!
I toiled night and day...

<Phoenix>
（まあ‥‥
　あるイミ、しかたないよな）
(I sympathize with Detective
Gumshoe... but I can see
why they moved it.)




<Gumshoe>
指紋が一致しないかぎり、
開けることはできないッス。
You can't open the lockers
if your fingerprint doesn't
match.

開けることができたら‥‥
５０円！　払うッス。
If you can open it...
they'll give you 50 cents!

<Ema>
‥‥警察にも、ゼッタイの
自信はないもよう、と。
Note: the Police Department
lacks faith in its lock
system.

<Gumshoe>
現に、事件が起こったとき、
保管庫を開けた多田敷刑事が‥‥
After all, Detective Goodman
was stabbed here after opening
his locker...

同じ時間に、検事局で
死体になったワケッスからねえ。
But at the same time he was
found dead over at the
Prosecutor's Office!




<Phoenix>
これ‥‥見ていただけますか。
Could you take a look
at this?

事件当日、この現場に入った
ヒトのＩＤなんですけど。
This is the ID card record of
the people who came in here
on the day of the stabbing.

<Gumshoe>
ああ。ウワサは聞いてるッス。
Ah, I heard the rumors.

事件の時間に保管室に入ったのは、
やっぱり多田敷刑事だった‥‥
So, it was Goodman who
came in here at the time
of the murder...

ああああああああああああああッ！
Whoooooooooah!!!

<Ema>
ど、どうしたんですか‥‥？
Wh-what is it?

<Gumshoe>
こ、こ、こ、こ、こ、こ、こ、こ。
この、２番目の番号‥‥
Th-th-th-th-th-th!
That second number...

<Phoenix>
ま、まさか‥‥
イトノコ刑事のＩＤ、ですか‥‥？
It's not your ID number
is it, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥みつるぎけんじ‥‥
Mr. Edgeworth!

<Ema>
え‥‥
What...?

<Gumshoe>
この、２番目の番号は‥‥
御剣検事のものッスゥゥゥッ！
The second number on this
list...
belongs to Mr. Edgeworth!

<Ema>
え‥‥‥えええええええええッ！
What...
Whaaaaaaaaat!?

< >
証拠品《ＩＤカード使用記録》に
データを追加した。
ID Card Record updated
in the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（御剣が‥‥なぜ、保管室に？）
(Why would Edgeworth have
come to the evidence room!?)




<Gumshoe>
多田敷刑事のメモと、
この飛び出しナイフ‥‥
Detective Goodman's note...
and that switchblade knife.

きっと、イチバン驚いたのは
御剣検事だったッス。
I bet Edgeworth was the most
surprised of anyone.

<Phoenix>
《ＳＬ９号事件》‥‥ですか。
Because of the SL-9 connection?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥２年前。御剣検事が
初めて扱った、大きな事件ッス。
That was Mr. Edgeworth's
first big case you know,
two years ago.

検事の実力を、世間に見せつけた
最初の事件だったッスよ。
That was the first time the
world knew Edgeworth was
a man to be feared!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥その証拠品が、
なぜ、今になって‥‥？
But, why would evidence
from that case turn up now?

<Gumshoe>
やっぱり‥‥まだ。
I guess it's not over, pal.

あの事件は、カタがついてない。
そういうコトッスかねえ‥‥
Maybe there are some loose
ends left on that case...




<Gumshoe>
イッピキの刑事として、
これだけは断言しておくッス！
Allow me to say one thing,
speaking as a detective.

ココロ当たりのないモノには、
断固！　チンモクを守るッス！
If I see a piece of evidence
I know nothing about, I say
nothing! Nothing!

<Phoenix>
か、かまいませんよ、それで。
That's... fine.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥ホッ。
You bet it's fine, pal!




<Phoenix>
‥‥このカケラ‥‥もともとは、
どんなカタチだったのかな。
I wonder what shape these
pieces were in before
whatever it was broke?

<Ema>
ちょっと、試してみましょうか。
ジッサイに作ってみて。
You want to try to put
it back together?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥ハッ！
シロートには、ムリッス。
Hah! Good luck, pal.
That's no job for amateurs.

なんせ、この自分が３時間かけても
歯が立たなかったッスからね！
Why, I spent a good three
hours on that before I had
to give up!

<Ema>
こんなこともあると思って、
ノリを持ち歩いてますからね！
That's why I always carry
around a tube of glue!

<Phoenix>
（どうやら、これが“底”だ。
　‥‥組み立ててみよう！）
(Well, this piece looks like 
the bottom. Let's try putting
the rest in place!)




<Phoenix>
‥‥ダメだ！　どう考えても、
カケラが合わないよ！
It's no use. These pieces
just don't add up to anything!

<Ema>
もしかしたら、カケラが
足りないのかもしれませんね。
Maybe some of the pieces
are missing?

とにかく、できるところまで
やってみましょうよ！
Let's just try to put
as many of the pieces in
place as we can!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥また、あとで
　がんばってみようかな）
(Hmm... maybe I'll give
it another shot later.)




<Ema>
あ、あれ‥‥‥
H-huh?

いちおう、できたみたいだけど‥‥
足りないみたいですね。カケラ。
Well, I think we did it.
But some of the pieces are
missing.

<Gumshoe>
自分も、そこまでなら２分ッス。
モンダイは、そこからッスねえ‥‥
That only took me two minutes
to do!
The problem is finishing it!

<Ema>
‥‥カケラ、
盗まれたんでしょうか？
Were some pieces stolen?

<Phoenix>
それとも‥‥
最初から、足りなかったのかな。
I bet they were missing
to begin with.

<Gumshoe>
それにしても‥‥
Still...

見ていて不安になるほど
不安定なツボ、ッスねえ。
It doesn't look like the
most stable kind of jar.

<Ema>
割れてトーゼン！　みたいな
ふてぶてしさを感じます。
I kind of understand how
it got broken.

< >
証拠品《不安定なツボ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Unstable Jar added
to the Court Record.




<Ema>
‥‥‥！
こ。こんなところに、反応が！
Hey! 
A reaction!

<Phoenix>
犯人がフツウに逃げたとしたら‥‥
こんなところ、さわるハズがない。
If the criminal was running
away normally, you wouldn't
think they'd touch here...

（何か、重要な手がかりになる
　‥‥そう考えるべきだ！）
(This could be a big clue!)

<Gumshoe>
あ、アンタ‥‥
すげェクスリ、持ってるッス！
Hey, pal...
Wow! That's some stuff you
got there!

<Ema>
あ、これですか？
Oh, this?

《ルミノール試薬》って
いうんですよ！
It's called Luminol Testing
Fluid!

<Gumshoe>
どこでッ！　いったい、
どこで売ってるッスかッ！
Where do they sell that??
Where!?

<Ema>
え。
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
自分も買うッス！
I want to buy some, too!

局長に５０００円借りて、
買ってくるッス！
I'll go borrow $50 from
the Chief and buy some now!

<Phoenix>
どこで売ってるの？　これ。
So, where do they sell it?

<Ema>
‥‥さあ。あたし、いつも
通信販売で買ってますから。
Well, I always order mine
through magazine offers...

<Phoenix>
（とりあえず、上面図に
　書きこんでおこう‥‥！）
(Let's mark this spot on
the floor plans, shall we?)




<Ema>
あ‥‥、やっぱり！
これって右手のアト、ですね！
Ah hah! Look!

<Ema>
It's a handprint!
Someone's right hand touched
here!

<Gumshoe>
なんッスとほほおおおおおおおッ！
Whaaaaaaaaaat!?

<Phoenix>
ど、どうしたんですか？
What?

<Gumshoe>
コレ‥‥この、保管庫。
よりによって、自分のッス！
This... this locker!
This is mine!

<Ema>
え。刑事さんの‥‥？
This is your evidence locker,
Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
あ、アンタ！　自分が‥‥
自分がタイホされたときは！
Hey, pal!When they...
When they arrest me I want
you to do me a favor, okay?

ちゃんと証言してほしいッス！
“ニクめないヤツだった”‥‥と！
I want you to testify for me,
pal! Tell 'em I was the kind
of guy everyone liked!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥これは、重要な手がかりだ！
　上面図に書きこんでおこう‥‥）
(This is a major clue!
Let's mark the position
on our floor plans.)

<Gumshoe>
ケーサツは信用できないッス！
ヨロシク証言、たのんだッスよ！
You can't trust those police!
You'll testify for me, right?

<Ema>
刑事さんが言わないでください！
But, you're a police officer,
too, Detective Gumshoe!




<Phoenix>
かなり出血があったみたいだ。
（こんなの、初めて見るぞ‥‥）
Someone lost a lot of blood
here. (I've never seen
anything like this!)

どう思いますか？　イトノコ刑事。
ぼく、シロートですから‥‥
What's your opinion, Detective
Gumshoe? I'm kind of an
amateur in this field...

<Gumshoe>
うーム‥‥‥‥
青白い血‥‥ッスか。
Well...
The blood does look a little
bluish.

多田敷刑事は、もしかしたら‥‥
宇宙人、だったッスかねえ。
Maybe, just maybe...
Detective Goodman was
an alien!?

<Ema>
でも、やっぱり‥‥この保管庫で
事件は起こったんですね。
Whatever the case may be, it
does look like the murder
happened here.

<Phoenix>
いちおう、上面図に
書きこんでおこうか。
Let's mark it on the
floor plans.

<Gumshoe>
自分のスイリは
ほったらかしッスかッ！
So that's it, huh? You're
just going to ignore my
deductions!?




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
証拠保管室／第３号庫
February 23
Evidence Room
Sector Three

<Phoenix>
（さっきの調査で‥‥気になる
　“手のアト”があった）
(Our investigation turned
up a suspicious handprint.)

<Ema>
この、刑事さんの保管庫に
付着した、血痕‥‥ですね。
Here, in this blood on
the detective's evidence
locker.

<Phoenix>
アイツから借りた、新兵器
‥‥試してみよう！
Let's use the secret weapon
we just borrowed!




<Ema>
さあ、始めましょう！
まず‥‥指を選んでください。
Right. Let's get started!
First... choose a finger.

<Phoenix>
ユビ‥‥？
A finger...?

<Ema>
５本それぞれ、指紋のつき方は
ちがうハズですからね。
Each finger leaves behind a
slightly different imprint.

指紋がキレイに残っていそうな
指を選びましょうよ！
So let's choose the finger
that will have left behind the
clearest print!

<Phoenix>
‥‥パッと見た感じ、
ちがいがわからないよ。
I really can't tell the
difference at a glance...

<Ema>
ぐずぐずモンクを言わないで、
さっさと１本、選ぶ選ぶ！
Quit procrastinating and
choose a finger!




<Ema>
よーし。じゃ、いよいよ
指紋の検出に移りますよ！
Okay. Now it's time to
check for prints!

ちょっと、あたしが
やって見せてあげますね。
Let me show you how it's
done.

<Phoenix>
（なんか、イキイキしてきたぞ
　‥‥あかねちゃん）
(Ema's starting to get that
sparkle in her eyes...)

<Ema>
まず、アルミの粉を
よーく、ふりかけます。
First, we sprinkle the
aluminum powder around.

<Phoenix>
え！　ど、どうやって？
Huh? How do you do that?

<Ema>
スクリーンに、トンって
さわれば‥‥ホラ！
Just touch the screen...
See?

<Phoenix>
おお。‥‥ソレっぽいね、なんか。
Ah... it looks like that did
the trick.

<Ema>
アルミ粉は、指紋にカンゼンに
吸着するんです。
The aluminum powder adheres
completely to the print.

いい具合に、アルミ粉を
トントンって、ふりかけたら‥‥
Once the powder is well
spread...

よぶんなコナを
吹きとばしちゃってください。
just blow away the excess.

<Phoenix>
え！　ど、どうやって？
Huh? How do I do that?

<Ema>
ジッサイに、
息を吹きかけるんですよ。
You just blow.
With your breath.

ふーっ、て。‥‥ホラね！
Imagine you're blowing out the
candles on a birthday cake.
See?

<Phoenix>
おお。‥‥楽しそうだね！
（なんか、抵抗があるケド‥‥）
Wow... that looks like fun!
(It might take some getting
used to though...)

<Ema>
大丈夫。　ハナに入ったり
しませんから。
It's fine! It won't go
up your nose or anything.

ほどよくコナをふりかける。
よけいなコナを吹きとばす。
You just pour the powder
on thick, and blow away
the extra!

‥‥指紋検出のキホンです！
Those are the basics of
fingerprinting, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
（やってみるしかないな、
　コレばっかりは‥‥）
(I guess I'd better give it
a try...)




<Phoenix>
（‥‥他の指紋を試してみたいな）
(I think I'd like to try one
of the other fingerprints.)

<Ema>
じゃあ、ベツの“指”に
変えてみましょうか！
Okay, let's move on to a 
different finger!




<Ema>
あ！　やりました！
検出できたみたいですね！
Aha! You did it!
You found one!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥‥コレ。
どう見ても“指紋”じゃないよ。
But...
this looks nothing like a
fingerprint.

<Ema>
う、うーん‥‥
たしかにそうですね。
Hmm... Now that you mention
it, I guess it doesn't...

<Phoenix>
どういうことかな。
What does it mean?

<Ema>
どうやら‥‥‥ハズレだった、
というコトじゃないでしょうか。
It think it means...
we're out of luck.

<Phoenix>
ハズレ‥‥？
Out of luck...?

<Ema>
この“手のアト”のヌシは、
手袋をしていた、ってコトですね。
The person who left this
handprint must have worn
gloves.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ここまでやらせといて、
そりゃないだろう！
Don't tell me we've been
wasting our time here!

<Ema>
まま。こんなもんですよ、
カガク捜査なんて。
Hey, calm down. That's just
the way it goes sometimes with
scientific investigations.

でも‥‥そうですね。
But... it does seem a shame.

せっかくだから、
他の指紋を探してみましょうか。
While we're at it, why don't
we look for other prints?

<Phoenix>
他の‥‥？
Other prints...?

<Ema>
保管庫のトビラを、もう一度
よーく見ると‥‥
Looking at the locker door
again closely...

“血のアト”以外の部分にも、
ユビの跡が残ってますよね？
it seems like there are
fingerprints outside the
bloody handprint as well.

いちばんハッキリ残っている
指紋を検出してみましょう！
Let's see if we can find a
clear print!

<Phoenix>
（“血のアト”以外の、
　ユビの跡、ねえ‥‥）
(Hmm... fingerprints outside
the blood...)




<Ema>
きゃあ！　ウットリするほどに
ミゴトな指紋ですね！
Yay! A print so clear it's
dazzling!

<Phoenix>
う、うっとり‥‥？
D-dazzling...?

<Ema>
それじゃ、セッカク検出した
指紋ですからね。
Anyway, this print took a lot
of effort to find.

さっそく、
《照合》してみましょう！
Let's match it up right
away!

<Phoenix>
まだ、あるんだ。
‥‥いろいろ、タイヘンだなあ。
So we're not done yet?
This is quite a process...

<Ema>
まあ、セッカク
指紋を検出しても‥‥
Well, there's no point in
finding a fingerprint...

持ち主がわからなくちゃ、
イミがないですからねー。
and not knowing who the
owner is, right?

<Phoenix>
（そりゃ、そうか‥‥）
(I guess she's right...)

<Ema>
御剣検事さんからもらった、
関係者の指紋データを見て‥‥
Look at the fingerprint data
we got from Mr. Edgeworth...

指紋のヌシだと思われるヒトを、
ズバリ！　指摘してください！
and point out the person
you think left these prints!

<Phoenix>
え‥‥！　そんなの、
わかるワケないじゃないか。
Huh? How am I supposed to
know who it was?

<Ema>
そんなコトないと思いますよ。
I could make a pretty good
guess.

“血のアト”と合わない以上、
この指紋は事件と無関係です。
The bloody handprint and the
fingerprints are in different
places right?

‥‥と、なれば。
That means that the prints
probably don't have anything
to do with our case.

この保管庫に、イチバン指紋が
残りそうな人物は‥‥？
So, whose fingerprints would
we most likely find on this
evidence locker?




<Phoenix>
（‥‥考えてみよう。
　この指紋の持ち主は‥‥）
(Let me think... who could have
left these prints...?)




<Ema>
‥‥一致しませんでしたね。
Hmm... no match.

<Phoenix>
だって‥‥こんなの、
わかるハズがないよ。
C'mon! How am I supposed to
guess whose they are?

<Ema>
そうでしょうか‥‥
Isn't it obvious?

血痕と位置が合わない以上、
指紋は、事件と無関係ですよね？
The bloody handprint and the
fingerprints are in different
places right?

だとすれば‥‥
That means that the prints
probably don't have anything
to do with our case.

この指紋は、保管庫のヌシのモノで
ある可能性が高いハズです。
They most likely belong
to the owner of this evidence
locker.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
ど、どうしましたか？
S-something wrong?

<Phoenix>
そこまでわかってるのなら、
やってくれればいいのに。
I was just thinking, if you're
so sure who it is, why don't
you match the fingerprints?

<Ema>
成歩堂さんッ！
Mr. Wright!

あたしは、これから先のコトを
思って、わざわざ‥‥
I was doing this for your
benefit, so you'd learn!

<Phoenix>
わわ、わかりました！
F-fine, fine!




<Ema>
やっぱり！
Ah hah!

この指紋、イトノコ刑事さんの
ものだったんですね！
So these prints belonged
to Detective Gumshoe!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
どうしました？　成歩堂さん。
Something wrong, Mr. Wright?

“だからなんだよ”みたいな
カオして。
You gave me this "so what?"
look.

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥“だからなんだよ”って
思ってるからね、ジッサイ。
I guess that's probably 
because I was thinking
"so what?"

<Ema>
まあ。今回はカラぶりでしたけど、
次があるじゃないですか！
Okay, so we came up with
nothing this time, but there's
always next time!

成歩堂さんのトモダチでしょ？
“カラぶり”と“ドシャぶり”は。
Sometimes you hit, sometimes
you miss! 

気にしない気にしない！
You gotta roll with the
punches, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんか、カドの立つ
なぐさめかただなあ。
Thanks for the sympathy.

（でも‥‥たしかに。
　この部屋には、もう１つ‥‥）
(Wait...
If I remember correctly...)

（“手のアト”があった。
　‥‥調べてみよう！）
(there was one other
handprint in this room.
Let's check it out!)




<Phoenix>
たしか‥‥ここに、
ルミノール反応があったよね。
This is where we got a 
luminol fluid reaction,
right?

<Ema>
あ、そうだ！
“手のアト”がありました！
Right! There was a 
handprint here!

じゃあ、じゃあ、
コレ、使ってみますか？
Okay!
Want to try using this?

<Phoenix>
（目つきが変わってる。
　キケンだな‥‥）
(There go her eyes sparkling
again...)



<Phoenix>
‥‥いや。ここはあえて
やめておこうか。
Actually, let's not check.

<Ema>
えー！　なんでですか！
What!? Why not!?

あんまりジラすと、このコナ、
アタマからブチまけますからね！
Try my patience any longer
and I'll dump this powder
over your head!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥早めにとったほうが
　いいかもしれないな‥‥）
(Hmm... maybe I better check
for those prints after all.)




<Phoenix>
‥‥よし。指紋を検出してみよう！
Okay, let's check for
prints!

<Ema>
そう来なくっちゃ！
That's the spirit!

あ！　でも、今回は、
１つ注意しなくちゃ！
Oh! But I have to warn you
about something first.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥？
What?

<Ema>
ここの血のアト、ふきとられて
いたわけですよね？
The area with the blood was
wiped away, right?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ああ。クスリの反応で
見つけたワケだからね。
We only ended up finding it
using chemical means.

<Ema>
つまり‥‥その部分の指紋も、
ふき取られているワケです。
Any prints in that area will
have been wiped away too.

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥そうか。
Oh... right.

じゃあ‥‥“指紋はない”って
コトじゃないか。
So... that means no prints.

<Ema>
そのカクリツは、カガク的に考えて
高いと言わざるを得ませんか？
Would you say the probability
of your hypothesis is high?

<Phoenix>
ぼ、ぼくに聞くなよ！
D-don't ask me!

<Ema>
とにかく。“ふき取られていない”
指紋を探しましょう！
Anyway...
We must try to find prints
that weren't wiped away.

<Phoenix>
（“手のアト”以外に残された
　指紋、か‥‥）
(Prints other than the ones
left by the bloody hand...)




<Phoenix>
こ‥‥この指紋‥‥
Hey, these fingerprints,
they...

<Ema>
だ、ダレですか！
あたしの知ってるヒトですか！
Whose are they? Whose!?
Is it someone I know?

<Phoenix>
ざ‥‥‥‥‥罪門　恭介‥‥！
It's Officer Marshall!!!

<Ema>
え。ざ、罪門さん‥‥？
Huh?
O-Officer Jake Marshall!?

< >
証拠品《罪門の指紋》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Marshall's Fingerprints added
to the Court Record.

<Ema>
そ、そんな！　グーゼンです！
事件とはカンケイありません！
Th-that's got to be
a coincidence! He's
not involved in the crime!

<Phoenix>
‥‥あかねちゃん。
Ema.

これは‥‥イトノコ刑事の指紋とは
決定的に、違うポイントがあるよ。
This are decidedly different
from Detective Gumshoe's
prints.

<Ema>
‥‥！
...!

<Phoenix>
ルミノール反応‥‥血のアトと、
指紋の位置が、一致している。
The luminol reaction. The
blood and the fingerprints
are in the same place.

<Ema>
あ‥‥ああッ‥‥！
Oh... Oh!!!

<Phoenix>
（ふきとられた、血のアト‥‥
　そこに、罪門　恭介の指紋が！）
(So, we have Jake Marshall's
fingerprints...
on a wiped bloodstain!)

<Ema>
罪門さんが、どうして‥‥
But why would Officer
Marshall...

<Phoenix>
どうやら‥‥長かった調査にも、
やっと、コタエが出たみたいだ。
It looks like our
investigation is finally
turning up some results!

<Ema>
‥‥！
...!

<Phoenix>
こういうのを‥‥“決定的な証拠”
っていうんじゃないのかな。
I guess this is what you'd
call "decisive evidence"!

<Ema>
そ、そんな！
罪門さんが‥‥どうして‥‥‥
I... I don't believe it!


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.

