< >
２月２３日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
February 23
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Phoenix>
‥‥ともえさん、
取調べ中らしいね。
Looks like Ms. Skye is
in questioning...

<Ema>
刑事さんに、ドナられてるのかな。
お姉ちゃん‥‥
I hope the detectives aren't
yelling at her...

《検事局と警察局の事件‥‥
　どうやって同時にやったッス？》
"How did you kill him in two
places at the same time!"

‥‥なんて。
Can you imagine?

<Phoenix>
答えにくい質問だよなあ。
なんにしても。
How's she supposed to answer
that!

（そういえば‥‥）
(Wait a second...)

（警察局側の“ハンニン”が
　タイホされたハズだよな‥‥）
(The Chief said they'd caught
the criminal at the
Police Department!)

<Ema>
あとで、また来てみましょう！
Let's come back later!




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors
the visitor's room.

検事局で起きた殺人事件に、
警察局で起きた殺人事件‥‥
One murder at the Prosecutor's
Office... one at the Police
Department...

次はここじゃないかと、
震え上がっている。
He must be frozen with fear
thinking that he might be
next...

<Ema>
勝手なコメント、しない！
Don't scare the poor guy!




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile for the camera...




２月２３日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
February 23
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Ema>
でも‥‥あたし。ほんの
少しだけ、安心しちゃいました。
Still, I do feel
better about things.
A little.

<Ema>
だって、多田敷刑事さんを刺した
ハンニン、つかまったんでしょ？
I mean, they caught the
person who stabbed Detective
Goodman, didn't they?

<Phoenix>
ええと‥‥。まあ、そうなのかな。
Uh, yeah, I guess they did.

（ギロンするのはやめておこう。
　‥‥こんがらがるばかりだ）
(Best to not go too far down
that road right now. Things
will just get confusing.)

< >
キイイィィ‥‥ィィイイ‥‥ンン！
*WHEEEEEEEEEEEEN*

<Ema>
な‥‥、なんですか？　今の‥‥
Wh-what was that!?

<???>
‥‥だから！　本官はあの。
加害者というのはどうかとその！
Sir! That's what I'm saying!
Me, a perpetrator?

‥‥むしろ！　本官はこの。
被害者というべきであるとその！
I-I-I'd say I-I-I was the
perpetrated against, sir!
That's what I'd say!

‥‥あ。ど、どうも！
こんにちはッ！　‥‥であります！
Ah, oh, uh. 
Hi.
Greetings, sir!

<Ema>
あ、あなたは。たしか‥‥
Wait, I know who you are...

<Officer>
スミマセン！　御剣検事ってヒト、
いらっしゃるでありますかッ！
Excuse me! But is
Mr. Edgeworth, uh...
anywhere on the premises?

<Officer>
本官！　警察局長のお使いで本官！
報告書を持ってきたでありますッ！
I'm here, sir, at the 
request of the Chief, sir!
I've got your report, sir!

<Ema>
へえー。おまわりさん、
留置所の看守だったんですか？
Officer Meekins!
So you're a guard here at
the detention center?

<Officer>
いえッ！　本官、アレであります！
子羊のような巡査でありましてッ！
No, sir! I'm not, sir!
I'm a little lost patrolman,
like a little lost lamb, sir!

<Ema>
あ、わかった！　今日は、こっちに
報告書を届けに来たんですね？
Oh, I get it. You're here to
deliver a report?

<Officer>
い。いやその本官。あの。
なんというかこの、本官その。
No, sir, I, uh, how should
I say this...

<Phoenix>
（ま‥‥‥まさか‥‥‥）
(Wait... he isn't... is he?)

もしかして、あなたが‥‥
多田敷　道夫捜査官を？
You... Officer Meekins...
You didn't... did you?

<Officer>
は‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
Err..........

<Meekins>
ハンニンの原灰（はらばい）巡査で
ありますからしてェェェェェェッ！
Perpetrator Officer Meekins
reporting, sir!!!

<Ema>
え‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
What...!?

ええええええええええええええっ！
Whaaaaaaaaat!?

<Phoenix>
（これは‥‥予想外の展開だな）
(Now this is an unexpected
turn of events...)




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors
the visitor's room.

被告人が巡査ということで、明日は
我が身か、と震え上がっている。
Seeing a fellow patrolman
in here must make him worry
about his own fate in life.

<Ema>
勝手なコメント、しない！
No comments from the peanut
gallery!




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile for the camera...

ハラバイ巡査が、ときおり
ビクッ！　と振り返っている。
Poor Officer Meekins...
I think he knows he's
being watched.




<Meekins>
本官！　本来は、総務課の
巡査でありますからしてェェェッ！
Sir! I'm a patrolman with 
General Affairs, sir!
SIR!

<Phoenix>
きき、聞こえてますから、
フツーにおねがいします！
Ow. I can hear you fine,
Officer Meekins.

<Meekins>
‥‥あの日、たまたま用があって
証拠保管室へ行ったところ‥‥
I had some business that
day, sir, and so I went to
the evidence room, sir...

保管室前の警備室が、
カラっぽだったのであります。
The guard office in front of
the room was empty, sir!

<Ema>
つまり‥‥いつもは、保管室は
警備員が見張っているんですね？
So, normally there's a guard
at the evidence room?

<Meekins>
なにぶん証拠保管室は、証拠を
保管しているでありますから。
That's right, sir! Because
evidence is kept in the
evidence room, sir!

保安課の巡査‥‥罪門巡査が
警備を担当しているでありますッ！
Now, the security officer...
was none other than
Officer Marshall!

<Phoenix>
（ざ、ザイモン‥‥？）
(M-Marshall!?)

<Meekins>
それで、本官。ふと警備室の
モニターを見たら‥‥
Then, sir, I happened to
glance at the security
room monitor!

<Meekins>
That's when I saw him, sir!

保管室にその。いわゆる不審者が。
そう！　不審者を見たであります！
A suspicious person in the
evidence room!
A suspicious person, sir!

不審者ッ！
あいててててててててててッ！
A suspicious person!
Yowwowowowowowow!!!

<Phoenix>
（ナニやってんだ、このヒト‥‥）
(What the heck is this
guy doing?)

<Ema>
それで、どうなったんですか？
So what happened then?

<Meekins>
その後は、本官‥‥カーッとこう、
アタマがまっ白になっちまって。
After that, sir, I...
I... everything went white!
I saw red! I blacked out!

‥‥フト気がついたら、今日。
こうして留置所に。
And... when I came to,
I was here. In the detention
center.

<Phoenix>
（長すぎるだろ！
　まっ白の時間が‥‥）
(How long were you out!?
Days!?)

<Ema>
あの‥‥ところで。
その手、どうなさったんですか？
Um, might I ask...
what happened to your hand?

<Meekins>
はッ！　本官。ホータイを
巻いてくれるヒトもいないので！
Sir! There was no one to
bandage me, sir!

自分なりにこう、グルグルとコレ、
巻いてみたのであります！
So I did what I could to
wrap it up, sir!

<Phoenix>
（手に包帯といえば‥‥
　ともえさんといっしょだな‥‥）
(A bandage on his hand...
just like Ms. Skye.)

<Ema>
‥‥どこまでも“同時”ですね。
警察局と、検事局の事件‥‥
Yet another similarity between
this case and the one at the
Prosecutor's Office...

<Phoenix>
とにかく‥‥聞かせてください。
その手のケガについて。
First things first...
tell us how you hurt your
hand!




<Phoenix>
あの。失礼ですけど、
ハンニン‥‥なんですよね。
Um, I don't mean to pry,
but you are the perpetrator,
correct?

多田敷　道夫捜査官を、
証拠保管室で殺害した‥‥
You killed Detective Bruce
Goodman in the evidence
room... right?

<Meekins>
本官を‥‥‥そんなカナしい目で
見つめないでほしいでありますッ！
Sir...
Please don't look at me with
those sad puppy dog eyes, sir!

ヒトを、あえて“被害者”と
“加害者”にくくるとすればッ！
If you have to label me as
persecutor or victim, sir...

さしづめ本官などは
かなり“被害者”のほうに‥‥
Then label me victim!

<Phoenix>
いやいや！　こうして
つかまってるワケじゃないですか。
Um, I would, but you happen
to be in detention. And alive
and well at that.

<Meekins>
は。まあ。たしかに。まあ。
本官アレなんでありますけれども。
Ah, yes, well, that's true,
sir. I suppose you could say
that.

<Phoenix>
被害者の多田敷捜査官とは、
知り合いだったんですか？
Did you know the victim,
Detective Goodman?

<Meekins>
その！　ヒトをあえて“他人”と
“赤の他人”にくくるとすればッ！
Well, sir, if I had to label
him as a "stranger" or a
"total stranger"...

さしづめ本官などは、
“まっ赤”寄りでありましてェェ！
Then I'd say he leans heavily
on the "total stranger" side!

<Phoenix>
つ、つまり‥‥
知らなかったワケですか？
So... you didn't know him?

<Meekins>
本官、日の当たらない部署で
働いているでありますからして。
Sir! I work in a tiny
department, devoid of light
or other creature comforts!

捜査官のカタに、知り合いなど
いないのでありますからして！
I don't know any detectives!

<Ema>
じゃあ‥‥なぜ、知らないヒトを
刺しちゃったんですか？
So, if he was a total
stranger, why did you stab
him?

<Meekins>
だ、だから本官！　殺すつもり
なんて、なかったであります！
Sir! I had n-no intention
of killing him, sir! None!

というか本官！　殺したつもりも
ないのでありますからしてェェッ！
N-nor do I have any
recollection of k-killing
him, sir!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥
　コンランしてるみたいだな）
(At least someone around here
is more confused than I am.)




<Phoenix>
“思い出したこと”‥‥
聞かせていただけますか？
Can you tell me what it is
you do "remember"?

<Meekins>
本官‥‥なにぶん総務課の、迷える
子羊のような巡査でありますから。
Well sir, you might say I'm a
lost little patrolman. A lost
little lamb, if you will!

保管室にいた多田敷捜査官殿は、
存じ上げなかったであります。
I didn't know Mr. Detective
Goodman who was in the
evidence room.

<Phoenix>
だから‥‥“不審者”だと
思いこんだワケですか‥‥
And that's why you thought he
looked suspicious...

<Meekins>
保管室に入った本官は、ＩＤカード
の提示を求めたであります！
Sir, I entered the evidence
room, and asked the man to
display his ID card!

<Ema>
なんだ。やるべきコト、
キチンとやってるじゃないですか！
Well, that sounds pretty
much by the book so far.

<Meekins>
そ、そうなんであります！　本官！
それが言いたかったであります！
Th-that's right, sir!
That's what I've been trying
to tell you!

<Phoenix>
それで‥‥ＩＤの提示を求められた
多田敷捜査官は？　どうしました？
So you asked Detective Goodman
to show his ID card. What
did he do?

<Meekins>
なんとッ！　いきなり、本官に
ナイフを向けたであります！
That's the thing! Suddenly
he pointed a knife at me!

<Ema>
え‥‥！
What...!?

<Meekins>
本官。もう、ナニがなんだか
わからなくなって。
Sir, I assure you I was as
flustered as you are right
now!

奇声を上げて、飛びかかって
いっちゃったであります！
So I whooped and leapt
at him!

<Phoenix>
（多田敷捜査官が‥‥
　ナイフを向けてきた？）
(Detective Goodman pointed
a knife at him?)

<Meekins>
『やられる前に、やれ！』‥‥
原灰家の家訓でありますからして！
"Do unto to others before
they do unto you"!
My own father's words, sir!

<Ema>
そ。それから、どうなりました！
Wh-what happened then?

<Meekins>
それから‥‥
Well...

本官。アタマがまっ白になって。
気がついたら、ここに。
My eyes, sir... everything
went white.
When I awoke, I was here.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Right...)




<Phoenix>
その、手‥‥やっぱり、
事件があったときに？
And your hand... that happened
when Detective Goodman was
stabbed?

<Meekins>
まあそのコレ本官ンンンンッ‥‥‥
‥‥ジツは、そうでありまして。
Well! You see, sir, 
I, er...

<Ema>
ダメじゃないですか！
ちゃんと、自首しなくちゃ。
Don't you think you
should just confess?

<Meekins>
だって！　本官、でも。だって！
しかたなかったでありますッ！
But, sir! Sir! But!
There was nothing I could do!

<Phoenix>
しかたなかった‥‥？
"Nothing you could do"...?

<Meekins>
じつは本官、アレ！
アレであります本官からしてッ！
Sir, to tell the truth,
sir, when it happened...

捜査官殿にナイフを向けられて、
“わー”ってなっちゃって。
When the detective pointed
that knife at me, I just
hollered, sir!

気がついたら、キゼツ
していたのであります！
And the next thing I knew,
I was unconscious!

<Phoenix>
き、キゼツ‥‥
The next thing you knew
you were... huh?

<Meekins>
そして、本官。同僚の巡査に
たたき起こされたでありますが‥‥
Then, when I opened my eyes...

保管室には、ダレもいなかった！
本官、なんとヒトリぽっち！
I was alone in the evidence
room, sir! All alone!

多田敷捜査官殿は‥‥
消えたのでありますからしてェッ！
Alone, because...
Because Detective Goodman
had disappeared!!!

<Ema>
えええッ！
What!?

<Meekins>
フト気がつけば、手ェから
どくどく血がコレ本官！
Then when I looked down,
I was gushing blood from
my hand, sir!

さみしかったでありますッ！
‥‥本官、ジツにコレッ！
Oh, the shock! Oh, the
sorrow, sir! Can you
imagine how I felt?

<Phoenix>
（被害者の死体が‥‥
　“消えた”‥‥？）
(The victim's body...
disappeared...?)

<Ema>
‥‥ううん。
ビミョーな話ですねえ‥‥
Hmm...
That's some story.




<Ema>
ケッキョク‥‥ハラバイさん、
どうしてタイホされたんですか？
So, Officer Meekins, why was
it that they arrested you?

<Phoenix>
どういうこと？　あかねちゃん。
What do you mean, Ema?

<Ema>
ちょっと、情報を
整理してみましょうよ。
Let's look at what we know.

ハラバイさん、多田敷さんのカオを
知らなかったんですよ。そして‥‥
Now, Officer Meekins didn't
know Detective Goodman...

現場で会った“被害者”は、
ＩＤを提示してくれなかった。
And the "victim" whom he met
at the scene of the crime
didn't show his ID card.

<Phoenix>
つまり‥‥それが“ホンモノ”
だったかどうか、わからない‥‥
In other words, we have no
way of knowing if the victim
was really the victim!

<Ema>
それに、死体が証拠保管室から
“消えた”ってコトは‥‥
And if this "body" just
"disappeared" from the
evidence room...

そもそも、ホントに死んだのか
どうかもわからないハズです！
We don't even know if anyone
actually died!

<Meekins>
そう！　それ、本官。それ！
それを言いたかったであります！
That's it, sir! That!
That's what I wanted to say!

‥‥っていうか、それに近いコトを
言ってみたであります。
That is... I did say
something along those
lines.

<Ema>
え！　‥‥でも。結果的に、
ここにいるワケですよね。
Huh?
But you still ended up
here...?

<Meekins>
本官。言われちゃったであります。
なんでも、あの日。あの時間‥‥
They told me that it had to be
him, sir.
"On that day, at that time...

多田敷捜査官殿が証拠保管室に
入ったのは、マチガイないとか。
Detective Goodman was
definitely in the evidence
room." That's what they said.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥あなたのキオクは
ハッキリしないんでしょう？
But... you don't remember
the events clearly?

<Meekins>
でも‥‥ハッキリ。
映っていたでありますからねェ‥‥
No... but the video tape
is quite clear.

<Ema>
え。“映っていた”‥‥？
Huh? Video tape...?

<Meekins>
防犯カメラであります。
From the security camera.

本官のニクむべき犯行が、すべて！
録画されていたでありますッ！
The crime, my crime, the crime
I swore to stamp out! It's
there! It's me! It's on tape!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Meekins>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
それを先に言ってくださいッ！
And you wait until now
to tell us this!?

<Meekins>
ハッ！　本官、その。アレ。
メンボクないでありますからして！
I'm sorry, really sorry, sir!
I'll hand over my badge!
I don't deserve it!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥とにかく、
　現場を調べないとな）
N-no thanks, I have my own.
(Well, guess we'd better go
check out the crime scene.)




<Phoenix>
ハラバイさん。
これ、なんですけど。
Officer Meekins, have a look
at this.

<Meekins>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

それで。本官に。
本官に、勝ったつもりですかッ！
Go ahead, sir, laugh!
Laugh at me, sir!

<Phoenix>
え‥‥‥
Ha ha... huh?

<Meekins>
ヨコの女の子と“オソロイ”だと。
こう言いたいワケですかッ！
I know what you want to say!
You're going to tell me how
she has one just like it!

<Ema>
あ‥‥あたしですか？
M-me? Why would I...?

<Meekins>
どーせ本官。“オソロイ”のお守り
を持ってくれる女の子なんて本官。
I know, sir, I know.
I'm the only one without a
girl with matching badges!

どこにも、いないであります！
それが、いけないコトですかッ！
Nowhere! I'm alone! All alone!
Is that so wrong!?

アオいハルが青春だなんて、本官。
決して認めないでありますッ！
Life isn't all about high
school sweethearts and
youthful romance, sir!

<Phoenix>
（“オソロイ”って‥‥
　バッジ、のコトか？）
(Is he talking about those
badges on her coat?)

<Ema>
‥‥ふふん。
Hmph.

<Phoenix>
（弁護士バッジと
　いっしょにしないでほしいな）
(I'd like to think there's a
difference between my badge
and a fashion accessory...)




<Ema>
あの‥‥これ。
見ていただけますか？
Um... do you think you could
take a look at this?

<Meekins>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
あ、ソレッ！
...
Hey!

ソレであります！　ソレ、本官。
ソレでありますからしてェェェッ！
That's it, sir! That's it!
That's it!!!

<Ema>
な‥‥ナニ。なんですか！
That's what!?

<Meekins>
今、このシュンカンまで‥‥本官の
アタマ、まっ白でありました！
My head was a blank until
this very moment!

しかし、すべて本官！　ここに今、
本官。思い出したでありますッ！
But, sir, now I remember!
I remember, sir!

<Phoenix>
“思い出した”‥‥って、
事件のコト、ですか？
You mean you remember
what happened?

<Meekins>
そうです！　いわゆる本官、
ソイツのせいで、こんな目にッ！
Correct! That card, that
card was the cause of it all!

<Ema>
この、ＩＤカード‥‥ですか？
This... ID card?

<Meekins>
そうであります！
ジツに、そうなのであります！
Exactly, sir!
That's exactly it!

ある種、そう言わざるを得ない
のでありますからしてェェェェッ！
Nothing could be more
exact, sir! Nothing!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥詳しく
　聞いてみたほうがよさそうだな）
(I'd better pry into this
one a little deeper.)




<Phoenix>
ハラバイさん、コレなんですけ
Officer Meekins, this
is for you!

<Meekins>
きゃあああああッ！
ナイフ、コワいであります本官ッ！
Eeeek!
I-I'm scared of knives, sir!

<Phoenix>
だ、大丈夫ですよ。
見てもらいたいだけですから
It's okay, I just wanted
you to take a look at it.

<Meekins>
コレ本官！　ゆうべも本官！
アレでありまして本官ッ！
That's it, sir! Last night,
sir! That's the one!

本官がリンゴになって、つるつる
カワをむかれるユメを‥‥
I was an apple, sir, in my
dream, sir, and I was...
I was being peeled!

<Ema>
‥‥スミマセン。
もう、いいです。
On second thought, you don't
have to look at the knife.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ヒドい目にあったんだろう。
　しかたないな‥‥）
(Hmm... He's overreacting to
the knife, but I guess he's
been through a lot.)




<Meekins>
アレ。なんでありますか？
‥‥コレ。
Hey! Why do you have that?
That's...

<Phoenix>
あの日の、同じ時間。
検事局で撮影された写真です。
From the day... It was
taken at the Prosecutor's
Office.

<Ema>
トランクから、多田敷さんの
死体が見つかったんですけど‥‥
The day that Detective 
Goodman's body was found 
in the trunk...

<Meekins>
‥‥と、するとコレ。
コレ、つまりヤッパリ本官‥‥
So this means...

本官、ヤッパリ！　ウスウス！
ムジツだったのでありますねッ！
This means I'm a free man!
Innocent!

<Meekins>
ああ‥‥コレが、ユメならば‥‥
If this is a dream, sir...

コレがユメならば、いつまでも
さめないでほしいでありますッ！
Then I hope I never wake up!

<Phoenix>
（コレがユメなら、
　さっさとさめてくれえ‥‥）
(If this is a dream you'd
better wake up right now!)




<Phoenix>
ハラバイさん。
コレ、なんですけど‥‥
Officer Meekins, could you
take a look at this?

<Meekins>
あ。もう。ダメ、本官。
ゼンゼンわからないであります！
I'm sorry, sir, really sorry,
but I have no idea what
that is.

それはもう。御剣検事殿にでも
聞いてほしいでありますッ！
Maybe you should ask 
Mr. Edgeworth, sir?

<Ema>
‥‥なんか、コシの低い
“お役所シゴト”みたいですね。
He's passing the buck,
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
御剣にシゴトをタライ回すなんて、
なかなか大物だよなあ。
It takes a special kind of
man to pass the buck to 
Edgeworth...




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
上級検事執務室・１２０２号
February 23
High Prosecutor's Office
Room 1202

<Ema>
‥‥今日もシャレてますね。
Well, this place is certainly
tidy today.

<Phoenix>
きっと、明日も
シャレてるんじゃないかな。
And it will be tidy tomorrow,
too.

そんなことより‥‥
いないぞ、アイツ。
Incidentally, 
he's not here.

<Ema>
きっと、元気に
捜査してるんですよ！
I'm sure he's off doing
important investigations!

<Phoenix>
それならいいけど、ね。
I hope that's what he's doing.

<Ema>
‥‥‥？
...?

<Phoenix>
（とにかく‥‥あとで、
　また来てみよう）
(I guess we'll have to
come back.)




<Ema>
ひゃあ！
Whoa!

すごいながめですねー。
１２階でしたっけ。ここ。
What a view! It must be
nice to have an office on
the 12th floor.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥なんか、
エラくなった気分になるね。
I guess you would feel...
important.

<Ema>
‥‥ちなみに。
Incidentally...

ここから飛び降りたとき、地面に
激突するときのスピードは‥‥
Were you to jump out this
window, the speed at the time
of impact would be...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

出ましたっ！
時速１１３．８キロメートルです！
Got it!
Approximately 70.71 miles
per hour!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥だから、なんなんだ）
(That's handy to know...)




<Phoenix>
シゴト机だ。さすが、
キレイに片づいているなあ。
A work desk. It's quite
tidy, as one might expect.

<Ema>
いいですねー、この机。
使いやすいけど、オシャレで。
What a nice desk! Easy to
use, and easy on the eyes!

カオが映るほど、よーく
みがきこんでありますよ。
It's polished so high I can
see my own reflection.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なぜだろう。イトノコ刑事の
　カオが浮かんだぞ‥‥）
(Strange... Why did I just
picture Detective Gumshoe?)

<Ema>
あのネームプレート、おみやげに
持って帰ろうかなあ。
Maybe I'll take that name
plaque as a souvenir.

<Phoenix>
やめたほうがいいよ。起訴される。
Don't. He'll sue you.




<Ema>
うわあ‥‥これ、ゼンブ
事件のファイルですか！
Whoa! These are all case
files!?

天井まで、ギッシリ詰まってます！
ハシゴもついていますね。
They're stacked up to the
ceiling! There's even a 
ladder...

<Phoenix>
‥‥おかしいな。アイツ、
地震がニガテなはずだから‥‥
Odd...

こんな危なっかしい本棚を
使うとは思えないんだけど。
I thought Edgeworth wasn't
good with heights.

<Ema>
だいじょうぶです！
He must have someone get
them for him.

<Ema>
ものすごく大きなボルトで、カベに
メリこむほど固定されています！

<Ema>
すごいパワーだなあ。
御剣検事さんがやったのかなあ。

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なぜだろう。イトノコ刑事の
　カオが浮かんだぞ‥‥）
(Strange... Why did I just
picture Detective Gumshoe?)

<Phoenix>
でもさ。地震が起こったら、
部屋中にファイルの雨が降るね。

<Ema>
だいじょうぶです！
He must study these case
reports so closely...
He's so cool!

<Ema>
ギュウギュウに詰まってますから、
ちょっとやそっとじゃ抜けません！

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
You wouldn't say that if you
saw him sweating bullets
up on that ladder.

<Phoenix>
やっぱり、なんか
おかしくない？　それ。




<Ema>
あ。チェスボードがありますよ！
Hey, a chessboard!

<Phoenix>
チェスはよくわからないけど‥‥
追いつめられてるね。青いコマが。
I'm not too up on my chess
but it looks like Blue's
in a bit of a tight spot.

<Ema>
赤いナイトたちが、よってたかって
青いポーンを取りかこんでいます。
The Red Knights have
surrounded the Blue Pawn...

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうこと？
Huh?

<Ema>
“ナイト”は“剣を持った騎士”
“ポーン”は“歩兵”です。
Those horses are mounted
knights. Their swords have
really sharp "edges!"

<Ema>
And check out that poor pawn,
his head is kind of spiky...
Kind of reminds me of you.

<Phoenix>
赤い“剣”が、青い“歩”を
追いつめている‥‥

<Ema>
御剣検事さん、チェス好きかあ。
‥‥どうしました？　成歩堂さん。
Mr. Edgeworth must be an
avid chess player!
What's wrong, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（気のせいだよな、きっと）
(Edges... surrounding a pawn
with spiky hair...
Nah... It's nothing.)




<Ema>
きゃあ、カワイイ！
ステキなティーセットですよ！
Oooh! Cute!
What a pretty tea set!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼく、ティーバッグ派だから。
I go more for the instant
tea bags myself.

<Ema>
すごい！　下のタナに、茶葉と缶が
ギッシリ詰まってます！
Amazing! The drawer below
is filled with packets of
tea leaves!

産地別にキチンと並んでますよ。
フレバリーも、種類ごとに！
They're all sorted by place of
origin and flavor!

お。このロイヤル、ミゴトなまでに
暴力的なブレンディングです！
Look at this Royal blend!
What an exquisitely splendid
concoction! 

<Phoenix>
（‥‥シュミって、なんでも
　奥が深いものなんだなあ‥‥）
(There's such a thing as
taking a hobby too far.)




<Ema>
わあ。ゴーカな花ですねェ。
御剣検事さんに、ピッタリ！
My, my, my!
What an amazing bouquet!

<Phoenix>
たしかにね。‥‥あ。
カードが添えてあるぞ。
No kidding. Hey, there's
a card on it...

‥‥《起死回生　　　カオル》
"Back from the Dead -- Wendy"

（“カオル”‥‥
　どこかで聞いたような）
("Wendy?"...
I've heard that name
somewhere before.)

<Ema>
となりにあるのは‥‥
巨大なトノサマンですっ！
And here beside it...
A giant Steel Samurai!

うわ、ほしいなあ。
御剣検事さん、マニアなのかなあ。
Wow, I want one!

<Phoenix>
イヤだな、それ。‥‥あ。
足のウラ、何か書いてあるぞ。
Huh? There's something
written on the bottom
of his foot.

‥‥《青息吐息　　　カオル》
"Between a rock and a
hard place. -- Wendy"

<Ema>
カオルさんって‥‥御剣検事さんの
フィアンセ、ですか？
Wendy? Is she Mr. Edgeworth's
fiancee?

<Phoenix>
‥‥たぶん、ちがうと思うよ。
Um... I don't think so.




<Ema>
さすが、御剣検事さん。
ふかふかですよ、ソファ！
Mr. Edgeworth has such a
comfy sofa!

<Phoenix>
こんなリッパなソファ、
座った瞬間に眠くなるよ。
Sofas like this make me want
to curl up and take a nap.

<Ema>
きっと、夜おそくまで
資料を調べて、つかれきって‥‥
I bet he pours over his case
files here until the wee hours
of the morning...

上着をぬいで、シャツのソデなんか
オシャレにまくっちゃって。
Then he takes off his jacket,
rolls up his sleeves...

ウデまくらで、ついウトウト
寝ちゃうんですよねー。
And goes to sleep using his
arms as a pillow!

<Phoenix>
（彼女の目には、見えている
　らしいな‥‥オソロシイことに）
(I don't believe it. She's
actually daydreaming about
Edgeworth working...)

<Ema>
寝グセや、ホッペにソファの
カドのアトがついちゃって。
I bet in the morning he has
sofa hair, and little creases
in his cheek from the seams!

‥‥カッコいいなあ。
He's so cool!

<Phoenix>
‥‥カッコいいかあ？
Sofa-hair is cool!?




<Ema>
うわ！　なんか、いちだんと
ヒラヒラした服ですよ！
Wow! This jacket is even
lacier than his usual ones!

いわゆる“勝負服”かな。
御剣検事さんの！
This must be his lucky
trial jacket!

<Phoenix>
勝負服、ねえ‥‥。
ぼくは見たことないけどな。
Lucky jacket, right...
I've never seen him wear it.

<Ema>
額に入れてかざっちゃって。
ナニか“いわく”がありそう！
I'm sure there's a story
behind why it's in a frame!

ちょっとシツレイして。
写真、撮っちゃお！
Maybe I'll be naughty...
and take a picture!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ。
　コーフンぎみだな‥‥）
(She's getting way too
excited about this.)




<Ema>
せっかくもらったのに、
ほったらかしですね。
He won such a prestigious
award. Why would he just leave
it on the couch?

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥トノサマンを
置いておくよりはいいと思うけど。
Better this than that giant
Steel Samurai.

（そういえば‥‥アイツ、
　ムカシからそうだったな）
(Edgeworth has always been
like that.)

<Ema>
え！　なんですか？
メモしますから、教えてください！
Really? Hey, I should write
this down. Tell me what he was
like as a kid!

<Phoenix>
アイツ、小学生のころ、やたら
いろんな賞をもらってたんだよ。
Back in elementary school, he
won awards for all kinds of
things.

弁論大会とか、論文とか、
フルートとか、ゴルフとか。
Speech contests, essays,
playing the flute, golf
tournaments...

<Ema>
‥‥どことなく、小学生っぽくない
ラインナップですね。
That doesn't exactly sound
like typical elementary school
stuff.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥アイツ自身は、
賞をもらうのがキライだったんだ。
But he always hated receiving
awards. He'd make some smart
remark like,

<Edgeworth>
「自分が歩いてきた道ならば、
　自分自身が知っているのだよ」
"I know the path I've walked.
No one else needs to tell me."

<Phoenix>
‥‥とか、なんとか。
That's how he's always been.

<Ema>
ちょっぴり、ハラ立ちますね。
Kind of gets under your skin,
doesn't it?




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
上級検事執務室・１２０２号
February 23
High Prosecutor's Office
Room 1202

<Bellboy>
‥‥おや。
これはシツレイいたしました。
Ah, guests!
My apologies.

<Phoenix>
あ！　あなたは‥‥！
Oh! It's you!

<Bellboy>
どこかでお会いしましたか？
Have we met somewhere...?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥‥！
Huh!?

<Bellboy>
それでは、シツレイいたします。
‥‥御剣さま。
Mr. Edgeworth!
I beg your leave. So long!

<Phoenix>
（御剣‥‥いるのか？）
(Is Edgeworth here...?)

<Ema>
あ。窓辺でたたずんでますよ！
ティーカップを片手に。
There, standing by the
window, a teacup in his hand!

<Edgeworth>
キミか‥‥
Ah, it's you.

<Phoenix>
（コイツ‥‥ホテルから紅茶を
　持ってこさせているのか‥‥）
(He has the hotel bring
him tea service!?)

<Ema>
御剣検事さん‥‥
地方検事局の、査問会から？
Mr. Edgeworth... you're
back from the District
Prosecutor's Office inquiry?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そのとおり。
Precisely.

<Phoenix>
そういえば‥‥
イトノコ刑事が探してたぞ。
By the way, Detective
Gumshoe was looking 
for you.

<Edgeworth>
ああ‥‥そういえば。
情報を持ってきてくれたようだ。
Oh yes... He brought me
some information, it seems.

<Ema>
え！　役に立つんですか？　それ。
Really? Was it helpful?

<Edgeworth>
この近くに、うまいフランス料理の
レストランがオープンするようだ。
Apparently, a new French
restaurant is opening
near here.

‥‥刑事の、せいいっぱいの
なぐさめ、なのだろう。
I think he was trying to
console me, somehow.

<Phoenix>
（御剣‥‥いちおう
　ウラだぞ、そっち側は‥‥）
(Er, I think the report is on
the other side, Edgeworth...)

<Ema>
御剣検事さん‥‥タマシイが
抜けちゃったみたいですね‥‥
Poor Mr. Edgeworth...
I think this whole thing is
really taking a toll on him.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥ところで、あかねさん。
主席検事から、うかがったのだが。
By the way, Ema.
The Chief Prosecutor wanted
to know something...

<Ema>
は、はいッ！
お。お姉ちゃんですか？
M-my sister?
What?

<Edgeworth>
今も、目指しているのだろうか。
その‥‥科学捜査官を。
You still working on that
scientific investigation?

<Ema>
はいっ！　もちろんです！
Huh? Y-yes! Of course!

今日だって、成歩堂さんと
コレを使って‥‥
Why, just today Mr. Wright
and I were using this...

<Edgeworth>
ルミノール試薬‥‥か。
Luminol testing fluid... Hm?

それならば‥‥
これも使ってみるといい。
Well then...
You might have use for this.

<Ema>
指紋をとるための
“アルミ粉”‥‥ですか！
Aluminum powder for taking
fingerprints!

<Edgeworth>
吸着をよくするために、
化学処理がほどこされている。
It's been chemically treated
for better adhesion.

<Ema>
い。いいんですか？
あたしたち‥‥“テキ”ですけど。
F-for me? Are you sure?
We are the "enemy" you know.

<Edgeworth>
今日の私に、捜査の指揮権はない。
‥‥好きにさせてもらうさ。
I've no say in today's
investigation... do as
you will.

<Phoenix>
御剣‥‥
Edgeworth... I'm really--

<Edgeworth>
礼は無用だ。
No need to thank me.

関係者の指紋データといっしょに
持っていきたまえ。
Here, take your powder and
these fingerprint files
for everyone involved.

<Phoenix>
い、いや。なんていうか‥‥
（イトノコ刑事にも貸してやれよ）
I, uh, th-thanks!
(How about giving these to
Detective Gumshoe as well!?)

< >
御剣から《指紋検出用具》と
関係者の指紋データを受け取った。
Fingerprinting Set and
fingerprint file received.

<Ema>
じゃあ‥‥最後に、もう一度！
調べてみましょうよ！
Well, let's get going!
One last investigation!

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうだね。
Right!

（たしか‥‥どこかで、気になる
“手のアト”を見たよな‥‥）
(I do seem to remember seeing
a suspicious handprint
somewhere...)




<Phoenix>
それで‥‥どうだったんだ？
査問会ってヤツは‥‥
So, how did the inquiry
committee go?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥どうやら、彼らは
認めることにしたようだ。
Actually, they decided to
treat this not as a case of
concealing evidence...

今回の一件は“証拠品の隠匿”では
ない。“捜査上の連絡ミス”だと。
But as a communications
error during the 
investigation.

<Ema>
“いんとく”‥‥
"Concealing evidence"...?

<Edgeworth>
この私が、証拠品をかくした‥‥
彼らは、そう信じていたようだ。
Yes. Apparently, there are
some who believe...
that I concealed evidence.

最後に警告されたよ。
『今回もイノチ拾いしたようだな』
They gave me a warning.
"You were lucky this
time... again."

<Phoenix>
今回“も”‥‥？
"Again"...?

<Edgeworth>
そのセリフを聞くのは、
もう何度目になるだろうか。
I've heard them say that so
many times.

２年前の、あの事件から‥‥な。
Ever since that case two
years ago...




<Phoenix>
明日の法廷は大丈夫なのか？
Are you okay for the
trial tomorrow?

<Edgeworth>
とりあえず、担当検事を
つづけることになった。しかし‥‥
Well, I'm still the presiding
prosecuting attorney.
However...

<Phoenix>
何か‥‥あったみたいだな。
Something happened?

<Edgeworth>
捜査の指揮権を、
警察局側に移された。
They gave control of the
investigation over to the
Police Department.

<Ema>
‥‥どういうことですか？
The Police Department!

<Edgeworth>
この事件は今後、巌徒局長の
指揮下で捜査が進められる。
Yes. Any further investigation
for this case will be directed
by the Chief of Police Gant.

私は、その結果を待つこと以外
‥‥何もできないのだ。
I can do nothing but wait
for his results...

<Phoenix>
そう‥‥なのか。
I... see.

<Edgeworth>
なぜ‥‥だ！
Why, I ask you? Why!?

私は、信じる道を歩んできた。
恥じるコトなどない！
All along, I've done only what
I believe is right. I have
nothing to be ashamed of!

それなのに‥‥
But still...

<Phoenix>
（かなりマイってる
　みたいだな‥‥）
(Wow, I've never seen him
this out of sorts...)




<Edgeworth>
《ＳＬ９号事件》‥‥
凶悪な連続殺人事件だった。
The SL-9 Incident was a
heinous serial killing
case.

捜査責任者は、当時、警察局副長
だったオトコ。‥‥巌徒　海慈。
The head of investigation
was the Deputy Chief of
Police at the time...

<Edgeworth>
Damon Gant.

<Phoenix>
（あのオジサン‥‥２年前は、
　捜査に関わっていたのか‥‥）
(That wacky old coot was
involved in the case two
years ago too then...)

<Edgeworth>
最も優秀な捜査官との、初シゴト
‥‥私も多少、舞い上がっていた。
He was the best we had, and
it was my first time working
with him... I was nervous.

<Ema>
御剣検事さんでも、
そんなコトがあるんですね。
Wow, you get nervous, too,
Mr. Edgeworth?

<Phoenix>
（それより、局長が“捜査官”
　のほうが意外だな‥‥）
(What I want to know is why
was a Deputy Chief of Police
on the investigation?)

<Edgeworth>
たしかに‥‥いつもより、
多少は強引な手を使った。
In truth, I used slightly
more... extreme methods
than normal.

相手は危険なサツジン犯だ。
野放しにするなど、私がユルさぬ。
We were dealing with a vicious
murderer. If I let him go, the
blood would be on my hands.

その結果、有罪判決が下って‥‥
ハンニンは処刑された。
We won our guilty verdict, and
the killer was executed.

<Phoenix>
‥‥まさか、おまえ‥‥
Wait, you didn't...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥バカな！
証拠に手など加えていない。
Of course not!
I didn't touch the evidence.

たしかに私は、判決のためならば
あらゆる手段を使う。
Yes, I will do anything in my
power to win a trial.

しかし‥‥
私自身のルールは存在するのだ。
However...
I do have a code, and I follow
it faithfully.




<Phoenix>
御剣。これ、なんだけど‥‥

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

キミのことだ。すでに
情報はつかんでいるのだろう。
I know you. You've probably
got a hold of some information
already, right?

<Phoenix>
《ＳＬ９号事件》‥‥おまえが
関わった事件、なんだよな。
It all has to do with that
case you were on... the SL-9
Incident.

この事件のせいで‥‥
“黒いギワク”に包まれた、とか。
And some "dark suspicion"
you were wrapped up in.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥キミは、私の最悪の記憶を
蘇らせたオトコだ。
You are the man who revived
the worst memory of my life,
as I recall.

いつか、話すことに
なるだろうとは思っていた。
I figured I'd be telling you
about this sooner or later.

<Phoenix>
（あの‥‥エレベータの事件、か）
(A bad memory... he's talking
about the murder in the
elevator...)

じゃあ、御剣。聞かせてくれ。
ホントのところを。
Okay, Edgeworth. Why don't
you tell me about it.
Tell me the truth.




<Phoenix>
あ‥‥そうだ！
これだけは、たしかめないと。
Oh, right! I'd better 
check this now...

<Edgeworth>
だから、私は‥‥
As I was saying, I...

！　それは‥‥
ＩＤカードの使用記録、か。
! What's this?
A record of ID card usage?

<Phoenix>
おまえ‥‥あの日、
証拠保管室に入ってるみたいだな。
Edgeworth, you went into
the evidence room that day,
didn't you?

しかも。あの事件が起きる
少し前に、だ。
Just before the incident
occurred, no less.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥ああ。たしかにな。
Yes, that's true.

<Ema>
ど、どうしてですか‥‥
御剣検事さん？
W-why, Mr. Edgeworth?

<Edgeworth>
そ、そんな目で
見つめないでいただきたい！
Please don't look at
me like that.

ただ‥‥たのまれただけだ。
巌徒局長に。
I... was asked to go.
By Chief Gant no less.

<Ema>
局長さん‥‥？
The Chief of Police...?

<Edgeworth>
半年前に解決した事件の
証拠品だ。
He wanted evidence for a 
case that wrapped up half a
year ago.

検事局のオフィスで保管して
おいてほしい、と言われた。
He told me he wanted me to
keep it here in the 
Prosecutor's Office.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥もう、解決したんだろ？
保管庫にあった、ってコトは。
But... it was solved, right?
It would have to be if the
evidence was already filed...

<Edgeworth>
巌徒局長は、自分の考えを
セツメイしたがらないからな。
The Chief is never one to
explain himself.

とにかく‥‥事件の日、私は
これを持って、ここへ戻ってきた。
In any case, on the day of
the stabbings, I brought this
back here.

<Ema>
あの！　ちなみに、
どんな事件なんですか？　それ。
Can I ask what kind of
case it was?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥それは、言えない。
I... can't say.

さすがに、今回の事件とは
カンケイないからね。
It really has nothing to
do with the current case.

<Phoenix>
（そう言われると、気になる。
　いちおう、記録しておこう）
(Now I'm curious about this
other case. I'd better make
a note of it.)

< >
無関係の証拠品《ドライバー》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
Unrelated evidence:
Screwdriver added 
to the Court Record.

<Edgeworth>
あいかわらず、ガンコなオトコだ。
カンケイないと言ってるのに‥‥
Stubborn as always. I told
you this has nothing to
do with the current case.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

まさか、成歩堂。
担当検事である、この私が‥‥
Wright, please.
I'm the prosecutor on this
case!

キミと事件の話をしながら
お茶を飲むとでも‥‥？
You don't expect me to sit
here and discuss the case
with you over a cup of tea!?

<Phoenix>
いや。お茶はいいんだ。
事件のハナシだけを‥‥
I'll pass on the tea.
Just tell me about the case...

<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　御剣検事さんは、
イキに断ってるんです！
Mr. Wright! Mr. Edgeworth
just told you "no" in a very
polite manner!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Whose side are you on,
anyway?)

（本当に必要なモノだけ、
　鼻先につきつけてやろう）
(Maybe if I just show him my
best evidence I can get
some reaction out of him.)




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
警察署内　刑事課
February 23
Police Department
Criminal Affairs

<Phoenix>
なんか‥‥やっぱり、
殺気立っているなあ。
Wow, everyone looks deadly
serious here...

<Ema>
警察局内で、捜査官が
殺害されちゃったワケですからね。
Well, there was a vicious
murder of a detective
in this department, after all.

<Phoenix>
でも。その多田敷捜査官なら
同時に、検事局の駐車場でも‥‥
Yes, but the same detective
was also killed at the same
time in the Prosecutor's lot.

<Ema>
ううう‥‥この話題、
ヤヤコシイから、キライです。
Ugh...
It makes my head hurt.

<Phoenix>
とりあえず、こっちの現場を
調べたいんだけどなあ。
Well, first things first.
I want to check out the
crime scene here.

<Ema>
なにぶん、殺気立ってますからね。
ヘタしたら、コロされます！
Yes, you sound "dead"-set
on investigating!

<Ema>
But don't mess up, or we
could wind up... dead!

<Phoenix>
‥‥彼らも、これ以上、死体は
増やしたくないんじゃないかな。
I doubt anyone wants more
mysteries or dead bodies
around here right now.

（なんにせよ‥‥ハナシを聞いて
　くれるフンイキじゃないな）
(But... it doesn't look like
anyone's going to help us
much, either.)




<Phoenix>
警察のマスコットキャラクター
‥‥って、こんなんだったっけ？
So this is the police mascot,
is it?

<Chief>
“タイホくん”だよ。
未来の警察のスターさ。
The Blue Badger!
The future star of the
police force!

<Ema>
ちょっとデザインがちがいますね。
‥‥ソトでおどっている子と。
The design's a little changed
from the one outside...

<Chief>
ああ。まだ、試作段階だがね。
《ミスター・ダンシングタイホ》。
Ah, well, the Dancing
Blue Badger(tm) is still
under development, you see.

<Ema>
‥‥なんで、英語なんだろ。
You have it trademarked?

<Chief>
アレはね。少し“今”ふうの
センスを取り入れてみたんだよ。
Absolutely! It's cutting
edge stuff. Very "now."

このぬいぐるみ、ムスメに見せたら
“コワい”と泣かれてしまってね。
I showed this doll here to
my daughter and she burst
into tears!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥あの動くベニヤ板を見たら、
　走って逃げ出すぞ、きっと）
(Don't show her the moving
mock-up outside then, you'll
give her nightmares.)




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of
the detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Police>
“わかった！　ハンニンは
　ドライアイスを使ったのだ！”
"I know! The killer used
dry ice!"

“カンヌキとドアの間に挟めば、
　自動的に密室が完成するのだ！”
"If you put it between the
latch and the door, the
room could be sealed shut!"

‥‥コイツは新しいな。
新人賞はイタダキだろう。
This is good! 
I'll win a writer's
award for sure.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

報告書‥‥じゃなくて、
小説を書いているようだ。
He's not writing a report...
he's writing a novel.




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
That must be the Head
Detective.

‥‥パソコンの画面を、
食いいるように見つめている。
He's glued to his computer
screen.

<Chief>
なにぃ‥‥！
“証拠保管室で、捜査官が殺害”
Wha...!?
"Detective killed in the
evidence room"!

“警察局外には、ゼッタイ
　情報をもらさないこと”だと？
"Tell no one outside the
Police Department"!?

しまった！　定食屋のオバチャンに
ゼンブしゃべっちまったぞ！
Nooo! I told that old lady
at the restaurant everything!

<Phoenix>
（ナニやってんだよ‥‥）
(Someone's getting a 
demotion...)




<Phoenix>
婦人警官がビシッと
敬礼している。
A poster of a female
police officer...

‥‥と思ったら、制服を着た
アイドルのグラビアだった。
Wait, no. That's the latest
"Babes in Uniform" calendar.
My bad.




<Phoenix>
刑事たちの机がならんでいる。
These are the detectives'
desks.

パソコンに、資料。
‥‥思ったより片づいているな。
There are computers and files
on each one. Funny, they're
a lot tidier than I'd expect.

たぶん、あまり席にいることが
ないんだろう。
I guess the detectives don't
spend a lot of time at their
desks.




< >
２月２３日　某時刻
警察署内　刑事課
February 23
Police Department
Criminal Affairs

<Ema>
あ‥‥あれ。成歩堂さん！
カチョーさんの席‥‥
H-hey, Mr. Wright!
Look who's standing at
the Head Detective's desk!

<Phoenix>
（あれは‥‥ガント局長？）
(It's Chief Gant!)

<Gant>
‥‥ホント、コレだけよね？
カチョーちゃんさ。
Are you sure this
is all, hmm?

見落としがあるとね。
トンでもないコトになるから。
You know what it means
if there is anything missing!

<Chief>
はっ！　たぶんおそらく、
もーカンペキでありますッ！
Sir! I'm sure it's most
likely totally perfect!

机の引き出しもロッカーもゴミ箱も
カバンもポケットもボウシのウラも
We checked the drawers,
the lockers, the garbage
cans, the coat pockets...

ザブトンのウラもパソコンのウラも
湯飲みの中も調べたでありますッ！
the pillowcases, behind the
computer monitors, the
coffee machine...

<Gant>
‥‥そ。じゃ、もし何か出たらさ。
すぐにね。連絡くれるかな。
I see. Well, if anything
does turn up, you call me
right away, deal?

<Chief>
は、は‥‥ははははあッ！
も一度！　調べてみるですッ！
Y-y-y-yessir!!!
We'll scour the place
again, sir!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥課長さん、
　みっともなく舞い上がってるな）
(The Head Detective
looks a little flustered...)

<Gant>
‥‥あれェ、ナルホドちゃん！
どうよ、最近。泳いでる？
Ah hah! Wrighto, my boy!
How ya been? Swim much?

<Phoenix>
はははあッ！　ガント局長殿ッ！
ごくろーさまですッ！
Oh ho ho, Chief Gant!
Reporting for duty, sir!

<Ema>
なんで成歩堂さんが
ケーレイしてるんですかっ！
Why are you saluting
him, Mr. Wright!?




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of
the detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Police>
“わかった！　ハンニンは
　カセットテープを使ったのだ！”
"I know! The killer used
a cassette tape!"

“なんて巧妙なトリックだろう‥‥
　あの銃声は、ニセモノなのだ！”
"What a crafty trick!
That gunshot was a fake!"

‥‥今の時代に、あえて
カセットテープってのがイイな。
This is good! No one will
expect a cassette tape in
this day and age!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

報告書‥‥じゃなくて、
小説を書いているようだ。
He's not writing a report...
he's writing a novel.




<Chief>
やれやれ‥‥みっともないトコ、
見られちゃった。
Ooh, sorry you had to
see that.

<Ema>
あの。何をたのまれたんですか？
局長さんに。
Uh... what exactly did
the Chief of Police want
you to do?

<Chief>
いやね。そこにホラ。被害者の
多田敷クンの席があるんだけど。
Well, see over there?
That's Goodman's desk.

手がかりになりそうな遺留品を、
ゼンブ提出しろ、って。
He wanted me to check it
for anything that might
be a clue...

ゴミ箱のゴミまで、ゼーンブ
持っていっちゃったよ。
They took away every last
piece of garbage in the trash
can.

<Ema>
じゃあ、もう多田敷さんの遺品、
ここにはないんですね。
So nothing belonging to
Detective Goodman is still
here?

<Chief>
モチロン。
残ったのは、コイツだけだよ。
Of course not!
Well, except for this.

<Ema>
残しちゃダメじゃないですか！
What!? You kept something!?

<Chief>
だってこれ、
書類の書きそこないだから。
Sure, why not? It's not
important. He didn't even
finish writing it!

《遺失物届》‥‥途中までしか
記入されてないしね。
It's a lost item report
but it's only half complete.

<Ema>
“いしつぶつ”‥‥
何か、なくしたんだ。多田敷さん。
A lost item?
Did Detective Goodman lose
something?

<Phoenix>
書類の日付は‥‥２月２１日、か。
（いちおう、記録しておこう）
The date on it is February 21.
(I'll make a note of that
just in case.)

< >
証拠品《多田敷の遺失物届》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
Goodman's Lost Item Report
added to the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とにかく）
(I should probably get a
quick look around the
crime scene...)

<Phoenix>
（なんとかして、
　現場を調べないとな‥‥）




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥大丈夫ですか？
御剣のヤツ‥‥
Um... is Edgeworth
going to be okay?

<Gant>
あー。御剣ちゃん。
今ね、アレ。検事局の査問会。
Oh, Worthy? Oh, you know,
they're doing a little
inquiry committee with him.

<Ema>
“さもんかい”って‥‥
不吉なヒビキですね。
Sounds like an inquisition...!

<Gant>
カレもホラ。イロイロあったから。
年末からこっち。イロイロ、ね。
Yep, well, we've had no end
of trouble with the boy since
last year...

<Phoenix>
もしかして‥‥あの。
ひょうたん湖の事件ですか？
You mean... the incident
on Gourd Lake?

<Gant>
ま。御剣ちゃん自身が被告人って
いうのもシャレにならないケド。
It doesn't look good having
one of our top people sitting
in the defendant's seat.

ナルホドちゃんが有罪にした
ヒト、いたでしょ？
Now, you got someone else
found guilty in that case,
right, Wrighto?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥狩魔検事‥‥）
(von Karma...)

<Gant>
４０年間無敗をホコった、
検事局の“生きる伝説”‥‥
A legend he was, undefeated
in his forty year career!

アレが“ねつ造”ってコトに
されちゃったでしょ？　キミにさ。
But in court you fixed it
so he was caught for forging
evidence...

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや！　ベツに、
ぼくがワルいわけでは‥‥
W-wait! I didn't do anything
wrong! He did forge evidence.

<Gant>
とにかく、今。アチラさん
タイヘンなのよ。検事局ね。
In any case, the Prosecutor's
Office is in a bit of
turmoil, you might say.

信頼を回復するためなら、
なんだってやっちゃうよ。
Why, they'd do just about
anything to restore their
reputation.

査問会しだいでは‥‥
アブナイね。御剣ちゃん。
Now, depending on what that
inquiry committee decides...
It could be bad for Worthy.

<Ema>
そ‥‥そんな！
Wh-what!?




<Gant>
いやー。さすがにコマっちゃうね。
同時でしょ？　向こうさんと。
It's downright odd, I tell
you. I mean, it happened
at exactly the same time!

<Phoenix>
（検事局、か‥‥）
(The murder at the
Prosecutor's Office...)

<Ema>
でも！　そんなの、カガク的に
あり得ないじゃないですか。
Scientifically speaking,
it's impossible!

<Gant>
でも！　‥‥今のところさ。
そう言ってるワケ。証拠がね。
Yes, but that's what
the evidence is saying.

“多田敷ちゃんは、２つの場所で
　同時に刺された”‥‥って。
"Goodman was stabbed in
two locations at the same
time!" That's what it says.

<Phoenix>
その“証拠”というのは‥‥？
What evidence is this...?

<Gant>
お。ちょっとそれは。
カンベンしてよ、ナルホドちゃん！
Now, now, Wrighto, I can't
give away all our secrets
just like that!

そのヘン、ビミョーでさあ。
ワルいけど、言えないの！
And this in particular, well
it's a little sensitive...
and I can't talk about it.

<Phoenix>
（まあ‥‥
　そうかもしれないな）
(I wasn't expecting much
anyway.)

<Gant>
ボクね。隠しゴトみたいなの、
キライなワケ。コレ、ホントに。
You know, one thing I hate
most of all is hiding stuff.
Secrets. Can't stand 'em!

<Gant>
But you know...

‥‥だから。カチョーちゃんにも
キビしく言ってあるんだけどさ。
It's a full-time job just
keeping the Head Detective's
trap shut!

<Ema>
あ。そういえば、いじめてましたね
‥‥カチョーさんのコト。
Ah, he was the one you were
picking on earlier?

<Gant>
あ。やだなー。
アレ、見てたの？　あはは。
Huh? You saw that?
Whoops!

<Phoenix>
（カチョーさん‥‥
　何をたのまれたんだろう？）
(I wonder what it was that
he wanted the Head
Detective to do?)

<Ema>
ちょっと、コッソリ
聞いてみましょうよ！
Let's see if we can kind
of discreetly ask him.




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥ところで。
おねがいがあるんですけど。
Actually, I was wondering
if I could ask you a favor?

<Gant>
あ。ナニ？　めずらしいね、
ナルホドちゃん。おねがいなんて。
Hmm? Well, I never thought
the day would come when
Wrighto asked me for help!

<Phoenix>
《証拠保管室》の調査を
させてもらえませんか？
I was wondering if we could
investigate the evidence
room?

<Gant>
あのさ、成歩堂ちゃん。
Now, Wrighto...

<Phoenix>
あ。すみませんでしたッ！
ケッコウでありますッ！
A-actually, I'm sorry,
I d-don't need to investigate
after all!

<Gant>
‥‥ボクさ。そんなね。
ケチなオトコじゃないワケ。
Wrighto, please, do I look
like a selfish man?

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

<Gant>
ダレにたのまれても、
５０００円までなら貸すし。
Heck, if anyone asked me
"sir, can I borrow $50?"
I'd give them $50, no problem.

‥‥ぜんぜんモンダイないよ。
好きに調べてくれていいから。
So, go ahead! Investigate 
that room to your heart's
content! Knock yourself out!

<Ema>
言ってみるモンですねー。
It just goes to show, you
never know until you ask!

<Gant>
じゃ、そこのおじょうちゃん。
コレ。貸してあげるから。
And for you, here,
you can borrow this.

<Ema>
あ‥‥それ！　刑事さんの
ＩＤカード‥‥ですか？
Huh... hey!
This is a detective's
ID card, isn't it?

<Gant>
お客さん用のトクベツだから。
なくさないでね。
That's a special card for
guests, so don't lose it.

<Ema>
は‥‥はいッ！
光栄でありますッ！
Y-yessir! 
It's an honor!

<Gant>
‥‥ま。とにかく、がんばってよ。
じゃ。またね。
You just run along and
do your best, now. Later,
folks!

<Ema>
へへ。ムネにつけちゃった。
ホンモノですよ！
Heh heh! It looks pretty
cool on my lapel, doesn't
it? Just think, a real ID!

<Phoenix>
うれしそうだね。ものすごく。
You seem... happy.

<Ema>
本官が入れてあげますからしてッ！
‥‥証拠保管室。
Yes, sir! Because, sir, we
get to go into the evidence
room now, sir!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ヘンな影響を
　受けているみたいだな）
(I think this place is a bad
influence on the girl.)




<Phoenix>
あの。ちょっと
見ていただきたいんですけど。
I was wondering, could
you take a look at this?

<Gant>
あ。ワルいけど。
Ah, sorry, Wrighto.

そういうのボク、もう
卒業しちゃったから。
I'm through with that
stuff. Through, I say.

そのへんをヒラヒラしてる
コートのヒトにでも見せてあげて。
Go find that guy who can't
seem to sit still out there.
The busy one...

<Ema>
ヒラヒラ‥‥
あの刑事さんのコトかな。
The guy who can't sit
still... does he mean
Detective Gumshoe?

<Phoenix>
せめて“フラフラ”と
言ってあげてほしいね。
Either him or the
Dancing Blue Badger.

