<Cellular>
　　プルルル‥‥‥‥
　　　　　　プルルル‥‥‥‥
Brrring...
   Brrrrring...

<Cellular>
　　　　　　　ピッ
*beep*

<???>
はい‥‥綾里ですけど。
Hello? This is Maya.

<Mia>
もしもし。私よ。
Hey Maya, it's me.

<???>
あ、チヒロお姉ちゃん！
どうしたの？　めずらしいね。
Mia! 
What's up? You haven't
called in a while.

<Mia>
ごめんね。最近、忙しくって。
‥‥どう？　元気？
Sorry, I've been so busy.
How you been?

<???>
もう！　かわいい妹を１人で
ほったらかして、ひどいなー。
Well, LONELY.
And it's all YOUR fault.

なーんて。
Nah, I'm just teasing.

だいじょうぶだよ！　もう、
慣れちゃったから‥‥１人ぐらし。
I've been great! I'm finally
getting used to having my
own place.

<Mia>
そう‥‥ありがとう。
That's good to hear.

‥‥あのね。実はちょっと、
たのみたいことがあるの。
Actually, I'm calling because
I have a favor to ask.

<???>
あー、わかった！　また、
証拠品あずかれって言うんでしょ？
I know, I know. You want me
to hold evidence for you?

<Mia>
よくわかったわね。
Sharp as always!

‥‥今度の事件、ちょっと
話が大きくなっていてね。
There's a lot of buzz about
the upcoming trial...

裁判の日まで、そばに
置いておきたくなくて。
I just don't feel safe
keeping the evidence here.

<???>
へえ‥‥。
で？　で？　今度は何？
I gotcha.
So, what is it this time?

<Mia>
置き時計よ。
It's... a clock.

<???>
‥‥時計？
A clock?

<Mia>
そう。考える人の形をしてて、
なんと、しゃべるのよ！
Yeah, it's made to look like
that statue, "The Thinker."
And it tells you the time!

あなた、好きでしょ？
こういう、オモチャみたいなの。
I thought you might like it.
You always liked toys.

<???>
あー。またあたしのコト、
コドモ扱いしたー。
Hey! I'm not a little
girl anymore, Sis!

<Mia>
ふふふ。
‥‥ごめんなさい。
Now, now. You know
I'm only teasing.

‥‥あ。でも、今はこの時計、
しゃべらないんだったっけ。
Ah, I should probably tell
you, the clock isn't talking
right now.

<???>
えー、なんでー？
‥‥つまんない。
Huh? It's not working?
That's lame!

<Mia>
さっき、
時計の機械を抜いちゃったから。
I had to take the
clockwork out. Sorry.

かわりに、書類が入っているの。
I put some papers
inside it instead.

<???>
書類？
‥‥それが“証拠品”なの？
Papers? Is that
the evidence, then?

うー。なんか、
話がソレっぽくなってきたね。
Hmm, well... there's a
possibility that it might
turn out that way, yes.

<Mia>
‥‥じゃあ、今晩の９時ごろ、
事務所に来てくれるかしら？
Can you come by the office
tonight, say 9:00, to pick
it up?

<Mia>
裁判の打ち合わせ、
たぶん、そのころまでかかるから。
I'll be in a pretrial
meeting until then.

<???>
お姉ちゃん！　また、何か
おいしいのゴチソウしてよね！
Okay, Sis, but I expect
dinner! Something good!

あ、みそラーメンがいいな
みそラーメン。
Like... burgers! I could
really go for a good burger.

<Mia>
はいはい。
じゃ、いつものお店、行こうね。
Okay, okay.
We'll hit the usual joint.

<???>
やったー！　ヤクソクだよ！
Alright! It's a deal!

じゃ、お姉ちゃん。
また、あとでね！
Okay, Sis, see you soon!

<Mia>
うん。
待ってるわよ、マヨイ。
Yep.
I'll be waiting, Maya.

<Cellular>
　　　　　　　ピー
*beep*

《ただ今の通話、録音しました。
　９月５日、午前９時２７分》
[Conversation recorded.
September 5, 9:27 AM]

< >
　９月　５日　午後８時５７分
　　　　綾里法律事務所
September 5, 8:57 PM
Fey & Co. Law Offices

<???>
‥‥じゃあ、ミス・チヒロ。
もらっていくよ‥‥書類を。
Now, Miss Fey, I'll take
what's mine... the papers.

<Mia>
悪いけど、渡せないわ。
‥‥ここには、ないもの。
I'm sorry, but I can't
give you what I don't have.

<???>
ミス・チヒロ‥‥、
ウソはヘタみたいだね。
Miss Fey,
you are a poor liar.

ちゃんとあるじゃないか、
そこに‥‥。
Why, I see it right
over there...

書類を飲み込んだ
《考える人》が、さ。
That must be "The Thinker"
that swallowed those papers.

<Mia>
‥‥ど、どうしてそれを！
How could you know...?

<???>
ははっ。
ドンチュノウ？　知らないのかい？
Ho hoh. You are not
cogniferous of my
background?

ぼかぁ、情報を集めるのが
仕事なんだよ。
Gathering information is
my business, you see.

<Mia>
油断‥‥したわ。
I... I should have been more
careful.

<???>
‥‥フン。
Ho hoh.

それと‥‥
ちょっと気の毒なんだけど、
My dear Miss Fey...
I am so very sorry.

キミには、約束してもらわなきゃ
ならないことがあるんだ。
But I am afraid I must ask
you for one more thing.

エターナル・サイレンス‥‥
永遠の沈黙、をね。
Your eternal silence...
Farewell, Miss Fey.

<Mia>
‥‥‥‥！
!!!




< >
‥‥コ‥‥ナ‥‥カ‥‥
Red... White... Blue...




< >
９月　５日　午後９時　８分
綾里法律事務所
September 5, 9:08 PM
Fey & Co. Law Offices




<Phoenix>
ふう。
すっかり遅くなっちまった。
Uh oh, I'm late.

‥‥おかしいな。
所長、帰っちゃったのかな。
Huh, that's strange.
The chief must have
gone home already.

妹さんが遊びにくるから、
ゴハン食べに行こうって‥‥。
She said her sister was
coming over so we should
all go out for dinner...

‥‥‥
...

なんだ‥‥このニオイ‥‥。
What's that smell...?

‥‥血‥‥？
Blood...?

ち、千尋さん！
（所長室か！）
Mia!
(Maybe she's in her office!)




<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

（さ、さっきの女の子は
　‥‥どこだ！）
(That girl just now...
where'd she go!?)

（そこのソファに
　寝かせておいたのに‥‥！）
(I put her right there
on that sofa...!)

（まさか‥‥逃げた、のか？）
(Uh oh... I hope she
didn't run on me.)

<Phoenix>
うわっ！
Yipes!

（‥‥ふう。　おどかすなよ‥‥）
(Don't scare me like that...)

‥‥あのさ。
Umm...

名前‥‥教えてくれないかな？
Excuse me but, who are you?

<???>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
だいじょうぶ。
ぼくは、この事務所の人間だから。
It's okay. I work here.

<Maya>
マヨイ‥‥。
Maya...

アヤサト・マヨイ。
Maya Fey.

<Phoenix>
あやさと‥‥まよい‥‥。
Maya... Fey?

（“マヨイ”だって‥‥？）
("Maya"...?)

（千尋さんが書き残したのは、
　この子のことだったのか‥‥？）
(So Mia was writing
this girl's name!)

（ちょっとこの子に、あの領収書を
　つきつけてみよう）
(Maybe I should show
her the receipt?)

（法廷で覚えたテクニックが、
　実生活で役に立つとは‥‥）
(I never thought there'd be a 
use for evidence like this
outside the courtroom!)




< >
ファン‥‥ファン‥‥
‥‥ファン‥‥ファン‥‥
*whee-ooo* *whee-ooo*...
*whee-ooo* *whee-ooo*...

<Phoenix>
！
!

パ、パトカーだ！
（ここへ向かってるみたいだ‥‥）
The police!
(Sounds like they're
coming this way!)

< >
動くな！　警察だ！
Freeze! Police!

<Gumshoe>
自分は、刑事課の
イトノコギリという者ッス。
Alright, I'm Detective
Dick Gumshoe, see?

<Phoenix>
（イトノコギリ‥‥
　ヘンな名前だな）
(Gumshoe...?
What an odd name.)

<Gumshoe>
このビルの向かいの
ホテルの客から、
We received a report from the
building across the way, see.

殺人を目撃したという通報が
入ったので、かけつけたッス。
Got a person saying
they saw a murder.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そうか。あの女の人だな）
(It must have been
that woman I saw.)

<Gumshoe>
とりあえずアンタたち、
そこを動いちゃダメッスよ。
Anyway, I don't want either
of you moving one inch, 'kay?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ‥‥）
(Great. Just great.)

（マヨイ‥‥ちゃんか。
　まさか、この子が‥‥？）
(Maya... Wait, she
wouldn't have... nah.)

<Gumshoe>
うおおおおおおおおおおおおおッ！
Whoaaaaaaaaaaaah!

ちょっといいッスかッ！
Scuze me!

<Maya>
きゃっ！
Eek!

<Gumshoe>
この“マヨイ”という文字に
心当たりはないッス？
This word "Maya" here
mean anything to you?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

あ。あの‥‥それ‥‥。
Um... that...

あ‥‥あたしの名前‥‥
That's my name...

<Gumshoe>
なんスとぉぉぉッ！
WHAAAAT!?

<Gumshoe>
これは、ヒガイシャが血で
書いたメモッス！
The victim drew this here
note in her own blood, see?

息を引き取るまぎわ、
ハンニンを告発したッス！
With her dying breath, she
wrote down the killer's name!

<Maya>
あ‥‥あたしじゃありま
K-killer...? I'm not--

<Gumshoe>
こりゃもう、キマリッス！
署まで来てもらうッス！
Case closed! You're coming
down to the precinct, ma'am.

<Maya>
え、え‥‥？
W-what?

<Phoenix>
千尋さんの妹・真宵ちゃんは、
緊急逮捕された。
Mia's younger sister, Maya,
was arrested on the spot.

ぼくも取り調べを受けて、
解放されたのは、明け方だった。
I was taken in for questioning
and didn't get out until the
next morning.

まぶたは重かったが、
眠れるわけがない。
My eyes were heavy...
but I couldn't sleep.

留置所の面会が始まる
時間を待って、
I sat around, waiting for
visiting hours to begin at
the detention center.

ぼくは、すぐに真宵ちゃんに
会いに行った。
I had to talk to Maya
as soon as possible.




<Phoenix>
（‥‥とにかく、早く
　警察を呼ぼう！）
(I'd better hurry up
and call the police!)




<Phoenix>
所長室へ通じるドアだ。
半開きになっている。
The door to the chief's
office. It's slightly open.

ドアノブには
触れない方がいいだろう。
I'd better not touch
the door knob.




<Phoenix>
受付に使っているデスクだ。
いつもぼくが座っている。
The reception desk.
I usually sit here.




<Phoenix>
来客用のソファだ。
革張りの高級品らしい。
This sofa is for clients.
It's leather... a real
luxury model.




<Phoenix>
大きな絵画だ。
モダン・アートというのだろうか。
A large painting.
I guess you'd call
this "modern art."

ぼくには、ただの
失敗作にしか見えない。
I, on the other hand,
call it a mistake.




<Phoenix>
法律関係の本が、イヤになるほど
ビッシリ並んでいる。
You couldn't cram more legal
books in here, even if you
wanted to.

事務所を訪れる客たちは、
かならずこの本棚にビビる。
Few can gaze upon the shelves
without feeling insignificant.




<Phoenix>
小さなライティングデスクには、
事務用品が整然と並んでいる。
A small writing desk cluttered
with office supplies.




<Phoenix>
‥‥今は、この血のニオイが
気になる！
I smell blood...
and that can't be good!

千尋さん‥‥所長の無事を
たしかめないと！
I have to check and see if
Mia... the Chief's okay!




<Phoenix>
名前、教えてくれないかな。
Excuse me but, who are you?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
だいじょうぶ。
ぼくは、この事務所の人間だから。
It's okay. I work here.

<Maya>
マヨイ‥‥。
Maya...

あやさと・まよい。
Maya Fey.

<Phoenix>
（“マヨイ”だって‥‥？）
("Maya"...?)

（千尋さんが書き残したのは、
　この子のことだったのか‥‥？）
(So Mia was writing
this girl's name!)

（ちょっとこの子に、あの領収書を
　つきつけてみよう）
(Maybe I should show
her the receipt...)

（法廷で覚えたテクニックが、
　実生活で役に立つとは‥‥）
(I never thought there'd be a 
use for evidence like this
outside the courtroom!)




<Phoenix>
（かなり弱っているみたいだけど、
　聞かないわけにはいかないな‥）
(She seems to be in shock.
I don't want to disturb her,
but I have to know...)

あの‥‥きみ。
Um... excuse me?

いったい、何が
あったんだい？
Can you tell me
what happened?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
‥‥あたしが来たら、
部屋が暗くて‥‥
I came in...
The room was dark.

もう、お姉ちゃんは‥‥
And Sis... Sis...!

<Phoenix>
（亡くなった後だった、
　というわけか）
(So she was already dead.)




<Phoenix>
きみは、所長の‥‥？
So, you're the chief's...?

<Maya>
‥‥妹です。
Sister. I'm her
younger sister.

<Phoenix>
こんな時間に‥‥遊びに来たの？
And you were here... visiting?
This late at night?

<Maya>
はい‥‥。
証拠品をあずかって欲しい、って。
Yes. She said she wanted me
to keep some evidence for her.

<Phoenix>
証拠品‥‥って？
Evidence...?

<Maya>
はい‥‥。
あ、あの‥‥、
Yes...
I-it was that clock...

《考える人》の置時計を‥‥。
It was "The Thinker."




<Maya>
‥‥すみません。
特に心当たり、ないです。
I'm sorry, I've never
seen that before.




<Phoenix>
これ、所長のそばに
散らばってたんだけど‥‥
This was lying next
to the chief.

<Maya>
はい。
あたしも見ました。
I know. I saw it there too.

たぶん、電気スタンドの
カケラかな、って。
I thought they might be
pieces of the light stand.

<Phoenix>
うん。たぶんね。
Hmm. Maybe.

（でも、ガラス製の電気スタンド
　なんて、めずらしいな‥‥）
(Never heard of a glass
light stand before...)




<Phoenix>
あの、《考える人》の
ことなんだけど‥‥
Um, about "The Thinker"...

<Maya>
！
!

い、いや！
The Th-Thinker...

‥‥お姉ちゃんは、あれで‥‥！
That was... 
Oh, Sis! *sob*

<Phoenix>
（今、凶器のことを聞くのは
　さすがにヒドいな‥‥）
(Hmm, probably shouldn't have
asked her about the murder
weapon...)




<Phoenix>
千尋さん、亡くなる前に
自分の血でメッセージを‥‥
Before Mia died, she wrote
a message with her own blood.

領収書のウラにね。
She wrote it on the
back of this receipt.

<Maya>
！
!

あ、あ、あたしの名前！
Th-th-that's MY name!

ど、どうして！
お姉ちゃんが‥‥？　どうして！
W-why!?
Why would she write my name?

<Phoenix>
お、落ち着いてくれ！
Please, just calm down.

<Maya>
なんで‥‥お姉ちゃんが、
あたしを‥‥？
W-why would
Sis write my name?

<Phoenix>
（う。そ、そんな目で
　見られてもなあ‥‥）
(Uh-oh. Now I've done it...)




< >
９月　６日　某時刻
綾里法律事務所
September 6
Fey & Co. Law Offices

<Phoenix>
（事務所は警官たちで
　いっぱいだ‥‥）
(The office is filled
with police officers.)

（みんな、忙しそうに
　動きまわっているぞ‥‥）
(They're all busily searching
for clues...)

<???>
コラ！
Hey! You there!

ここは立入禁止ッス！
This is a crime scene, pal!
No trespassing!

‥‥ん？
たしかアンタは‥‥、
Umm... Sorry, don't I
know you from somewhere?

ヤッパリくん‥‥
だったッス？
Wait, you're that Butz guy,
aren't you!

<Phoenix>
ナルホドです！
（アイツと間違えないでくれ！）
No, no, Phoenix Wright.
(How could anyone mistake
me for Larry!?)

<???>
あ、そうそう。
なんかそんな名前だったッス！
Ah, guess I got the
wrong name, Mr. Wright.
Sorry 'bout that.

“ヤッパリ”は、たしか
殺人犯の名前だったッス。
That Butz guy, he was
a killer! And you're
no killer! Right?

<Phoenix>
（アイツたしか、
　ムザイになったはずだけど‥‥）
(He WAS proven innocent...)

えーと。
そういうあなたは、たしか‥‥
Umm... right.
And you were...




<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事‥‥
でしたよね。
Um... Gumshoe, wasn't it?
Dick Gumshoe?

<???>
そッス。
イトノコッス‥‥。
Right!
At your service.

ってアンタ！　人の名前、
勝手に縮めちゃダメッス！
Hang on! That's Detective
Gumshoe to you, pal!


<Phoenix>
えーと、カメノコ刑事‥‥
でしたっけ。
Um... Suedeshoes, wasn't it?

<???>
そッス。
カメノコッス‥‥。
That's me! Don't step on
my blue suede shoes...

って、それはタワシッス！
Wait! That's a song, pal!

自分は、イトノコ‥‥
My name's Dick Gumshoe...

いやいやいや。
W-wait!

そもそも、人の名前を
勝手に縮めちゃダメッス！
That's Detective
Gumshoe to you, pal!


<Phoenix>
えーと、ノコノコ刑事‥‥
でしたっけ？
Um... Gumtree, was it?
Detective Gumtree?

<???>
ノ、ノコノコ‥‥。
G-Gumtree...?

‥‥アンタ、ちょっと
おふざけがすぎたッス‥‥。
Gum doesn't grow
on trees, pal!

本官をナメると、イタい目に
あうッスよ‥‥！
And I'm the one in charge here
so don't push your luck!

<Phoenix>
（うわあ、急に自分のコト
“本官”とか言い出したよ‥‥）
(Whatever you say,
Detective...)


<Gumshoe>
自分は、糸鋸　圭介
（いとのこぎりけいすけ）ッス！
Anyway, get the name right.

なんぴとたりとも、
自分を“イトノコ”なんて‥‥
And don't go calling me
"Dick"...

<Police>
おい、イトノコ！
こっち、早くたのむよ！
Hey, Dick!
Get over here!

<Gumshoe>
ハ、ハッ！
Y-yes, sir!

す、すぐ行くッス！
B-be right there!

あー、オホン！
Umm... ahem!

たしかアンタ、
弁護士だったッスな。
You're her lawyer,
right, pal?

用なら、早くしてほしいッス！
If you got business here,
you'd better do it quick!

<Phoenix>
（しめた！　ぼくを真宵ちゃんの
　弁護士だと思っているぞ‥‥！）
(Whew! He thinks I'm
Maya's lawyer...!)




<Phoenix>
（‥‥だいたい、聞くべきことは
　おさえたかな‥‥）
(I guess I've asked all
the questions I need to.)

<Gumshoe>
もういいッス？
You all done, pal?

<Phoenix>
あ。ありがとうございました。
‥‥そろそろ、帰ります。
Um, yes, thank you.
I'll be heading out now.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥あ、そうそう。
Oh, wait.

あんたに、１つ言っておくッス。
One more thing I wanted
to mention to you.

おおかた、これからあの
目撃証人に会おうとか、
I don't suppose you're
planning on talking to
that witness.

そんなフラチなことを
考えてるかもしれないッスが、
Anyway, you'd better not!

会ってもムダッスよ！
No influencing the witness
with your lawyerly ways, pal!

<Phoenix>
‥‥
...

（そういえば、彼女のコト、
　忘れてたな‥‥）
(Come to think of it, I had
completely forgotten about 
her...)

目撃証人、ですか‥‥？
The... witness?

<Gumshoe>
松竹　梅世（しょうちくうめよ）
のことッス！
Yeah, Miss April May.

あいにくッスが、
I'm sorry 'bout this...

自分は、彼女の情報は
ゼッタイもらさないッス！
But I can't tell you
anything about her!

<Phoenix>
（名前は松竹　梅世、か）
(Well, you just told me
her name. Miss May, huh?)

もう彼女、家に帰らせて
あげたんですよね？
So you've sent her
home already, then?

<Gumshoe>
ワレワレをナメちゃ
ダメッス。
Ahah! You're trying your
lawyerly tricks on me now!

彼女には、裁判が終わるまで、
勝手な外出は禁止してるッス！
She's not to go outside her
room until the trial!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥てことは、まだ彼女は
　この向かいのホテルにいる、と）
(So... she's still in the
hotel across the way.)

はあ。
さすが警察ですね。
I guess I should know better
than to try to get a
detective to leak information.

<Gumshoe>
わかればいいッス！
You got that right, pal!

<Phoenix>
（よし！　ホテルにも
　行ってみよう！）
(Time to pay a visit
to Miss May!)




<Phoenix>
所長室へ通じるドアだ。
The door to the
chief's office.

ドアの向こうでは、警官たちが
捜査をしているようだ。
The police are in there
searching for clues.

‥‥入らない方がいいな。
I'd better not go in.




<Phoenix>
千尋さんお気に入りの
観葉植物だ。
Mia's favorite potted plant.

名前は、とても常人には
おぼえられそうもないような‥‥
I remember it had this
bizarre name no one
could ever remember.

<???>
“コルディリネ・ストリクター”
ッス！
"Cordyline stricta," pal!

<Phoenix>
（誰だ、今の声‥‥）
(Who was that!?)




<Phoenix>
法律関係のムズカシイ本が
いやというほど並んでいる。
There's a horrendous amount
of legal books here.

恐ろしいことに、千尋さん、
この本を全部、読んでいるそうだ。
Scarier still is that Mia
probably read all of these.




<Phoenix>
ぼくの気持ちとウラハラに、
そとはいい天気だ。
The sky is blue,
and so am I...

目の前に、例のホテルが見える。
There's that hotel,
right across the way.




<Phoenix>
千尋さんのデスクだ。
Mia's desk.

いつもどおり、
キレイに片づいている。
Perfectly clean, as always.

足りないのは、千尋さんの
姿だけ、だ‥‥。
The only thing it's
missing is... Mia.




<Phoenix>
古い映画のポスターだ。
An old movie poster.

千尋さんが初めて泣いた
映画なのだそうだ。
Apparently, this was the
first movie that made Mia
cry when she saw it.

今度、ぼくも見てみるか。
I'll have to check it
out one of these days.




<Phoenix>
千尋さん‥‥
解剖は、したんですか‥‥？
About Ms. Fey...
did you do an autopsy?

<Gumshoe>
なんス？
知りたいッスか？　結果？
Hmm?
You want to know
the results, eh?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Gumshoe>
‥‥そ、そんな目で見つめちゃ
ダメッス。
Now don't you look
at me like that, pal!

‥‥そッスね‥‥。
It's no use!

あんたは、彼女のもとで
働いていたこともあるし、
She might have been your
boss, but that doesn't mean
you get any special treatment.

報告書を見せてあげるッス。
Alright, alright.
You can see the report,
but that's all!

< >
証拠品《解剖記録》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Autopsy Report added
to the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
千尋さん‥‥即死だったんですか。
So, Mia's death was
instantaneous.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥そッスね。
That's right, pal.

キレイなヒト、だったッス‥‥。
She was... a beautiful person.

<Phoenix>
あれ。刑事さん、所長のこと
知ってるんですか？
You knew her, Detective?

<Gumshoe>
警察の関係者で、彼女のことを
知らない人間はいないッス。
Sure. All of us down at
the precinct knew Ms. Fey.

くやしいッスけど、彼女は
エラい弁護士だったッス。
Much as it pains me to say
this, she was a darn good
lawyer.

‥‥い、いや、何でもないッス。
め、目にホコリが入っただけッス。
Hey, what are you looking at?
I just got a little dust
in my eye, that's all.




<Phoenix>
あの、真宵さんのこと
なんですけど‥‥。
Um, about Maya...

<Gumshoe>
ああ。
裁判が楽しみッスね。
Yeah!
I'm looking forward
to the trial!

あんたには気の毒ッス。
ゼッタイに勝てないッス！
Sorry, pal, but this is
one trial you aren't
going to win!

<Phoenix>
ど、どうしてですか？
W-why do you say that?

<Gumshoe>
検事局は、この事件の担当に、
あの御剣検事を任命したッス！
The city's put Prosecutor
Edgeworth on the prosecution!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ミツルギ‥‥）
(Edgeworth...)

<Gumshoe>
これがどういうことか、
弁護士ならわかるッスね？
I'm sure you know what
that means, you being a
lawyer and all.




<Phoenix>
ミツルギ検事‥‥。
Prosecutor Edgeworth...

<Gumshoe>
そッス。御剣　怜侍
（みつるぎれいじ）その人ッス！
That's right, pal!
Mr. Miles Edgeworth himself!

まさか、知らないなんてこと、
ないッスよね？
Wait... you do know him,
don't you!?



<Phoenix>
有罪判決を獲得するためには
手段を選ばない、
I know him. He's a feared
prosecutor. He doesn't feel
pain, he doesn't feel remorse.

血も涙もない、オニのような
検事‥‥ですよね。
He won't stop until he gets
his "guilty" verdict.

<Gumshoe>
ヒト聞きの悪いこと、
言っちゃダメッス。
Aww, don't talk about him
that way. You make him
barely sound human!

‥‥でも。これで、もう勝負は
決まったようなものッス。
Still, I'm afraid this pretty
much decides the case.

<Phoenix>
（御剣検事が出てくるのか‥‥）
(So, Edgeworth is on this
one...)

（２０歳という、異例の若さで
　検事になって以来、負け知らず）
(He hasn't lost a case since
he became prosecutor at the
incredibly young age of 20.)

（黒いウワサも絶えない。
　裏取引や証拠のでっち上げ‥‥）
(Of course, there are rumors
of back-alley deals and
forged evidence...)

（そして、ほとんど異常ともいえる
　“犯罪”に対する憎しみ‥‥）
(All I know for sure is that
Edgeworth hates crime with
an almost abnormal passion.)


<Phoenix>
聞いたこと、ないですけど‥‥。
Never heard of him.

<Gumshoe>
はん！
あきれた弁護士ッスね。
Whoa!
And you call yourself
a lawyer, pal!?

２０歳で検事になってから４年。
About four years ago, this
Edgeworth guy became a
prosecutor at the age of 20!

検事局始まって以来の天才と
言われている彼を知らないとは！
Everyone says he's a genius.
Surprised you don't know him!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥知らないワケ、ないだろ。
　ちょっと、トボけてみただけさ）
(Of course I know him...
I was just playing dumb.)

（有罪判決を獲得するためには
　なんでもする、冷酷な男！）
(He's a cold, heartless
machine who'll do anything
to get a "guilty" verdict!)

（裏取引や証拠のでっち上げ‥‥
　偽証させるってウワサもある）
(There are rumors of 
back-alley deals and forged
evidence...)

（ほとんど異常ともいえる、
　“犯罪”に対する憎しみ‥‥）
(All I know for sure is that
Edgeworth hates crime with
an almost abnormal passion.)


<Phoenix>
（まさか、こんなに早く
　会うことになるとは‥‥）
(I never imagined I'd be
facing him so soon...)




<Gumshoe>
‥‥なんスか、それ？
Hmm? What's that?

悪いッスが、アンタに
やる情報なんか、ないッス！
Sorry, pal, but I got no
info for the likes of you!




<Phoenix>
あの。綾里　真宵の
携帯電話のことなんですけど‥‥。
I was wondering... did you
see Maya Fey's cell phone?

<Gumshoe>
ああ。
自分があずかっているッス。
Oh that?
I have that.

<Phoenix>
できれば、返して
もらいたいんですけど。
Do you think you
could give it back?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥！
あやしいッス！
Sure!
I mean, wait a second, pal!

 
Tricky lawyer!

<Phoenix>
（うわあ‥‥。どうしよう！）
(Uh-oh, he's on to me!)



<Phoenix>
（ダメだ！　正直に話したら、
　ゼッタイ返してくれないぞ！）
(Hmm... if I tell him why
I want it there's no way
he'll give it to me!)

<Gumshoe>
どうしたッス？
Something the matter?

<Phoenix>
あ、いや、その‥‥。
わかるでしょう、刑事さん？
Oh, no, it's just...
You know, Detective!

<Gumshoe>
いいや。
わからねッス！
Nope.
I know nothing, pal!

<Phoenix>
その電話には、あの子の
ボーイフレンドの番号とか、
That cell phone has a lot of
numbers on it... like her
boyfriend's...

<Phoenix>
あま酸っぱいオトメのヒミツが
いっぱい、つまってるんですよ。
A cell phone holds all a
little girl's sweetest
and spiciest secrets!

<Gumshoe>
ハッ。ワレワレ警察を
ナメてもらっちゃ困るッス！
Urk? Y-you're trying
to confuse me!

悪いッスが、メモリーされた番号は
すべて、チェックしたッス！
Sorry, pal. I already checked
all the numbers in memory!

<Phoenix>
さ、さすが警察！
すばやいですね‥‥。
Impressive! You're
quite the detective.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥まあ、いいッス。
返すッス。
Uh huh. Oh, here, you
can have the phone back.

あいにく、あやしい電話番号は
なかったッスから。
There weren't any suspicious
call records in there,
after all.


<Phoenix>
（うーん‥‥。
　ごまかすって言ってもなあ‥‥）
(Okay, I can't be straight
with this guy... but what
should I tell him?)

<Gumshoe>
どうしたッス？
Something the matter?

<Phoenix>
あ、いや。そ、その。
Oh, no, um...

そ、その携帯電話についている
ストラップなんですけど‥‥。
T-that carrying strap
on the cell phone...

<Gumshoe>
《大江戸戦士・トノサマン》って
プリントされているッスね‥‥。
This? Hmm... it says "The
Steel Samurai: Warrior of
Neo Olde Tokyo"...

トノサマン‥‥、たしかテレビの
人気ヒーローだったッスな？
"The Steel Samurai"... that
action hero on TV?

<Phoenix>
そ、そのストラップ、なかなか
手に入らないものらしくって。
Yeah, you see that strap is
a collector's item...

警察にあずけておいて、
なくなったらイヤだわ、って。
She... was worried it might
get lost if it went down
to the precinct.

<Gumshoe>
あの子が言ってるッスか。
That what she said?

<Phoenix>
まあ、そうです。
Um. Yes.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥
...

いいッス。
Okay, pal.

メモリーされた電話番号は
ひかえたッスから、
I wrote down all the numbers
she called anyway.

返すッス。
Here you go.


<Phoenix>
（録音された会話には
　気づかなかったみたいだな‥‥）
(Seems he didn't notice
the recorded conversation...)

< >
《真宵の携帯電話》を
返してもらった。
Received: Maya's Cell Phone.

法廷記録で、録音された
会話を聞くことができる。
Check the Court Record to hear
the recorded conversation.




<Phoenix>
刑事さん‥‥
あの、これなんですけど‥‥。
Detective Gumshoe?
Could you take
a look at this?

<Gumshoe>
なんスか？
電話ならもう返したッス。
Huh?
I already gave you the
girl's cell phone, pal.

<Phoenix>
（よし。後で録音された会話を
　聞いてみよう‥‥）
(Right. I'll have to listen
to that recorded conversation
later.)




<Phoenix>
こいつなんですけど‥‥
何かわかりましたか？
I was wondering, do you
know anything about this?

<Gumshoe>
それは‥‥、
凶器の置物ッスね。
That statue?
That's the murder weapon.

<Phoenix>
（あれ？　置時計のことを、
　この刑事も“置物”だって）
(Huh? He thinks the clock
is just a statue, too...)

（よくよく不運な時計だよ、
　コイツは‥‥）
(I'm starting to wish I'd
never seen this thing.)




<Phoenix>
現場には、
ガラスが散らばってましたよね？
There was broken glass
at the crime scene, right?

<Gumshoe>
ああ。あれッスか。
Hmm? Oh, that?

<Gumshoe>
死体のそばに、ガラスで
できたスタンドが倒れていたッス。
Seems like a glass stand
next to the victim fell over.

あのガラスは、
そのスタンドの破片ッス。
The glass shards were pieces
of the broken stand.

<Phoenix>



<Phoenix>
死体のそばに、紙切れが
落ちてましたよね？
There was a piece of
paper next to the victim,
wasn't there?

<Gumshoe>
ああ。犯人の名前が
書いてあった、あれッスか。
Yeah. The one with the
killer's name written on it!

<Phoenix>
あの文字、間違いなく
千尋さんが‥‥？
Are you sure that Mia
wrote it herself?

<Gumshoe>
残念ながら、あんな状態では
筆跡の鑑定はできないッス。
Given the condition of the
writing, it's hard to say if
it's her handwriting or not.

<Phoenix>
（千尋さんが書いたという
　証拠は、ないわけか‥‥）
(So there's no proof
that Mia wrote it.)




<Phoenix>
これ、ありがとうございます。
Thanks for this!

<Gumshoe>
“弁護士とは、正々堂々たたかう”
が、ワレワレのテーマッス。
Don't mention it, pal.

気にすること、ないッス。
When it comes to dealing
with lawyers, "fight fair
and square," is our motto!

<Phoenix>
（でも、こういう書類に
　まとまっちゃうと‥‥）
(I don't know how I feel,
seeing everything written
up like this...)

（所長の死がひどく事務的な
　ものに見えて、悲しいな‥‥）
(It makes Mia's death
seem so... routine.)




<Phoenix>
‥‥。
...

（どうやら、イトノコ刑事は
　帰ってしまったみたいだな）
(Looks like Detective
Gumshoe has gone home.)

（あいかわらず、所長室では
　警察官たちが忙しそうだ）
(The police are still keeping
themselves busy in the
chief's office.)

（誰も相手をしてくれそうにない。
　‥‥退散したほうがいいかな）
(No one has time to talk
to me. Guess I'll head out.)




<Phoenix>
千尋さんお気に入りの
観葉植物だ。
Mia's favorite potted plant.

これから、ぼくが
水をやることになるのか‥‥？
I guess I'll have to
water it now...




<Phoenix>
‥‥血のニオイだ！
That smell... Blood!

<???>
‥‥
...

‥‥うう‥‥
*sob*

‥‥お姉ちゃあん‥‥
Sis...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥だれか、いる！）
(Someone's there!)

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

しょ、しょ、‥‥
Chief? Chief...?

　　　　　所　　長　　！
Chief!!!

<Phoenix>
きみは‥‥？
Who are you?

<???>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥気絶した少女を
　事務室のソファに寝かせて、）
(The strange girl dropped out
cold. I left her lying on
the office sofa.)

（ぼくは所長のそばに戻ってきた）
(I went back to the chief
where she lay under the
window.)

<Phoenix>
（‥‥所長の身体には、
　まだ少しぬくもりが残っている）
(Her body was still warm...)

（肩を抱くぼくの手を通して
　はっきり感じることができる）
(I could feel it when I
held her shoulder.)

（でも、そのぬくもりは、
　急速に、そして確実に、）
(Then, all too quickly,
it began to fade...)

（この手から失われていった‥‥）
(Until finally she was cold.)

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥所長‥‥‥‥
Chief...




<Phoenix>
大小のガラスの破片が
散らばっている。
Some shards of glass are
scattered on the floor.

どうやら、ガラスでできた
電気スタンドだったようだ。
They seem to be the remains
of a glass light stand.




<Phoenix>
この事務所のすぐ目の前に、
ビルが見える。
There's a large building
right across from the office.

“板東ホテル”という
ビジネスホテルだ。
The "Gatewater Hotel."
A nice, luxurious place.




<Phoenix>
血がベットリついている。
なんともヒニクなことに‥‥
It's encrusted with
dried blood.

今度は、所長の命を
奪ってしまったらしい。
How ironic that this became
the murder weapon... again.




<Phoenix>
手さげ金庫だ。
A portable safe.

いくら入っているのかは
わからない。
No way to tell how
much is inside.

誰か持ち出そうとしたのだろうか。
I wonder if someone was
trying to take it out?




<Phoenix>
‥‥所長‥‥。
Chief...

見るのもツラいけど、
調べないわけにはいかないな。
It's hard seeing her like
this, but if there are any
clues here...

‥‥鈍器で頭部を殴られている。
She was struck on the head
with a blunt object.

たぶん、即死だったんじゃ
ないだろうか。
She probably died instantly.

死体のそばに転がっている
《考える人》が凶器か。
"The Thinker" lying next
to her must have been
the murder weapon.

< >
証拠品《考える人》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
The Thinker added
to the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
それと‥‥所長の身体のまわりに、
ガラスのカケラが散らばっている。
Hmm... there are some glass
shards near the chief's body.

部屋の奥にたおれている
ガラス製の電気スタンドの破片か？
Must be pieces of the glass
light stand lying broken in
the back of the room.

< >
証拠品《ガラスの破片》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Glass Shards added
to the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
‥‥他にはもう、手がかりに
なるようなものは‥‥
Nothing else that seems
like a clue here...

ん‥‥？
Hmm...?

千尋さんの身体から、
何か紙切れが落ちたぞ。
A piece of paper! It must
have fallen from Mia's hand!

なんだろう？
What could it be?




<Phoenix>
見るのもツラいけど、
調べないわけにはいかないよな。
It's painful to look... but
I have to, for Mia's sake.

‥‥鈍器で後頭部を殴られている。
Looks like she was hit
in the head with a blunt
weapon.

たぶん、即死だったんじゃ
ないだろうか。
She probably died
instantly.




<Phoenix>
！
!

小さな紙切れに、血で文字が
書かれている！
A word is written in blood
on this scrap of paper!

“マヨイ”‥‥だな。
千尋さんが書いたのか‥‥？
"Maya"...?
Did Mia write this?

ちなみにこの紙切れは、デパートの
領収書で、昨日発行されたものだ。
This piece of paper is a
receipt from a department
store, dated yesterday.

（‥‥待てよ‥‥！）
(Wait a second!)

（“マヨイ”だって‥‥？）
("Maya"...!)

（千尋さんが書き残したのは、
　あの子のことだったのか‥‥？）
(Was Mia trying to tell us
something about that girl?)

（ちょっとあの子に、この領収書を
　つきつけてみよう）
(I think I'd better show
her this receipt.)

（法廷で覚えたテクニックが、
　実生活で役に立つとは‥‥）
(I never thought there'd be a 
use for evidence like this
outside the courtroom!)

< >
証拠品《領収書》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Receipt added to
the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（とりあえず、調べるのは
　これぐらいでいいだろう）
(I think that's enough
snooping around for now.)

（警察に通報‥‥、それに、）
(I'd better call the police...)

（あの女の子のことも
　気になるな‥‥）
(and find out what that
girl was doing here.)




<Phoenix>
そうだ！
とにかく、警察に通報しよう。
Right!
I'd better call the police!

‥‥‥‥？
...?

この電話、ヘンだな。
That's funny...

受話器のネジが、いくつか
はずされている。
A few of the screws on the
receiver are missing...

何かの作業を、とちゅうで
やめたような感じだ。
It looks like someone was
halfway through taking
it apart.

<???>
‥‥‥‥来てぇっ！
Police!?

早く来てぇっ！　おまわりさぁん！
Please, come quick!

<Phoenix>
（な、なんだなんだ！）
(Wh-what was that!?)

<Phoenix>
（窓の向こうで叫び声が！）
(Someone screaming from
outside the window!?)

‥‥‥‥！
...!

こ、こっちをじっと
見つめているぞ！
She's staring right at me!

‥‥受話器を
にぎっているような‥‥。
She's holding a phone
in her hand...




<Phoenix>
この電話‥‥受話器のネジが
いくつか、はずされている。
The phone receiver is missing
a few screws.

‥‥使わない方がいいな‥‥。
I'd better not use it.




<Phoenix>
綾里法律事務所の帳簿だ。
The Fey & Co. ledger book.

所長のキレイな字で
数字がビッシリ書かれている。
Everything is written in
the chief's ultra-neat
handwriting.

小さなオフィスだけど、
けっこう、もうかってるみたいだ。
It's a small office, but
it makes a good bit of money.




<Phoenix>
ちょっと意外なことに、
所長はキカイに弱い。
Surprisingly, the chief
was never good with machines.

このパソコンも、ほとんど
電子メール専用に使っていた。
About all she used this
PC for was e-mail.

とても古いモデルを、タダで
もらってきたそうだ。
She picked up this ancient
model at some garage sale
for practically nothing.




<Phoenix>
ごくふつうのオフィス用
デスクだ。
A perfectly normal office
desk.

依頼人も使う家具には
タップリお金をかけて、
The chief had a very
particular policy about
office décor:

自分が使うものはシンプルに‥‥
というのが、所長の方針だ。
"Spend big on stuff the
clients use, but keep your
own stuff simple."




<Phoenix>
所長の大切な資料が
ぎっしり並んでいる。
All the chief's important
documents are packed in here.

事件の調書や、最近の判例なんかが
ファイルされているそうだ。
This is where she filed 
her case records and
recent rulings.




<Phoenix>
所長のイスだ。
The chief's chair.

機能重視の、シンプルな
デザインで、座りやすいんだ。
A simple, functional design.
Feels pretty good to sit in,
too.




< >
９月　６日　午前９時　７分
留置所　面会室
September 6, 9:07 AM
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Phoenix>
（真宵ちゃん‥‥
　すっかり犯人あつかい、か‥‥）
(Wow, they have poor Maya
locked up like a criminal.)

<Maya>
‥‥あ。
あのときの‥‥弁護士さん。
Oh!

 
It's you! The lawyer...

お、おはようございます。
G-good morning.

<Phoenix>
おはよう！
Good morning!

（かわいそうに‥‥。ずいぶん、
　つかれているみたいだ）
(She looks so tired...)

<Maya>
あの‥‥
Um...

あなたが、あたしの弁護士さんに
なるんですか‥‥？
Are you going to
be my attorney?

<Phoenix>
え。そ、それは‥‥
Well, that's what I wanted
to talk to you about... 




<Phoenix>
（ここは、マジメに
　答えるべきだな‥‥）
(I'd better give it
to her straight...)

‥‥きみしだい、だよ。
It's up to you.

<Maya>
あたし‥‥ですか？
Up... to me?

<Phoenix>
うん。ぼくが決めることじゃ
ないと思うよ。
Yes. I don't think this is
something I should decide.

‥‥これは、きみの問題だからね。
After all, you're the one
in trouble here.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥。
...

信じてもらえるわけ、
ないもん‥‥あたしのこと。
They're never going to
believe me... are they?

あのときの、弁護士さんの目。
“こいつが犯人だ”って‥‥。
Even you, when you found me
in the office. You looked at
me like I had done it!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥彼女を見たとき、ぼくは
　そんな顔をしてたのか‥‥）
(Did I look at her
like that?)

い、いや！　そんなことは‥‥。
No, no! I never thought...

<Maya>
あ。‥‥いいんです。
ムリしなくても‥‥。
I-it's okay.
I understand.

‥‥‥‥
...

うん。‥‥それに、
あたし、聞いちゃったから。
And... I've also heard
about you.

<Phoenix>
え？　何を？
Heard...? Heard what
about me?

<Maya>
実は、この前、お姉ちゃんと
電話で話したの‥‥。
I... was talking to my sister
on the phone the other day...


<Phoenix>
（何はともあれ、ここは
　元気づけてあげるべきだよな）
(First things first, I better
get her cheered up...)

ああ。もちろんそうだよ！
だから、元気出して！
Yeah, of course I will!
Cheer up!

<Maya>
‥‥そ、そうなんですか。
R-really...?

<Phoenix>
（な、なぜだ！　さらに
　悲しげなカオになっちまった！）
(Whoa! Did I say the wrong
thing? She looks sadder now!)

あれ‥‥ど、どうしたのかな？
ぼくじゃ、不安、とか‥‥？
Um... what... what's wrong?
You don't think I can do it?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥だって。
No... no one could!

信じてもらえるわけ、
ないもん‥‥あたしのこと。
Who would believe me?

あのときの、弁護士さんの目。
“こいつが犯人だ”って‥‥。
Even you, when you found me
in the office. You looked at
me like I had done it!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥彼女を見たとき、ぼくは
　そんな顔をしてたのか‥‥）
(Did I look at her
like that?)

い、いや！　そんなことは‥‥。
No, no! I never thought...

<Maya>
あ。‥‥いいんです。
ムリしなくても‥‥。
I-it's okay.
I understand.

‥‥‥‥
...

うん。‥‥それに、
あたし、聞いちゃったから。
And... I've also heard
about you.

<Phoenix>
え？　何を？
Heard...? Heard what
about me?

<Maya>
実は、この前、お姉ちゃんと
電話で話したの‥‥。
I... was talking to my sister
on the phone the other day...


<Phoenix>
（よし。ジョークの１つも飛ばして
　元気づけてあげるとするか）
(Maybe if I joke a bit
she'll cheer up...)

はっはっは。
ぜーったい、ゴメンだね！
Hah hah!
No way, Jose!

なーんて。
Just kidding...

<Maya>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（うわわわ、しまった。
　さすがに、シュミが悪すぎたか）
(Eh heh. Whoops.
That didn't go so well.)

<Maya>
‥‥ホッ‥‥。
...Heh...

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

あ、あの。
M-Maya...?

今、心なしか“ホッ”と
しなかった？
Was that a... chuckle?

<Maya>
えっ？
What?

あ、い、いえそんな‥‥！
N-no!

‥‥‥‥
...

ば‥‥バレちゃいました？
It wasn't very
believable, was it?

<Phoenix>
（な‥‥なんでだあ‥‥）
(Not really...)

<Maya>
あ、す、すいません！
I-I'm sorry!

せっかく力づけようとして
くださってるのに‥‥
I just thought, since
you'd made a joke...

あの、気にしないで
がんばってください！
Please, don't mind me!
You're doing just fine!

<Phoenix>
（こっちが元気づけられて
　しまった）
(Who's trying to
cheer up who here!?)

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥だって。
I knew it.

し‥‥信じてもらえるわけ、
ないもん‥‥あたしのこと。
No one will believe me.

<Phoenix>
え？
What?

<Maya>
あのときの、弁護士さんの目。
“こいつが犯人だ”って‥‥。
Even you--when you found me
in the office. You looked at
me like I had done it!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥彼女を見たとき、ぼくは
　そんな顔をしてたのか‥‥）
(Did I look at her
like that?)

い、いや！　そんなことは‥‥。
No, no! I never thought...

<Maya>
あ。‥‥いいんです。
ムリしなくても‥‥。
I-it's okay.
I understand.

‥‥‥‥
...

うん。‥‥それに、
あたし、聞いちゃったから。
And... I've also heard
about you.

<Phoenix>
え？　何を？
Heard...? Heard what
about me?

<Maya>
実は、この前、お姉ちゃんと
電話で話したの‥‥。
I... was talking to my sister
on the phone the other day...


<Mia>
“今日はね、私の部下の
　初舞台だったの”
"Today was my junior partner's
first time in court."

<Maya>
へー！　そうなんだ。
で、で、どうだった？
Wow! Really?
How'd that go?

<Mia>
“それはもう、あらゆる意味で
　大騒ぎだったわ”
"It was quite the scene!"

“正直、ヤバかったわ。
　‥‥こんなこと、ひさしぶり”
"Honestly, I was on edge
the whole time. It's
been a while..."

<Maya>
えー！　そうなんだ。
デキの悪いブカなんだね？
Hah! So, he crashed and
burned?

<Mia>
“‥‥彼は天才よ”
"...He's a genius."

“まさに《恐怖のツッコミ男》と
　いったところかしら”
"One of those 'strike fear
into the hearts of evil'
types..."

“彼にたりないのは、
　‥‥そう、ケイケンだけ”
"The only thing he's lacking
is... experience."

<Maya>
ふーん。
Huh, sounds like it was fun!

じゃあ、あたしに何かあったら、
おねがいしちゃおうかな！
Well, I know who to go to if
I ever get into trouble now!

<Mia>
“いい？　真宵”
"I don't know, Maya."

“今は、まだダメ。
　あと３年待ちなさい”
"I think you might want
to wait... give him three
more years."

“無罪になりたかったら‥‥ね”
"That is, unless you want
to be found guilty."

<Maya>
‥‥って。
That's what she said!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
‥‥あ！　す、すみません。
I-I'm sorry!

シツレイなこと言っちゃって。
I didn't mean to
trouble you...

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。
ホントのことだし。
No, it's okay.
It's true, I guess.

‥‥でも、やっぱり
じっとしていられないんだ。
But... at the same time,
I can't just sit and watch!

千尋さんを、あんな目にあわせた
ヤツのこと、考えると。
When I think of the person
who did this to Mia...

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

弁護士さん‥‥。
I know...




<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

あの‥‥！
Um...!

<Phoenix>
ん？　どうしたの？
Huh? Something the matter?

<Maya>
すみません‥‥。おねがいしたい
ことがあるんですけど‥‥。
Um... I was wondering,
could I ask you a favor?

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
...?

<Maya>
このメモ、えらい弁護士さんの
住所なんです。
This is the address of
a famous lawyer.

昔、お姉ちゃんが
書いてくれて‥‥。
My sister gave me
this a long time ago.

困ったときは、この方に頼めば
だいじょうぶだ、って。
She said if I was ever in
trouble, I should call him.

<Maya>
それで‥‥、
And, well, I'm in trouble.

よかったら、弁護をおねがいして
いただきたいな、って‥‥。
Do you think you could go
ask him to represent me?

<Phoenix>
（どうしよう‥‥？）
(Hmm...)



<Phoenix>
ああ、いいよ。
頼んできてあげる。
Sure, why not?
I'll go ask.

<Maya>
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!

あたし、他に頼める人が
いなくて‥‥。
I have no one 
else to turn to...

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
...?

そういえば、ご両親とかは‥‥？
Say, what about
your parents?

<Maya>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
そ、そうか。
‥‥うん。ぼくにまかせて。
I... I see.
Don't worry, leave it to me.

<Maya>
お願いします。
‥‥明日、１０時からです。
Thank you!
The trial's tomorrow...
at 10:00.

<Phoenix>
え、ええっ！　‥‥あ、明日！
W-what!? Tomorrow!?

<Maya>
はい。
Tomorrow.

<Phoenix>
も、もしこの人に断られたら、
どうするんだよ！
What if this guy refuses!?


<Phoenix>
‥‥悪いけど、
I'm sorry...

そういうことは、
自分でやった方がいいと思うよ。
I think this is the kind
of thing you should really
do yourself.

<Maya>
‥‥そうですよね。
...You're right.

‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
どうしたの？
Something wrong?

<Maya>
実は、警察の人におねがいして、
何度も連絡してみたんです。
Actually, I asked the police
to contact him, and they
tried calling a few times.

全然‥‥つかまらなくて。
Nobody could get
a hold of him!

<Phoenix>
つかまらない？
They couldn't find him?

<Maya>
あたし、もう‥‥
相談できる人、いないんです。
I have no one left to ask!

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
...?

そういえば、ご両親とかは‥‥？
Say, what about
your parents...?

<Maya>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
わ、わかった！
ぼくが行ってみるよ。
O-okay! Don't worry,
I'll go ask him for you.

<Maya>
ほ、ほんとですか！
ありがとうございます！
Y-you will?
Thank you so much!

<Phoenix>
‥‥でも、もし、その先生に
会えなかったら、どうするの？
I'm just worried what will
happen if I can't find him.


<Maya>
そのときは、国で選んでくれた
弁護士さんが来るそうです。
They told me that if I don't
find one, the state will pick
an attorney to defend me.

<Phoenix>
それは、いつ？
When will that happen?

<Maya>
今日の４時まで
待ってもらっています。
They're giving me until
4:00 this afternoon.

<Phoenix>
（面会時間、ギリギリだな‥‥。
　もう、時間がないぞ）
(And visiting hours are almost
up... I'd better hurry!)

わかった。また来るよ！
Right, I'll be back!




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors
the visitor's room.

さっきから、まったく動かない。
さすが、プロだな。
He hasn't moved an inch.
A real pro, this guy.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile for the camera...




<Phoenix>
事件があった日のこと、
聞かせてくれないかな。
Could you tell me about
the day of the murder?

<Maya>
はい！
Yes!

‥‥ええと。あの日の朝、
お姉ちゃんから電話がありました。
Let's see... that morning,
I got a call from my sister.

今度の裁判の証拠品を
あずかってくれ、‥‥って。
She wanted me to hold onto
a piece of evidence for an
upcoming trial.

<Phoenix>
証拠品？
Evidence?

<Maya>
はい。‥‥《考える人》の置時計。
Yes. That clock shaped like
"The Thinker."

<Phoenix>
（‥‥矢張の作った、
　例のヤツか。）
(The one Larry made...)

でも、なんであんなのが
証拠品なのかなあ‥‥？
How could that have been
evidence in a case?

<Maya>
えーと‥‥
なんででしたっけ‥‥。
Um, right, she said
something about that...

‥‥‥‥
...

あっ、そうだ！
I remember!

よかったら、そのときの
お姉ちゃんの話、聞きますか？
Do you want to hear it
in her own voice?

<Phoenix>
えっ、聞けるの？
H-her own voice!?

<Maya>
はい。
Yes.

あの、あたしの携帯電話に、
そのときの会話が‥‥
I'm pretty sure our
conversation is on
my cell phone.

<Phoenix>
録音してあるんだ！
You recorded it!

<Maya>
はい！
‥‥消し方を知らないから‥‥。
Yeah! I forgot how to
delete those things.




<Phoenix>
‥‥あのさ。前から
ちょっと気になってたんだけど。
There's something I've
been wanting to ask you...

<Maya>
はい？
Yes?

<Phoenix>
どうして
そんなカッコウを‥‥？
What's with that outfit?

<Maya>
あ、これですか？
Oh, this?

これは、見習いの修行者が
着る‥‥装束の一種、です。
This is what all acolytes
wear. It's my uniform, you
could say.

<Phoenix>
見習い？　修行者？
‥‥きみはいったい、なんなんだ？
A-acolytes? Like people in
religious training? What is
it you do?

<Maya>
‥‥あ！　べつにあたし、
アヤシイ者じゃないですよ！
Oh! It's nothing
strange, really!

ただの霊媒師です。
‥‥修行中の。
I'm a spirit medium.
...In training.

<Phoenix>
れ、れいばいしぃ？
（じゅうぶんアヤシイ‥‥）
A s-spirit medium!?
(I'm pretty sure that
qualifies as strange.)




<Phoenix>
きみは、修行中の身なんだ‥‥
その、霊媒師の。
So you're an acolyte.
A, er, medium-in-training.

<Maya>
そうですよ。
That's right.

綾里家は、とっても
霊力が強い家系で、特に女性は‥‥
The Fey family, especially the
women, have always been very
sensitive to the spirit world.

<Phoenix>
ちょっと待って‥‥！
あ、“綾里家”？
Wait a second, you said
the "Fey Family"?

ってことは‥‥千尋さんも？
So, Mia was into
this stuff too?

<Maya>
もちろん！
Of course!

“きゃりあうーまんになる”って、
急に山を下りちゃったけど‥‥
She left the mountain to
"follow her career," she said.

お姉ちゃんの霊力、ホント、
シャレにならなかったんですよ。
Her powers were first-
class, too!

<Phoenix>
（し‥‥知らなかった‥‥
　あの千尋さんが‥‥）
(I... I had no idea.)

ん？
Hmm...

‥‥待てよ。
Wait...!

<Maya>
なんですか？
What?

<Phoenix>
ホンモノの霊媒師なんだよね？
So, you're a real, honest-
to-goodness spirit medium?
With E.S.P. and all that?

<Maya>
はい。
‥‥修行中ですけど。
Yes.
...In training.

<Phoenix>
じゃあ、千尋さんの霊を
呼び出せばいいじゃないか！
Well, can't you contact
Mia's spirit, then?

本人に直接、
誰に殺されたか、聞いてみようよ。
We can just ask
her who killed her!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

す、すみません‥‥。
I-I'm sorry...

なにぶん、
修行中の身ですから‥‥。
I'm still in training.

そんな大それたこと、
とてもとても‥‥。
I couldn't do something
on that level...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ。
　そんなウマい話、ないか）
(Hmm... I thought that
would be too easy.)




<Phoenix>
その、携帯電話に録音されている
会話だけど、
So, you say you have a
conversation with your
sister on your cell phone?

さっそく、聞かせてよ！
Let's hear it!

<Maya>
はい！
Right!

‥‥あれ？
Oh!

そうだ。電話、あの刑事さんが
持っていっちゃいました。
I just remembered: that
detective took my cell phone.

‥‥すみません‥‥。
Sorry.

<Phoenix>
あ、そう。
（‥‥そりゃ、そうだな）
Oh, right.
(Of course...)

わかった。今度、刑事さんに
会ったら、聞いてみるよ。
Next time I see Detective
Gumshoe I'll ask him for it.

<Maya>
じゃあ、わすれないように、
メモを書きますね。
I'll write you a note so
you don't forget, okay?

<Phoenix>
あ、ありがとう。
Sure, thanks.

< >
《真宵のメモ》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Maya's Memo added
to the Court Record.




<Maya>
‥‥すみません。
特に心当たり、ないです。
Sorry... I've never
seen that before.




<Phoenix>
これ、所長のそばに
散らばってたんだけど‥‥
This was lying next
to the chief's body...

<Maya>
はい。
あたしも見ました。
I saw that too.

たぶん、電気スタンドの
カケラかな、って。
They said they thought
these were pieces of a
broken light stand.

<Phoenix>
うん。たぶん、そうだね。
Yeah, that seems
about right.

（でも、ガラス製の電気スタンド
　なんて、めずらしいな‥‥）
(Though I'd never heard
of a glass light stand
before this...)




<Phoenix>
あの、凶器のことなんだけど。
I wanted to ask you
about the murder weapon...

<Maya>
お姉ちゃん、かわいそう‥‥。
Poor Sis... *sniff*

<Phoenix>
（‥‥これについては、
　あまり聞かない方がいいな）
(Hmm. Better not ask
her about this now.)




<Phoenix>
携帯電話のことだけど‥‥。
I wanted to ask you
about your cell phone...

<Maya>
あの刑事さんが
持っていっちゃいました。
That detective took it
when they brought me in.

<Phoenix>
（あの刑事か‥‥）
(So, Gumshoe took it...)

（今度見かけたら、返してくれって
　頼んでみよう‥‥）
(I'll have to try to
get it back next time
I see him...)




<Phoenix>
あの領収書、覚えてる？
Remember that receipt?

<Maya>
‥‥あ、あたしの名前が
書いてあったやつですか。
Y-you mean the one
with my name on it?

<Phoenix>
心当たりは‥‥
Any idea why she...

<Maya>
ゼッタイありません！
Absolutely none!

‥‥あの。
Um...

信じてくれますか？
Do you trust me?



<Phoenix>
信じるよ。
I trust you.

<Maya>
‥‥どうしてですか？
Why?

あたしがやったんだ‥‥って、
考えないんですか？
Don't you think
I did it, too?

<Phoenix>
考えない。
No, I don't.

（‥‥カン、だけどね）
(It's just a hunch, but...)

<Maya>
‥‥刑事さんたちは、
信じてくれなかった‥‥。
That detective
thinks I did it.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...




<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Maya>
やっぱり、
信じてくれないんですね。
I didn't think
you'd believe me.

刑事さんたちと、いっしょだ‥‥。
You're just like
the detective.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ごめん。
I'm sorry...

いいかげんななぐさめを
言うのは、キライなんだ。
I don't like lying just to
make people feel better.

でも、きみがやったと
決めつけてるわけじゃないよ。
But it doesn't mean that
I've decided you did it!

（‥‥あの姿を見てるからな）
(She seemed so lost
at the crime scene.)




<Maya>
あっ！
Hey!

ど、どうでした？
弁護士の先生‥‥？
What is it? Did you
meet the lawyer?

<Phoenix>
ご、ごめん。
Sorry.

まだ、会えないんだ。
I haven't seen him yet.

<Maya>
そうですか‥‥。
I see...

<Phoenix>
（そうだな‥‥。行ってみるか、
　エラい弁護士さんの事務所に）
(Hmm. I'd better go see
if I can find this elite
lawyer she's talking about.)




<Phoenix>
事件があった日のこと、
聞かせてくれないかな。
Could you tell me about
the day of the murder?

‥‥イヤなこと、思い出させて
悪いけど。
Sorry... I know
it must be hard.

<Maya>
気にしないでください。
No, it's okay.

最近は、その話ばっかり
くり返していたから、
All I've been doing the
last few hours is talking
about it.

少し、慣れちゃいました‥‥。
I've kind of gotten
used to it...

‥‥ええと。あの日の朝、
お姉ちゃんから電話がありました。
Let's see... that morning,
I got a call from my sister.

今度の裁判の証拠品を
あずかってくれっていう話で‥‥。
She wanted me to hold on to
a piece of evidence for an
upcoming trial.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥矢張が作った、
　例の《考える人》か）
(That's "The Thinker" clock
that Larry made.)

（ある種、連続殺人犯とも
　いうべきシロモノだな）
(It practically qualifies
as a serial murderer by now.)

それで、事務所に着いたのが‥‥？
So then, when did you
arrive at the office?

<Maya>
ちょうど、９時ぐらいでした。
It was right around 9:00.

電気が消えていて、
そして‥‥血のニオイがして‥‥、
The lights were off and...
I could smell blood.

そ、そして、
お、お、おねえちゃんが‥‥。
Th-then I found her.
My sister...

<Phoenix>
わ、わかった。
Thanks, Maya.

もういいよ‥‥ありがとう。
That's all I need
to hear for now.




<Phoenix>
‥‥あの。家族は‥‥？
What about your family?

<Maya>
お姉ちゃんだけ、でした。
I only had my sister.

父は、小さいころに亡くなって、
My father died when
I was very young.

母は、どこにいるのか‥‥
わかりません。
And I don't know
where my mother is.

<Phoenix>
（わからない‥‥
　死んだわけじゃないのか？）
(Don't know...?
So she could still be alive?)




<Maya>
あたしたち綾里家の女は、代々、
霊媒師として生きてきたんです。
The women in my family have
been mediums for generations.

綾里の血は、強い霊力を
宿しているから‥‥。
They say that E.S.P.
runs in our blood.

今から、１５年ぐらい前。
About fifteen years ago,

あたしたちは、ある事件に
巻き込まれました。
our family was involved
in an... incident.

そして、ある１人の男によって、
母は‥‥
There was a man,
and he... he...

‥‥母は、破滅‥‥したんです。
He ruined our mother's life.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥破滅‥‥？）
("Ruined"...?)

<Maya>
そして母は、姿を
消してしまいました。
After that, she disappeared.

それから数年後、
Several years after that,

お姉ちゃんは“弁護士になる”と
言って‥‥山を下りたんです。
my sister announced she would
"become a lawyer" and she
left the mountain.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

じゃあ、今は１人で‥‥？
So, you live by yourself?

<Maya>
そうですね。
もう、慣れちゃいましたけど。
Yes.
I've gotten used to it.

それに。
Oh, also...

あたしが一人前にならなきゃ、
綾里の霊力が消えちゃうし。
I had to become independent,
or I would lose my E.S.P.!

<Phoenix>
（この子‥‥ずっと、１人ぼっち
　なのか‥‥）
(I feel bad for her,
all by herself up
on that mountain...)




<Phoenix>
その、きみのお母さんを
破滅させた男、って‥‥？
So, who was this man
who, um, "ruined" your mother?

<Maya>
今から１５年ぐらい前‥‥。
ふしぎな殺人事件がありました。
About 15 years ago...
there was an unusual
murder case.

世間は、その話題で
大変なさわぎだったそうです。
It made quite a stir,
everyone was talking
about it, apparently.

警察は、どんな手を使ってでも
犯人を逮捕したかった‥‥。
The police were running out
of leads, and they were
getting desperate...

<Phoenix>
まさか‥‥、それで‥‥霊媒を？
Wait... they didn't use
a spirit medium, did they?

<Maya>
警察に説得されて、
母は、被害者の霊媒をしました。
The police convinced my mother
to try to contact the victim.

<Phoenix>
へえ、すごいな。
‥‥じゃあ、事件は？
Wow...
So, what happened?

<Maya>
解決しました。
‥‥一度は。
The case was solved...
we thought.

<Phoenix>
“一度は”？
You "thought"...?

<Maya>
母の言葉で逮捕された男は、
無実だったんです。
The man my mother helped
the police capture was
innocent.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Maya>
このことは、すべて極秘で
すすめられていました。
The police's consultation with
a medium had all been carried
out in secret, of course.

‥‥でも。
But...

それをスクープした
男がいたんです。
A man found out about it
and leaked it to the press.

その男は、大々的にマスコミを
動かして、母をインチキだ、って。
He told all the papers that
my mother was a fraud, and the
media jumped on it big time.

‥‥母は‥‥日本中の‥‥
笑いものに‥‥。
She... my mother... became
the laughing stock of the
nation.

<Phoenix>
‥‥なるほどね。
I see.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥コナカ‥‥。
White...

<Phoenix>
え、コナカ？
Excuse me? White?

<Maya>
その男の名前。
‥‥お姉ちゃんから‥‥。
That was his name.
My sister told me.

<Phoenix>
‥‥コナカ‥‥。
White? Hmm...




<Phoenix>
あの、凶器のことなんだけど‥‥。
Um, about the weapon...

<Maya>
お姉ちゃん、かわいそう‥‥。
Poor Sis...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥これについては、
　あまり聞かない方がいいな）
(Hmm. Best not to talk
about that subject 
right now.)




<Phoenix>
携帯電話のことだけど‥‥。
About your cell phone...

<Maya>
ああ‥‥。
Yes.

あれには、お姉ちゃんと
話したことが録音されています。
It has a recording of the
conversation I had with my
sister on it...

そうか‥‥考えてみたら、
Say...

あれがあれば、またお姉ちゃんの
声が聞けるんだ‥‥。
If I listened to that,
I could hear my sister's
voice again.




<Phoenix>
ほら‥‥携帯電話。
もらってきたよ。
Hey, I got your
cell phone back.

<Maya>
あ、あの‥‥。
Oh! Say...

お姉ちゃんの声、
聞かせてもらえますか‥‥？
Can I listen
to my sister's voice?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

（‥‥真宵ちゃんは、目を閉じて
　千尋さんの声に聞き入っている）
(Maya's eyes closed...
She listened to every word
with such intensity...)

（やがてその目に涙があふれ、
　こぼれ落ちていった）
(Before long, tears began
to roll down her cheeks.)

‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ありがとう‥‥。
Thank you.




<Phoenix>
あの領収書、覚えてる？
Do you remember
the receipt?

<Maya>
‥‥あ、あたしの名前が
書いてあったやつですか。
Oh, you mean the one
with my name on it?

<Phoenix>
心当たりは‥‥
Any idea why...

<Maya>
ゼッタイありません！
Absolutely none!




< >
９月　６日　午後３時４２分
留置所　面会室
September 6, 3:42 PM
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Phoenix>
や、やあ。
Hiya.

<Maya>
あっ！
どっ、どうでした！
Oh!
You're back!

会えました？
‥‥弁護士の先生に！
Did you find the lawyer?

<Phoenix>
うん‥‥まあね。
（どうしよう）
Um... well...
(What do I tell her?)

あ、あのさ。
（とても、正直に話せない！）
Well, see...
(Just be honest!)

や、やめた方がいいと思うなあ、
あの先生だけは。
I... I really don't think
you should use that guy.

ぐあい悪そうだったよ。
ガリガリにヤセ細っていて。
He... didn't seem healthy.
He was all skin and bones!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

何があったんですか？
What really happened?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
もしかして‥‥
断られたんですか‥‥？
You don't mean...
He refused to help?

<Phoenix>
‥‥う。
Urp.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

そうなんだ‥‥。
I see.

見捨てられちゃったんですね、
あたし‥‥。
I've been abandoned, then.




<Maya>
あ。そろそろ、国選弁護士の先生が
来る時間‥‥。
Just a little longer now
before the state-appointed
lawyer comes, I guess...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

（４時。タイムリミットか）
(4:00 PM. Time's up.)

（‥‥どうする？）
(What should I do?)

（この子を見捨てて、
　このまま帰るのか？）
(Do I just leave her
and go home...?)



<Phoenix>
（‥‥ぼくに、できることは
　もう、ないよな）
(There's nothing left
here for me to do...)

（国選弁護士がついた方が、
　この子のためになるはずだ）
(She'll be better off with
a state-appointed lawyer.)

‥‥じゃあ。帰るよ。
I think I'd better
get home now.

<Maya>
‥‥さよなら。
Good-bye.

<Phoenix>
そして、数日後。
It was a few days later when
I found out how the story
ended.

ぼくは、裁判の結果を
新聞で知った。
The result of the trial
was in the newspaper.

有罪だった。
"Guilty."

もう、彼女に会うことは
ないだろう‥‥二度と。
I'll probably never
meet her again.

‥‥これで、
正しかったんだろうか？
Did I make the
right choice?

ほんとうに、
よかったんだろうか？
Will I ever know?

千尋さん‥‥教えてよ‥‥。
Mia... if you can hear
me, please, tell me!

‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
なんてことになったら
どうするんだよ！
Not! I can't let
that happen!

やっぱり、このまま
帰るわけにはいかない！
I'm not leaving here until
she takes me as her lawyer!


<Phoenix>
‥‥決めた！
I've made up my mind!

きみがなんと言おうと、
ぼくが弁護をする。
I'm going to defend you
whether you want me to
or not!

<Maya>
！
!

どうして？
Why?

<Phoenix>
どうしてって？
‥‥それは、
Why?
Well...




<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

（味方が１人もいない悲しさ、
　そして孤独な感じ）
(No one is as sad as a
person without any friends.)

（実はぼくにも、おぼえがあった。
　‥‥遠い、昔の話だ）
(I know... I've been there.
A long time ago.)

（そもそも、ぼくはなぜ、
　弁護士になったのか‥‥？）
(Why did I become a lawyer
in the first place...?)

（そういう孤独な人の味方になれる
　唯一の存在が、弁護士だからだ）
(Because someone has to look
out for the people who have
no one on their side.)

‥‥真宵ちゃん。
Maya...

ぼくは、きみの味方だから。
見捨てることは、できない。
I won't abandon you.
You can count on me.


<Phoenix>
犯人はきみじゃない。
他にいる。
You aren't the culprit!
Someone else is!

<Maya>
え‥‥。
どうして、わかるんですか？
H-how do you know?

<Phoenix>
う。‥‥そんな気が、する。
I, um, I have a hunch...

（たしかに、この真宵ちゃんを
　犯人と考えるのは、カンタンだ）
(Given the evidence, it would
be easy to assume that Maya
was the killer.)

（でも、なんとなく気になる
　ことがあるのも、たしかだ）
(But there's something
about this whole thing
that smells... fishy.)

（ぼくをバカにしたような、
　あの妙な目撃証人‥‥）
(That witness's strange
behavior... was that
all an act?)

（依頼を断った弁護士の、
　あの不自然な態度‥‥）
(And the way that lawyer
refused to help out Maya...)

（そして何より、この子には
　味方が１人もいない）
(But more than all that,
she has no one left
to help her!)

（味方が１人もいない悲しさ、
　そして孤独な感じ）
(Nothing is more sad,
or more lonely than that.)

（実はぼくにも、おぼえがあった。
　‥‥遠い、昔の話だ）
(I know... I've been there.
A long, long time ago.)

（そもそも、ぼくはなぜ、
　弁護士になったのか‥‥？）
(Why did I become a lawyer
in the first place...?)

（そういう孤独な人の味方になれる
　唯一の存在が、弁護士だからだ）
(Because someone has to look
out for the people who have
no one on their side.)

‥‥真宵ちゃん。
Maya...

ぼくは、きみの味方だ。
ぜったい見捨てたりしない。
I won't abandon you.
You can count on me.


<Phoenix>
‥‥正直なところ、
よくわからないよ。
To be honest,
I don't know.

<Maya>
わからない‥‥？
You don't know?

<Phoenix>
（目の前の少女は、
　本当に犯人なのか‥‥？）
(Is this girl sitting in
front of me the killer?)

（証拠品は、そうであることを
　示しているように見える）
(All the evidence
seems to say "yes.")

（だが、なんとなく気になる
　ことがあるのも、たしかだ）
(But there's something
about this whole thing
that smells fishy.)

（ぼくをバカにしたような、
　あの妙な目撃証人‥‥）
(That witness's strange
behavior... was that
all an act?)

（依頼を断った弁護士の、
　あの不自然な態度‥‥）
(And the way that lawyer
refused to help out Maya...)

（そして何より、この子には
　味方が１人もいない）
(But more than all that,
she has no one left
to help her!)

（味方が１人もいない悲しさ、
　そして孤独な感じ）
(Nothing is more sad,
or more lonely than that.)

（実はぼくにも、おぼえがあった。
　‥‥遠い、昔の話だ）
(I know... I've been there.
A long, long time ago.)

（そもそも、ぼくはなぜ、
　弁護士になったのか‥‥？）
(Why did I become a lawyer
in the first place...?)

（そういう孤独な人の味方になれる
　唯一の存在が、弁護士だからだ）
(Because someone has to look
out for the people who have
no one on their side.)

‥‥ぼくの中で、１つだけ
ハッキリしてることがあるよ。
There's only one thing
I know for certain.

ぼくは、きみの味方だ。
見捨てることは、できない。
I won't abandon you.
You can count on me.


<Maya>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥弁護士さん‥‥。
That's so kind of you...

‥‥う、うう‥‥
*sniff*...

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
‥‥さて。
Well!

そういうことだから。
よろしくね。
Let's fight this one
and get you out of here!

<Maya>
は、はい！
こちらこそ、おねがいします！
R-right!
Thank you!

<Phoenix>
（なんか、見違えるように
　元気になったぞ）
(Whew, she smiled at last.
She looks like an entirely
different person!)

最後に確認するけど、
“無実”と信じていいんだね？
One last question...
You are innocent, right?

<Maya>
はい！
Yes!

あたし、弁護士さんを信じます。
And I trust you...

だから、弁護士さんも‥‥。
So you trust me,
too, okay?

<Phoenix>
うん。わかった。
It's a deal.

（さて‥‥。）
(So, what next...)

（こうなると、確認しなきゃ
　ならないことがあるな）
(There's something that's
been bugging me...)

（あのアヤシイ女の、
　引き出しの中‥‥）
(Just what was inside
that strange woman's
drawer?)

（あの女の態度が変わったのは、
　引き出しを調べたときだけだ）
(It was when I tried to
look into the drawer that
she got all defensive.)

（何かあるに、ちがいない！）
(There has to be
something in there!)

<Maya>



<Phoenix>
ほら‥‥携帯電話。
もらってきたよ。
Hey, I got your
cell phone back.

<Maya>
あ、あの‥‥。
Oh! Say...

お姉ちゃんの声、
聞かせてもらえますか‥‥？
Can I listen
to my sister's voice?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

（‥‥真宵ちゃんは、目を閉じて
　千尋さんの声に聞き入っている）
(Maya's eyes closed...
She listened to every word
with such intensity...)

（やがてその目に涙があふれ、
　こぼれ落ちていった）
(Before long, tears began
to roll down her cheeks.)

‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ありがとう‥‥。
Thank you.




<Phoenix>
‥‥どうやら、真宵ちゃんは
今、取り調べを受けてるみたいだ。
Hmm... Maya's not here.
She must be in questioning.

しばらく、会えそうにないな。
They probably won't let
her out for a while.

とりあえず、あの弁護士先生の話、
もう少し聞いておくか‥‥。
Maybe I'd better go talk
to that lawyer again.




< >
９月　６日　某時刻
板東ホテル　３０３号室
September 6
Gatewater Hotel - Room 303

<April>
あらあ。
いらっしゃーい。
Well!
Hello there, handsome.

<Phoenix>
は、はあ。
（なんか、調子くるうなあ）
Umm... hi.
(Smooth, Wright, real smooth.)

<April>
あなた、弁護士さんよね？
刑事さんから、お電話あったわ。
You're the lawyer, aren't you?
The detective told me...

“なんにもしゃべっちゃダメッス”
‥‥って。
He said, "Don't say nothing
to that lawyer, pal!" Tee hee!

<Phoenix>
（あの刑事‥‥よけいなこと、
　してくれるよ‥‥）
(Memo to self: thank
Detective Gumshoe for
making my job harder.)

<April>
なんかぁ、映画みたいねぇ！
Gee! This is all like
something out of a movie!

梅世、ちょっぴりコーフンぎみ？
みたいな。
It's all so exciting
I can hardly contain
myself!

あん。ちょっと待っててね。
お化粧してくるから。
Ooh! Let me go freshen up
so I can look the part of
the beautiful eyewitness!

<Phoenix>
（“あん”って言われても‥‥）
(I pity the lawyer that
has to cross-examine
this one.)




<Phoenix>
（この引き出し、ドライバーが
　挟まっているけど‥‥）
(There's a screwdriver
stuck in this drawer.)

（何が入ってるんだ？
　見てみよう‥‥）
(I wonder what's inside?
Let's take a look...)

<April>
ちょ、ちょちょっと！
Hey! H-h-hey!!!

何してんのよアンタ！
さわるんじゃないわよ！
What are you doing!?
No touching!

あ、ああら‥‥いやぁん。
Oooh. Bad boy!

ひ、ヒトの部屋を
カッテにいじるなんて、
Y-you really shouldn't
pry around in other
people's rooms, now.

梅世、信じらんなぁい！
You wouldn't want to
make me upset, would you?

<Phoenix>
（い、今、一瞬だけ、
　カオつきが変わったぞ！）
(Upset!? I thought she
was going to explode
for a second there!)

（あの引き出し‥‥
　何が入ってるんだろう‥‥？）
(I wonder what could be
inside the drawer?)




<Phoenix>
思ったとおり、造花だ。
The flowers are fake,
as expected.

ひまわりとチューリップ以外、
ぼくは花の名前は知らない。
I know sunflowers and tulips,
but that's about the extent
of my floral knowledge.




<Phoenix>
テーブルの上には、ボトルと
２つのグラス。
A bottle and two glasses 
are on the table.

誰か、いっしょに
泊まっているのだろうか。
Somebody must be
staying with her.




<Phoenix>
窓からは、夏の終わりの日差しが
降りそそいでいる。
The late summer sunlight
streams through the window.

すぐ目の前には、もちろん
綾里法律事務所が見える。
There's the Fey & Co.
Law Offices building,
of course.

たしかに、部屋の中まで
丸見えだけど‥‥、
You can see the inside of
the room pretty clearly 
from here.

誰がいるか、まで見わけるのは
むずかしいと思う。
I think it would be a little
difficult to recognize a face
from this distance, though.




<Phoenix>
シンプルなデザインの
ベッドだ。
A simple bed.

きちんと整えられていて、
目を引くところはない。
It's been recently made.
Nothing eye-catching here.




<Phoenix>
静物画‥‥あれ？　“生物画”
だったっけ？
Ah. A still-scene painting.
Wait, should that be
"still life"?

まあ、そんなような絵が
かかっている。
Whatever. One of those
is hanging on the wall.







<Phoenix>
（何が入ってるのか、
　気になるなあ‥‥）
(Hmm... what's inside
I wonder?)

<April>
コホン、コホン。
*cough* *cough*

<Phoenix>
（‥‥今はダメだな‥‥）
(Maybe later...)




<Phoenix>
事件があったとき
あなたが何を見たのか、
Do you think you 
could tell me something?

聞かせてくれませんか？
I need you to describe what
you observed at the time of
the incident.

<April>
えー。いやぁん、
そんなカタ苦しい聞きかた。
Ooh. "Observe," "incident"!
You sound just like a lawyer
in the movies!

もっと、なかよく
やりましょうよぅ‥‥。
I like a man with
a big... vocabulary.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥うむむ）
(Umm... *gulp*
Better not encourage her.)

あー。事件があったときの
ことなんだけどさあ。
Er... you know that thing
that occur... um... happened
the other day? The bad thing?

きみー、何か
見ちゃったんだろお？
What did you see
when it happened?

ボクにさあ、
教えてくれないかあ？
I don't suppose you
could tell me about it?
Pretty please?

<April>
‥‥や。
Let me see...
Um, well...
Dream on!

聞きたかったら、明日の
法廷に来ればぁ。
If you want to know, you'll
just have to come to the
court tomorrow, Mr. Lawyer!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とほほ‥‥）
(Oh boy.)




<Phoenix>
あの。そもそもあなたは、
どういう方なんですか？
Um, could you... just
who exactly are you?

<April>
うわあ！　なあに、
クドいてるの、あたしをー？
Oooh, Mr. Lawyer!
Are you hitting on me?

<Phoenix>
ち、ち、ちがいますよ！
し、仕事で聞いてるんです！
N-n-no! Hey! I'm just
doing my job here!

<April>
きゃー、かっわいー。
テレちゃってもお！
Tee hee! You know, you're
cute when you blush.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥今だかつて、ここまで
　赤面したことがあっただろうか）
(Believe me, this is the
first time in my life I've
blushed this much...)

え、えへん。
Umm... eh heh.

えー。し、仕事は、何を
されてるんですか。
Right... can you just tell
me what it is you do?

<April>
‥‥教えない。
Well...

バッカみたい。
言うワケ、ないでしょー。
No! Tee hee!
And you had your little
hopes up, didn't you!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とほほ‥‥）
(Oh boy.)




<Phoenix>
あの、テーブルに
グラスが２つあるけど、
I see there are two
glasses on the table.

誰か、いっしょに
泊まってるんですか？
Is someone staying
here with you?

<April>
うっわあ、スルドい推理！
Oooh! What amazing
powers of observation!

あなたって、メータンテー？
みたいな！
You must be one of those
famous detectives, like
on television!

<Phoenix>
い、いやあ、そんな。
大したことじゃあ‥‥。
Oh, no, not me,
I'm, er, just a lawyer!

<April>
探偵は、ウラでゴミでも
あさってればぁ。
Say, Mr. Big Detective, why
don't you go look for clues...
in the garbage? Hmm?

梅世、センサクされるの、
好きくない？　みたいな。
Miss May doesn't like
nosey little lawyers...
Hmph!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥とほほ‥‥）
(Oh boy.)




<April>
あたし、証人なのよ？
ケンサツ側の。わかるぅ？
Excuse me, but I'm
a witness? Police
witness? You understand?

あなたの役に立つ情報なんか、
あげるわけないでしょー？
How could I possibly give you
any information in good
conscience, hmm?

刑事さんに“めっ”て
言われちゃうしぃ。
Me... "the witness"!
It's just like the movie!




<Bellboy>
いらっしゃいませ。
Good afternoon, sir!

<Phoenix>
あ、あなたは？
Excuse me, you are...?

<Bellboy>
あ。申し遅れました。
Ah, I beg your pardon, sir!

ワタクシ、このホテルの
ボーイでございます。
I am the bellboy of
this establishment,
at your service, sir.

<Phoenix>
は、はあ。
Oh, right.

<Bellboy>
ルームサービスをお届けに
上がったしだいでございます。
I've just come up to
deliver room service, sir.

<Phoenix>
‥‥あの。梅世さんは？
Um... do you know where
Miss May might be?

<Bellboy>
‥‥は。お客様は今、
バスルームでございます。
Ah. I believe our guest 
Miss May is currently using
the, er, facilities...?

では。シツレイいたします。
If you've no need of
anything, I'll be
taking my leave.

ま。どうぞごゆっくり、
おたのしみを‥‥。
Please, stay as long as you
like. Enjoy...

<Phoenix>
え。
Yeah...

い、いや違う‥‥！
Wait... no! Hey!

‥‥‥‥
...

（‥‥ここに来るたび、
　ヒドい目にあってばかりだ）
(Why does it seem like every
time I come here, I end up
embarrassing myself?)

（しかし、部屋を調べる
　絶好のチャンスだな！）
(Wait... now's my chance
to snoop around a bit!)

<Bellboy>
あ、そうそう、そうでした。
Ah, I almost forgot!

<Phoenix>
わっ！
‥‥な、何？
Gah!
Y-you came back quick!

<Bellboy>
お客さまに、お電話があったことを
伝えていただけますか？
Might I ask you to inform
Miss May that there is a
message for her?

株式会社《コナカルチャー》の
小中様からでございます。
Please tell her that
Mr. White, of Bluecorp phoned.

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
Oh, right. Sure.

<Phoenix>
（“コナカルチャーの小中”‥‥？
　なんか、引っかかる名前だな）
(Mr. White... of Bluecorp?
Where have I heard that name?)

<Maya>
‥‥コナカ‥‥。
White...

<Maya>
その男の名前。
‥‥お姉ちゃんから‥‥。
That was his name.
My sister told me.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥お母さんを破滅させた
　男の名前‥‥か‥‥）
("White" was the name of the
guy who ruined Mia and
Maya's mother!)

（‥‥コ・ナ・カ‥‥。
　偶然なのか‥‥？）
(Could it be a coincidence?)




<Phoenix>
やっぱり、
松竹　梅世はアヤシイぞ！
There is definitely 
something suspicious
about this "Miss May"!

こんなものを持って、
ホテルに泊まっているなんて‥‥。
Why would she have something
like this in her hotel room?

ぜったい、何かウラがあるに
違いない！
There's a story behind all
this, I know it!

よし‥‥。
Alright...

明日の法廷は、コイツも武器にして
戦ってやるぞ！
I'll be using this bit of
evidence in tomorrow's
trial, that's for sure.

真宵ちゃんのためにも‥‥
For Maya's sake...

絶対に、この女の正体を
あばいてやる！
I'll get to this woman's
bottom! Wait... I mean
... you know what I mean.

<April>
ボーイさあん。
‥‥まだいるのぉ？
Oh, bellboy...?
Still there?

<Phoenix>
（おっと。そろそろ退散するか！）
(Uh oh, time to scram!)

（明日、また遊ぼうぜ梅世さん！）
(I look forward to tangoing
with you tomorrow, Miss May!)

（‥‥法廷でな！）
(In court!)


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.


<Phoenix>
ドライバーが引っかかって
引き出しが半開きになっている。
There's a screwdriver sticking
out of that half-open drawer.

今のうち、中を調べておこう‥‥
Now's my chance to
see what's inside!

‥‥‥‥！
...!

こ、これは！
What do we have here!

と、盗聴器‥‥だよな。
間違いなく。
A... wiretap?
Hmm!

あの女、なんでこんなものを‥‥？
What would a woman like her
be doing with a thing like this?

< >
証拠品《盗聴器》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Wiretap added to
the Court Record.




< >
９月　６日　某時刻
星影法律事務所
September 6
Grossberg Law Offices

<Phoenix>
（受付によると、大先生は
　“外出中”らしい）
(According to the
receptionist, the 
big boss is "out".)

（いつ戻ってくるかは
　わからないそうだ）
(She couldn't say
when he'd be back.)

（‥‥それにしても、
　ヤリ手の弁護士ともなると、）
(It must be hard to keep
track of everything when
you're a famous lawyer...)

（事務所も大変なことに
　なってるなあ）
(Not to mention run an
office like this.)

（‥‥まあ、またあとで
　来てみるか‥‥）
(I guess I'll just have
to come back later.)




<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ。大先生は
　お出かけ中、か‥‥）
(Hmm... seems like Mr.
Grossberg is out.)

（しかたない、もう少ししてから
　また来るか‥‥）
(Well, maybe I should
just wait here for him
to come back.)

<???>
ウォッホォン！
*Ah-HHHHEM!*

<Phoenix>
（お‥‥この、エラそうなヒト
　特有のセキ払いは‥‥）
(If that wasn't the most
over-the-top clearing of the
throat I've ever heard!)

<Grossberg>
あー、チミかね。
ワシを待っておるというのは。
Ah hah! So, you're the
one they say has been
looking for me?

<Phoenix>
あ、は、はい。
（思った以上にエラそうな先生だ）
Uh... y-yes, that's me!
(He looks even... grander
than I imagined!)

<Grossberg>
ん‥‥そのエリのバッジ‥‥。
Hmm...? That badge
on your collar...?

なんぢゃい。弁護士かねチミも。
Ah, so you're a lawyer,
are you now?

<Phoenix>
え、ええ、まあ。
Y-yes, well... yes.

<Grossberg>
‥‥で、何かねチミ？
And what do you want?

最近はヒマだから、話を
聞いてやろうぢゃないか。
I'm not particularly busy
these days... Please, proceed!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ヒマだって？　じゃあ、
　なぜ連絡がとれなかったんだ？）
(Not busy...? Then how come
no one could get in touch
with you?)

<Grossberg>
ん？　どうした？
Hmm? Something the matter?

この星影　宇宙ノ介
（ほしかげそらのすけ）が、
You came to see the
one-and-only Marvin
Grossberg, did you not?

話を聞いてやろうと
言っとるんぢゃよチミ？
Well, here I am, boy!
What do you want?
Out with it!

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥実は、綾里　真宵さんの件
で来たんですけど‥‥。
Um... w-well, sir, actually,
it's about Maya. Maya Fey.

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

あ、綾里　真宵‥‥ねえ。
Ah... yes. Maya Fey.
Go on.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんだ？
　ようすがオカシイぞ‥‥）
(Hmm?
Why the strange reaction?)

<Grossberg>
あー‥‥。
A-cha-cha.

ワシは、そう。
忙しいんぢゃよチミ。
I'm really quite
busy here, son.

いきなり明日と言われても‥‥。
ムリぢゃな、ムリ。
I can't go taking cases
on a day's notice!
No, it's quite impossible.

<Phoenix>
ちょっと待ってください！
W-wait a second!

なぜ、“明日”って
知ってるんですか？
How did you know the
trial was tomorrow!?

<Grossberg>
むぐぐ‥‥。
Urk? Ahem!

と、とにかく。
A-anyway...

ダメぢゃ。その件だけは、
ぜーったい、引き受けられん！
I'm afraid it's entirely
impossible for me to represent
her. Sorry. End of discussion.

<Phoenix>
（ど、どうなってるんだ？
　話が違うぞ‥‥！）
(What's going on!? He refused
me before I even got a chance
to ask him!)

（真宵ちゃんに、なんて言えば
　いいんだよ‥‥）
(What do I tell Maya...?)




<Phoenix>
さっきから、ずっと
気になってたんだよ、あの絵。
That painting has been
bugging me ever since
I stepped in here.

あつくるしいほどコッテリした
アブラ絵だ。
The oil paint is so
thick it's practically
giving me a stuffed nose.

お値段の方も、さぞかし
コッテリしているんだろうな。
I'm sure the price is
nothing to sneeze at
either, for that matter.




<Phoenix>
マホガニー製のどっしりした
デスクだ。
A solid mahogany desk.

深いツヤが出るまで
みがき込まれている。
The wood's been polished
to a deep luster.




<Phoenix>
来客用のテーブルだ。
A table for clients.

上品な黒檀のシガレットケースと、
純金製のライター、か？
Hmm... an elegant ebony case,
and if I'm not mistaken, that
lighter's made of solid gold.

なんだかわからないけど、
高そうなことに間違いはない。
Even I can tell someone
here's got money to burn.




<Phoenix>
最高級の観葉植物だ。
An expensive potted plant.

名前はわからないが、
どうせ高いんだろう。
No idea what kind of plant it
is, but it's probably the
most expensive one available.




<Phoenix>
マホガニー製の高そうな本棚に、
高そうな本がズラリ。
Expensive-looking mahogany
bookshelves, filled with
expensive-looking books.

‥‥でも、あまり読まれたような
あとがないのが気になるな‥‥。
Hmm... funny... they don't
look like they've ever been
read.




<Phoenix>
どうして断るんですか！
理由を聞かせてください！
How can you just refuse
like that! Please, tell me
why you won't take the case!

<Grossberg>
い、いや、その‥‥
だから、忙しい‥‥からぢゃ。
Hmm? Eh, ahem! Well, you
see it's just... I'm busy,
you see!

<Phoenix>
依頼人は、綾里　千尋さんの
妹さんですよ！
But the client is
Mia Fey's sister!

<Grossberg>
う‥‥うむむ‥‥。
Hmm... ahem.

<Phoenix>
千尋さんは、あなたを信頼して
彼女をお願いしたんです。
Mia trusted you... She knew
her sister would be in good
hands.

<Grossberg>
そんなことは、わかっておる‥‥。
Yes, yes, of course
I know that.

ぢゃが‥‥
However!

すまないが、
引き受けるわけには、いかん。
I'm sorry but, I must
refuse. Sorry. Good-bye.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ヒドい人だな‥‥。
Creep.

わかりました。
Fine.

時間がない。
‥‥他を当たることにします。
I don't have time to argue
with you anyway. I'll go
look elsewhere.

<Grossberg>
‥‥ぢゃ。
*grumble*... Think not.

<Phoenix>
？　何か言いましたか？
Huh? Did you say something?

<Grossberg>
‥‥ムダぢゃ、と言った。
I think not, I said.

<Phoenix>
ど、どういうことですか？
Wh-what do you mean?

<Grossberg>
気の毒ぢゃが‥‥その依頼、
I'm terribly, terribly sorry.

まともな弁護士ならば、決して
引き受けることはない。
But I'm afraid that no lawyer
worth their salt will take
on this particular case.

‥‥まこと、モウシワケないが。
Terribly sorry, m'boy.

<Phoenix>
な、なぜです！
Why!?

<Grossberg>
それは‥‥言えん。
I...
I cannot say.

‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

悪いが、帰ってくれんか。
もう話すことはない。
I beg your pardon, but could
you leave? Now? I've nothing
more to discuss with you.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どういうことなんだ！）
(What's going on here!?)




<Phoenix>
千尋さんとは、どういう‥‥？
How did you know
Mia Fey...?

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥
...

彼女は、ここにおったんぢゃよ。
‥‥昔な。
She... worked here.
A long time ago.

すごい子ぢゃった‥‥。
Quite the apprentice,
that one.

あっという間に、ワシの
テクニックを身につけてな。
Learned my techniques
in the blink of an eye!

ある日、突然
ここを出て行きおった‥‥。
She left one day,
quite suddenly...

あの子には“やるべきこと”が
あったんぢゃ。
She had a mission, you see.

<Phoenix>
“やるべきこと”‥‥？
A "mission"?

<Grossberg>
あの子の目はいつも、それを
まっすぐに見すえておったよ。
You could see it in her eyes.

決して、
ゆらぐことはなかった。
She followed it with
a burning passion.
Never looked back, that one.




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥すごい絵ですね。
That's... quite a painting.

<Grossberg>
おお！　よく聞いてくれたな！
Ahah! You noticed!

ワシのごじまんの絵ぢゃ！
すんばらしいぢゃろ？　ぢゃろ？
It's my pride and joy!
Impressive, isn't it?
Well? ISN'T IT?

この空の色！　この海の色！
このムギワラぼうしの色！
The color of the sky!
The hue of the sea!
The weave of the straw hat!

３億か４億の値がついとるが、
ワシゃ、手ばなすつもりはないぞ！
It's worth at least three
million. I have no intention
of parting with it, of course.

ああ。ぜーったい、売らん！
‥‥チミにもな！
No, I won't sell it!
Not even to you!

<Phoenix>
（買うつもりもないよ‥‥）
(I wasn't interested...)

<Grossberg>
売らんぞ！
It's not for sale!

<Phoenix>
買いません！
I'm not buying!
(Geez!)




<Grossberg>
悪いが、この件については、
何も言うことはできんのぢゃ。
Very sorry, but I've
got nothing to say
regarding this matter.



