< >
１０月１９日　午前９時４２分
地方裁判所　被告人第１控え室
October 19, 9:42 AM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 1

<Will>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

あ、あの‥‥成歩堂さん。
Umm... Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
はい？
Yes?

<Will>
さっきから、なんで
そんなケワしいカオを‥‥？
Why do you look
so... unhappy?

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥いえ。ははは。
O-oh! Oh, nothing!
Eh heh heh.

なんでもないですよ‥‥
Really, it's nothing.

ね、千尋さん‥‥。
Right, Mia?

（‥‥うわ、コワいカオ‥‥）
(Uh oh. She looks even
unhappier...)

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

あなたの依頼人は今、
ほとんど死にかけているわ。
Your client is now practically
a dead man walking...

そういう意味で、彼には
とても親近感をおぼえるわね。
Perhaps that's why I feel
particularly close to him.

<Phoenix>
悪い冗談はやめてくださいよ‥‥。
This is no time for dead-
people jokes, please.

<Mia>
今回は、こちらに武器が
まったくないわ。
You know we're going into this
trial utterly defenseless.

でも、荷星さんが本当に
無実ならば、
Yet, if Mr. Powers is
truly innocent...

私たちは、どこかで
見落としをしているはず‥‥。
We should be able to find
something overlooked in the
evidence to prove it.

<Phoenix>
“見落とし”‥‥。
Something "overlooked"...?

<Mia>
この法廷で、それを
見つけ出せなければ、
We have to find something,
Phoenix, today.

私たちは負けるわ。
‥‥今日中に、かならず。
It's that, or lose the trial.

<Phoenix>
（キビシイ戦いになるな‥‥）
(This isn't going to be easy.)

< >
１０月１９日　午前１０時
地方裁判所　第４法廷
October 19, 10:00 AM
District Court
Courtroom No. 4

<Judge>
これより、荷星　三郎の
法廷を開廷します。
The court is now in
session for the trial
of Mr. Will Powers.

<Edgeworth>
検察側、
準備完了しております。
The prosecution is ready,
Your Honor.

<Phoenix>
弁護側も、
準備完了しています。
The defense is ready,
Your Honor.

<Judge>
では、御剣検事。
冒頭弁論をおねがいします。
Very well. Mr. Edgeworth, your
opening statement, please.

<Edgeworth>
昨日の法廷で、意外な事実が
あきらかになった。
An unexpected fact has come
to the attention of the court.

事件当日、英都撮影所には、
他にも関係者がいた、という。
Yesterday, we learned that
there were other people
present at the studios!

今日は、彼らが、事件には
関係なかったことを証明したい。
Today, I would like to show
evidence proving they had
nothing to do with the murder.

<Judge>
‥‥わかりました。
Very well.

では、さっそく証人を
呼んでいただきましょう。
You may call your first
witness, Mr. Edgeworth.

<Phoenix>
（あのプロデューサーが
　出てくるのかな‥‥）
(I wonder if that producer
is going to come out...)

<Edgeworth>
最初の証人、宇在　拓也を
入廷させていただきたい。
The prosecution calls
Mr. Sal Manella to the stand.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥カントクが来たか‥‥）
(... or that director.)

<Edgeworth>
証人。名前と職業は？
Will the witness state
his name and profession?

<Manella>
‥‥‥‥。
...

なんだよぅ。
シッケイだなぁ！（怒）
How r00d can j00 get! 

ボクを知らないのかよぅ！
J00 don't know ME!?

カントクだぞぅ！　トノサマンは、
ボクが作ってるんだぞぅ！（爆）
I'm the director! I make
the Steel Samurai, n00b! ROFL!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Manella>
う、宇在　拓也。
カ、カントクしてます。テレビの。
S... Sal Manella.
I'm a director.
Television.

<Judge>
証人は事件当日、
英都撮影所にいたんですね？
Were you at Global Studios
on the day of the murder?

<Manella>
は、はい。
Y-yes, Your Honor.

<Judge>
‥‥ふむう。
Hmm...

では、その日のことを
《証言》してもらいましょうか。
Very well. Please testify
to the court about the
events of that day.

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

まずは、この証人の証言を
くずしましょう。
Let's start by picking this
testimony apart.

荷星さんが犯人でないとしたら、
If Powers is innocent,
you know what that means.

あやしいのは、あの日コテージに
いた人たちですから。
Someone in the trailer
on that day did it!

<Phoenix>
は、はい。
（いきなりプレッシャーだ‥‥）
R-right.
(She doesn't waste any time
putting on the pressure!)

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
 -- The Day of the Murder --

<Manella>
あの日は、朝の９時ごろ、
英都スタジオに入ったけど。
I was at the studios from
around 9:00 that morning.

午前中は、んーと、アクションの
打ち合わせ、かな。（考）
During the morning, I was
doing... umm... an action
scene run-through.

なんか、思ったより、時間が
かかっちゃったんだよなあ。
It took a lot more time
than I thought it would.

おヒル、みんなはスタッフエリアで
ゴハン食べたみたいだけど。
I hear that everyone else
ate lunch in the Employee
Area...

コテージでカイギがあったから、
ボク、食べられなくて。
But I had a meeting in the
Studio Two trailer, so I ended
up skipping lunch.

カイギは、ケッキョク
４時までやってたのかな。
We were in the meeting
until around 4:00...

カイギ中は、‥‥えーと、誰も
席を、その、立たなかったな。
During the meeting, well,
I'm pretty sure no one
left their chairs.

<Manella>
‥‥そんなところかな。
That's about it.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

被害者のイブクロさんが
殺害されたのが、２時３０分ごろ。
The time of Mr. Hammer's
death was 2:30 PM.

そのころは、会議中だったわけ
ですか‥‥。
And according to your
testimony, you were in
a meeting at that time.

では、弁護人。
‥‥《尋問》を。
Mr. Wright, you may begin
your cross-examination.

<Phoenix>
はい。
Yes, Your Honor.

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
 -- The Day of the Murder --




<Manella>
あの日は、朝の９時ごろ、
英都スタジオに入ったけど。
I was at the studios from
around 9:00 that morning.


<Manella>
午前中は、んーと、アクションの
打ち合わせ、かな。（考）
During the morning, I was
doing... umm... an action
scene run-through.


<Manella>
なんか、思ったより、時間が
かかっちゃったんだよなあ。
It took a lot more time
than I thought it would.


<Manella>
おヒル、みんなはスタッフエリアで
ゴハン食べたみたいだけど。
I hear that everyone else
ate lunch in the Employee
Area...


<Manella>
コテージでカイギがあったから、
ボク、食べられなくて。
But I had a meeting in the
Studio Two trailer, so I ended
up skipping lunch.


<Manella>
カイギは、ケッキョク
４時までやってたのかな。
We were in the meeting
until around 4:00...


<Manella>
カイギ中は、‥‥えーと、誰も
席を、その、立たなかったな。
During the meeting, well,
I'm pretty sure no one
left their chairs.


<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

このアリバイが成立しちゃったら、
荷星さんはオシマイよ。
If his alibi holds,
Powers is finished.

なんとかゆさぶって、
‥‥情報を引き出すの。
Press him as hard as
you can and find out
where he's lying!

<Phoenix>
は、はい！
R-right!

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
いつも、その時間に？
Is that when you always
come in to work?

<Manella>
いやあ。‥‥時間はバラバラかな。
それが“ギョーカイ人”だよ。
Oh, oh no. I come in all
sort of hours. It's the
"industry" way.

<Phoenix>
（“ギョーカイ人”って、
　そういう意味だったのか‥‥）
(Yeah, I know all about
the freaks in your
"industry"...)

<Manella>
でも、あの日は１日、
忙しかったなあ‥‥。（泣）
Still, FWIW, I was pretty
busy all that day. :(

<Edgeworth>
それを聞かせていただきたい。
Tell us more about that.

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
スタッフエリアで？
In the Employee Area?

<Manella>
そうだよ。
That's right.

トノサマンとアクダイカーンの
決闘シーン。
It was a fight scene between
the Steel Samurai and the
Evil Magistrate.

<Phoenix>
その打ち合わせ、
他には、誰がいましたか？
Was anyone else at
the run-through?

<Manella>
そういえば、警備員のオバチャン
が、じーっと見ていたなあ。（笑）
Oh, yeah. That security lady
was sitting there watching
the whole thing. LOL.

イブクロちゃんに
茶色い声援を送っていたよ。
She was cheering on Hammer,
if you can believe it.

<Phoenix>
（“茶色い声援”ねえ‥‥）
(She certainly has the
lungs for it...)

他には、誰も‥‥？
Anyone else?

<Manella>
うん。‥‥それだけ。
Nope, just us four.

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
それは、どうしてですか？
Why did it go on so long?

<Manella>
えーと、知ってると思うけど。
Um, I'm pretty sure j00've
already heard about this...

ニボサブちゃんが、
足をヒネっちゃって。
But WP twisted his ankle
during the run-through, see...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ああ。
　そんな話があったな‥‥）
(Oh, right, thus the limp.)

<Manella>
おかげで、おヒル、
食べそこなっちゃった。（恨）
Which of course led to me
missing my lunch. ROFS!

<Phoenix>
“おヒル”‥‥ですか。
(ROFS? Rolling on the Floor...
Starving?)

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
“ゴハン”ですか。
メニューは、何を‥‥？
What exactly did they
have for lunch?

<Manella>
ホネつきステーキだよ。
‥‥スタッフに焼かせてさぁ。
T-bone steak!
The assistant cooked some up.

<Phoenix>
（そういえば、スタッフエリアに
　ホネの乗った皿があったっけ）
(Come to think of it, there
was a plate with some bones
on it in the Employee Area.)

<Edgeworth>
“みんなは食べた”ということは、
証人は食べなかったというわけだ。
"Everyone else" meaning
that the witness did not
eat with them.

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
じゃあケッキョク、ホネつき
ステーキは食べずじまいですか？
So, in the end, you didn't
get to eat?

<Manella>
そうなんだよ。ステーキはね。
‥‥ヒドい話だろ？
Yeah. No steak, at least!
Can j00 believe it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥はあ。
That must have been tough.

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

<Phoenix>
はい？
Yeah?

<Mia>
今の話、どう？
オカシイと思わない？
Doesn't something about
that seem odd to you?




<Phoenix>
そうですね。‥‥別に、
オカシイとは思いませんけど。
Well, no, not really.
Seems pretty straightforward.

<Mia>
そう。‥‥私の思い違いかしらね。
Oh. Perhaps I was wrong, then.

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
ええ。実は、ちょっと
気になることがあるんですよ。
Actually, there is something
bothering me.

<Phoenix>
カントク。今、“ステーキは”
食べなかったと言いましたが、
Mr. Manella, just now you
said "steak, at least."

それ以外のものは
食べたわけですか？
So you ate something
other than steak?

<Manella>
お！　よくわかったねぇ！
Yeah, good call!

ポケットにチョコがあったからさ。
それで、飢えをしのいだんだ。
I had some chocolate in
my pocket, which I used to
stave off starvation!

<Phoenix>
‥‥な、なるほど。
I see...

（たいしたことじゃなかったな‥‥
　もっと何かあると思うんだけど）
(Is that all? I was sure
I was on to something there.)

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
そうですね。たしかにヘンです。
Yeah, it does seem odd,
now that you mention it.

<Phoenix>
カントク！
Mr. Manella!

<Manella>
え、えっ！
な、なんだよぅ‥‥（汗）
H-hmm?
W-what do j00 mean? *sweats*

<Phoenix>
ぼくがコテージに行ったとき、
テーブルの上には、
When I went to that trailer,
I saw something on the table.

スタッフエリアと同じ皿が
２人前、ありましたよ。
There were two plates on the
table--the same kind of plates
as in the Employee Area.

あれは、誰が食べたんですか？
Who ate lunch there?

<Manella>
う、うがッ！
M-mmpf!

いや、あの、その、どの、この
‥‥よ、よくわかったねぇ。（汗）
No, er, ah, um, eh
heh. Good call! *sweats*

その‥‥はずかしいから
言わなかったんだケド‥‥。
I, er, I was embarrassed so
I didn't mention it...

食べたんだよね、ケッキョク。
But I did eat, after all.

<Phoenix>
ホネつきステーキを、ですか。
A t-bone steak, you mean?

<Manella>
まァね。せっかくスタッフに
焼かせたんだし。
Yeah, well, I mean the
assistant went through
all that trouble...

あとで食べようと思って、
持って行ったから、コテージに。
I brought it to the trailer,
thinking I could eat it later.

<Phoenix>
（食いイジが張ってるなあ‥‥）
(Clearly a man who likes
to eat. I'd suspected
as much...)

で？　いつ食べたんですか？
So, when exactly did
you eat it?

<Manella>
カイギ中に、１回だけ
休憩があったからさ。
We took one break during
that meeting.

そのときに、ペロリと。（汁）
I, er, wolfed it down then.
*drool*

<Phoenix>
（キタナイなあ‥‥）
(A mental image I will carry
with me to my grave...)

（でも‥‥待てよ）
(Wait a second...!)

（休憩をとったとなると、証言に
　おかしいところが出てくるぞ）
(If they took a break in that
meeting, that contradicts
his testimony!)

（‥‥もう一度、そのへんを
　ゆさぶってみるか‥‥）
(I'll press on that one
a bit more...)

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
なんの話をしていたんですか？
What were you discussing?

<Manella>
トノサマンの、これからの
ストーリーとか、予算のこと。
The Steel Samurai story,
and our budget.

スポンサーの連中、
このボクに向かってさぁ、
Get this! The sponsors turn
to me and say, "Mr. Manella."

“キミの書くシナリオは、コドモ
向けじゃないねえ”だって。
"Those scripts of yours are
not appropriate for children."
Can j00 believe it!?

<Phoenix>
（なんか、わかる気がする‥‥）
(Actually, I kind of can.)

あの。誰か途中で席をはずしたり
しなかったんですか？
So, nobody left the table
during the whole meeting?

<Manella>






<Phoenix>
一度も休憩を
とらなかったんですか？
You didn't take a single
break?

<Manella>
えーとぉ‥‥。
Er... well...

そ、そうさぁ！
とらなかったぞぉ！（汗）
Y-yeah!
Not a one! *sweats*

<Phoenix>
（‥‥“（汗）”がちょっと
　気になるけど‥‥）
(Hmm... what's he sweating
so much about, I wonder?)

（キメ手がないからなあ‥‥）
(If only I had an idea...)

（何かつかんでから、あとで
　もう一度、ゆさぶってみるか）
(I'll wait for one to come
up and hit him with it
later.)


<Phoenix>
一度も休憩を
とらなかったんですか？
You didn't take a single
break?

<Manella>
えーとぉ‥‥。
Er... well...

そ、そうさぁ！
とらなかったぞぉ！（汗）
Y-yeah!
Not a one! *sweats*

<Phoenix>
（‥‥“（汗）”がちょっと
　気になるけど‥‥）
(Hmm... what's he sweating
so much about, I wonder?)

（キメ手がないからなあ‥‥）
(If only I had an idea...)

（‥‥って、待てよ！）
(Wait a second...)

（なんか、引っかかるような‥‥）
(Maybe I do have an idea!)



<Phoenix>
（‥‥いや。気のせいだろ）
(No, on second thought,
I'm drawing a blank.)

（ヘタにつっかかって、気を悪く
　させるのもなんだし‥‥）
(If I press too hard in the
wrong place, I'll just end
up scaring him into silence.)

（うん。ここは、ようすを見よう）
(Maybe I'll just sit back
and see what happens.)


<Phoenix>
ちょっと待ってください！
Wait a second!

カントク！　‥‥さっきあなたは、
こう言いましたね？
Mr. Manella, you've just
contradicted yourself!

“休憩中にステーキを食べた”と！
Didn't you just tell the court
that you ate that t-bone
steak during a break?

<Manella>
あッ！
Oops! ROFL!

<Phoenix>
どうなんですか！
Well?

<Manella>
‥‥う、うう。
Umm...

<Judge>
証人。‥‥どうなんですか？
Mr. Manella, what's this
all about?

<Manella>
ま、まあ‥‥。
とったかな‥‥休憩。
W-well, yeah, I guess
we did take a little break.

<Mia>
なるほどくん！
よくやったわ！
Phoenix!
Great job!

休憩をとったなら、そのあいだに、
スタジオに行けたかもしれない！
If they took a break, one
of them could have gone to
the studio during that time!

<Phoenix>
裁判長！
Your Honor!

休憩時間について、
《証言》をおねがいします！
I call on the witness to
testify to the court about
this break!

<Judge>
わかりました。
Very well.

では、証人。
《証言》をおねがいします。
Mr. Manella, your
testimony, please.

<Manella>
ひいぃ‥‥。
Urk!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥クックックッ‥‥。
Heh heh heh...

<Phoenix>
（笑ってるよ‥‥）
(Uh oh. Edgeworth is
laughing...)

< >
～“休憩”について～
-- The Break --

<Manella>
たしかに、休憩は
とったけどさあ‥‥。（爆）
Yeah, FWIW, we took a break...
ROFL!

たった１５分だよ、１５分。
But it was only 15 minutes!
15! That's only 13 in Base 12!

第１スタジオで殺人なんて、
できるわけないだろお。（笑）
Not enough time for someone
to, say, commit murder in
Studio One! LOL!

ホネつきステーキ食べてるだけで
終わっちゃうって！（怒）
That's only just enough time
to eat a t-bone steak, if
you ask me! *steams*

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

私なら、ステーキも
食べ終わらないでしょうな。
I don't think it would even
be enough time for that,
but that's just me.

‥‥では、《尋問》を。
Very well. You may begin
the cross-examination.

< >
～“休憩”について～
-- The Break --




<Manella>
たしかに、休憩は
とったけどさあ‥‥。（爆）
Yeah, FWIW, we took a break...
ROFL!


<Manella>
たった１５分だよ、１５分。
But it was only 15 minutes!
15! That's only 13 in Base 12!


<Manella>
第１スタジオで殺人なんて、
できるわけないだろお。（笑）
Not enough time for someone
to, say, commit murder in
Studio One! LOL!


<Manella>
ホネつきステーキ食べてるだけで
終わっちゃうって！（怒）
That's only just enough time
to eat a t-bone steak, if
you ask me! *steams*


<Mia>
どう？　なるほどくん。
Well, Phoenix?

<Phoenix>
こんな短い証言じゃあ、
ムジュンしようがないですよ！
That testimony was too short
to wring any kind of useful
information out of!

<Mia>
とにかく、第１スタジオに
行けたことを証明しましょう！
All you have to do is prove
that he was able to go to
Studio One in that time!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥できるかなあ‥‥）
(Oh, great. Is that all...)

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
その休憩は、
何時にとったんですか！
What time exactly did you
take this break?

<Manella>
えーと‥‥。
Hmm...

たしか、２時３０分から
１５分間だったと思うけど。
I'd say it was from around
2:30 or so until 2:45.

<Phoenix>
（２時３０分！）
(2:30!!!)

（事件が起こった時間だ！）
(That's the time of death!)

（第１スタジオで、衣袋さんを
　殺害して、もどってくる‥‥）
(So he could have gone to
Studio One, killed Hammer,
and come back...)

（時間的には、
　なんとか可能だな‥‥）
(I guess it's possible,
time-wise...)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
その１５分間は、
何をしていたんですか？
What were you doing for
those 15 minutes?

<Manella>
ホネつきステーキを食べていたに
決まってるだろ？
Eating my t-bone steak!
What else!?

<Phoenix>
たしか、コテージのテーブルには、
皿は２枚、ありましたけど‥‥？
There were two plates on
the trailer table...?

<Manella>
ああ、もう１皿は、
姫神さんが食べたんだ。
Oh, right. The other one
was Diva's... sorry, Dee
Vasquez's plate.

<Phoenix>
（姫神‥‥あの、
　プロデューサーか‥‥）
(Dee Vasquez... the producer.)

<Edgeworth>
ホネつきステーキを１５分で食べる
とは、なかなか早い‥‥。
To eat a t-bone steak in
15 minutes... that's quite
a feat.

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
どうしてですか？
Why is that?

<Manella>



<Phoenix>
食べるのは早そうに
見えますけどね。
I have to say, you look like
a guy who gets through his
meals pretty fast.

<Manella>
相手は、さめてコチコチになった
ホネつきステーキだよ。
Well, I was facing a cold,
slightly chewy t-bone steak...

さすがのボクも、ちょっと
手こずったね。（笑）
Even I have to take my time
eating that kind of food. LOL


<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
‥‥もう、イミのない
尋問は、たくさんだ。
Haven't we had enough of this
pointless line of questioning?

裁判長！
Your Honor!

これまでの証言で
アキラカなとおり、
The testimony to this point
has made one certain fact
painfully clear:

コテージにいた人間は、
今回の事件には関係ない！
The people in the trailer
had nothing to do with this
murder!

なぜなら、第１スタジオに
行くのはムリだったからだ！
It was impossible for any
of them to go to Studio One!

<Phoenix>
‥‥何ッ！
What!?

<Edgeworth>
それとも弁護人は、
Something wrong, Mr. Wright?

コテージにいた人間が、
殺人現場に行ったと言うつもりか！
Surely you aren't suggesting
one of the people in the
trailer went to Studio One!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

どうですか？　弁護人。
Well, Mr. Wright?

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
‥‥ここは、大事なポイントよ。
Phoenix, this is critical!

よく考えてね！
Think about it before
you give your answer!

<Judge>
コテージの人間が、第１スタジオに
行ったと主張しますか？
Do you claim someone from the
trailer went to Studio One?



<Phoenix>
（‥‥ここでコテージの人間が
　無関係と認めてしまっては）
(If I agree to let everyone
in that trailer off the hook
then the trial is over...)

（犯人は荷星さんしか
　いなくなってしまう！）
(Mr. Powers will be
found guilty for sure!)

被害者が殺害された２時３０分。
コテージでは、休憩時間でした。
The victim was murdered
at 2:30, the exact time
of the break in the meeting.

１５分も時間があれば、
犯行をすませることは可能です！
With 15 minutes, murder
is certainly a possibility!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

そういう考え方もできますね‥‥。
I suppose you might
say that...

<Phoenix>
（よしよし‥‥。裁判長が
　考え込んでるぞ‥‥）
(Alright, I've got the judge
thinking now!)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥クックックッ‥‥。
Tsk, tsk, tsk...

毎度まいど、笑わせてくれるな、
キミは‥‥。
Never a dull moment with
you, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんだと！
What's your point, Edgeworth!

<Edgeworth>
キミも、それなりに調査は
しているんだろう？
You've been doing your
homework, haven't you?

法廷記録をよく見てみたまえ。
Look at the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
法廷記録‥‥？
The Court Record...?

<Edgeworth>
２時１５分から４時まで、
あの道は通れなかったのだよ？
Surely, you knew that from
2:15 to 4:00 the path between
the studios was blocked?

“サルマゲくん”のクビが
道をふさいでいたのだから！
Mrs. Monkey's head had
fallen across the path!

<Phoenix>
あっ！　そういえば！
Whoa! You're right!

<Edgeworth>
たしかに被害者が死んだ時間、
コテージは休憩に入っていた。
True, the break in the trailer
meeting came right at the
time of death...

しかし！
However!

スタジオへ通じる道は、
ふさがっていたのだ！
The path from there to
the scene of the crime
was blocked!

<Edgeworth>
“サルマゲくん”のクビによって！
The fallen Mrs. Monkey head
barred the way!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥。
...

（ホントは“サルマゲどん”
　なんだけど‥‥）
(It's actually "Mr. Monkey,"
but Edgeworth has a point...)

（それにツッコミを入れる気にも
　なれないな‥‥）
(And somehow, I feel no
desire to correct him.)

<Judge>
返すコトバも
見つからないようですね。
No counter-argument,
Mr. Wright?

あなたの負けですな、弁護人。
Then I'm afraid you lose
this round.





<Phoenix>
（‥‥ここで認めたくは
　ないけど‥‥）
(I don't want to write off
so many possible suspects...)

（ムリだとわかっていることを
　主張するワケにも行かない‥‥）
(But I can't keep claiming
the impossible, either...)

‥‥たしかに、コテージの人間が
スタジオに行くのは、不可能です。
I agree that it was impossible
for anyone in the trailer to
go to the studio in that time.

<Edgeworth>
ハッ！
Ha hah!

いつものように、考えもなく
つっかかってくるかと思えば、
I thought you might be
thoughtlessly treading on
thin ice again!

なかなかモノわかりがいいな‥‥。
But I see you had at least
an inkling of the truth.

<Judge>
どういうことですか？
‥‥御剣検事。
What do you mean,
Mr. Edgeworth?

<Edgeworth>
カンタンなこと‥‥。
It's quite simple...

たしかに被害者が死んだ時間、
コテージは休憩に入っていた。
True, the break in the trailer
meeting came right at the
time of death...

しかし！
However!

スタジオへ通じる道は、
ふさがっていたのだ！
The path from there to
the scene of the crime
was blocked!

“サルマゲくん”のクビによって！
The fallen Mrs. Monkey head
barred the way!

強風によってクビが折れたのは、
２時１５分だった。
At around 2:15, a strong
gust of wind knocked off
the studio mascot's head.

つまり。
Ergo!

２時３０分に休憩をとっても、
あの道は通れなかったわけだ。
When the people in the trailer
took a break at 2:30, the
way to the studio was blocked.

“サルマゲくん”のクビが
あったのだから。
Blocked... by Mrs. Monkey's
severed head!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥。
...

（ホントは“サルマゲどん”
　なんだけど‥‥）
(It's actually "Mr. Monkey,"
but Edgeworth has a point...)

（それにツッコミを入れる気にも
　なれないな‥‥）
(And somehow, I feel no
desire to correct him.)


<Edgeworth>
以上をもって‥‥。
I believe we have seen
enough evidence.

この証人に対する質問は、
終了する。
I would like to relieve
Mr. Manella from the stand.

<Phoenix>
（お、終わっちまったよ‥‥）
(Wh-what? It's over?)

<Judge>
では、
私の意見を申し上げましょう。
Very well.
The court's opinion on this
case is as follows:

事件当日、第２スタジオの
コテージに、数名の人間がいた。
We have found that there were
several other people in Studio
2 on the day of the murder.

しかし、彼らは、第１スタジオに
行けなかったわけだから、
However, it is also clear that
none of these people could
have gone to Studio One.

この事件に関係ないことは
あきらかです。
They therefore have no
relation to this case.

また、このトノサマンの
写真ですが、
Furthermore, with regards
to the photo of the Steel
Samurai...

体格から考えて、被告人以外の
人間は、着ることはできない。
Given the size of the costume,
no one other than Mr. Powers
could have worn it that day.

あとは、このトノサマンが
犯人であるという、
All that is lacking is
decisive evidence that
he is the one who did it.

その決定的な証拠があれば、
それで決まるのですが‥‥。
If we had that, I'm afraid
I would have to find Mr.
Powers guilty.

<Edgeworth>
裁判長。
Your Honor.

当然、検察側は用意している。
‥‥決定的な証人を。
The prosecution is pleased to
announce that we indeed have
decisive evidence: a witness.

<Judge>
御剣検事！　“決定的な証人”
とは、どういう‥‥？
Who is this witness,
Mr. Edgeworth?

<Edgeworth>
彼は、トノサマンが被害者を
殺害した瞬間を目撃しているッ！
My witness saw the very 
moment when the Steel Samurai
skewered the victim!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！
Order! I will have order!

わかりました。
I see.

１０分間の休憩を挟んで、
その証人に話を聞きましょう。
The court will take a 10
minute recess, after which we
will hear your witness.

それでは、休憩に入ります！
Court is adjourned for
recess!

< >
１０月１９日　午前１１時４分
地方裁判所　被告人第１控え室
October 19, 11:04 AM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 1

<Mia>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
ち、千尋さん。
どうしましょう‥‥。
What do we do now, Mia?

コテージの人間は、
事件には無関係、ってことに‥‥。
If everyone in that trailer
has an alibi...

<Mia>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥ゴメンね、なるほどくん。
I'm sorry, Phoenix.

どうやら、
私の見込み違いだったみたいね。
I guess I was wrong.

<Phoenix>
そ、そんな！
M-Mia!

千尋さんがあきらめちゃったら、
ぼくは、もう‥‥！
Don't tell me you're giving
up! If you give up, what
hope do I have...?

<Mia>
‥‥‥‥
...

カン違いしないで。
Don't get me wrong.

私は今まで、あきらめた
ことなんて、一度もないわ。
I've never given up on a trial
before, not while there was
a chance.

今の尋問であきらかになったのは、
ただ１つよ。
Only one thing became clear
in your cross-examination.

“コテージにいた人間は、
第１スタジオには行けなかった”
The people in the trailer
could not have gone to
Studio One.

私、そこに何か秘密があると
思っていたんだけど‥‥。
I thought there was more
to it than that...

そうじゃなかった。
‥‥それだけのことよ。
But I was wrong.

<Mia>
That's all there is.

<Will>
あの‥‥。
Umm...

ボク‥‥、
どうなっちゃうんでしょう？
Er...
What's going to happen to me?

なんだか、もう、法廷中の人たちが
“お前がやったんだ！”って、
It kinda seems like everyone
in that courtroom thinks
I did it...

そう言ってるような気がして‥‥。
They think I'm a murderer!

<Mia>
だいじょうぶです。
Don't worry, Mr. Powers.

あなたが無実ならば、私たちは
かならず、それを証明します。
If you are innocent, we will
prove it. I guarantee it.

私たちにまかせて、
堂々としていてください。
Leave it to us, and... be
yourself. Be strong.

‥‥トノサマンなんですから。
あなたは。
You are the Steel Samurai,
hero to children everywhere,
after all.

<Will>
は‥‥
I...

きょ‥‥
You...

恐縮です。
Thanks.
*sniff*

<Mia>
さあ。なるほどくん。
Okay, Phoenix.

がんばらないとね。
This one's for the kids!

トノサマンが大好きな、
子供たちのためにも‥‥！
Let's do it!

< >
１０月１９日　午前１１時１５分
地方裁判所　第４法廷
October 19, 11:15 AM
District Court
Courtroom No. 4

<Judge>
では、審理を再開しましょう。
Court is back in session for
the trial of Mr. Will Powers.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥検察側としては、
The prosecution has a concern.

まだおさなく、イタイケな小学生を
殺人事件の証人として呼んだうえ、
As our witness is a grade
schooler of tender years,
and this is a murder case...

そこの弁護人に、イジの悪い
質問をさせたくはない‥‥。
We worry that the defense
might cause unnecessary trauma
with his cruel questioning!

<Phoenix>
（好きなコト言いやがって‥‥）
(Nice to see Edgeworth taking
the moral high ground...)

<Edgeworth>
しかし、こうなっては
いたしかたない。
However, we have no choice.

証人として、大滝　九太少年を
入廷させていただこう！
The prosecution calls
Cody Hackins to the stand.

<Edgeworth>
裁判長。
‥‥とりあえず証人に、何か台を。
Your Honor.
Perhaps you could arrange
a box for him to stand on?

<Judge>
そ、そうですね。
Oh, r-right.

係官。
‥‥みかん箱を。
Guard, please bring him a box.
One of those donut crates
should do.

<Edgeworth>
では証人。名前と学年を。
Will the witness state his
name and grade in school.

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
証人ッ！
Witness!

<Cody>
なんだよ！
オトナだからって、イバるなよな！
What!? Just 'cause you're all
grown-up don't mean you can
push me around!

<Edgeworth>
むぐぐ‥‥。
Mrph...

<Mia>
だめよ、九太くん。
Cody?

ちゃんと、質問には答えるの。
Answer his question, okay?

<Cody>
あっ、お姉ちゃん！
H-hey, it's you!
The nice lady!

ボク、大滝　九太。
小学校２年生です！
I'm Cody Hackins.
I'm in 2nd grade!

<Phoenix>
（先が思いやられるな‥‥）
(I get the feeling this is
going to be a long, long
day...)

<Judge>
御剣検事。
Mr. Edgeworth.

相手は子供なんですから、
もっとこう、ヤサシクするように。
Please remember that you're
speaking to a child. Try to
be gentle.

<Edgeworth>
む、むむむむむ。
M-mrrrrph!

‥‥証人。いや、‥‥九太くん。
Witness! Er, I mean,
Cody.

<Phoenix>
（なんか、イタイタしいな‥‥）
(He's having trouble with
this "gentle" thing.)

<Edgeworth>
キミは、その、事件のあった日、
英都撮影所に行ったね？
You were present, er, you 
were at Global Studios on the
day of the, er, incident?

<Cody>
行っちゃ悪ィかよ！
You got a problem with that!?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そのとき見たことを、その。
ワレワレに聞かせてほしいなあ。
Please tell us what you
saw that day.

<Cody>
え？　オジさんと、そこの
エラそうなヒゲのおジイさんに？
What, pops? You want me to
tell you and gramps with
the beard over there?

<Edgeworth>
“おニイさん”だ。
Just... Mr. Edgeworth will
be fine.

<Judge>
“ヒゲのおじさん”です。
I prefer "bearded gentleman"
myself.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(A very long day...)

<Judge>
ところで。
Incidentally,

法廷内は、カメラの持ち込みは
キンシされているはずですが。
photographic equipment is
strictly forbidden in this
courtroom.

<Edgeworth>
う、うむむ。
M-mpht!

“カメラがダメなら証言しない”と
言われてしまったもので‥‥
M-my apologies, Your Honor.
He said he wouldn't testify
if he couldn't bring it...

トクベツに許可していただきたい。
I'd like special permission,
if that's possible.

<Phoenix>
コドモとトリヒキして、
しかも負けるなよ！
Wait, so you're saying you had
to bargain terms with a kid...
and you LOST?

<Cody>
このカメラ、こないだ買って
もらったばっかりなんだぜ！
Hey! I just got
this new camera!

まだ、ちょっと使い方、
よくわかんないんだけどさ！
Don't really know how to
use it all that good yet!

最近は、どこかへ行くときは、
ゼッタイ持っていくんだぜ！
But I bring it with me
wherever I go!

<Mia>
‥‥なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

あのカメラ、ビミョーに
気になるわ‥‥。
I wonder if he had that
camera on the day of the
murder...

ちょっと、法廷記録に
ファイルを作った方がいいわね。
You'd better make a note of
it in the Court Record.

< >
証拠品《九太のデジタルカメラ》の
データを法廷記録にファイルした。
Cody's Camera added to
the Court Record.

<Judge>
では、九太くん。
Very well, Cody.

事件のあった日、見たことを
《証言》してもらいましょう。
Please testify to the court
about what you saw the
day of the incident.

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
-- Witness's Account --

<Cody>
オレ、一度トノサマンのリハーサル
が見たくてさあ。
I wanted to see a Steel
Samurai rehearsal, just once.

インターネットで地図を見て、
あの日、撮影所に行ったんだ。
I found a map on the Internet,
and went to the studios that
day.

警備員のオバチャンに見つからない
ように、道のそとの林を通って、
I went through the woods,
off the path, so that old
lady wouldn't catch me.

オレ、とにかく
スタジオに行こうとしたんだ。
I was going for the studio.

とちゅう、３０分ぐらい道に
まよっちゃったんだけど。
I got kinda lost on the way,
though. For about 30 minutes.

スタジオのところに出たら、
トノサマンがいたんだ！
When I came out by the studio,
there was the Steel Samurai!

オレ、うれしくて。
見てたら、悪人が出てきてさあ。
It totally rocked!
Right before my eyes,
out came the bad guy!

トノサマンは‥‥モチロン、
その悪人をたおしたよ！
Of course, the Steel Samurai
took him down! Pow!

もしカメラを持っていれば、
シャッターチャンスだったよ。
If I had my camera with
me, that woulda been the
time for a shot, I tell you.

ケッキョク、スタジオには
入れなくて、その日は帰ったんだ。
Anyway, I couldn't get into
the studio, so I went home.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

では弁護人、《尋問》を
おねがいしますが、
Very well. The defense may
begin its cross-examination.

相手は少年です。
‥‥ヤサシクするように。
And, be gentle. Remember
you're talking to a child.

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Phoenix>
（そんな必要、
　ないような気がするけど‥‥）
(This kid is tougher than
most adults we see in here,
honestly...)

< >
～事件があった日のこと～
-- Witness's Account --




<Cody>
オレ、一度トノサマンのリハーサル
が見たくてさあ。
I wanted to see a Steel
Samurai rehearsal, just once.


<Cody>
インターネットで地図を見て、
あの日、撮影所に行ったんだ。
I found a map on the Internet,
and went to the studios that
day.


<Cody>
警備員のオバチャンに見つからない
ように、道のそとの林をとおって、
I went through the woods,
off the path, so that old
lady wouldn't catch me.


<Cody>
オレ、とにかく
スタジオに行こうとしたんだ。
I was going for the studio.


<Cody>
とちゅう、３０分ぐらい道に
まよっちゃったんだけど。
I got kinda lost on the way,
though. For about 30 minutes.


<Cody>
スタジオのところに出たら、
トノサマンがいたんだ！
When I came out by the studio,
there was the Steel Samurai!


<Cody>
オレ、うれしくて。
見てたら、悪人が出てきてさあ。
It totally rocked!
Right before my eyes,
out came the bad guy!


<Cody>
トノサマンは‥‥モチロン、
その悪人をたおしたよ！
Of course, the Steel Samurai
took him down! Pow!


<Cody>
もしカメラを持っていれば、
シャッターチャンスだったよ。
If I had my camera with
me, that woulda been the
time for a shot, I tell you.


<Phoenix>
（それを見て、コワくなって
　家に帰ったわけか‥‥）
(I guess seeing the killing
freaked him out and he went
home...)

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

相手は少年よ。
Remember, he's a child.

あまりキツく言わずに、
でもヨウシャしちゃダメよ。
Use gentle words...
but be firm.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そんなムチャな‥‥）
(Easy for you to say...)

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
そんなにトノサマンが
好きなんだ。
You really like the Steel
Samurai, huh?

<Cody>
アッタリマエだろ！
Course I do!

オレ、テレビはゼンブ、
ビデオに録画してるし、
I've taped every show!

デパートのショーも、
ゼッタイに行くんだ！
And I go to all the live
performances!

<Phoenix>
たいしたもんだね。
That's impressive.

遊園地とかにも行くの？
Have you been to the
amusement park?

<Cody>
アッタリマエだろ！
Course! Duh!

オレのお父さん、
つきあいがいいんだから！
My Dad always takes me!

<Phoenix>
（“オトウサン”か。
　タイヘンな職業だよな‥‥）
(Poor, poor Dad...)

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
スタジオに行ったのは、
あの日が初めてだったの？
Was that day the first time
you'd been to the studio?

<Cody>
実は、何回か行ったことが
あるんだけどさ。
Uh, actually I've been a
couple of times.

まだ、リハーサルの日に
当たったことがないんだよ！
I never manage to get
there on a rehearsal day!

警備員のオバサンは
うるさいしさあ‥‥。
And that security lady's
always yelling...

<Edgeworth>
ほほお。‥‥では、つづきを。
Right, right.
Please continue.

<Cody>
言われなくても話してやるよ。
Chill, pops!
I'm getting to it!

人の話のコシを折るなよな！
How am I supposed to talk
with you cuttin' me off
all the time? Geez!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
“道のそとの林”‥‥？
"Off the path"...?

<Cody>
うん。あの撮影所、山を切り開いて
作っただろ？
Yeah, you know how the
studios are in a valley
there?

だから、ちょっと道をはずれると、
もう林になってるんだよ。
If you go off the path
a little, there's woods.
That's where I was!

<Phoenix>
‥‥なるほどね。
I see.

<Cody>
それでさあ。
Anyhow...

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
スタジオに行くとちゅう、
何か変わったことはなかった？
Did nothing unusual happen
on your way to the studio?

<Cody>
“変わったこと”？
"Unusual"?

<Phoenix>
たとえば、こんなサルは見た？
Did you see this monkey
by any chance?

<Cody>
ああ。“サルマゲどん”ね。
Oh, you mean Mr. Monkey?

そいつは見たけど。
クビは折れてなかったよ！
Yeah I saw him, but
his head wasn't busted!

<Edgeworth>
スタジオには、すぐ
行けたのか‥‥な？
So you went straight
to the studio?

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
林の中でまよったの？
You got lost in the woods?

<Cody>
そうだよ。もう、どこに向かって
歩いてるのか、わかんなくて。
Yeah. I couldn't figure
out which way I was walking.

スタジオの青いトビラが見えた
ときは、ホント、うれしかったよ。
Man, was I relieved when
I saw the blue studio doors.

それでさぁ。
But guess what happened next!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
トノサマンが？
The Steel Samurai?

<Cody>
うん。スタジオの門の
ところにいたんだ。
Yeah, he was standing by
the studio gate.

ちょっと門のところで
何か考えていたみたいだけど、
It looked like he was
thinking about something
before going in.

そのうち、門を開けて、
中に入っていったんだよ。
Then he opened up the gate
and went inside.

<Phoenix>
ふうん。‥‥それから？
I see. What then?

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
“悪人”って、どんなヤツだった？
What sort of "bad guy" was it?

<Cody>
‥‥人間だったよ。
背が高くて、ヤセたヤツ。
A guy. A person.
Kinda tall. Skinny.

<Phoenix>
男？　女？
Are you sure it was
a guy?

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥。
...

わかんない。‥‥遠かったし。
I dunno.
He was kinda far away.

<Phoenix>
（なんだよ。‥‥ハッキリ
　しないな‥‥）
(Huh, he's being awfully
vague...)

<Mia>
‥‥‥‥。
...

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
その悪人は、どうなった？
What happened to the bad guy?

<Cody>
え？
Huh?

ええと‥‥。
Well...

うん‥‥。動かなくなっちゃった。
死んだみたいに、ピクリとも。
Well, he kinda didn't move.
Not a bit. Like he was dead.

さすが、プロのアクションスター
だよね！
I-I guess he's a real pro!
What a great actor!

<Phoenix>
そ、そうだね。
Y-yes, I suppose he was.

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
“もし”カメラを持っていれば？
"If" you had your camera?

なんだ、カメラ、なかったの？
You mean, you weren't carrying
your camera then?

<Cody>
そ、そうだよ。
N-no, I wasn't.

オ、オレだって、いつも
カメラ持ってるわけじゃないさ！
I-it's not like I have
it all the time!

<Phoenix>
（ふーん‥‥？）
(Really...?)


<Phoenix>
九太くん。‥‥今の話、
ちょっとおかしいな。
Cody, what you just said
seems, well, a little strange.

きみ。さっきは、いつでも
デジカメは持ち歩く、って、
Didn't you say before that
you always bring your digital
camera wherever you go?

ハッキリ、そう言ってたじゃない。
You were quite clear about
that.

<Cody>
え！
Huh!?

<Phoenix>
ダメだよ。ウソついちゃあ！
Cody, you shouldn't lie here.
You understand that, right?

<Judge>
弁護人！
‥‥ちょっといいですかな？
Mr. Wright!
A word with you...

<Phoenix>
（しまった。
　‥‥キツく言いすぎたか？）
(Uh oh... was I putting the
pressure on too much?)

<Judge>
なんですか？　
“でじかめ”って？
What is this "digital" camera
contraption you're talking
about?

<Phoenix>
えーと。‥‥“デジタル・カメラ”
のことです。
It's umm... a digital camera,
Your Honor.

最近はやっている、
カメラの一種です。
It's kind of a new sort of
camera.

（セツメイのしようがない‥‥）
(How do I explain that!?)

<Judge>
なるほど。
I see.

<Phoenix>
とにかく。九太くん。
Anyway, Cody...

きみが撮影所に行くとしたら、
カメラをわすれるはずがない！
I can't believe you wouldn't
bring your camera on a trip
to the studios!

‥‥持っていたんだろう？
You did bring it, didn't you?

<Cody>
うう‥‥。
Umm...

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
弁護人ッ！
Mr. Wright!

少年をオドすとは、
見下げはてた男だな！
How cruel you are, to
terrorize a poor child so!

<Phoenix>
少年だろうが検事だろうが、
ウソはよくない！
I don't care if he's a child
or a prosecuting attorney!
No one should lie in court!

<Edgeworth>
なんでそこに“検事”が
出てくるのだ‥‥。
What do you mean
"or a prosecuting attorney"!?

<Phoenix>
どうなのかな、九太くん。
Well, Cody?

<Cody>
な、なんだよ！
Wh-what!

ああ。たしかにカメラは
持ってたよ！
Yeah, so I had my
camera. So what!?

それがなんだってんだよぉ！
You got a problem
with that!?

<Judge>
じゃあ、そのカメラは？
So, you did have a camera?

使わなかったのかな？
And did you use this camera?

<Cody>
つ、使うわけないよ。
W-why would I use it?

‥‥オレ、ムチュウで
見てたから‥‥。
I... I was too busy watching.

<Judge>
ふむう。
Hmm...

では、その“見ていたこと”を
《証言》してもらいましょうか。
Very well. Please testify to
the court about what you were
so busy watching.

< >
～見ていたことについて～
-- What I saw --

<Cody>
た、たしかにカメラは
持ってたけど。
Y-yeah, I had my camera
with me.

もう、イッシュンも目が
はなせなかったんだ。
But I was glued to the
action! I couldn't take
my eyes off it!

トノサマンに悪人が
おそいかかってさあ！
The Steel Samurai, he goes
for the bad guy... wham!

そして‥‥悪人は、
動かなくなったんだ！
Then... then the bad
guy stopped moving!

強いよなぁ！
やっぱり、トノサマンは！
He's so strong!
The Steel Samurai rules!

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

あれ。もう終わりですか。
Ah? Is that all?

‥‥ずいぶんアッサリした
証言でしたね。
Well, that was brief.

‥‥では、《尋問》を。
Mr. Wright, your cross-
examination.

< >
～見ていたことについて～
-- What I saw --




<Cody>
た、たしかにカメラは
持ってたけど。
Y-yeah, I had my camera
with me.


<Cody>
もう、イッシュンも目が
はなせなかったんだ。
But I was glued to the
action! I couldn't take
my eyes off it!


<Cody>
トノサマンに悪人が
おそいかかってさあ！
The Steel Samurai, he goes
for the bad guy... wham!


<Cody>
そして‥‥悪人は、
動かなくなったんだ！
Then... then the bad
guy stopped moving!


<Cody>
強いよなぁ！
やっぱり、トノサマンは！
He's so strong!
The Steel Samurai rules!


<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんか、不自然な
　感じがするんだよな‥‥）
(Something about his account
doesn't seem right...)

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

それは、あの子の証言に、
アイマイなところがあるからよ。
It doesn't seem right
because he's being 
deliberately vague!

そこをトコトンゆさぶって、
ハッキリさせることね‥‥！
Press him on the facts,
Phoenix! Find out what he saw!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
じゃあ、なんで
使わなかったのかな？
So, why didn't you use it?

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
これからそれを言おうとしている。
He's getting to that!

おちついて、聞きたまえ。
Relax and listen.

<Cody>
‥‥えーと。
Umm...

トノサマンのアクションって、
すごくカッコイイからさ！
I didn't use it 'cause
I was too busy watching
the real thing!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
じゃあ、トノサマンが戦ってるのを
ずっと見ていたんだ。
So you were watching the Steel
Samurai. Did you watch the
whole fight?

<Cody>
そ、そりゃあそうさ！
Y-yeah, of course!

<Phoenix>
目をはなさなかったんだね？
You didn't turn away,
not even once?

<Cody>
う‥‥うん！
N... no!

<Phoenix>
じゃあ、聞かせてくれるかな。
‥‥トノサマンの戦いのこと。
Okay, then tell us exactly
what happened.

<Cody>
い、いいぜ！
Y-yeah! I'm getting to that!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
悪人のほうから、
おそいかかったんだね？
So the bad guy attacked
him first?

<Cody>
そうだよ！
Yeah!

<Phoenix>
どんなヤツだった？
その“悪人”って？
What sort of person was
this "bad guy"?

<Cody>
さっき言わなかったっけ？
人間だよ、ニンゲン。
I told you, a person.
He was a person.

<Phoenix>
どんなカッコウをしてた？
How was he dressed?

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥
...

よく、おぼえてないや。
I kinda don't remember.

オレ、トノサマンしか
見てなかったから。
I was too busy watching
the Steel Samurai!

<Edgeworth>
なるほど。
‥‥それで、どうなったかな？
I see.
And what happened next?

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
どうして？
Why?

<Cody>
え？　‥‥何が“どうして”
なんだよ？
Huh? Whaddya mean, "why"?

<Phoenix>
悪人は、どうして動かなく
なったのかな？
Why wasn't the bad
guy moving?

<Cody>
そ、そりゃあ、トノサマンが
やっつけたからだよ。
W-well 'cause the Steel
Samurai brought him to
justice!

<Phoenix>
だから、どうやって
やっつけたのかな‥‥？
And how exactly did he
do that?

<Cody>
ど、どうやって、って‥‥。
H-how did he do it?

トノサマン・キックに
トノサマン・パンチ、
With a Samurai Kick!
And a Samurai Punch!

トノサマン・チョップに
トノサマン・ビンタ‥‥
Samurai Chop!
... Samurai Slap!

‥‥そ、そんな感じかな。
S-something like that.

<Phoenix>
（どうも、このあたりが
　スッキリしないんだよな‥‥）
(He's still being vague
about this...)

<Cody>
なんだよォ！　その目は！
What! Don't gimme that
look, pops!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どうしよう？）
(How should I play this?)



<Phoenix>
（そうだな‥‥）
(Yeah...)

（ヘタに揺さぶって、裁判長の
　心証を悪くするのはマズい）
(If I press too hard now,
the judge might keep me
from continuing.)

（ここは、ようすを見ておこう）
(I'll sit back and see
how the rest of this goes.)

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
悪人をたおしたあと、
九太くんはどうしたの？
What did you do after
the bad guy fell, Cody?

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥。
...

実はさあ。
Um, actually...

その戦いが、すごいハクリョク
だったから、コワくなっちゃって。
The fight was so... so intense
that I got kinda scared.

そのまますぐ、ウチに
帰ったんだ‥‥。
So I went straight home.

<Phoenix>
（うーん‥‥この九太くんの
　証言なんだけど‥‥）
(Something isn't adding
up here...)


<Phoenix>
九太くん。
Cody.

<Cody>
な、なんだよ！
Wh-what!?

<Phoenix>
きみは最初に、こう言ったね。
Something's bothering me.

トノサマンから“イッシュンも目を
はなせなかった”って。
Before you said that you
"couldn't take your eyes
off" the action.

<Cody>
そ‥‥それがなんだってんだよ。
Y-yeah? So what?

<Phoenix>
なのになぜ、一番カンジンな部分
を見ていないんだい？
Yet you missed the
most important part!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
少年は、キチンと証言を‥‥！
What is the meaning of this?
The witness has stated what
he saw quite clearly...

<Objection!>

<Phoenix>
キチンと証言していないことは、
あなたにもわかっているでしょう？
You know as well as I do
that he's being vague!

殺人犯は、ふつう
“トノサマン・ビンタ”はしない！
Tell me, what kind of
murderer uses a "Samurai
Slap"!?

<Edgeworth>
ぐぐぅ！
M-mmph!

<Phoenix>
つまり！
My point is this:

九太くんは、トノサマンの戦いの、
一番重要なところ、
Cody, you may have seen
some of the Steel Samurai's
fight...

テキにトドメを刺すところを
見ていないのです！
But you missed the most
important part: the
killing blow!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！
Order! Order!

弁護人！
Mr. Wright!

しかし、それはタイヘン
おかしなことです！
How could this be?

その理由を、あなたは
説明できますか？
Can you explain how he
might have missed something
so vital?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥、そ、それは‥‥
ちょっと‥‥。
Um, well... er, that's
the thing...

<Mia>
なるほどくん！
Phoenix!

あなたは今、とても
いいセンを行っているわ！
I believe you're on the
right track with this!

“なぜ、九太くんは戦いの
クライマックスを見てないか？”
Think: why didn't Cody see
the climax of the fight?

その理由もわかるはずよ！
あなたなら！
I know you!
You can figure this out!

<Judge>
弁護人！
‥‥答えてもらいましょう。
Mr. Wright,
your answer!




<Judge>
トノサマンの
大ファンである少年が、
We have ascertained that
this young boy is a great fan
of the Steel Samurai...

なぜ、戦いのクライマックスを
見ていなかったのですか！
Why wouldn't he watch
the climax of the fight?




<Phoenix>
九太くんは、見ていることが
できなかったのです！
Because he couldn't watch it!

だってそれは、殺人の瞬間
だったわけですからね！
How could he calmly watch
a murder taking place at 
his age!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
ちょっと待ってほしい。
Just a moment, please...

今までの証言の内容から、
One thing has become quite
clear in this boy's testimony.

少年は、“殺人を目撃した”
と思っていないのは、あきらかだ。
He did not believe he
was witnessing a murder!

彼は、あくまでトノサマンの
戦いを見たつもりでいる。
He was watching the Steel
Samurai fight, like on TV.

ならば、戦いがリアルであるほど、
よけいに目をそらすハズがない！
The more real the fight,
the more he would have
watched!

<Phoenix>
うううう‥‥。
Umm... huh.

<Judge>
そのとおりですな。
I have to agree with
Mr. Edgeworth.

では、弁護人。‥‥もう一度
答えてもらいましょう。
Well, Mr. Wright.
Do you have another
explanation?


<Phoenix>
トノサマンがトドメをさしたとき、
He missed the climax of
the fight...

おそらく九太くんは、
他のものを見ていたのです！
because he was looking at
something else! Probably!

<Edgeworth>
“おそらく”？
"Probably"?

<Judge>
“他のもの”？
"Something else"?

<Edgeworth>
成歩堂！
‥‥答えてもらおう！
Mr. Wright, 
explain yourself!

あの少年にとって、トノサマンの
戦いよりも気を引くものなどない！
What could possibly distract
this boy from seeing his idol,
the Steel Samurai, fight!?

いったい、何を見ていた
と言うのか！
What do you claim he
was looking at?

<Phoenix>
ぐぐうっ！
（‥‥思いつかない‥‥）
O-ooof!

<Phoenix>
(C'mon, think of something...
think of something...
Nothing.)

<Judge>
成歩堂くん！
Mr. Wright!

‥‥コンキョのない発言は、
ひかえてください！
Please refrain from making
baseless claims!

<Phoenix>
は‥‥はい。
スミマセン‥‥。
Y-yes...
Sorry, Your Honor.

<Judge>
もう一度、考えなおしてください。
Do you have another
explanation for this?


<Phoenix>
裁判長。
‥‥証拠品があるんです。
Your Honor,
I have evidence.

<Judge>
“証拠品”‥‥ですか？
"Evidence"...?

<Phoenix>
そうです。
Yes, Your Honor.




<Phoenix>
“なぜ九太くんは、戦いから
目をそらしたか”‥‥？
Why did Cody look away
from the fight?


<Phoenix>
その証拠は‥‥！
Here's my proof!

<Judge>
証拠は？
Proof?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
Um, uh...

ちょっと待ってください。
‥‥もう一度、考えます。
Can I... do that again?

（さすがに、
　これは違うだろう‥‥）
(This doesn't prove
anything...!)

<Edgeworth>
ハッ！　自信がなくなったか！
Hah! Lost your nerve,
have you?

<Judge>
‥‥しかたがありませんね。
もう一度、聞きます。
Very well... I'll ask
you the question again.


<Phoenix>
その証拠は、これです！
Here's my proof!

<Judge>
なんですか‥‥？
そのカメラが、どういう‥‥？
What's that?
The camera...?

<Phoenix>
このカメラは、最近、
買ってもらったばかりです。
The witness stated that he
recently received this camera.

<Judge>
それは知っています。
Yes, I'm aware of that.

<Phoenix>
まだ彼は、カメラのあつかいに
慣れていません。
He wasn't entirely familiar
with its operation.

<Judge>
それもわかっています。
‥‥あっ！
I'm aware of that, too.

<Judge>
Ah!

<Phoenix>
九太くんは、トノサマンが
トドメをさす瞬間、
Correct! Why would Cody be
looking somewhere else at
the critical moment?

カメラを見ていたんですよ！
Because he was looking
at his camera!

もちろん、写真を撮るためにね！
He was trying to take
a picture!

<Cody>
あッ！
Hey!

<Phoenix>
どうやら、図星だったみたいだね。
Bullseye!

<Cody>
なんなんだよ、オマエ‥‥。
オレをイジメて、たのしいかよ！
W-what's your problem, pops!
You got a thing for picking
on little kids!?

<Phoenix>
（イジメているわけじゃ
　ないんだけど）
(Pressing, not picking...)

<Mia>
よくやったわ、なるほどくん！
Good job, Phoenix!

九太くんは、ウソをついていた。
Cody was lying, clearly.

目の前でトノサマンが戦っていて、
彼が写真を撮らないなんて、
Smart of you to realize there
was no way he could just stand
there, watching his hero...

あり得ないものね。
and not take a picture!

<Phoenix>
はい！
Right!

<Phoenix>
いいかい。
Cody?

きみがトノサマンの戦いから
目をそらした理由は、ただ１つ。
There was only one reason
why you would have looked
away from the fight.

それを写真に撮ろうと思って、
カメラをいじっていたからだ。
And that was because you
wanted to take a picture.

買ったばかりで、まだ操作に
慣れていなかったから、
But having just received your
camera, you weren't used
to using it yet!

決定的なシュンカンを
見のがしちゃったんだろう？
So, you missed the climax
of the fight. Correct?

<Cody>
‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥そうだよ‥‥。
Yeah.

<Mia>
さあ、なるほどくん。
Well, Phoenix.

この子は、まだ何かを
かくしているわ！
I'll bet you anything he's
hiding more than that.

もう一度、《証言》させるの！
Have him testify again!

<Phoenix>
は、はい。
（千尋さん、コワい‥‥）
R-right.
(Mia means business!)

<Phoenix>
裁判長。
Your Honor.

九太くんに、もう一度
《証言》をおねがいします。
The defense would like to
request that Cody Hackins
testify once more.

<Judge>
わ、わかりました。
V-very well.

では、九太くん。
Cody?

そのカメラと、写真を撮らなかった
ことについて、
Could you please tell us
about your camera...

もう少し、くわしく話して
もらえるかな？
And about why you didn't
take a picture of the fight?

<Cody>
ううう‥‥。
Umm...

<Phoenix>
（オトナの世界は
　キビシイんだぞ‥‥！）
(Welcome to the real world,
kid!)

< >
～“写真は撮らなかった”？～
-- No Photo? --

<Cody>
オマエの言うとおりだよ。
Yeah, you're right, pops.

トノサマンが、悪人の手を
ふりほどいたから、
The Steel Samurai had just
escaped from the clutches of
the villain.

オレ、写真を撮ろうと思って、
カメラをかまえたんだけど。
So I held up my camera
to take a picture!

レンズが開かなくって。
ちょっと間に合わなかったんだ。
But the lens wouldn't open
in time, so I missed it.

そ‥‥それで、オシマイかな。
Th-that's all that happened.
Yup.

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

この証言に、何か
おかしなところはありますか？
Anything strange in that
testimony, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
‥‥わかりません。
I'm not sure...

でも、《尋問》は
させてもらいます。
But I'd like to proceed with
the cross-examination anyway.

< >
～“写真は撮らなかった”？～
-- No Photo? --




<Cody>
オマエの言うとおりだよ。
Yeah, you're right, pops.


<Cody>
トノサマンが、悪人の手を
ふりほどいたから、
The Steel Samurai had just
escaped from the clutches of
the villain.


<Cody>
オレ、写真を撮ろうと思って、
カメラをかまえたんだけど。
So I held up my camera
to take a picture!


<Cody>
レンズが開かなくって。
ちょっと間に合わなかったんだ。
But the lens wouldn't open
in time, so I missed it.


<Cody>
そ‥‥それで、オシマイかな。
Th-that's all that happened.
Yup.

少しおくれて何枚か撮ったけど、
データはもう、消しちゃったよ。
I took a few shots, but it
was too late, so I erased 'em.


<Phoenix>
（こんなみじかい証言で、
　何かおかしなところがあるか？）
(How can I pick holes in
such a short testimony?)

<Mia>
何かあるはずよ。
There has to be something.

探り出すの。
‥‥あの子のホンネを！
Dig up the dirt, Phoenix!
Find out what this kid's
all about!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
“オマエ”‥‥？
"Pops"...?

<Cody>
なんだよ！
トンガリアタマのオッサン！
Yeah, I called you "pops,"
you spiky-haired geezer!

<Phoenix>
オ‥‥オッサン‥‥？
G-geezer...?

<Edgeworth>
私は“おニイさん”だ。
I'm "Mr. Edgeworth."

<Judge>
“オジさん”ということで。
And I guess I'm the "bearded
gentleman"...

<Cody>
オトナは、メンツで
生きているからイヤだよ‥‥。
That's what I hate about
grown-ups. You're all so
self-conscious!

<Phoenix>
もう、ヨウシャしないぞ！
‥‥証人！　つづきを！
Okay, off with the kid
gloves! Testify, witness,
testify!

<Cody>
ひひィィッ！
Yipes!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
そこまでは見ていたんだ。
So you did see the
beginning of the fight?

<Cody>
うん。
Yeah.

<Phoenix>
何か、気がついたことは
なかった？
Did you notice anything
unusual?

<Cody>
‥‥う‥‥ううんと‥‥。
Umm... well... uh...

‥‥いつものトノサマンと、
ちょっと動きが違ったみたい‥‥。
I guess the Steel Samurai was
moving a little strange...

<Phoenix>
（動きが‥‥違った？）
(Moving... strangely?)

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
なんで写真が撮れなかったの？
Why couldn't you take
a picture?

<Cody>
新しいカメラ、ボタンが
いっぱいあって、ややこしいんだ。
My new camera has too many
buttons. I couldn't figure
it out.

シャッターを
押そうと思ったんだけど‥‥、
I tried to take a picture,
I really tried.

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
レンズが開いたら、
何が見えたの？
When the lens opened,
what did you see?

<Cody>
‥‥えーと‥‥
たおれた人と、トノサマン。
Uh... well, a person on
the ground. And the Steel
Samurai!

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
“オシマイ”‥‥？
That's all?

<Cody>
そ‥‥そうだよ！
写真は、撮らなかったんだ！
Y-yeah!
I told you, I didn't
take a picture!

<Phoenix>
（ぼくだったら、写真、
　撮ると思うけどなあ‥‥）
(Hmm... I would have, once I
got that lens open...)

（この少年は、本当に写真を
　撮らなかったのだろうか？）
(Did he really not take
a picture? Not even one?)



<Phoenix>
（九太くん、半分泣いてるしなあ）
(He looks ready to burst
into tears...)

（ここは、カンベンしておいて
　あげるか‥‥）
(I'd better lay off
him for now.)


<Phoenix>
（九太くんだったら、シャッターを
　押さないはずはない！）
(Nah, he definitely would
have taken a picture.)

<Phoenix>
(There's got to be something
here I can use!)

九太くん！
Cody!

ぼくには、何もかも
わかってるんだよ！
Listen up, Cody Hackins.
I know exactly what happened
that day.

きみは、写真を撮ったはずだ！
You took a picture!

<Cody>
‥‥あッ！
... Hey!

<Phoenix>
（思ったとおり、か‥‥）
(Bullseye...?)

<Cody>
ど、どうしてわかるんだよ‥‥？
H-how did you know!?

<Phoenix>
おニイさんには、九太くんの
ウソが、みんなわかるんだよ。
I see through all your
lies Cody Hackins. It's
one of my powers!

<Cody>
‥‥す、すげェや！
W-wow!

<Phoenix>
（お。‥‥なんか、いいキモチ）
(This feels great!)

<Cody>
オレ‥‥、
たしかに撮ったよ‥‥写真。
Y-yeah...
Yeah, I took a picture.

<Judge>
では、そのように証言を
変えてもらいましょうか。
Perhaps you can change
your testimony to reflect
this, Cody?

<Cody>



<Phoenix>
データを‥‥“消した”？
You "erased" them?

<Cody>
そ、そうだよ！
Y-yeah!

<Phoenix>
なんで？　大好きなトノサマンが
勝負に勝った写真なのに‥‥。
Why would you erase a picture
of your beloved Steel
Samurai, victorious?

<Cody>
べ‥‥べつに。
Well... y'know.

とっておいても、
‥‥しょうがないだろ？
W-why would I want to
keep a picture like that?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ヘソを曲げたか‥‥）
(Hmm... he's becoming less
and less cooperative.)

（そろそろ、ムジュンでも
　たたきつけてやらないとな‥‥）
(I better find a clear
contradiction soon...
or some solid evidence.)


<Phoenix>
九太くん！
Cody!

<Cody>
な、な、な、なんだよ！
Wh-wh-what!?

さっきからアンタに名前を呼ばれる
と、ロクなことがないや！
Man, every time you say
"Cody" you follow it with
something bad.

<Phoenix>
昨日は、これ、どうもありがとう。
I just wanted to thank you
for giving me this the
other day.

<Cody>
‥‥え？　あ、ああ‥‥。
Huh? O-oh... right.

<Phoenix>
きみ、昨日、こんなことを
言ってたよね？
What was it you
told me then?

<Cody>
オレ、トノサマンのショーには、
かならず行くんだよ！
I go to every live
performance!

でさ。トノサマンが勝った瞬間を、
こうして写真に撮るのさ！
I always take a picture when
the Steel Samurai lands the
final blow! Whizzam!

１つ残らず、ぜーんぶ写真に
撮ってるんだぜ。‥‥カンペキに！
I got 'em all! I never missed
one! A perfect collection!

<Phoenix>
いいかい。
Cody.

もし、トノサマンが戦いに勝った
シーンをきみが撮ったのなら、
Did you really get a picture
of the Steel Samurai standing
victorious over his foe?

それを消すハズがない。
If you did, I find it hard
to believe that you would
just erase it!

このアルバムに、かざらなければ
ならないからね！
Wouldn't you keep it for
your album?

<Cody>
ああああッ！
Ah!

<Judge>
‥‥弁護人。
Mr. Wright...

そのアルバム、なんですか？
What exactly is this album?

<Phoenix>
これは、“栄光の足跡”といって、
It's called "Path to Glory."

九太くんが、トノサマンの写真を
撮って、集めたものです。
It's a collection of pictures
of the Steel Samurai, all
taken by Cody Hackins.

これまでの、トノサマンの勝利の
シーンが、すべて撮影されている！
He claims it's a perfect
collection of every battle
the Steel Samurai has won!

<Judge>
は‥‥はあ。
I... I see.

<Phoenix>
しかし！
Don't you find this very
odd, Your Honor?

事件当日のトノサマンの写真は、
このアルバムには、ない！
Among all his pictures of
the Steel Samurai, none
were taken that day!

<Judge>
静粛に！
Order!

成歩堂くん。
‥‥それは、なぜでしょう？
Mr. Wright.
Have you an explanation?

トノサマンが誰かをやっつけた
のならば‥‥、
If the Steel Samurai
had just defeated his
adversary...

そのアルバムに、写真が
なければおかしい‥‥。
I certainly would expect
to see a picture of it
in this album...

<Phoenix>
そのとおりです！
Exactly my point,
Your Honor!

‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥！
（ま‥‥まさか‥‥‥‥まさか！）
.........!
(No... wait... no way!)

<Mia>
‥‥なるほどくん。
Phoenix?

どうやら私たちは、
たどりついたみたいね。
I think we've finally
discovered the truth.

‥‥とんでもない“真相”に。
And what a truth it is!

<Phoenix>
ち‥‥千尋さん！
M-Mia... are we sure
about this?

じゃあ、やっぱり‥‥？
Did he actually...?

<Mia>
‥‥そう。
Yes.

あなたが考えていること
‥‥それはたぶん、正しいわ‥‥。
I'm pretty sure what you're
thinking is right.

教えてあげなさい。
裁判長に‥‥真相を、ね。
Tell them, Phoenix.
Tell them what the truth is.

<Judge>
弁護人！
どういうことですか？
Mr. Wright!
Please explain to the court
what is going on here!




<Judge>
アルバムには、なぜ事件当日の
写真がないのですか？
Why was there no picture in
the album from the day of
the murder?

なぜ、少年は写真のデータを
消してしまったのですか？
Why would the boy have
erased the photos he took?




<Phoenix>
おそらく、九太くんは、
“芸術家”なのです！
I believe that Cody Hackins
is what we call an "artiste."

<Judge>
“ゲージュツカ”？
An... "artiste"...?

<Phoenix>
彼は、撮った写真が
気に入らなかったのです！
He didn't like the photos
he had taken!

ピントがボケていたか、
センターがズレていたか‥‥。
They were blurry, or maybe
his framing was off...

<Phoenix>
とにかく、そういう理由で
彼は、データを消したのです。
Anyway, for some reason,
he erased the data!

<Judge>
そうなのかな、九太くん？
Is that right, Cody?

<Cody>
“センターがズレていた”
って、なんのことだよ！
Wh-what do you mean
"framing was off"!?

<Judge>
‥‥違うみたいですね。
It seems the only thing "off"
is your guesswork, Mr. Wright.




<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥。
Um, uh...

じゃあ、きっと、本当の答えは‥‥
Yes, well, I'm sure
the real reason is...

<Judge>
なんですか？
聞かせてもらいましょう。
Yes? The real reason is?


<Phoenix>
カンタンなことです。
Simple, Your Honor.

九太くんは、カメラのあつかいに
慣れていなかった。
Cody wasn't used to using
his new camera.

だから、間違ってデータを
消してしまったのです！
He erased those photos
he took by mistake!

<Mia>
ちょ、ちょっと待って、
なるほどくん。
W-wait a second, Phoenix.

そんな答えじゃ、
何も状況は変わらないじゃない！
If that's your answer, we're
back where we started!

<Phoenix>
え？　‥‥違うんですか？
Huh? You mean, that wasn't it?

<Judge>
弁護人！　コソコソ話はしない！
Mr. Wright! If you have
something to say to
the court, speak up!

<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥。
Um, well...

すみません。‥‥あの、もう一度、
発言させてください。
S-sorry, Your Honor. 
Can I change my answer?

<Judge>
ふう‥‥。やれやれ‥‥。
Hmm... *sigh*





<Phoenix>
その理由は、１つしか
考えられません！
I can think of only
one reason, your honor.

“トノサマンは勝たなかった”
The Steel Samurai didn't win!

‥‥だから、九太くんは
写真のデータを消したんです。
That's why Cody deleted
those photos.

<Judge>
トノサマンが‥‥“負けた”？
You mean the Steel Samurai...
lost?

<Phoenix>
そうなんだろ？　九太くん。
Well, Cody?
I'm right, aren't I?

トノサマン、ほんとうは、悪人に
やられちゃったんじゃないか？
Tell the truth. The bad guy
defeated the Steel Samurai!

<Cody>
ナ、ナ、ナ、ナニ言ってんだ！
N-n-n-no way! No!

ト‥‥トノサマンは負けないんだ！
‥‥ゼ、ゼッタイ！
I-it's impossible!
Th-the Steel Samurai
never loses!

誰にも、負けたりなんか、
するもんかァッ！
He never loses to anyone!
Ever!

<Phoenix>
裁判長‥‥。
Your Honor...

今の九太くんのコトバが、
すべてを物語っています。
The witness has revealed
everything with his words.

“写真を撮らなかった”と
ウソをついた理由‥‥、
There was a reason why
he lied and told us he
didn't take a picture.

そして、せっかく撮った写真の
データを消した理由‥‥。
The same reason he erased
his precious photos!

九太くんにとって、トノサマンは
ゼッタイ負けてはならなかった。
For Cody, it was inconceivable
that the Steel Samurai could
be defeated.

しかし九太くんは、とんでもない
シーンを目撃してしまったのです！
However, Cody witnessed
the impossible!

そう！　トノサマンが
戦いに敗れるシーンを！
He saw the Steel Samurai lose!

九太くんは、それを認める
ワケにはいかなかった！
Yet to admit what he saw
would destroy everything
he believed in!

だから、“トノサマンが勝った
ところを見た”と‥‥
That's why he lied and said
the Steel Samurai won.

ウソをついてしまったのです！
He couldn't handle the truth!

<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛に！　静粛に！
O-Order! I will have order!

ど‥‥どうなんですか！
証人‥‥九太くん！
W-witness! I mean, Cody!
Is this true!?

あ、あなたはいったい‥‥
何を見たんですか！
W-what did you see?
Tell the court what you saw!

<Cody>
う‥‥。
I......

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥

<Cody>
うわああああああああああああああ
ああああああああああああああん！
Uwaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaargh!

<Phoenix>
‥‥九太くん。
Cody...

あの日、きみが見たのは、
トノサマンが負けるところだった。
That day, you saw the Steel
Samurai lose a fight.

‥‥そうなんだろう？
Right?

<Cody>
うわああああああああああああん！
Waaaaaaaaaaaaah!

そうだよ！
Okay okay!

そうなんだよ！
Y-you're right!

トノサマンが
‥‥た、たおれちゃって！
Th-the Steel Samurai f-fell
down...

う‥‥うごかなく
なっちゃったんだ‥‥
Th-then he didn't m-move...

うわああああああああああああん！
Waaaaaaaaah!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
Order! Order! Order!

<Edgeworth>
成歩堂！　い、いったいこれは、
なんのさわぎだッ！
What kind of stunt are you
trying to pull, Wright!?

トノサマンは、
“殺人者”なのだぞ！
The Steel Samurai was the
murderer, not the victim!

<Phoenix>
しかし証言によれば、トノサマンは
たおれて動かなくなっている！
Yet according to your
witness's testimony, the Steel
Samurai was the one who fell!

<Judge>
弁護人！
‥‥どういうことなんですか！
Mr. Wright!
What's going on?

<Phoenix>
ぼくたちは、大きなカン違いを
していたことになります‥‥。
Apparently, we have all made
a serious error.

<Edgeworth>
カン違いだと‥‥？
An... error?




<Edgeworth>
それはいったい、
どういうことかッ！
What's this all about!?




<Phoenix>
つまり、被害者はイブクロさん
だったのです！
Quite simply, the victim
was Jack Hammer!

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

< >
　　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
‥‥ああ。その、弁護人。
Umm... Mr. Wright?

それはみんな、知ってます。
We all know that.

<Phoenix>
はい。
Right.

<Judge>
自分が言ったことを、
もう一度、考えてごらんなさい。
Perhaps you'd like to
reconsider your last
statement?




<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥
...

すみません。
I'm sorry.

大きなカン違いをしていたのは、
ぼくだったんですね‥‥。
It was I who was wrong.

<Edgeworth>
成歩堂ッ！
ふざけるにも、ほどがあるぞ！
Okay, Wright! First you're
right, now you're wrong!?
Which is it!?




<Phoenix>
し、しかし！　どこかに見落としが
あるのは間違いない！
L-look, I'm sure there's
something we're overlooking!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥ならば、それを
ズバリと言ってもらいたい！
If you're so sure,
then tell us what it is!


<Phoenix>
この事件では、被害者は
いなかったのです！
There was no victim
in this case!

<Judge>
な、な、な、なんですとォ！
Wh-wh-what!? Has the defense
taken leave of its senses!?

<Phoenix>
たしかに、衣袋　武志は
死んでしまった。
Of course, Jack Hammer died.

しかし、トノサマンの方も、
たおされているのです！
But the Steel Samurai
fell too!

これはもう、“引きわけ”
ということに‥‥。
It was a draw!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あきれて、ちょっと
コトバが見つからなかった。
Sorry. I was too shocked to
say anything for a bit there.

いいか！
Listen, Wright!

この事件で死んだのは、
衣袋　武志、１人だけだッ！
Only one person died in this
incident, and that is Jack
Hammer!

被害者はいなかった、だと？
Yet now you claim there
"was no victim"?

何年ニンゲンをやっているんだッ！
Are you insane?

<Phoenix>
（うう‥‥そこまで言うか‥‥？）
(Uh oh, he's pulling out all
the stops now.)


<Phoenix>
わかってみれば
カンタンなことです。
If you understand what
really happened, it's
actually quite simple.

戦った結果、トノサマンが
たおれて、動かなくなった。
At the end of the fight,
the Steel Samurai fell to
the ground, and lay still.

つまり、トノサマンは“殺人者”
ではなく、“被害者”だった‥‥。
In other words, the Steel
Samurai was not the killer,
he was the victim!

ということは！
Don't you see?

トノサマンは、
衣袋　武志だったのです！
Jack Hammer was the Steel
Samurai!

<Judge>
静粛に！　静粛に！　静粛に！
Order! Order! Order!

では、この写真に写っている
トノサマンも‥‥、
So, the Steel Samurai
in this photograph...

被害者の、衣袋　武志が
中に入っていたと言うのですか！
You're saying the man in this
costume was the victim,
Mr. Jack Hammer?

<Phoenix>
そういうことになります。
That's what I'm saying,
Your Honor.

衣袋　武志は、午前中、アクション
シーンの打ち合わせをしていた。
Jack Hammer was present at the
action scene run-through
that morning.

だから当然、荷星さんが足をケガ
したコトを知っています。
Thus, he obviously knew about
Will Powers's foot injury.

<Judge>
し‥‥しかし！
B-but wait!

イブクロさんは、第１スタジオに
行ったはずでは‥‥？
Hadn't Mr. Hammer gone
to Studio One already?

<Phoenix>
みんなそう思っていました。
That's what everyone thought!

しかし、警備員のオバチャンは、
こう証言していた！
But remember what Ms. Oldbag
said in her testimony?

<Oldbag>
オバチャン、午後１時に
詰所に入ったわけョ。
On the day of the murder,
I arrived at the guard
station at 1:00 PM.

イブクロちゃん？
ああ、見てないよ。
Did I see poor old Hammer?
Nope.

オバチャンが詰所にもどる前に、
もうスタジオへ行ったみたいだネ。
He'd already gone to the
studio before I got back
to the guard station.

<Phoenix>
衣袋　武志は、昼食後、
スタッフエリアを去った。
Mr. Jack Hammer left the
Employee Area after lunch.

しかし、彼が第１スタジオに
行ったのは、誰も見ていない。
However, no one saw him
going to Studio One.

<Phoenix>
Nor was there a
picture of him.

彼は、荷星さんが楽屋で
ヒルネするのを待った。
He waited for Mr. Powers
to take a nap in his
dressing room.

そして楽屋に忍び込み、
着ぐるみを盗んだのです。
Then he snuck into the
dressing room and stole
the Steel Samurai costume.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

<Judge>
しかし！　いったい、なぜ
被害者は、そんなことを‥‥？
But why would the
victim do such a thing?

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥わかりませんけど。
I... don't know.

<Cody>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥そうか‥‥。
I get it!

<Phoenix>
‥‥？
?

<Cody>
オレ、トノサマンの動きが、
いつもと違うと思ったんだけど、
I thought that the Steel
Samurai was moving strange.

中に入ってる人、違ったのか‥‥。
So it was a different
person inside the suit!

おじさん！
Pops!

<Phoenix>
な、なんだい？
Huh, me? What?

<Cody>
実はオレ、１枚だけ
消していないデータがあるんだ。
Actually, there was one
piece of data I saved.

<Phoenix>
“でーた”？
Data?

<Cody>
写真だよ。デジカメの！
Yeah, a photo on my
digital camera!

<Phoenix>
!

<Phoenix>
な、なんだって！
W-what!?

<Edgeworth>
み、見せるのだッ！
Show us, quick!

<Cody>
そ、そんなコワいカオ、
すんなよな‥‥。
No way man, not if you're
gonna look at me like that!

<Judge>
早くするッ！
Now!

<Cody>
ううう‥‥。
*sniff*

<Cody>
Here...
This is it.

<Judge>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

これだけ見たのでは、トノサマンの
中に誰が入っていたのかは、
Well, looking at this it's
still a little hard to say.

ちょっと判断ができませんね。
I'm afraid that it could
be anyone in that costume.

<Judge>
Your opinion, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
I agree, Your Honor.
This isn't decisive evidence.

<Judge>
証人。ザンネンですが、これは
証拠にはなりそうもありません。
I'm sorry, this doesn't look
like it's the proof we need.

お返ししておきましょう。
I'll give it back.

<Mia>
待って！
なるほどくん！
Wait, Phoenix!

<Phoenix>
な、なんですか！
Mia? What?

<Mia>
写真を
もう一度、よく見て！
Look at that photo once more!

その写真は‥‥、
That's it Phoenix!

この事件のすべてを物語る、
最強の証拠品よ！
That photo is all the evidence
you need to win this trial!

<Phoenix>
え‥‥ええええっ！
Wh-what!?

<Phoenix>
さ、裁判長！
Y-Your Honor!

その写真、もう一度
見せてください！
May I see that photo
once more please?

<Judge>
は、はあ。
‥‥かまいませんが。
C-certainly.
I don't see why not.

<Mia>
なるほどくん！
裁判長に教えてあげなさい！
Phoenix!
Show him!

この写真がはらんでいる、
決定的なムジュン点を！
There's a glaring, decisive
inconsistency with the facts
as we know them in that photo!

< >



<Phoenix>
（この写真で、ムジュンしている
　ポイントを示そう！）
(Find the inconsistency
in the photo!)


<Phoenix>
ここ、じゃないでしょうか。
I think it's here.

<Judge>
いつにもまして、自信が
なさそうな口ぶりですね。
You seem to be lacking even
more confidence than usual.

<Phoenix>
まあ、自信ありませんから。
I suppose that's because I'm
not confident about it at all.

<Judge>
‥‥考えなおした方が
いいようですね。
Maybe you want to rethink
your case, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうします。
Yes, please, Your Honor.


<Phoenix>
それは、ここです！
It's right here!

<Judge>
‥‥トノサマン、ですか？
The Steel Samurai...?

<Phoenix>
ええ。‥‥この写真の中で、
何かムジュンしそうなのは、
Yes, that's about the only
thing in this picture that
could be inconsistent.

この人しかいませんから。
The Steel Samurai is
inconsistent with...
something.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
成歩堂！
Wright!

イイカゲンなことを
言わないでもらいたいッ！
This is no time for 
daydreaming and pointless
pontification!

聞いている方の身にも
なってくれ！
Think about your client, and
us, who are forced to listen
to your rambling!

<Judge>
弁護人。もう一度、
考えなおしなさい。
Mr. Wright, please rethink
your position.


<Phoenix>
裁判長！
ここを見てください！
Your Honor!
Look at this!

<Judge>
‥‥門柱、ですか‥‥。
I see... a gate?

<Phoenix>
重要なのは、門柱に書かれている
数字です。
Might I draw your attention
to the number on that gate?

<Judge>
‥‥数字？
The number?

これは‥‥“２”ですか？
ハッキリしませんが‥‥。
Ah yes. Well, it's hard to
see, but it looks like a "2."

<Phoenix>
ハッキリしているのは、
“１”ではない、ということです。
Clearly not a "1," Your
Honor, correct?

<Edgeworth>
ああああああっ！
Aaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
どうやらわかったようだね、
御剣検事。
I believe Mr. Edgeworth
sees what I'm getting at.

<Edgeworth>
そ、そんな‥‥
B-but...

そんな、バカなッ！
Th-that's impossible!

<Judge>
え？　え？
‥‥なんですか？
Hmm? Eh?
What's this all about?

私にも、わかるように
セツメイしてください！
Please explain so that I might
be shocked along with the
rest of the court.

<Phoenix>
上面図で説明しましょう。
I'll use the studio guidemap.

死体は、ここ。第１スタジオで
発見されました。
The body was found here,
in Studio One.

しかし、事件のとき撮影された
写真の門柱には、
However, what do we see
in this photo taken at the
time of the murder?

“１”とは書かれていない。
It does NOT say "1" on that
gate in the photo.

裁判長！
Your Honor!

事件は、ほんとうは
ここで起こったのです！
Here is the true
scene of the crime!




<Phoenix>
（裁判長に、ほんとうの
　殺人現場を示そう！）
(Show the judge where
the murder took place!)


<Phoenix>
それは、ここだったのです！
It was here!

<Judge>
‥‥それが、門柱の数字と
何かカンケイがあるのですか。
What does that have to do
with the number on the gate
in the photograph...?

<Phoenix>
ええ‥‥と。
Umm... well...

そこまでは考えていませんでした。
Sorry, Your Honor, I guess
I hadn't thought it that
far through yet.

<Judge>
そこまで考えて
ポイントを指定してください。
Think it through before
you point at the map this
time, Mr. Wright!

もう一度、示しなさい！
Once again! Where is the
scene of this crime?


<Phoenix>
ここです。第２スタジオ。
Here, at Studio Two.

<Judge>
な‥‥、なるほど。
門柱に“２”とありますからな。
I see!
That would explain the "2"
on the gate in the photo.




<Phoenix>
この第２スタジオには、
重要なポイントがあります。
Your Honor, I find it very
significant that the murder
took place in Studio Two!




<Phoenix>
ここは、撮影には使って
いないんですよ！
Studio Two is no longer being
used for filming!

<Judge>
そうですか。
I see...

‥‥それが、何か？
And this is significant...
why?

<Phoenix>
（なんでぼくは、自分でも
　よくわからん発言をするんだ？）
(Good question!
I really should think
these things through more.)

<Judge>
‥‥もう一度、行ってみますか？
Would you like to take
another stab at it?
So to speak?

<Phoenix>
はい。‥‥行ってみます。
S-stabbing away, Your Honor.


<Phoenix>
コテージに通じる道は、
ふさがっていました！
The path to the trailer
was blocked!

<Judge>
それは聞いています。
So we have heard.

<Phoenix>
道がふさがったのは、
２時１５分です。
The path was blocked
at 2:15...

つまり被害者は、それ以前に
第２スタジオに行ったんです！
In other words, the victim
went to Studio Two before
that time!

<Judge>
そ‥‥そうなりますね。
Yes... yes, I suppose
that would be the case.

<Phoenix>
宇在カントクの証言を
思い出していただきたい！
Remember Mr. Sal Manella's
testimony?

彼はこう言った。
Allow me to remind the court:

第１スタジオへは行けなかったから
コテージの人間は犯人でない、と。
He said no one in the trailer
was guilty because they could
not have gone to Studio One.

しかし、事実は逆だったのです！
Yet, in actuality, the
reverse was true!

犯人は、コテージにいた人間しか
あり得ない！
Only someone in the trailer
could have committed this
murder!

なぜなら、犯行は第２スタジオで
行われたわけですから！
They were the only ones with
access to the scene of the
crime: Studio Two!




<Phoenix>
第２スタジオには、
コテージがあります。
As you may recall, there is
a trailer in Studio Two.

コテージでは、事件当日、
カイギが行われていた。
Now, on that day, a meeting
was held in that very trailer.

そして、被害者が死んだ時間に
休憩時間に入った。
There was a break in the
meeting corresponding to
the time of death.

宇在カントクとプロデューサーの
姫神は、ステーキを食べました。
During that break, Mr. Sal
Manella and Ms. Dee Vasquez
were outside, eating steak.

<Phoenix>
そこはまさに、
殺人現場だったのです！
They were at the scene
of the crime!




<Judge>
せ‥‥静粛に！　静粛に！
O-order! Order!

<Phoenix>
弁護側は、
次のように主張します！
The defense makes the
following claims:

殺人現場は、第２スタジオだった！
The scene of the crime
was Studio Two!

そして、オバチャンが見たのは、
被害者の衣袋　武志だった！
The person that the security
guard, Ms. Oldbag saw was
the victim, Mr. Jack Hammer!

イブクロさんは、なんらかの理由で
トノサマンの着ぐるみを盗み、
Mr. Hammer, for some reason,
stole a Steel Samurai costume.

第２スタジオへ行ったのです！
Then he went to Studio Two!

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
バカげている！
This is madness!

衣袋　武志は、被害者なのだぞ！
Jack Hammer is the victim!
The victim!

トノサマンの着ぐるみを盗んだのは
なんのためだ！
Why would he steal a
Steel Samurai costume!?

わざわざ殺害されるために、
そんなことをしたと言うのか？
Are you suggesting he did
so to cover up the details
of his own murder!?

<Phoenix>
‥‥そ、それは‥‥。
W-well, no, of course not...

<Judge>
ふむう‥‥。
Hmm...

<Edgeworth>
それとも、何か証拠でもあるのか！
Or do you have proof!?

被害者の衣袋氏が、
着ぐるみを盗んだ証拠だ！
Give me proof that the
victim, Jack Hammer, stole
the costume!



<Phoenix>
‥‥あります！
I have proof!

<Edgeworth>
な、なんだと！
Y-you do!?

<Judge>
あるんですか‥‥証拠が？
You do, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（そ、そんなにおどろかれると
　自信がなくなるなあ‥‥）
(Now that they're so surprised
suddenly I'm much less
confident...)

（たぶん、間違いないとは
　思うんだけど‥‥）
(I think I'm right, though!)




<Phoenix>
イブクロさんが、トノサマンの
着ぐるみを盗んだ証拠は！
Here's my proof that
Jack Hammer stole the
costume!


<Phoenix>
（いやいや、それはさすがに
　違うはずだ）
(Wait, no, that can't
be right...)

（もっとこう、人をナットク
　させられそうな‥‥）
(I've got to have some proof
that will knock their socks
off...)

<Judge>
弁護人！
‥‥早くおねがいします。
Mr. Wright!
We don't have all the time
in the world, here.

<Phoenix>
は、はい！
Y-yes, Your Honor!


<Phoenix>
（‥‥くやしいけど、
　そんな証拠は持ってないな‥‥）
(Proof? Uh oh... I'm pretty
sure I don't have anything
like that...)

<Mia>
なるほどくん。
Phoenix.

たしかに、１００％確実とは
言えないけど、
Even if you're not 100%
sure about this, you have
to try.

じゅうぶん、コンキョになる
証拠品を、あなたは持っているわ！
And I think you've got
proof that's good enough
to win them over!

イチかバチか、
たたきつけてみましょう！
Just go for it!
All or nothing!

<Phoenix>
‥‥裁判長。
Your Honor...

<Judge>
なんでしょう。
Yes, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
ええと、やっぱりお見せします。
‥‥証拠品を。
Actually... I do have proof.


<Phoenix>
証拠は、これです。
This is it.

<Judge>
薬の‥‥ビンですか。
An empty... medicine bottle?

<Phoenix>
これは、荷星さんたちが
昼食を食べた‥‥、
I found this on the table
in the Employee Area.

スタッフエリアのテーブルから
見つけました。
The same table where Mr.
Hammer and Mr. Powers ate.

ラベルには“睡眠薬”と
書いてあります。
The label reads
"sleeping pills."

<Judge>
“スイミンヤク”‥‥？
"Sleeping pills"...?

<Phoenix>
あの日、被告人の荷星さんは、
午後はずっとヒルネをしてました。
The defendant, Mr. Powers,
spent that entire afternoon
sleeping.

眠らされていたんですよ。
‥‥イブクロさんによって。
He was drugged...
by Mr. Hammer!

<Judge>
待ってください！
Wait a moment...

たしかに、そのビンは
アヤシイですが、
That bottle does raise
some suspicions, yes.

イブクロさんがそれを
使ったか、その証拠はありません。
But there is no proof
that Mr. Hammer used it.




<Phoenix>
裁判長。
‥‥提案があります。
Your Honor,
I have an idea.




<Judge>
‥‥提案、ですか？
なんでしょう。
An... idea?
Continue.

<Phoenix>
荷星さんの血液を
検査してください。
Run a test of Powers's blood.

きっと、睡眠薬のコンセキが
あるはずです。
You should find traces
of the sleeping pills.

<Objection!>

<Edgeworth>
事件があってから、何日
たつと思っているのかな？
This much time after
the day of the murder!?

それに、コンセキが
残っていたとしても、
Even if there were traces
it still proves nothing!

衣袋　武志が睡眠薬を使った
証拠にはならない！
No blood test could tell that
Hammer was the one who
drugged him, Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
（また、１本とられたな‥‥）
(He's right. Darn.)




<Phoenix>
（しかたない。‥‥もう１回、
　提案をしてみるか‥‥）
(That didn't work.
Time to try another idea.)


<Judge>
‥‥提案、ですか？
なんでしょう。
An idea, Mr. Wright?
And that would be?

<Phoenix>
ええと。‥‥イブクロさんの
死体を調べてほしいんですけど。
Er... we should examine
Mr. Hammer's body.

<Judge>
“イブクロさん”‥‥ですか？
Mr. Hammer...?

睡眠薬を飲まされたというのは、
荷星さんなのでは‥‥？
I thought that it was
Mr. Powers who was made
to take the sleeping pills?

<Phoenix>
そ、そうでしたね。
I-indeed it was, Your Honor.

（また、間違えたみたいだな）
(Wrong again...)


<Judge>
‥‥提案、ですか？
なんでしょう。
An... idea?
Very well, let's hear it.

<Phoenix>
もちろん、このビンの
指紋を調べるんですよ。
I want to check this bottle
for fingerprints!

‥‥イブクロさんの
指紋が見つかるはずですッ！
If my claim is true, Mr.
Hammer's fingerprints should
show up on this bottle!

<Edgeworth>
うむむ‥‥ッ！
Hmm...

<Judge>
なるほど‥‥。
I suppose you're right.

わかりました。
ビンをあずかりましょう。
Very well. 
The court will take possession
of the bottle.

< >
証拠品《カラッポの小ビン》を
裁判長に渡した。
Empty Bottle given
to the judge.

<Judge>
本日の審理は、
ここまでとします。
This court will suspend
proceedings on the current
trial for today.

九太少年の証言によって、
Cody Hackin's testimony has
revealed new possibilities
in this case.

事件は、まったく違った可能性を
見せ始めました。
In fact, things may have
happened very differently
than we previously thought.

警備員が見たトノサマンは、
被害者の衣袋　武志だった。
The Steel Samurai seen
by Ms. Oldbag may have been
the victim, Jack Hammer.

殺人現場は、第１スタジオでは
なく、第２スタジオだった。
The scene of the crime was not
Studio One, but Studio Two.

そして、コテージにいた人間には、
犯行を行う時間的よゆうがあった。
And those in the trailer did
have time to commit murder.

成歩堂くん。
Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
はい。
Yes, Your Honor?

<Judge>
あなたに与える宿題は、
次の問題の答えを見つけること。
Your homework is to find
the answer to the following
question:

衣袋さんは、なぜ着ぐるみを
盗まなければならなかったのか？
Why would Mr. Hammer steal
the Steel Samurai costume?

そして、誰が彼を殺害したか？
‥‥その動機は？
Also, who killed him,
and why?

明日までに、その答えを
見つけてください。
Find the answers for
me by tomorrow.

<Phoenix>
（多いよ‥‥宿題）
(That's a lot of homework!)

<Judge>
御剣検事。
Mr. Edgeworth.

<Edgeworth>
うむ。
Mm?

<Judge>
あなたの方は、
荷星さんに対する容疑を、
You will need to reconsider
your stance in this case.

もう一度、はじめから
あらいなおすように。
Above all, you will need to
reconsider your suspicion
of Mr. Will Powers.

<Edgeworth>
こころえた。
As you say, Your Honor.

<Judge>
この審理は、最終日の
明日まで持ち越すことにします！
This trial will be extended
until tomorrow. This is the
last extension!

<Judge>
‥‥では、
本日はこれにて閉廷！
Very well...
Court is adjourned!




< >
１０月１９日　午後２時４７分
地方裁判所　被告人第１控え室
October 19, 2:47 PM
District Court
Defendant Lobby No. 1

<Phoenix>
いやー‥‥。
Whew!

ホント、アブなかったなあ！
That was a close one!

<Mia>
まさに危機イッパツ、といった
ところだったわね。
We were saved by a hair,
but that's all that counts.

とちゅうで、もう帰っちゃおうかな
って、３回ぐらい思いました。
I thought seriously about
going home about three
times during the trial.

<Phoenix>
あ、ぼくもです！
M-me too!

<Will>
‥‥そ、そうだったんですか！
Really?

お２人とも、自信タップリに
見えましたけど。
You both seemed so...
so confident!

<Phoenix>
トンでもない！
フリですよ、フリ。
Hah! Maybe I should take
up a career in acting?

もう、“荷星さん、ご臨終！”って
３回ぐらい思っちゃいました。
I was ready to pronounce
you dead about three times
back there.

<Mia>
あ、私も！
Me too!

<Will>
‥‥ひ、ヒドイ‥‥。
D-dead!?

<Mia>
‥‥ふふふ。さすがにそれは
冗談ですから。
Hoh hoh. Of course, we're
kidding.

<Will>
そうなんですか？
Are you sure?

<Phoenix>
（ぼくはべつに、冗談を
　言ったつもりはないぞ‥‥）
(I wasn't kidding...)

じゃあ、荷星さん。
Now, Mr. Powers.

ぼくたちはこれから、
最後の調査に行きますから。
We have to go make
our final investigation.

明日の法廷では、かならず
真犯人をつきとめて見せますよ。
But I promise you, we'll
find the true killer by
tomorrow's trial!

<Will>
は、はい！　恐縮です‥‥。
R-right! Thanks!
*sniff*


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.


<Judge>
そこまで！
That's enough!

本法廷は、これ以上の審議の
必要性を認めません。
This court sees no reason to
further prolong the trial.

<Phoenix>
（し、しまった‥‥）
(Uh oh...)

<Judge>
被告人、荷星　三郎に
この場で判決を言い渡します！
This court finds the
defendant, Mr. Will Powers...

被告人はこれより身柄を
司直に預けるものとし、
The accused will surrender
to the court immediately,

１ヶ月以内に、高等裁判所において
通常裁判を受けることとします。
to be held pending trial at
a higher court within a
month from today's date.

では、本日はこれにて閉廷！
That is all.
The court is adjourned!

