< >
２月２４日　某時刻
検事局・地下駐車場
February 24
Prosecutor's Office
Underground Parking Lot

<Phoenix>
今日は、ダレもいないね。
‥‥おキョウさんも。
No one's here today...
Not even Ms. Starr.

<Ema>
証拠保管室のナゾが
キョーレツでしたからねー。
Everyone's probably busy
looking into what exactly went
down in the evidence room.

刑事さんたち、あっちに
行ってるんじゃないかなあ。
That must be where the
detectives are.

<Phoenix>
でも、今日の法廷で
ハッキリ立証したからね。
But we proved in court today
that no one was murdered in
the evidence room at 5:15 PM,

《事件当日の５時１５分、
　証拠保管室で、事件はなかった》
on the day of the crime.

<Ema>
それって、なんか‥‥１歩、
前進したような気がするケド。
Yeah. I thought we were
finally making some headway in
our case!

<Phoenix>
ケッキョク、ともえさんが
アヤシイ、ってコトになるかな。
But instead it looks like we
just ended up making Lana look
even more guilty.

<Ema>
うううう‥‥
Hang in there, Lana...

<Phoenix>
（明日までに‥‥すべて、
　コタエを見つけないと！）
(I've got to find all the
answers by tomorrow!)




<Ema>
ここは‥‥クルマの出口ですね。
This is where the cars leave
the lot.

<Phoenix>
床のヤジルシを見ると、
“入口”みたいだけどね。
The arrow on the ground
makes it look more like
an entrance.

<Ema>
ナニ言ってるんですか！
どう見ても出口じゃないですか！
What are you talking about?
It's plainly an exit!

<Phoenix>
ま、まあ‥‥出口であると同時に、
入口でもある、というコトかな。
Well, maybe it's both.
Kind of a dual purpose?

<Ema>
あ！　それ！　あの有名な
“ソータイセー理論”ですね！
Ah hah! The theory of
relativity!

<Phoenix>
え！　は、はあ‥‥
What? Uh...

<Ema>
メモしとかないとね‥‥
あ！　ね。ね。成歩堂さん。
I've got to write this down.
Ah! Hey, hey, Mr. Wright!
Maybe you know...

どこの国のヒトでしたっけ？
ソー・タイセーさんって。
Was Mr. Relativity, German?
Or was he British?

<Phoenix>
‥‥知らないよ。
Mr. Relativity? Are you
sure that was his name?




<Ema>
あ。ハシゴですよ。
Ah hah! A ladder.

<Phoenix>
それはキャタツだよ。
Um... That's a stepladder.

<Ema>
どこが違うんですか？
カガク的に証明してください。
What's the difference?
In scientific terms, please.

<Phoenix>
か、カガク的‥‥
S-scientific huh?

<Ema>
もっとホンシツを見ましょうよ、
成歩堂さん。
Look at the basic nature of
the thing, Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
（なぜだろう‥‥あまずっぱい
　キモチになってきた）
(This all seems so horribly
 familiar somehow...)




<Ema>
お。こんなところに
イミありげなドアが！
Look! A door!
This must mean something!

<Phoenix>
ドアに“イミ”なんてないよ。
I'm not sure that doors
"mean" anything.

<Ema>
クッ！　開きません！
ナゾのカギがかかってます！
No! It won't open!
A mysterious lock!

<Phoenix>
カギに“ナゾ”なんてないよ。
I fail to see what's
mysterious about it.

<Ema>
‥‥成歩堂さん。
もっと人生を楽しみましょうよ。
Mr. Wright...
You need to learn
to enjoy life more.

<Phoenix>
先に調査をすませようよ。
Let's finish our investigation
first, shall we?




<Ema>
おキョウさん‥‥
あそこから見たんですね‥‥事件。
So that's where Ms. Starr
saw the incident from.

<Phoenix>
高いぶん、フツウよりも
よく見えたかもしれないね。
You can probably see quite
a lot from up there.

（そうなると‥‥）
(Hmm...)

（“彼女が刺したのを見た”と
　いう証言も、ウソとは思えない）
(That probably means she
wasn't lying when she saw
Ms. Skye stab him...)

そもそも‥‥警備員は
ナニをしてたんだろう。
Where's the security
guard, anyway?

<Ema>
ええと。あたしが
聞いてきたトコロによると‥‥
Well, this is just something
I heard...

どうやら、おキョウさんのお茶を
買いに行ってたみたいです！
But apparently he went out
to buy coffee for Ms. Starr.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(That woman is a force
to be reckoned with...)




<Phoenix>
これが‥‥モンダイの
ドラム缶だね。
So, this is the famous
oil drum.

<Ema>
ちょっと、ケリ倒してみますね。
ここはひとつ、あたしも。
Well, no time like the 
present! I'll try to kick
it over myself!

えいっ！
Hii-yah!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
...

<Phoenix>
な、泣かないでほしいな。
（ともえさん‥‥スゴいパワーだ）
Th-that's okay. Don't cry.
(That Lana Skye must be a
powerful woman...)




<Ema>
これが‥‥あの
“ついたて”ですね。
So, this is the famous
divider.

<Phoenix>
おキョウさんの証言のウソを
立証してくれたカベ、だったな。
It sure helped us knock a
hole in that testimony 
yesterday.

あるイミ、このカベこそが
ホンモノの証人だったのかもね。
Come to think of it, this
divider helped our case more
than the actual witness.

<Ema>
《カベに耳あり、正直メアリー》
‥‥まさに、そんな感じですね。
The great divider!
A chip off the old parking
block!

<Phoenix>
メアリーはないよ、あかねちゃん。
（今の子は知らないのかな、障子）
It's just a wall.
(Scientifically speaking...)




<Ema>
お。電話がありますよ。
‥‥どれどれ。
Here, a phone.
Let's see if it works...

<Phoenix>
こらこら。
勝手にさわらないほうがいいよ。
Hey. Don't touch stuff we
don't need to be touching.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
な、何も聞こえません！
...
I can't hear anything!

あたしの耳、ヘンになったのカモ！
気圧のせい、でしょうか‥‥
My ears! No, my ears!
Maybe it's due to the
barometric pressure...

<Phoenix>
（ナニを、バカなコトを‥‥）
(What is she babbling about?)

<Ema>
あ、そこ！　なんですか！
H-hello!? What did you just
say?

<Phoenix>
聞こえてるじゃないか！
電話がコワれてるんだよ！
Look, you can hear just fine.
The phone's broken!




<Ema>
まっかなすぽーつかーですね。
That's about as red as
a sports car can get.

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうだね。ジツにまっかだ。
Yup, it's pretty red alright.

（アイツのクルマから
　被害者の死体が発見された）
(The body was found in
Edgeworth's car trunk...)

（トランクのカギも
　コワされている）
(And the lock on the trunk
was broken.)

（ともえさんは‥‥なぜ、
　アレを選んだのか‥‥）
(So, the question is why did
Ms. Skye choose his car?)

<Ema>
で？　で？　なんていう
クルマなんですか？　アレ。
So, what model car is it?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

“セダン”か“クーペ”だと
思うんだ。クルマの名前なら。
I think it was called
a "Sedan" or a "Coupe." 
Something like that.

<Ema>
‥‥それ、車種です。
成歩堂さん、オトコの子でしょ！
Those are car types,
Mr. Wright. Not models.

<Ema>
You're a guy, aren't you,
Mr. Wright? You're supposed
to know these things!

<Phoenix>
（この事件が解決したら、
　免許をとろう‥‥）
(Maybe it is about time I got
my driver's license...)




<Ema>
《Ａブロック》‥‥
検察関係者のエリアですね。
"A Block"... This area is
reserved for prosecutors.

<Phoenix>
ぼくは弁護士だから、
《Ｂブロック》になるのかな。
Defense attorneys are 
relegated to "B Block."

<Ema>
いつかあたし、ここに
クルマをとめるのがユメなんです！
I dream of the day when 
I will be able to park
my car here!

それで、Ｂブロックの成歩堂さん
から、ハンバーグ弁当を買うの。
I'll go over to B Block to
buy my hamburgers from you,
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
‥‥とうぶん、弁護士を
やめるつもりはないよ。
I'm not giving up my job
that soon.




<Phoenix>
この向こうが《Ｂブロック》
‥‥外来者用のエリアだね。
"B Block" is through there.
That's where visitors park.

<Ema>
おキョウさん‥‥
この金網を乗り越えたんですか！
So...
Ms. Starr climbed over
this fence!?

<Phoenix>
そ、そうみたいだね。
（３メートル以上あるぞ‥‥）
I-it seems so, yeah.
(That fence is 9 feet high
 at least!)

<Ema>
ちょっと、のぼってみますね。
ここはひとつ、あたしも。
Well no time like the 
present! I think I'll
give it a little try!

きゃあっ！
Eeeek!

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
...

<Phoenix>
だ。だから、泣かないでほしいな。
（おキョウさん‥‥さすがだな）
I-it's okay, don't cry.
(Maybe there's a Lunchland
Olympics team?)




<Ema>
このロープ‥‥やっぱり？
This rope... is it...?

<Phoenix>
うん。被害者の死体のカタチを
ロープでなぞってあるんだよ。
Yep. They laid it in the
outline of the victim's body.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
So wait...

被害者‥‥トランクを閉めるとき、
挟まって死んだのでしょうか！
The victim must have died
when the killer closed the
trunk on him!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（こんな発想をする子、
　他にはゼッタイいないだろうな）
(You have got to be the only
person I know that would
come to that conclusion.)




<Ema>
ここにあったんですよね。
‥‥このメモ。
That's where we found
that note.

<Phoenix>
“２／２１　ＳＬ－９”
‥‥《ＳＬ９号事件》か。
"2/21 SL-9"...
The SL-9 Incident.

<Ema>
事件があった日、《申し送り》に
なるはずだった事件。
A case that was due for
transferal the day of
the murder.

まさか、それが‥‥
あの事件だった、なんて‥‥
I never knew...
The "SL-9 incident" referred
to...

<Phoenix>
《青影事件》‥‥か。
The Joe Darke Killings.

（今回の事件の関係者が全員、
　何かの形で関わっている事件）
(Everyone in this case played
some part in that incident.)

（ゼッタイに‥‥
　グーゼンなんかじゃない！）
(This has to be more than just
sheer coincidence!)




< >
２月２４日　某時刻
検事局・地下駐車場
February 24
Prosecutor's Office
Underground Parking Lot

<???>
‥‥そちら‥‥
Excuse me...

<Angel>
最高級和牛のシンタマ、
９０グラムでよろしかったかしら。
Would either of you care for
a quarter pound of roast
beef?

<Phoenix>
お、おキョウさん！
（すでに弁当ですらないな）
Ms. Starr!
(I guess she's out of lunches.)

<Angel>
あなたたちも、よほどのモノ好きで
いらっしゃるコトですわねぇ‥‥
You certainly are the curious
sort, aren't you?

まるで‥‥そう。この世で初めて
ナットウを口にした殿方のごとく。
Kind of like the first person
who sucked a cow's nipple to
discover milk.

あの‥‥２年前の事件まで
レンジであたためなおすとは‥‥
Still, I never thought you'd 
go digging up that case from
two years ago.

<Phoenix>
《ＳＬ９号事件》は‥‥関係者
すべての名前が登場する事件です。
Everyone in this trial was
involved in the SL-9 Incident.

それが《申し送り》によって完全に
終わる日、今回の事件が起こった。
Not only that, but the murder
occurred on the very day the
evidence from that case was

グーゼンとは思えません。
due for transferal. This can't
all be attributed to mere
"coincidence."

<Angel>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ワタクシの見た、あの光景‥‥
よもや、お忘れじゃないでしょう？
Aren't you forgetting
something?

<Angel>
You know, that little scene I
happened to witness?

<Phoenix>
（ともえさんが、多田敷捜査官に
　ナイフを突き立てた、瞬間‥‥）
(The instant Lana stabbed
Detective Goodman with a
knife.)

<Angel>
過去のヒミツを暴いても‥‥
その瞬間を変えるコトは、不可能。
No matter how much of the past
you dig up, it won't change
what I saw.

ソテーにしたシンタマは、味わって
飲みくだすしかないんだよ。
Roast beef is meant to be
savored when eaten.

<Phoenix>
（おキョウさんの、ともえさんに
　対する“悪意”‥‥）
(Ms. Starr's hatred toward
Lana...)

（すべては、やはり‥‥
　２年前に始まっているんだ！）
(It all dates back to two
years ago!)




<Angel>
青影　丈‥‥その名前は、
今も忘れちゃいないさ。
Joe Darke...
That's a name I'll not soon
forget!

ヒドい緊張とプレッシャーの下で、
アイツを追っていた、半年間。
We trailed him for half a
year. Oh, the pressure!

今、思えば。あれほど充実していた
日々はなかったねぇ。
Still, I don't think I was
ever more alive than I was
then.

ひたすら熱く、濃く煮つめた
グレービーソースのような毎日‥‥
Those days were steamier than
a bowl of hot gravy!

もっとも‥‥罪門　恭介にとっては
ジゴクのような日々だったろうが。
Poor old Jake Marshall,
though, must have been going
through hell.

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥やっぱり、
弟さんの“死”ですか。
You mean, because of his
brother's death?

<Angel>
‥‥罪門兄弟は、それは仲が
よかったからねぇ。
They were close, those two.

ナオトが死んでからのキョウスケの
執念‥‥見ていて恐ろしかった。
After Neil died, something
took over Jake. He became
obsessed.

そんなアイツを見て‥‥あの女も
ほっておけなかったんだろうさ。
Seeing Jake like that made her
all the more desperate.

<Phoenix>
あの女‥‥？
"Her"...?

<Angel>
宝月　巴だよ。
Lana Skye.

<Ema>
お‥‥‥お姉ちゃん、ですか‥‥
My sister...?

<Angel>
《ＳＬ９号事件》には、最高の
捜査班が組まれたモノさ。
The best of the best were put
on that SL-9 case.

当然‥‥その指揮には、
伝説のコンビがあたった。
Of course they were lead by
that legendary duo.

<Ema>
お姉ちゃんと‥‥巌徒局長！
Lana... and Chief Gant!




<Angel>
巌徒　海慈に、宝月　巴‥‥
Damon Gant and Lana Skye...

２年前は、主席捜査官と、副主席。
警察捜査のトップだった。
Two years ago Gant was Chief
Detective, and Lana second in
command. They were the best.

<Ema>
ふたりで、数々の難事件を
カイケツしたんですよね！
They solved all kinds of cases
together, didn't they?

<Angel>
‥‥特に、巌徒　海慈の磁力は、
異常なほどだったねぇ。
Damon Gant's magnetism in
particular was almost unreal.

<Phoenix>
“磁力”‥‥？
His "magnetism"?

<Angel>
“証拠品”を
引きつけるチカラだよ。
By that I mean his ability to
attract evidence.

彼が扱った事件では‥‥不自然な
ほど、意外な証拠が出たものさ。
He'd produce the most
incredible evidence in the
cases he handled.

<Phoenix>
（“意外な証拠”‥‥まさか！）
("Incredible evidence"? You
mean...)

<Angel>
そう。そのころから、
ある種の“ギワク”はあった。
Oh, yes. There were rumors
about him even back then.

‥‥ダレも、口には
出せなかったけどね。
No one dared confront him,
though.

<Phoenix>
（“ねつ造”だろうな
　‥‥言うまでもなく）
(I take it she's talking about
forged evidence.)

<Angel>
あのころの宝月　巴は、
捜査官全員のアコガレだったよ。
Back then, everyone looked up
to Lana. All the detectives
wanted to be like her.

<Ema>
！　そうだったんですか？
! Really?

<Angel>
このおキョウも、そのひとりさ。
‥‥バカみたいだけどねェ。
Oh yes... myself included.
I was a fool, really.

曲がったコトがキライで、いつも
捜査官のコトを考えてくれていた。
She hated anything crooked,
and always watched out for
the other detectives.

だから‥‥あの事件でも、
キョウスケのコトを気にしてたよ。
That's why she was so
concerned for Jake.

<Ema>
罪門さんを‥‥
Mr. Marshall...

<Angel>
弟を殺害された苦しみを、
自分のコトのように感じていたね。
When Jake's brother was
murdered, she felt as if she
had lost her own brother.

キョウスケが、弟の死に耐えられた
のは、彼女のおかげだった。
If it wasn't for her, I don't
think Jake would ever have
recovered from his shock.

‥‥ちょっと、クヤシイけどね。
That's what makes it all the
more infuriating.

<Ema>
おキョウさん‥‥
Ms. Starr...

<Angel>
だからこそ‥‥よけいに、
あの女がユルせないのさ。
That's why...
I'll never be able to forgive
her.

どうして。あんなふうに、
冷たい女に変わっちまったのか‥‥
Why did she have to turn so
cold after that...?

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥
...




<Angel>
《伝説のコンビ》を信じていたから
‥‥キビしい捜査をつづけられた。
That legendary pair was the
reason we were able to keep up
our investigation.

それだけに、あの事件の結末は
あまりにショックだったね‥‥
That's why we're so shocked
over how it turned out...

<Phoenix>
証拠品の“ねつ造”‥‥ですか。
You mean, with the forging of
the evidence?

<Angel>
たしかに、青影　丈は
ムクイを受けた。‥‥それはいい。
Don't get me wrong. Joe Darke
got what he deserved.

でも！　法廷に提出された証拠は、
あきらかに“操作”されていた！
Still, it was obvious the
evidence produced in court was
being manipulated.

捜査班の知らない証拠や‥‥
逆に、提出されなかった証拠。
Items our team never found
would suddenly appear, while
other items were kept secret.

<Ema>
でも。ジッサイに
不正があったという証拠は‥‥
But you didn't have proof
anything illegal was done...

<Angel>
このおキョウを見れば‥‥
何があったか、アキラカだろうさ。
I'm proof enough of what
happened.

<Ema>
‥‥！
!

<Angel>
事件のあと‥‥多田敷をのぞいた
捜査官たちは、その任を解かれた。
After that case, all of us
save Goodman were relieved of
our duties...

‥‥ほとんど、なんの説明もなく。
most without even so much as
an explanation.

そして‥‥宝月　巴は、主席検事
として、検事局に移転したのさ。
Then Lana Skye transferred to
the Prosecutor's Office and
became Chief Prosecutor.

<Ema>
お姉ちゃん‥‥ムカシから、
検事を志望していたから。
Lana always wanted to be a
prosecutor.

<Angel>
‥‥コトは、そう
タンジュンじゃないよ。
Nothing's quite as simple as
it appears.

<Ema>
え‥‥
Huh?

<Angel>
宝月　巴は‥‥操られていた。
おキョウは、そうニラんでるねェ。
Lana Skye was merely being
used as a pawn.
That's my take on the matter.

<Phoenix>
“操られていた”‥‥‥？
She was being used?




<Phoenix>
ともえさんが移転したのは‥‥
２年前、だったそうですね。
Lana transferred to the
Prosecutor's Office two years
ago, didn't she?

<Angel>
‥‥そう。巌徒《局長》の、
強力な後押しのおかげで、ね。
Yes, thanks to "Chief" Gant's
powerful influence.

<Ema>
《局長》‥‥
Chief...

<Angel>
《ＳＬ９号事件》を解決した功績で
巌徒は、警察局のトップに立った。
That's right. Having solved
the SL-9 case, his position as
chief was secured.

その彼が、次に狙うエモノは‥‥
当然、ひとつしかない。
There was only one thing left
for him to control,
and then no one could stand in

<Angel>
his way:

‥‥検事局さ。
the Prosecutor's Office.

<Phoenix>
！　ま、まさか‥‥
そのために、ともえさんを！
What? You mean...
That's why Lana was
transferred!?

<Angel>
《主席検事》を押さえれば、事実上
検事局を動かすことができる。
If he could control the Chief
Prosecutor, he could control
the Prosecutor's Office.

‥‥それが、巌徒　海慈の
狙いだったんだろうねェ‥‥
That must have been his goal
all along.

<Ema>
でも！　なぜ、お姉ちゃんが
局長さんの言いなりに‥‥
B-but how could he control
Lana?

<Angel>
それは、わからないさ。‥‥でも。
I don't know, but one thing's
for sure.

彼女が“変わった”のは、
あの事件が終わってから、だ。
Ever since that case ended,
she's never been the same.

そこに“何か”ある‥‥
そう考えるべきじゃないかねェ。
It's only logical to
conclude...

<Angel>
there must have been a reason
for her change.

<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥）
(At last...)

（やっと、この事件のポイントが
　見えてきたような気がするな）
(I'm finally getting close to
the bottom of this ugly
mess.)

‥‥ありがとうこざいます。
おキョウさん。
Thank you, Ms. Starr.

<Angel>
ボウヤ‥‥
You listen to me, Rookie.

食材を活かすも殺すも、
料理のウデしだい、さ。
It takes more than just
ingredients to create fine
cuisine. 

‥‥アンタに、この情報を
活かすコトができるかしらね‥‥
I hope you turn out to be a
better chef than I've been...




<Angel>
‥‥今さら、ボウヤにあげる
情報など、ございませんわ。
I don't have anything else to
tell you.

<Ema>
おキョウさん‥‥
Ms. Starr...

<Angel>
ワタクシにあげられるのは‥‥
ゴマシオ弁当ぐらいかしら。
The only thing I can give you
now, is a poppyseed rice set.

<Phoenix>
（安いな、コイツは‥‥）
(Talk about cheap...)

<Angel>
ゴマシオを食べて‥‥明日は
シロクロ、ハッキリすることね。
Eat this, and maybe you'll be
able to tell black from white
in court tomorrow.




< >
２月２４日　某時刻
上級検事執務室・１２０２号
February 24
High Prosecutor's Office
Room 1202

<Ema>
‥‥いませんね。御剣検事さん。
Mr. Edgeworth isn't here.

<Phoenix>
また、査問会で
シボられてるのかな。
Maybe he's being questioned
by an inquiry committee?

（今日もヒドかったからな
　‥‥法廷）
(He took a real beating in
court today...)

<Ema>
お姉ちゃん、認めちゃいました
からね‥‥２年前の、不正。
Yeah, with Lana admitting to
falsifying evidence two years
ago...

<Phoenix>
‥‥とにかく、
またあとで来てみようか。
I guess we'll just have to
come back later.




<Ema>
せっかくもらったのに、
ほったらかしですね。
He won such a prestigious
award. Why would he just leave
it on the couch?

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥トノサマンを
置いておくよりはいいと思うけど。
Better this than that giant
Steel Samurai.

（そういえば‥‥アイツ、
　ムカシからそうだったな）
(Edgeworth has always been
like that.)

<Ema>
え！　なんですか？
メモしますから、教えてください！
Really? Hey, I should write
this down. Tell me what he was
like as a kid!

<Phoenix>
アイツ、小学生のころ、やたら
いろんな賞をもらってたんだよ。
Back in elementary school, he
won awards for all kinds of
things.

弁論大会とか、論文とか、
フルートとか、ゴルフとか。
Speech contests, essays,
playing the flute, golf
tournaments...

<Ema>
‥‥どことなく、小学生っぽくない
ラインナップですね。
That doesn't exactly sound
like typical elementary school
stuff.

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥アイツ自身は、
賞をもらうのがキライだったんだ。
But he always hated receiving
awards. He'd make some smart
remark like,

<Edgeworth>
「自分が歩いてきた道ならば、
　自分自身が知っているのだよ」
"I know the path I've walked.
No one else needs to tell me."

<Phoenix>
‥‥とか、なんとか。
That's how he's always been.

<Ema>
ちょっぴり、ハラ立ちますね。
Kind of gets under your skin,
doesn't it?




<Ema>
ひゃあ！
Whoa!

すごいながめですねー。
１２階でしたっけ。ここ。
What a view! It must be
nice to have an office on
the 12th floor.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥なんか、
エラくなった気分になるね。
I guess you would feel...
important.

<Ema>
‥‥ちなみに。
Incidentally...

ここから飛び降りたとき、
イノチを落とすカクリツは‥‥
Were you to jump out this
window, your chance of
fatality would be...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

出ましたっ！
９９．９９９８パーセントです！
Got it!
99.9998 percent!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥０．０００２パーセントは
　助かるのか‥‥）
(There's a 0.0002% chance
you'd live?)




<Phoenix>
シゴト机だ。さすが、
キレイに片づいているなあ。
A work desk. It's quite
tidy, as one might expect.

<Ema>
いいですねー、この机。
使いやすいけど、オシャレで。
What a nice desk! Easy to
use, and easy on the eyes!

カオが映るほど、よーく
みがきこんでありますよ。
It's polished so high I can
see my own reflection.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なぜだろう。イトノコ刑事の
　カオが浮かんだぞ‥‥）
(Strange... Why did I just
picture Detective Gumshoe?)

<Ema>
あのネームプレート、おみやげに
持って帰ろうかなあ。
Maybe I'll take that name
plaque as a souvenir.

<Phoenix>
やめたほうがいいよ。起訴される。
Don't. He'll sue you.




<Ema>
うわあ‥‥これ、ゼンブ
事件のファイルですか！
Whoa! These are all case
files!?

天井まで、ギッシリ詰まってます！
ハシゴもついていますね。
They're stacked up to the
ceiling! There's even a 
ladder...

<Phoenix>
‥‥おかしいな。アイツ、
地震がニガテなはずだから‥‥
Odd...

こんな危なっかしい本棚を
使うとは思えないんだけど。
I thought Edgeworth wasn't
good with heights.

<Ema>
だいじょうぶです！
He must have someone get
them for him.

<Ema>
ものすごく大きなボルトで、カベに
メリこむほど固定されています！

<Ema>
すごいパワーだなあ。
御剣検事さんがやったのかなあ。

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なぜだろう。イトノコ刑事の
　カオが浮かんだぞ‥‥）
(Strange... Why did I just
picture Detective Gumshoe?)

<Phoenix>
でもさ。地震が起こったら、
部屋中にファイルの雨が降るね。

<Ema>
だいじょうぶです！
He must study these case
reports so closely...
He's so cool!

<Ema>
ギュウギュウに詰まってますから、
ちょっとやそっとじゃ抜けません！

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥

<Phoenix>
やっぱり、なんか
おかしくない？　それ。
You wouldn't say that if you
saw him sweating bullets
up on that ladder.




<Ema>
あ。チェスボードがありますよ！
Hey, a chessboard!

<Phoenix>
チェスはよくわからないけど‥‥
追いつめられてるね。青いコマが。
I'm not too up on my chess
but it looks like Blue's
in a bit of a tight spot.

<Ema>
赤いナイトたちが、よってたかって
青いポーンを取りかこんでいます。
The Red Knights have
surrounded the Blue Pawn...

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうこと？
Huh?

<Ema>
“ナイト”は“剣を持った騎士”
“ポーン”は“歩兵”です。
Those horses are mounted
knights. Their swords have
really sharp "edges!"

<Ema>
And check out that poor pawn,
his head is kind of spiky...
Kind of reminds me of you.

<Phoenix>
赤い“剣”が、青い“歩”を
追いつめている‥‥

<Ema>
御剣検事さん、チェス好きかあ。
‥‥どうしました？　成歩堂さん。
Mr. Edgeworth must be an
avid chess player!
What's wrong, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（気のせいだよな、きっと）
(Edges... surrounding a pawn
with spiky hair...
Nah... It's nothing.)




<Ema>
きゃあ、カワイイ！
ステキなティーセットですよ！
Oooh! Cute!
What a pretty tea set!

<Phoenix>
‥‥ぼく、ティーバッグ派だから。
I go more for the instant
tea bags myself.

<Ema>
すごい！　下のタナに、茶葉と缶が
ギッシリ詰まってます！
Amazing! The drawer below
is filled with packets of
tea leaves!

産地別にキチンと並んでますよ。
フレバリーも、種類ごとに！
They're all sorted by place of
origin and flavor!

お。このロイヤル、ミゴトなまでに
暴力的なブレンディングです！
Look at this Royal blend!
What an exquisitely splendid
concoction! 

<Phoenix>
（‥‥シュミって、なんでも
　奥が深いものなんだなあ‥‥）
(There's such a thing as
taking a hobby too far...)




<Ema>
わあ。ゴーカな花ですねェ。
御剣検事さんに、ピッタリ！
My, my, my! What an amazing
bouquet! Just right for
Mr. Edgeworth.

<Phoenix>
たしかにね。‥‥あ。
カードが添えてあるぞ。
No kidding. Hey, there's
a card on it...

‥‥《恐怖政治　　　カオル》
"To be or not to be -- Wendy"

（“カオル”‥‥
　どこかで聞いたような）
("Wendy?"...
I've heard that name
somewhere before.)

<Ema>
となりにあるのは‥‥
巨大なトノサマンですっ！
And beside it...
A giant Steel Samurai!

うわ、ほしいなあ。
御剣検事さん、マニアなのかなあ。
Wow, I want one!

<Phoenix>
イヤだな、それ。‥‥あ。
足のウラ、何か書いてあるぞ。
Huh? There's something
written on the bottom
of his foot.

‥‥《三割打者　　　カオル》
"To every cloud, there is
a silver lining -- Wendy"

<Ema>
なんか、きのうまでと
モンクが変わってませんか？
Was this the same message
that was here yesterday?




<Ema>
さすが、御剣検事さん。
ふかふかですよ、ソファ！
Mr. Edgeworth has such a
comfy sofa!

<Phoenix>
こんなリッパなソファ、
座った瞬間に眠くなるよ。
Sofas like this make me want
to curl up and take a nap.

<Ema>
きっと、夜おそくまで
資料を調べて、つかれきって‥‥
I bet he pours over his case
files here until the wee hours
of the morning...

上着をぬいで、シャツのソデなんか
オシャレにまくっちゃって。
Then he takes off his jacket,
rolls up his sleeves...

ウデまくらで、ついウトウト
寝ちゃうんですよねー。
And goes to sleep using his
arms as a pillow!

<Phoenix>
（彼女の目には、見えている
　らしいな‥‥オソロシイことに）
(I don't believe it. She's
actually daydreaming about
Edgeworth working...)

<Ema>
寝グセや、ホッペにソファの
カドのアトがついちゃって。
I bet in the morning he has
sofa hair, and little creases
in his cheek from the seams!

‥‥カッコいいなあ。
He's so cool!

<Phoenix>
‥‥カッコいいかあ？
Sofa-hair is cool!?




<Ema>
うわ！　なんか、いちだんと
ヒラヒラした服ですよ！
Wow! This jacket is even
lacier than his usual ones!

いわゆる“勝負服”かな。
御剣検事さんの！
This must be his lucky
trial jacket!

<Phoenix>
勝負服、ねえ‥‥。
ぼくは見たことないけどな。
Lucky jacket, right...
I've never seen him wear it.

<Ema>
額に入れてかざっちゃって。
ナニか“いわく”がありそう！
I'm sure there's a story
behind why it's in a frame!

ちょっとシツレイして。
写真、撮っちゃお！
Maybe I'll be naughty...
and take a picture!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ。
　コーフンぎみだな‥‥）
(She's getting way too 
excited about this.)




< >
２月２４日　某時刻
上級検事執務室・１２０２号
February 24
High Prosecutor's Office
Room 1202

<Phoenix>
（御剣‥‥戻ってるかな）
(I wonder if Edgeworth is back
yet.)

<Ema>
あ。いましたよ！
‥‥何か、書いてます。
There he is!
It looks like he's writing
something.

<Edgeworth>
な、なんだ！　こんなところに‥‥
Huh? What are you doing here?

<Phoenix>
（御剣のヤツ‥‥書いてたモノを
　あわてて床に捨てたぞ）
(He sure was quick to throw
that paper on the floor...)

タイヘンだったな。
‥‥今日の法廷も。
Tough day in court, huh?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥フッ。
Hmph.

この２年間、私はつねに
ギワクのキリに包まれてきた。
I've had to live the past two
years with rumors flying
around.

今さら、どうということもない。
What's another allegation to
me?

<Ema>
元気出してくださいね！
あたし、オウエンしてますから！
Cheer up, Mr. Edgeworth!
I'm rooting for you!

<Phoenix>
（コイツは、
　ムカシからそうだった‥‥）
(That's Edgeworth for you...)

（‥‥本当に苦しいときこそ、
　それをかくそうとする‥‥）
(Always trying to hide his
real feelings.)

<Edgeworth>
それで‥‥なんの用だ？
こう見えて、私も忙しいのだが。
So, what do you want?
Unlike some people,
I don't have all day.




<Ema>
せっかくもらったのに、
ほったらかしですね。
He won such a prestigious
award. Why would he just leave
it on the couch?

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥トノサマンを
置いておくよりはいいと思うけど。
Better this than that giant
Steel Samurai.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
どうしたの？
What is it?

<Ema>
これ、《検事・オブ・ザ・イヤー》
の賞品ですよね？
This is the "King of
Prosecutors" award, right?

<Phoenix>
そうだよ。‥‥何を今さら。
Of course it is. You know
that!

<Ema>
なんか、今日。どこかで、
コレと似たものを見た気が‥‥
I saw something today that
looked like this, somewhere...

<Phoenix>
“似たもの”‥‥？
Something that looked like
that?

<Ema>
でも、どこかちがうような‥‥
なんだっけなあ、あれ。
Yeah, only different. What was
it...?

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥何か、引っかかる。
　アイツに見せてみるか‥‥？）
(She's right. Something's
amiss here. Maybe I should
show him a certain item...)




<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥さっき
　アイツ、何を書いていたんだ？）
(I wonder what he was writing
before?)

<Ema>
ね。ちょっと調べてみましょうよ、
成歩堂さん！
Come on, Mr. Wright! Let's
take a look!

<Phoenix>
え！　‥‥やめとこうよ。
シュミが悪いし。
Are you crazy? Edgeworth is
sitting right there!

<Ema>
じゃ。検事さんの目をそらして
くださいね。おねがいします！
Just distract him. I'll check
it out.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥！
え。ええと、御剣‥‥
Uh...
Hey, Edgeworth.

窓のソト、コートをハタめかせて
イトノコ刑事が落ちていくぞ！
Is that Detective Gumshoe out
the window there? Oh no! He's
falling to the ground!!!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そんなコトより、この子は
私の足元で、何をしているのだ。
Hold on. First let me see what
this girl's doing crawling
around my feet.

<Phoenix>
（見もしない）
(He didn't even look.)

<Ema>
あ！　こ、これは！
じ‥‥じ。じ‥‥‥
What!?
"Letter of r-r-r-r..."

<Edgeworth>
読めないのなら、教えてあげよう。
《じひょうとどけ》‥‥そう読む。
If you can't read, I'll read
it for you.

<Edgeworth>
It says, "Letter of
Resignation."

<Phoenix>
じ‥‥“辞表”？
御剣！　おまえ‥‥
"Resignation"!?
Edgeworth, you don't mean...?

<Edgeworth>
どうやら‥‥
少し、つかれたようだ。
I'm tired, Mr. Wright.

私の中の“何か”が死んでしまった
‥‥そんな気がしている。
I feel as if...
something inside me has died.

<Ema>
でも！　御剣検事さんは、
なんにも悪くないのに‥‥
But Mr. Edgeworth! None of it
is your fault!

<Edgeworth>
自分が歩いてきた道は
私自身、よく知っている。
I know the path I've walked.
You don't need to tell me.

‥‥しかし。それは必ずしも、
正しいものではなかったようだ。
And the path I've walked...
hasn't been a just one.

私には、それがユルせないし‥‥
また、ユルされるべきでもない！
I can't forgive myself for
what I've done...

<Edgeworth>
and no one else should forgive
me either.

<Phoenix>
（こいつ‥‥ホンキだぞ！）
(Uh oh. I think he's serious!)

<Ema>
な‥‥成歩堂さん！
なんとかしないと、検事さんが！
Mr. Wright!
Please, you have to do
something!

<Phoenix>
（この、辞表‥‥
　何かに使えないか‥‥？）
(This Letter of Resignation...
I wonder if I can use it for
anything?)

< >
《御剣の辞表》を
ポケットにしまいこんだ。
Put Letter of Resignation in
pocket.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥イイワケは、無意味だ。
There's no excuse for what
I've done.

２年前‥‥私は、ニセの証拠に
よって、有罪判決を得た。
Two years ago, I used false
evidence to obtain a guilty
verdict.

これは、ぬぐい去るコトの
できない“ジジツ”なのだからな。
That's what it all breaks down
to, and nothing I do can erase
that fact.

<Phoenix>
でも！　おまえは
知らなかったんだろう？
But you didn't know, did you?

それが、“ねつ造”された
証拠品だった、なんて。
I mean, that the evidence was
falsified.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥警察局と検事局は、
２つで１つなのだ。
The Police Department and the
Prosecutor's Office share a
bond of trust.

その“信頼関係”がコワれたとき
‥‥我々は、すべてを失うだろう。
If that bond is broken, we
stand to lose everything.

警察局のミスは、私のミスで‥‥
担当検事である、私のセキニンだ。
The Police Department's error
is my error, my responsibility
as the prosecutor in charge.

理由など、モンダイにはならぬ。
That fact remains the same no
matter what excuses I might
have.

<Ema>
御剣検事さん‥‥
Mr. Edgeworth...

<Edgeworth>
私は‥‥自分のシゴトに
ホコリを持っている。
I take pride in my work.

それなのに、なぜ！
ここまで、ココロが乱れる‥‥
So tell me why!
Why has it all come to this...

<Phoenix>
（やっぱり‥‥ショックは
　かくしきれないみたいだ）
(Even Edgeworth can't keep
this kind of emotion
bottled up...)




<Phoenix>
明日の法廷‥‥
おまえ、やれそうなのか？
Are you up for the trial
tomorrow?

<Edgeworth>
フッ‥‥
Hmph.

去年の事件といい、
キミにシンパイされてばかりだな。
First last year's trial, and
now this one. It seems all you
do is worry about me.

正直‥‥歯がゆい。
To be honest, you're getting
on my nerves.

<Ema>
まさか！　担当検事を
はずれる、なんてコトは‥‥
But Mr. Edgeworth! You can't
just walk out on the trial...

<Edgeworth>
明日は最終日だ。今さら、担当を
変えることなど、できない‥‥
Tomorrow is the last day. It's
too late to change
prosecutors.

それが、上層部のホンネだろう。
I'll bet that's what my
superiors are banking on.

２年前の、あの事件が‥‥
今さら、私の足元をすくうとは。
I never thought that case
would come back to haunt me
like this.

<Phoenix>
それは‥‥？
What do you mean?

<Edgeworth>
あの事件の証拠品リストだ。
たしかに、妙に少ない気がする。
That list of evidence. It
seems too short.

リストの大きさも‥‥
いつもの半分ほど、だしな。
Most lists...
run twice as long.

<Phoenix>
はんぶん‥‥
（そりゃ、たしかに少ないな）
It's only half as long as
most lists?
(That is odd...)

<Edgeworth>
罪門　直斗検事が殺害されて‥‥
私は、彼のかわりに法廷に立った。
After Neil Marshall was
murdered,

<Edgeworth>
I became prosecutor for that
case.

捜査には加われなかったが、
与えられた証拠で、罪を立証する！
I may not have been part of
the investigation,

‥‥当時は、そのコトしか
アタマになかったよ。
but at the time there was only
one thing on my mind:

<Edgeworth>
I'd use the evidence I was
given to prove the suspect
guilty!

<Ema>
そういえば‥‥そのころの
写真を見かけましたね。
Say, we just saw a picture
taken around that time.

<Phoenix>
（あの写真‥‥
　何か“違和感”があったっけ）
(That picture...
Something seemed strange
about it...)




<Phoenix>
最後に、もう一度‥‥事件が
あった日のコトを聞かせてくれ。
Could you tell us again about
what happened that day?

‥‥多田敷捜査官が
殺害された、あの日‥‥
The day Detective Goodman was
murdered?

おまえ、警察局の式典に
参加していたんだよな？
You were participating in a
ceremony over at the station,
right?

<Edgeworth>
式典はスキではない。しかし‥‥
欠席するわけには行かなかった。
I've never cared for
ceremonies, but I had to
attend that one.

<Ema>
やっぱり‥‥コレ、ですか？
Because you were awarded this?

<Edgeworth>
表彰される本人が
欠席するワケにも行くまい。
Those receiving awards can't
exactly skip out on the
ceremony.

シゴトを午前中にかたづけて、
クルマで警察局へ向かったのだ。
I finished up at the office in
the morning, then drove over
to the Police Department.

<Phoenix>
“シゴトをかたづけた”‥‥？
You, "finished up" at the
office?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥ああ。
つまらぬ事務シゴトだ。
Yes. Just odds and ends-
clerical stuff.

その日はもう、検事局に
戻るつもりはなかったからな。
I didn't plan on returning to
the office that day.

あの、たのみごとを
されるまでは。
That is, until I was asked to
take something back.

<Ema>
“たのみごと”‥‥ですか？
Take something back?

<Edgeworth>
コイツだよ。
This.

<Ema>
ああ。巌徒局長さんから
たのまれたんでしたっけ、それ。
Oh yeah. Chief Gant asked you
to hold onto that, didn't he?

<Edgeworth>
すでに、半年前。
解決した事件の証拠品だ。
Yes. It was a piece of
evidence in a case that was
closed half a year ago.

これを、検事局に持って帰って
ほしい‥‥そう言われたのだ。
He asked me to bring it back
to the Prosecutor's Office.

<Phoenix>
（たしか‥‥
　きのうも聞いたな‥‥）
(That's the story we heard
yesterday...)

<Phoenix>
あの日、検事局に帰ってきたのは、
局長に言われたから、なんだな？
So you came back here to the
Prosecutor's Office because
the Chief asked you to?

<Edgeworth>
まあ‥‥そういうことになるが。
That's right.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...




<Edgeworth>
ムジュン‥‥《矛盾》と書く。
このコトバの由来は‥‥
This award originates from an
ancient Chinese tale.

ヤリのような武器《矛（ホコ）》と
防具である《盾（タテ）》だ。
In Chinese, the word
"contradiction" is written
with two characters:

このコトバには、有名な物語が
あるのだが‥‥知っているな？
the first means "halberd,"
and the second means "shield."
Have you heard this story?

<Phoenix>
あ、ああ。聞いたことはあるよ。
‥‥ちょっと、ド忘れしたけど。
Me? Oh, uh... sure. Everyone
knows that! Why don't you tell
it though... for Ema's sake.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥中国の、古い故事だ。
Very well.

ムカシ、楚（そ）の国に、
ある武器商人がいた。
Long ago in the kingdom of
Chu, there was an arms
merchant.

王の前に出た彼は、
２つの商品を取り出した。
One day, he presented the king
with two items.

１つ目は‥‥すべてを貫く《矛》。
どんな防具も貫く、最強の武器だ。
The first was a halberd he
claimed could slice through
any shield or armor.

もう１つは、決して破れぬ《盾》。
どんな攻撃も防ぐ、最強の防具だ。
The second was a shield he
claimed could withstand any
weapon.

<Phoenix>
ふうん‥‥‥アレ。
Hmm... Wait a minute.

<Objection!>

その証人の発言は、
アキラカにムジュンしているッ！
Those claims contradict each
other!

<Edgeworth>
“その証人”ではない。
“楚の商人”‥‥だ。
Very perceptive.
But then again, you've heard
this story before, right?

そのとおり。この《矛》と《盾》は
互いに、あり得ない存在だ。
Anyway, as you mentioned, the
very descriptions of these
items discredit them both.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥王は、商人にたずねた。

<Edgeworth>
『ならば、その《矛》で《盾》を
　突いたら、どうなるのか？』と。

‥‥その商人は、
コトバを失ったという。
When the king pointed this
out, the merchant was left
speechless.

そこから、《ムジュン》という
コトバが生まれた。
And thus, the Chinese word for
"contradiction" was born.

<Ema>
あ！　もしかして。
《割れた盾》と《折れた剣》は‥‥
Oh, I see! So the "chipped
shield" and "broken knife"
symbolize...

<Edgeworth>
その賞品は‥‥
楚の商品、というわけだ。
Precisely so. They symbolize
the merchant's items.

中国の物語は、商人が答えに
詰まったところで終わっている。
The ancient tale ends with the
merchant at a loss for words,

しかし‥‥我々は、その先にある
《答え》を追求しなければならぬ。
but it's in our nature to
pursue matters to their
conclusion...

その結果が‥‥たとえ、このように
ミニクイものであっても、な。
even if it results in
something as ugly as this.

<Ema>
へええ。ベンキョウに
なりましたね、成歩堂さん！
Wow. Thanks, Mr. Edgeworth! 
I learned something new today!

<Phoenix>
‥‥でも。ちょっと、
ヘンじゃないか？
That's funny...

じゃあ、おまえの賞品には
なぜ、《盾》しかないんだ？
If that's so, then why were
you only given a shield?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
私にも、よくわからない。
...
You'll have to ask Chief Gant.

２年前、巌徒局長の提言で、
《矛》は廃止されたようだ。
Two years ago, he had the
"halberd" part of the award
abolished.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥巌徒局長が‥‥）
(Chief Gant...)

< >
《検事局賞の盾》のデータを
書きなおした。
King of Prosecutors Trophy
updated in the Court Record.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥ムカシ、あこがれていた
時期があったものだ。
I once dreamed of being
a defense attorney, a 
long time ago.

<Ema>
え！　御剣検事さんが、
弁護士に‥‥？
What? You wanted to
be a defense attorney, 
Mr. Edgeworth?

<Edgeworth>
しかし、進むべき道が目の前に
のびている以上‥‥
Yet, a clear path is laid out
before me.

今さら振りかえるわけには
いかないのだろうな。
I have no time to look
back on what might have been.




<Phoenix>
巌徒局長の部屋に、
こんな写真がかざってあったよ。
This picture was hanging on
the wall in Chief Gant's
office.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥罪門　直斗検事、か。
将来がキタイされていたよ。
Prosecutor Neil Marshall...
He had just started making a
name for himself.

《検事・オブ・ザ・イヤー》を
受賞したときの写真のようだ。
Looks like this was taken when
he received the King of
Prosecutors trophy.

<Ema>
あ。そういえば‥‥
気になることがあるんですけど。
Speaking of that,
there's something that bothers
me.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥なんだろうか。
Yes?

<Ema>
罪門検事さんが、
手に持っている“賞品”‥‥
The trophy Mr. Marshall is
holding...

御剣検事さんのと、
ちょっと、ちがいますよね。
it's a little different than
yours.

<Edgeworth>
あ、ああ。たしかに。
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
Yes, you're right.
...

‥‥そう。思い出したようだ。
I remember now.

<Phoenix>
？　何をだ？
Remember what?

<Edgeworth>
２年前まで‥‥検事局賞の
賞品は、あのカタチが正式だった。
That was the official
prosecutor trophy used until
that time.

モチロン‥‥それには、
ちゃんとした由来がある。
There's a story behind it.

<Ema>
ゆらい‥‥？
A story?

<Phoenix>
（ちょっと、キョーミがあるな）
聞かせてくれるか？　そのハナシ。
(Sounds interesting.)
Would you mind telling it to
us?

<Edgeworth>
カンタンなコトだがな。
It's simple, really.

《ムジュン》‥‥
それが、コタエだ。
"Contradiction."
That's what the award's based
on.




<Phoenix>
いつまで置いておくんだよ。
せっかくもらったのに。
You know, it wouldn't hurt if
you put this up somewhere,
like on a shelf.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そんなものには、すでに
なんのイミもない。
That has no meaning for me
anymore.

<Phoenix>
“すでに”‥‥って。
What do you mean, "anymore"?

<Edgeworth>
それは、去年の私の姿だ。
‥‥振り返るコトに、何かイミが？
That's who I was last year.
What good is it to dwell on
the past?

<Phoenix>
問いかけられたよ。
He's asking me?

<Ema>
ちょっぴり、ハラ立ちますね。
That makes me kind of mad.

あの‥‥それより、あたし。
少し、気になるんですけど。
Actually, something's been
troubling me about this
shield.

この《盾》‥‥
なんか、ちがいませんか？
Look...
Do you notice anything
different?

<Phoenix>
“ちがう”‥‥？
Different...?

<Ema>
ほら。法廷記録に、もう１つ
あるじゃないですか。《盾》が。
Yeah, don't you remember? The
other shield in the Court
Record?

<Phoenix>
（見せてみるか‥‥
　もう１つの《盾》を）
(I guess I'd better present
this other shield...)




<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

まさか、成歩堂。
担当検事である、この私が‥‥
Come now, Mr. Wright.
You can't seriously expect me
to just sit down...

キミと事件の話をしながら
お茶を飲むとでも‥‥？
and chat with you about the
case over a cup of tea.

<Phoenix>
いやいや。これは
関係ないんだろ？　事件とは。
But this isn't related to the
case, remember? You said so
yourself.

<Edgeworth>
む‥‥むゥ、たしかに。
So I did...

<Ema>
あの日、局長さんから
たのまれていたんですよね？
Chief Gant gave this to you
that day, didn't he?

警察局から、ここへ
持ってくるように、って。
He asked you to bring it here
from the Police Department...

<Edgeworth>
あの局長‥‥
The Chief is a very competent
man...

ヤリ手なのだが、たまに
イミがわからないことがある。
but sometimes he does things
that don't make any sense.

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

まあ。ヤリ手ではない上、
イミがわからないよりはイイが。
At least it's better than
being incompetent and doing
things that don't make sense.

<Phoenix>
（ある刑事さんのカオを
　思い浮かべたようだ）
(A certain detective comes
to mind...)




<Edgeworth>
今回の事件‥‥何から何まで、
私を疑わしく見せているようだ。
It seems everything in this
case is designed to cast doubt
on me.

<Phoenix>
ぼくをニラまないでほしいな。
Hey, don't look at me.

<Edgeworth>
事件があった日‥‥たしかに、
私は証拠保管室に入った。
Yes, I went into the evidence
room on the day of the crime.

巌徒局長から、急に
たのまれたものでね。
Chief Gant asked me to do
something.

<Ema>
《半年前に解決した事件の証拠を
　検事局に持ち帰ってほしい》‥‥
To take evidence from a case
solved six months ago back to
the Prosecutor's Office...

<Edgeworth>
あそこには、私自身の
保管庫が用意されているのだ。
I have a locker in there as
well.

<Phoenix>
そのとき、保管室のようすは？
Did you notice anything amiss
when you were in the evidence
room?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥あの部屋は、いつも暗い。
That room's always dark and I
was in a hurry.

私も急いでいたし、
特に気になることはなかったな。
I didn't see anything out of
the ordinary.




<Edgeworth>
“火のないところに
　ケムリは立たない”‥‥
They say where there's smoke,
there's fire.

どうやら‥‥そのケムリに巻かれて
真実を見失っていたようだ。
Apparently I was so caught up
in the smoke, I lost sight of
the truth.

<Phoenix>
御剣‥‥
Edgeworth...

<Edgeworth>
彼らは正しかった。私には‥‥
検事席に立つ資格など、ない。
The others are right.
I have no right to serve as
a prosecutor.

<Ema>
でも！　検事さんは、自分の
シゴトをしただけじゃないですか！
But Mr. Edgeworth! You were
only doing your job!

<Edgeworth>
私のなすべきコトは、つねに
私自身が決めてきた。
I've always made my own
decisions about what I can
or cannot do.

今回のコト‥‥
自分をユルすことはできない。
That hasn't changed.
Forgiving myself... is
something I cannot do.

<Phoenix>
（こいつ‥‥ホンキだぞ！）
(Uh oh. I think he's serious!)

<Ema>
‥‥成歩堂さん！
なんとかしないと、検事さんが！
Mr. Wright!
Please, you have to do
something!

<Phoenix>
（この、辞表‥‥
　何かに使えないか‥‥？）
(This Letter of Resignation...
I wonder if I can use it for
anything?)




<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

まさか、成歩堂。
担当検事である、この私が‥‥
Wright, please.
I'm the prosecutor on this
case!

キミと事件の話をしながら
お茶を飲むとでも‥‥？
You don't expect me to sit
here and discuss the case
with you over a cup of tea!

<Phoenix>
いや。お茶はいいんだ。
事件のハナシだけを‥‥
I'll pass on the tea.
Just tell me about the case...

<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　御剣検事さんは
イキに断ってるんです！
Mr. Wright! Mr. Edgeworth
just told you "no" in a very
stylish manner!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(Whose side are you on,
anyway?)

（本当に必要なものだけ
　鼻先につきつけてやろう）
(Maybe if I just show him my
best evidence I can get
some reaction out of him.)

