< >
２月２２日　某時刻
検事局・地下駐車場
February 22
Prosecutor's Office
Underground Parking Lot

<Phoenix>
ここが、事件のあった駐車場か。
So this is the lot
where it all happened?

<Ema>
まだ、捜査中みたいですね‥‥
Looks like they're still
investigating...

<Phoenix>
（そういえば、検事局に
　来るのって、初めてだな‥‥）
(Funny that my first visit
to the Prosecutor's Office
should be like this...)

<Ema>
みなさーん、ゴクローさまですッ！
Hey everyone!
Keep up the good work!

<Phoenix>
こ‥‥こらこら！
ナニしてるんだよ！
H-hey!
What are you thinking?

<Ema>
あ、ホラ。あたしも３年後には
シゴト仲間になるわけですから。
Well, they are going to be
my coworkers three years
from now after all.

ここはひとつ、ごアイサツを‥‥
No harm in saying hello...

<Phoenix>
あのね。弁護士には、現場を
捜査するケンリはないんだよ。
Actually, there is. You know
attorneys aren't supposed to
examine crime scenes?

あんまりハデに目立つと‥‥
I'm trying to not stand out
too much, here, see?

<???>
ヘイ！
Hey there!

それでジミを気取ってるつもりかい
‥‥カウボーイ！
You 'specting to go unnoticed
here, pardner?

<Ema>
か、かうぼーい‥‥？
P-Pardner?

<???>
どうやら‥‥
What do we have here?

牧場をはぐれたバンビーナが、
おイタをしてるようだよ。
Looks like a bambina got loose
from the ranch and is up to
no good!

しっかり、ナワでつないで
もらいたいものだね。
Folks gotta learn to keep them
dogies tied down, pardner.

<Ema>
ざ‥‥ザイモンさん！
M-Mr. Marshall!

<Phoenix>
（ざいもん‥‥
　このアメリカ人の名前か？）
(Marshall? Looks more like
a sheriff to me...)

<???>
いいかい、バンビーナ。
キミのキモチはわかるさ。
Lookie here, bambina.
I know how you feel.

だがしかし。ここはオレたちの
ゴールドラッシュ‥‥わかるだろ？
But this is my gang's
gold strike, see?

<Ema>
ごーるどらっしゅ‥‥？
Strike...?

<???>
“証拠”というおタカラが眠る、
ユメの金鉱‥‥ナワバリ、なのさ。
This is our claim, our
territory. And the goldmine
is... evidence.

荒らそうってハラなら‥‥
タダじゃすまないね、カウボーイ！
If you're fixin' to mess
with what's ours...
You'll regret it, pardner!

‥‥荒野のサボテンが見るユメ。
アンタも見てみたいかい‥‥？
You know what dreams the
cacti out in the desert
dream? You want to?

<Phoenix>
（イミがわかんないよ！）
(What's this guy talking
about!?)

<???>
とにかく、おウチへ帰るコトさ。
‥‥あばよ、バンビーナ！
You head along home now.
Happy trails, bambina!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
あの。今の宇宙じ‥‥外国人、
きみの知り合いなの？
Was that uh, hombre,
a friend of yours?

<Ema>
え。‥‥あ、はい。まあ‥‥
Uh... kind of... sort of...
Yeah. He's a detective.

<Phoenix>
（捜査官‥‥というより、
　保安官だよな、アレ‥‥）
(Who thinks he's a sheriff
from the Wild West it seems.)




<Ema>
さあ！　こうなったら、
調べまくっちゃいましょうよ！
Well, no time to waste!
Let's get hunting for clues!

ええと、これはナニかな‥‥
Hmm... I wonder what this is?

<???>
どうやら‥‥カウボーイ。
おとなしく帰る気はないようだ。
Well, pardner. Looks like
you got no intention of
going home quietly.

<Phoenix>
（さっきの保安官‥‥！）
(The sheriff!)

<???>
言ったハズだよ。
ここは、オレたちのナワバリさ。
Like I said before, this
here's our claim.

おとなしく帰らないと‥‥
弾丸を噛むコトになるさ。
You'd best be moseying along.
Unless you're fixing to bite
the bullet.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥怖ェ！）
(Gah! Scary!)

<Ema>
あ、あの！　せめて‥‥
あの赤いクルマの持ち主だけでも！
C-could you just tell us
one thing...?
Who owns that car?

<???>
やれやれ‥‥
ハナのきく子馬ちゃんだね。
Well, well. The little filly's
got a good nose on her!

<???>
死体をくわえた、赤いジャジャ馬の
ご主人を知りたい、ってワケだ。
You want to know who rides
that red mustang with the
body in her saddle, eh?

<Ema>
お‥‥おねがいしますっ！
Please!

<???>
‥‥オーライ。いいだろうさ。
マチネーにはちょうどいい時間だ。
No problem, pardner. 'Bout
time for vittles anyway.

１２階の、このサルーンに
行ってみるといい。
Get yourself to the saloon
up on the 12th floor of the
Prospector's Office.

今なら、ウマいエールに
ありつけるかも、だぜ。
Might just find you a
cervesa you like.

<Phoenix>
（どうもこのヒト、国境と時代を
　飛び越えてるんだよな‥‥）
(Prospector's Office? Where
does this guy think he is? 
And when, for that matter!?)

<Ema>
マチネー、サルーン、エール‥‥
あとで調べておくこと、と。
Note to self: look up
vittles, saloon, cervesa.

<Phoenix>
（上級検事執務室、１２０２号。
　行ってみるか！）
(Maybe we should check out
room 1202... the High
Prosecutor's Office!)

<???>
とにかく‥‥クルマのまわりは
立入禁止にさせてもらうよ。
In any case, stay away from
the car.

遊びたけりゃ、このへんに
しておくことだね。
You can look around here
all you like, just keep your
paws off our claim.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥しかたないな）
(Right... great.)

<Ema>
よおし！　このへんだけでも、
シッカリ調べましょう！
Great! Maybe there are some
clues around here, Mr. Wright!
Let's check it out!







<Phoenix>
これは‥‥サイフ、かな。
What's this? 
A wallet?

あのー、すみませーん！
おまわりさーん！
Um, excuse me!
Officer!

<Ema>
ちょ、ちょ、ちょっとちょっと！
ナニしてるんですか、成歩堂さん！
W-w-waaaait!
What are you doing,
Mr. Wright!?

<Phoenix>
な、ナニって、サイフを拾ったら、
ちゃんとケーサツに‥‥
What am I doing? I just found
this wallet, so I'm handing it
over to the police...

<Ema>
‥‥はああああ。
I don't believe it!

いいですか。現場で拾ったものは
《証拠物件》なんです。
This is real basic: anything
at a crime scene is evidence!

もっと、カガク的に行きましょう！
ホラ。ポケットにしまうしまう。
Let's be scientific about
this, please!
Just put it in your pocket.

<Phoenix>
か、かがくてき、って‥‥
（ドロボーにされちまったぞ‥‥）
H-how is that scientific?
(Sounds like theft to me!)

< >
《サイフ》をポケットに
ぎゅっとネジこまれた。
Wallet hastily stuffed
into pocket.

<Ema>
さあ、あたしの出番ですね！
すでにこのトシにして、もう！
I'm called to duty already,
and at my tender age!

トクベツに、《証拠品》を詳しく
調べる方法を教えちゃいますね！
Here, I'll teach you the
trick to examining evidence
in detail, okay?

<Phoenix>
（異様にうれしそうだな‥‥
　目がギラギラかがやいているぞ）
(By the way her eyes are 
sparkling I can tell she's
been waiting for this...)

<Ema>
じゃあ、じゃあ、サッソク。
《法廷記録》を見てください！
Okay, okay, now.
Look at the Court Record!




<Ema>
《証拠品》は、タテからヨコから
ジックリ見るのがダイジなんです！
You have to be sure to
examine evidence carefully
on all sides!

さ。さ。調べてみましょうよ！
いろんな角度から！
Now. Let's start examining!
From every angle!




<Ema>
‥‥あ。そこ！
何か手がかりがありますよ！
Oh look! I think there might
be a clue there.

さっそく、《調べる》ボタンに
タッチしてみてください！
You should check it out!
Press the Examine button.




<Phoenix>
こ、これは‥‥ＩＤカード、かな。
This... This is an ID card.

《捜査官：タダシキ　ミチオ
　　ＩＤ：５８４２１８９》‥‥
(Detective Bruce Goodman,
ID # 5842189...)

<Ema>
ほら、ほら。どうですか！
ベンリでしょ？　カガク捜査。
See? Well?
Isn't scientific investigation
useful?

<Phoenix>
そうだね。‥‥カガクは
あまりカンケイない気がするけど。
I guess... Though I don't
see what "science" has to
do with it.

< >



《多田敷捜査官のＩＤ》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Goodman's ID added
to the Court Record.

<Ema>
証拠品を見つけたら
いろいろ調べてみましょうね！
Let's be sure to examine
every piece of evidence
we find!

<Phoenix>
（なんというか‥‥
　気が抜けなくなったな）
(I guess I've got to be on
my toes from now on...)




<???>
‥‥ちょっと。
Excuse me?

よろしかったかしら。
そこの、おふたかた。
Were you two all set?

<Ema>
あ。あたしたちですか？
Us?

<Phoenix>
（なんだ？　まさか‥‥）
(What's this?
She couldn't be...)

<Ema>
お、お弁当屋さん、かな。
‥‥殺人現場なのに。
Y-you're selling lunches?
Here? This is a crime scene!

<???>
はい。こちら、とりそぼろ弁当で
よろしかったかしら？
Hello! Half n' Half, was it?

<Ema>
あ、ど。どうもスミマセン‥‥
Oh. Uh, thanks.

<???>
そちらの殿方も。
And you, sir?

<Phoenix>
は、はい！
Y-yes?

<???>
ノリ弁当でよろしかったかしら？
Some Crunchy Goodness coming
at you!

<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥
（ぼくももらっちゃったよ‥‥）
Uh... thanks.
(Interesting way of doing
business.)

<???>
こちら、関係者以外は
立入禁止ですのよ。
This area is off limits to
anyone without clearance.

‥‥特に、一般のカタは。
おわかりだったかしら‥‥？
Especially passers-by.
Or are you officers?

<Ema>
あ。でも、あなたも、その。
カンケイ者には見えませんけど。
Uh... no, but you...
You don't exactly look like
the type to have clearance.

<???>
ふう‥‥。これはまた、
ずいぶんなゴアイサツですわねえ。
Well, that's hardly a way
to greet someone!

この“ゲロまみれのおキョウ”も
今はムカシ。はかないユメ‥‥
Even if my days as the
"Cough-up Queen" are over...

<Phoenix>
げ、“げろまみれ”‥‥？
あ、あなたが？
C-cough-up? Huh?

<Ema>
あ、あたし。おなかいっぱいだし、
やっぱり、このお弁当は‥‥
You know, I'm feeling kind
of full. Maybe I'll pass on
lunch...

<???>
ワタクシ、この件には深い
ゆかりがございますのよ。
I'm quite connected to this
case, you see.

今も、目に焼きついていますの。
あのツヤっぽい、ヒメゴトが‥‥
The images are burned into
my eyes, you might say.
Yes, all the sordid secrets...

<Ema>
‥‥ひめごと‥‥？
Secrets...?

<???>
‥‥やれやれ。
じれったいコムスメだねえ。
Dear me.
You are a slow one,
aren't you?

捜査官が刺された、
あの事件に決まってるだろうが。
I'm referring to the murder.
The stabbing of that
detective.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥‥ええええッ！
Whaaaat!?

<Lana>
‥‥私、犯行の瞬間を
ハッキリ見られましたので。
A witness clearly saw me
committing the crime.

<Ema>
じゃ、じゃあ‥‥お姉ちゃんが
言ってた“目撃者”って‥‥
You mean you're the witness
my sister was talking about?

<Phoenix>
あの！　詳しく聞かせてください、
ゲロまみれさん！
Please! Cough-up Queen!
Tell us what happened!

<Angel>
市ノ谷　響華
（いちのたにきょうか）ですわ。
The name is Angel Starr.
Don't you go forgetting it.

<Angel>
‥‥以後、お見知りおきを。

さもないと‥‥おキョウのカカトに
むせび泣くコトになるだろうさ。
Or before you know it 
I'll have you whimpering at
my heels.

<Phoenix>
は、ははは、はいッ！
（なんだ、このムチャな迫力は！）
Y-y-yes, ma'am!
(Yipes! She means it!)






<Ema>
ここは‥‥クルマの出口ですね。
This is where the cars leave
the lot.

<Phoenix>
床のヤジルシを見ると、
“入口”みたいだけどね。
The arrow on the ground
makes it look more like
an entrance.

<Ema>
ナニ言ってるんですか！
どう見ても出口じゃないですか！
What are you talking about?
It's plainly an exit!

<Phoenix>
ま、まあ‥‥出口であると同時に、
入口でもある、というコトかな。
Well, maybe it's both.
Kind of a dual purpose?

<Ema>
あ！　それ！　あの有名な
“ソータイセー理論”ですね！
Ah hah! The theory of
relativity!

<Phoenix>
え！　は、はあ‥‥
What? Uh...

<Ema>
メモしとかないとね‥‥
あ！　ね。ね。成歩堂さん。
I've got to write this down.
Ah! Hey, hey, Mr. Wright!

どこの国のヒトでしたっけ？
ソー・タイセーさんって。
Maybe you know...
Was Mr. Relativity, German?
Or was he British?

<Phoenix>
‥‥知らないよ。
Mr. Relativity? Are you
sure that was his name?







<Ema>
あ。ハシゴですよ。
Ah hah! A ladder.

<Phoenix>
それはキャタツだよ。
Um... That's a stepladder.

<Ema>
どこが違うんですか？
カガク的に証明してください。
What's the difference?
In scientific terms, please.

<Phoenix>
か、カガク的‥‥
S-scientific huh?

<Ema>
もっとホンシツを見ましょうよ、
成歩堂さん。
Look at the basic nature of
things, Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
（なぜだろう‥‥あまずっぱい
　キモチになってきた）
(This all seems so horribly
familiar somehow...)







<Ema>
お。こんなところに
イミありげなドアが！
Look! A door!
This must mean something!

<Phoenix>
ドアに“イミ”なんてないよ。
I'm not sure that doors
"mean" anything.

<Ema>
クッ！　開きません！
ナゾのカギがかかってます！
No! It won't open!
A mysterious lock!

<Phoenix>
カギに“ナゾ”なんてないよ。
I fail to see what's
mysterious about it.

<Ema>
‥‥成歩堂さん。
もっと人生を楽しみましょうよ。
Mr. Wright...
You need to learn
to enjoy life more.

<Phoenix>
先に調査をすませようよ。
Let's finish our investigation
first, shall we?







<Ema>
‥‥あんなところに、ガラス張りの
オシャレな部屋があります！
Look! A stylish, glass-walled
room! Very nice.

<Phoenix>
あそこからだったら、駐車場を
カンゼンに見わたせるね。
You could see the whole
parking lot from in there.

<Ema>
“ＳＥＣＵＲＩＴＹ”‥‥ね。
キッサ室でしょうか。
It says "SECURITY."
Perhaps it's a cafe?

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

<Ema>
‥‥キッサ・セキュリティ、と。
あとで、行ってみましょう！
"Cafe Security"...
Yeah, that must be it.
Let's check it out later!

<Phoenix>
ザンネンだけど‥‥たぶん
警備室だぞ、あれ。
Um. I hate to break it to you,
but I think that's probably
just a security guard office.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あ。あたし、こないだのテスト、
カガクは９７点でしたから！
You know, I scored a 97
on my science test the
other day!

<Phoenix>
（英語は何点だったんだよ‥‥）
(Too bad they don't have
a test for common sense.)







<Phoenix>
ドラム缶だ。
‥‥水が入ってるみたいだ。
An oil drum.
Looks like it's filled
with water.

<Ema>
お、重いです！
さすがにこれは。あたしでも。
I-it's heavy!
I can't even budge it!

<Phoenix>
‥‥こっちのドラム缶は、
倒れてるね。
The drum over here is on its
side.

<Ema>
あ。あたし、この中に入って
“はりこみ”しましょうか！
Wait! I know! I'll hide in
here and do a stake-out!

<Phoenix>
‥‥そんなところに入ってたら
タイホされちゃうよ。
I think you'll probably just
get arrested.

（ただでさえアヤシイのに）
(In fact, you may not even 
have to hide in the drum
to get arrested.)

<Ema>
アヤしくないっ！
What? I'm not suspicious!







<Ema>
ちょっとジャマですね。
‥‥このカベ。
This wall is in our way.

<Phoenix>
小さな蛇口がついてるね。水道の。
It's got a faucet for water.

<Ema>
あ。もしかして、コレ！
Wait! I know!

“カベ”は世をしのぶ
仮のスガタで‥‥その正体は！
This "wall" is merely a 
facade, hiding the truth...

非常用のタンクかもしれません！
This is no wall,
but a water tank!!!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥どっちでも
　いいんじゃないかな）
(I fail to see how it makes
any difference either way...)







<Ema>
お。電話がありますよ。
‥‥どれどれ。
Here, a phone.
Let's see if it works...

<Phoenix>
こらこら。
勝手にさわらないほうがいいよ。
Hey. Don't touch stuff we
don't need to be touching.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
な、何も聞こえません！
...
I can't hear anything!

あたしの耳、ヘンになったのカモ！
気圧のせい、でしょうか‥‥
My ears! No, my ears!
Maybe it's due to the
barometric pressure...

<Phoenix>
（ナニを、バカなコトを‥‥）
(What is she babbling about?)

<Ema>
あ、そこ！　なんですか！
Hey!? What did you just
say?

<Phoenix>
聞こえてるじゃないか！
電話がコワれてるんだよ！
See? You can hear just fine.
The phone's broken!




<Angel>
ワタクシ‥‥知っていたような
気がしますの。
Somehow... I knew.

毎週、金曜日の日替わり弁当が
シャケであるように‥‥
Yesterday was a day of
destiny... I knew something
was going to happen...

きのうこそは、何が起こっても
おかしくない‥‥ウンメイの日。
Just like I know that the
Daily Special on Friday
every week is salmon.

<Phoenix>
“ウンメイ”‥‥あの。
何かトクベツな日だったんですか？
Destiny...? Was yesterday
special for some reason?

<Angel>
‥‥そちら、弁護士でしたわねぇ。
ならば、ご存じなのでは？
You're a defense attorney,
right? You should know then.

ここに巣食うツミ深い殿方たちの、
非道のかぎりをつくした悪行。
You should know the foul
misdeeds of the evil ones who
haunt this den of inequity!

<Ema>
あ、あくぎょう‥‥
E-evil ones?

<Angel>
ヒトに罪の汚名を着せるため、
手段を選ばない‥‥それが、検事。
Prosecutors! They have no
qualms at all about blackening
the name of innocents!

きのうは‥‥そう。最も邪悪なる
者をたたえる日でしたのよ。
And yesterday they paid
homage to the most evil
one of all!

“優秀な検事”を、表彰する‥‥
まさに茶番、ですわね。
They gave an award for
"King of Prosecutors"...
What a farce!

<Ema>
カンタンに言うと‥‥
So, she's saying...

検事さんたちの大会が
あったみたいですね。きのう。
There was some sort of
prosecutor's convention
yesterday.

<Angel>
お弁当に、カラダに悪いオカズを
入れようか、迷いあぐねましたわ。
I was almost compelled to
lace their lunches with
something foul...

<Ema>
あの。どうして検事さんのコト、
そんなふうに言うんですか？
Do you have a personal
grievance against prosecutors,
or something?

検事さんがワルモノだっていう、
カガク的な証拠でも‥‥
Or is there some kind of
scientific evidence of this,
um, "evil"?

<Angel>
‥‥おじょうちゃん。
Young miss...

このおキョウ、
ナメるとゲロの味がしますわよ。
Mock me at your own risk!
You'll soon find out why they
call me the "Cough-up Queen"!

<Ema>
え！
Ew!

<Angel>
きのう表彰された、
この辺で最もコッケイなオトコ‥‥
The most heinous of all
the evil ones, the one they
awarded yesterday... 

被害者の遺体が発見されたのは、
その検事のクルマだったのさ。
It was in his car that they
found the body!

ヤツらが、極悪の弁当をむさぼり
食ってる、何よりの証拠さね！
Proof that he devours the
evilest lunches of all!

<Ema>
そ‥‥そうなんですか！
R-really!?

<Phoenix>
（なんなんだろう‥‥）
(Really what? I'm totally
confused...)

（このひとの、“検事”に対する
　憎しみのようなものは‥‥）
(One thing's clear. This
lunch lady has a thing
against prosecutors.)




<Phoenix>
それで、その。響華さんが
目撃した、というのは‥‥？
So, what exactly was it that
you witnessed, Ms. Starr?

<Angel>
それは‥‥ナマめかしいながめ、
でしたわねえ。
It was a fascinating
spectacle, to be sure!

オンナの情念‥‥そのようなものを
感じてしまいましたわ。
I now feel I know what they
say when they talk about
a "woman's wrath."

あの、宝月　巴が
ナイフを使った瞬間に。
To see Lana Skye wield
that knife so...

<Phoenix>
！
!

<Angel>
怒りのタンザク切り、悲しみは
イチョウ切りのナイフさばき‥‥
Her knife flashed in anger,
bringing him to a sad end.

それはそれはミゴトなモノ、
でしたわねぇ‥‥
It was truly a sight to see.

<Ema>
ま、まさか！
おキョウさん、犯行の瞬間を‥‥？
Y-you mean you saw the
very moment of the crime!?

<Angel>
イノチの赤い糸が千切りにされる
マナイタの音‥‥今も、この耳に。
The sound of his silvery ties
to this world being cruelly
cut still rings in my ears.

宝月　巴の赤い糸を刻む
包丁のリズムも、ここまでだねぇ。
And the rhythmic beat of
Lana Skye's knife...

<Phoenix>
あの‥‥あなたは、
宝月　巴さんを知ってるんですか？
Wait a second!
You know Lana Skye?

<Angel>
主席検事サマ、かしら？
Hmph. Of course.
It's quite a feat... becoming
Chief Prosecutor.

どれだけの罪を重ねて、
その名をつかんだコトか‥‥
How many lunchboxes of sin
did she pack to make that
journey, I wonder!

<Ema>
に‥‥２段がさね‥‥
She... always travels light.

<Phoenix>
（キレイな弁当屋のお姉さんが、
　なぜ主席検事の名前を‥‥？）
(Now why would this pretty
lunch lady know the
Chief Prosecutor's name?)




<Ema>
あの。おキョウさんのコト、
聞かせていただけますか？
Um... Could we ask you a
bit about yourself, Ms. Starr?

<Angel>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
I come here every day
to sell lunches.

オンナもこのトシになると‥‥
ひとつやふたつ、昔話があるもの。
I import only the freshest
and best from the Far East.

‥‥オコサマには
聞かせられないような、ねぇ。
For some reason, the box
lunches are a hit here.

<Ema>
Why not make the lunches here
rather than import them?

<Angel>
Did you say something?

<Ema>
は、はあ。
N-no...

<Angel>
Only true conossieurs can
understand...

<Angel>
くさや弁当の味がわかるように
なったら、またいらっしゃいな。
The kind you can only tell
someone who has tried General
Tso's Trilobite lunch set.

<Ema>
ま、まいりましたっ！
Ah... Nevermind...
You win.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥クサいな）
(I don't even want to
appreciate part of a
trilobite's flavor.)

<Angel>
ワタクシ、毎日ここへ
お弁当を売りにまいりますの。
Anyway, I come here every
day to sell lunches.

この検事局の守衛室に、
カレがいるんですのよ。
My boyfriend works in the
security room here at the
Prosecutor's Office.

<Ema>
か、“カレ”‥‥？
Y-your boyfriend?

<Angel>
ほら。あそこに、
守衛室が見えますでしょ？
See the security room
over there?

<Phoenix>
“ＳＥＣＵＲＩＴＹ”と書かれた、
あのガラス張りの部屋ですか。
The glass-walled booth?

<Angel>
お弁当を売りに来るついでに、
カオを出してさしあげますの。
I sell my lunches and,
since I'm here anyway,
I drop in to see him.

<Phoenix>
（カレのほうは“ついで”か）
(Since you're here anyway...
I guess selling lunches is
more important than romance.)

<Ema>
とりあえず、これまでの情報を
カガク的に整理すると‥‥
So, to scientifically analyze
the data available so far...

おキョウさんは、何かワケありの
お弁当屋さん、というコトですね！
You, Ms. Starr, are a lunch
vendor with an ulterior
motive for coming here!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥役に立たない情報だな）
(Useful analysis. Not.)




<Phoenix>
おキョウさん‥‥検事局で、
何かあったんですか？
Did you have a bad experience
with a prosecutor, Ms. Starr?

強い“悪意”のようなものを
感じるんですけど‥‥
I sense some... hostility.

<Angel>
悪意‥‥
そうかもしれないわねぇ‥‥
Hostility? Hah!
Perhaps.

<Angel>
検事なんて、みんな同じ。
エラいヤツほど、始末が悪い‥‥
Prosecutors are all alike.
And the bigger they get, 
the worse they smell.

シジミのおみおつけに、あえて
アワビを入れるようなものかしら。
Kind of like 10-day old
clams in the chowder.

<Phoenix>
（おキョウさん‥‥ムカシ、
　事件にまきこまれたのかな）
(I wonder if Ms. Starr was
involved in some sort of
legal trouble in the past?)

<Ema>
あ。きっと、食中毒がらみですよ！
カガク的に考えて。
That'd be a sure cause of
food poisoning! Scientifically
speaking, of course.

だって、なんと言っても
《ゲロまみれ》だし！
I mean, now you're
talking "Cough-up Queen"!

<Phoenix>
（おキョウさん‥‥いったい、
　何をしていたヒトなんだ‥‥？）
(I thought she was just a
lunch vendor, but now I'm
not so sure...)




<Angel>
弁護士は、たたかうオトコ。
そちら‥‥勝てるのかしら？
A defense attorney must
be able to fight...

<Angel>
How about you? Do you think
you can win?

ベントーランドがこだわりぬいた、
自家製タクアン弁当の歯ごたえに！
How about tackling
Lunchland's Pickle Supreme
lunchbox!?

<Ema>
うん！　カリカリしてて、
とってもオイシイですっ！
Wow! It's really crunchy!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥こだわりぬくのはいいけど、
　さみしいオカズだな）
(A box of pickles...?
Kind of a sad lunch if you
ask me.)




<Phoenix>
あの。このカードなんですけど。
About this card...

<Angel>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ベントーランドは、現金のみ。
カードは扱っておりませんの。
Lunchland vendors only 
accept cash. No cards.

しかも、他人サマのカードは。
Especially not a card
belonging to someone else!

<Phoenix>
い、いやいや。これ、捜査官の
ＩＤカードみたいなんですけど‥‥
No, no, this isn't a credit
card. It's an ID card. It
belongs to a detective...

<Angel>
‥‥そんなものを弁当屋に
見せられてもねぇ。
And you're showing this to
me, the lunch lady, why?

捜査官に、ハマチの切り身を
見せるようなものですわ。
That's like showing a fine
honeyed ham to a detective!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんか、
　バカにされているような‥‥）
(Why do I always feel like
I'm being mocked?)




<Phoenix>
これ、見ていただけますか？
Could you take a look at this?

<Angel>
‥‥そちら。
You!

<Phoenix>
は、はい！
Y-yes!?

<Angel>
アガリは、ほうじ茶で
よろしかったかしら。
You said you wanted some
hot tea, right?

<Phoenix>
あ、どうも‥‥
（見る気はないみたいだな‥‥）
Uh, no, but thanks.
(She didn't even look at me.)

<Ema>
うん。とってもオイシイ！
深炒りでしか出ない味ですよねー。
Mmm! You must have to brew
the leaves a long time to get
rich flavor like this!

<Angel>
炒ったときのケムリで、
茶葉をいぶしてますのよ。
We "pre-infuse" the leaves
with steam before brewing.

<Ema>
やっぱり！　香ばしさのヒミツは
そこにあったんですねー！
I knew it! So that's the
secret to their aroma!
Exquisite!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんなんだ、
　この香ばしい空気は‥‥）
(The only thing I'm smelling
here is wasted time...)




< >
２月２２日　某時刻
警察局・エントランス
February 22
Police Department
Entrance

<Ema>
うー‥‥
やっと着きましたね。
Whew...
We're finally here.

なんでこんなに検事局から離れた
トコに建てるかなあ、警察局。
Why would they put the
detectives so far away
from the Prosecutor's Office?

<Phoenix>
タクシーで３０分近くかかったね。
That took almost 30 minutes
by taxi... and traffic wasn't
even that bad.

いつも刑事課に行くから、
警察局に来るのは初めて‥‥ん？
This is my first time to the
Police Department, actually.
?

なんだ？　アレ。
Hold on, what's that?

<Ema>
ぶ‥‥ブキミですね、なんか。
ワキワキとうごめいてますよ。
Disturbing! Why does it
undulate like that?

<Phoenix>
‥‥ああ。コイツならたしか、
“タイホくん”とか言ったっけ。
Oh, wait I know. This is
the "Blue Badger."

将来、警察のマスコットに
なるかもしれないよ。
They're trying to make him
the police mascot.

<Ema>
うわ。成歩堂さん、
ケーサツマニアですねー！
Wow, Mr. Wright!
You know a lot about the
Police Department!

‥‥でも。なんか、どこかで
見たことがあるような‥‥
Still, he does seem
familiar, somehow...

<Phoenix>
それより‥‥
タイホくんの、となりだけど。
Forget the Blue Badger!
Who's that next to him!?

<Ema>
タイホくんと、いっしょに
おどってるヒトがいますね‥‥
Someone appears to be...
dancing with the Blue
Badger...

‥‥あ。
あたしたちに気がついたみたい。
Uh oh.
He noticed me.

<Phoenix>
スゴいイキオイで
こっちに走ってくるな‥‥
He sure is running
over here fast...

<Gumshoe>
あ。あ。あ。あ。アンタ！
こ。こ。こ。こ。ここで何を！
H-h-h-hey, pal!
W-w-w-what're you doin' here!?

<Phoenix>
それは、こっちのセリフですよ
イトノコ刑事。
That's my line,
Detective Gumshoe.

どうしてこんなトコロで
おどってるんですか？
Specifically, why were
you dancing over there?

<Gumshoe>
えッ！　それは‥‥その。
What!? Um, well...

<Phoenix>
（せっかくだ。ヒマみたいだし、
　いろいろ聞かせてもらおう）
(Well, at least he doesn't
seem to be busy. This is our
chance to get information!)

<Gumshoe>
ヒマじゃないッス！
Hey! I'll have you know
I'm a very busy man, pal.




<Gumshoe>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

まあ。自分が話せるのは、
こんなところッスかね。
And that's all I know
about that.

なにぶん、
事件を担当してないッスから。
I'm not officially on
the case, you know.

<Ema>
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!

<Phoenix>
‥‥でも、イトノコ刑事が担当して
いないなんて、めずらしいですね。
Why aren't you handling
the case, Detective Gumshoe?

地下駐車場の担当のヒト‥‥
なんて言いましたっけ？
We met the guy who is...
what was his name? The
guy in the parking lot...

<Gumshoe>
ザイモン巡査ッスか。
That'd be Officer Marshall.

警察局長、じきじきの
任命ッスから‥‥勝てないッス。
He was appointed directly
by the Chief of Police...

<Phoenix>
ミスター・サイモン‥‥
やっぱり、アメリカから？
Officer Marshall...
Is he some kind of Wild West
sheriff or something?

<Gumshoe>
いやいや、ザイモンッス。
罪門　恭介（キョウスケ）。
No, Jake Marshall's just
a regular officer...

リッパなニッポン人ッス。
From West LA.

<Phoenix>
え！　そ、そうなんですか！
For a moment there,
I wasn't sure.

<Gumshoe>
まま。ここはヒトツ、自分が
ベンギをはかってあげるッス。
Look, pal, let me try to
make things a little
easier for you.

これを見せれば、現場を調べさせて
もらえるッスよ。‥‥たぶん。
Show them this and they'll
let you examine the
crime scene... maybe.

< >
イトノコ刑事の《紹介状》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Letter of Introduction from
Detective Gumshoe added to
the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（この刑事さんに、そんな
　チカラがあるのか‥‥？）
(I'll be surprised if this
gets us anywhere...)

<Gumshoe>
でっかいドロ舟に乗った気分で
ひとっぱしり、行ってくるッス！
Just act like you're supposed
to be there, and nobody will
look at you twice, pal!




<Ema>
あの‥‥。
アレのコトなんですけど。
Uh, I was wondering about
that...

<Gumshoe>
《おどるタイホくん》ッスか。
‥‥ズバリ、自信作ッス。
What?
The Dancing Blue Badger?
It's my masterpiece!

<Phoenix>
‥‥イトノコ刑事が
作ったんですか、コレ。
You made this, Detective
Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
カチョー殿の設計図をもとに、
自分がウデをふるってみたッス。
The chief threw together some
designs and I just did my
thing, pal.

<Ema>
‥‥へえ！
N-nice work...

<Gumshoe>
どこでも置けるように、
デンチで動くようにしてあるッス。
It's battery-powered,
so it can go anywhere!

スイッチがないから、デンチが
切れるまで、おどり狂うッス。
There's no switch, so it
just dance dance dances until
the batteries die!

<Ema>
カナしい運命なんですね、
タイホくん‥‥
Poor Blue Badger... fated
to dance until he drops.

< >
《タイホくん》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Blue Badger added
to the Court Record.

<Gumshoe>



<Phoenix>
刑事さんたちが見える。
みんな、忙しそうだ。
The detectives in there
look pretty busy.

<Ema>
あのドアの向こうで、
今、まさに！
Just imagine!
Right now...

くり広げられているんですね。
‥‥“刑事ドラマ”がッ！
Behind those doors...!
A police drama in action!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（たしかに、マチガイではないけど
　‥‥ミョーにモヤモヤするな）
(Somehow the thought fails
to excite me...)




<Phoenix>
掲示板には、おなじみの
ポスターが張ってある。
The usual wanted posters are
hanging up on the bulletin
board here.

《このカオに、ピン！　と来たら
　１１０番》‥‥か。
«Do you know this face!?
If you do, dial 911!»

<Ema>
‥‥でも。
こういうポスターのカオって‥‥
You know, Mr. Wright,
I've always thought it
was kind of funny...

なーんか、
ピン！　と来ないんですよねー。
I've never seen anyone who
looked like the people in
these posters.

<Ema>
They hardly even look human!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（たしかに、マチガイではないけど
　‥‥ミョーにモヤモヤするな）
(She has a point...)




<Ema>
《真冬の防犯フェア・開催中！》
‥‥って、書いてあります。
The banner here is announcing
the "Crime Fighting Campaign."

<Phoenix>
大ざっぱなスローガンだな。
Nice slogan...

<Ema>
ルミノール試薬とか、
安く売ってないかなあ。
I wonder if they'll be selling
fingerprinting sets.

<Phoenix>
‥‥バーゲンセールじゃ
ないからね。
I don't think it's that kind
of campaign.

<Ema>
家庭に１本あると、
安心だと思うけどなあ。
What family wouldn't want
a set at home?

‥‥サツジン事件が
起きたとき、とか。
It's good for finding out who
snuck into the cookie jar.

<Phoenix>
安心のためなら、他のものを
買ったほうがいいと思うよ。
I think most families can
figure that out without the
extra help.




<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　パトカーの色、
なんでシロクロか知ってますか？
Mr. Wright! Do you know
why patrol cars are painted
black and white?

<Phoenix>
知らないよ。どうして？
No idea. Why?

<Ema>
あたしね。アレ、おむすびを
デザインしたんだと思うんですよ。
Well, I think they're 
designed after a panda!

<Phoenix>
お、おむすび‥‥？
A panda...?

<Ema>
まあ。カガク的なコンキョは
ありませんけどね。
Not that I have scientific
proof. It's just a theory.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ちなみに、
どうしてそう思うの？
Um... do you mind me asking
how you came up with that
theory?

<Ema>
小学生のころ、遠足で見学に来た
とき、パッとヒラめいたんです！
It was when I was on a school
trip! I saw a patrol car and
it came to me!

‥‥お弁当の時間に。
We had just been at the
zoo, see...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

今度、パンダを見に行くときは、
サンドイッチにしたほうがいいよ。
What about zebras?
Or did they not have
those at your zoo?




<Ema>
成歩堂さん！　警察のマーク、
どういうイミか、知ってますか？
I always get excited when I 
come to the police station.

<Phoenix>
知らないよ。なんなの？
Why is that?

<Ema>
あたしね。コレ、宇宙ステーション
だと思ってたんですよ。ムカシ。
It just feels like I've
jumped into a movie.

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

<Ema>
小さいコロの話ですけど。
ホラ、カタチが似てるでしょ？
You know, with all the police
and criminals.

<Phoenix>
あ‥‥ああ。見たことないから。
‥‥宇宙ステーションは。
W-well, I don't know if this
is all that exciting.

<Ema>
でも、“それはあり得ない”って
気づいたんです。去年。
Sure it is! Look at those two
officers over there.

だって、“ポリスステーション”
ですからね。“警察署”は。
They're probably talking about
the latest bust!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

もっと早く気づきたかったね。
それも、別のカタチで。
Funny, I thought they were
talking about the weather.




<Phoenix>
おまわりさんがケーレイしている。
相手は刑事さんだろうか。
Look, that patrolman is
saluting the other guy.
He must be a detective!

<Police>
そこで、オレは言ってやったのさ。
《カツ丼‥‥さめるぜ》ってな。
And then I said "hey,
you do that, your soup
will get cold, buddy."

<Patrolman>
い‥‥いいハナシでありますッ！
本官、泣けてきましたッ！
Th-That's hilarious, sir!
I laughed so hard I cried!

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ケーレイじゃなくて、
ナミダをふいてるみたいですね。
I guess he wasn't saluting,
he was wiping tears from his
eyes.

<Phoenix>
‥‥いいコンビになりそうだ。
They make a good pair.




<Gumshoe>
とにかく、アンタに１つだけ
忠告しておくッス。
I'll give you one word
of advice, pal.

‥‥彼女のベンゴだけは、
引き受けちゃダメッス。
You'd better not agree
to defend the suspect
in this case.

<Ema>
ど。どうしてそんなコト
言うんですかッ！
Wh... Why not?

<Gumshoe>
え！　えーと、その。主席検事殿は
ハッキリ犯行を認めているッス。
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
Well... It's just that the
Chief Prosecutor has confessed
to the crime.

被害者の捜査官を検事局に
呼び出して‥‥殺害したと。
She says she summoned the
detective to the Prosecutor's
Office and... she killed him.

<Ema>
でも！　それがホンネかどうか、
わからないじゃないですかっ！
But, what if she's
not telling the truth!?

<Gumshoe>
い、いやその。決定的な証拠も
たくさんあるッスし。
Yes, well... no!
C'mon, pal! There's plenty of
evidence against her!

<Ema>
でも！　そんなの、デッチ上げ
かもしれないじゃないですかっ！
B-but what if the evidence
was faked?

<Gumshoe>
あの‥‥アンタ。
ちょっといいッスか？
Hey, pal.
Can I speak to you
for a second?

<Phoenix>
はい？　ぼくですか。
Huh? Me?

<Gumshoe>
なんで自分、こんなちっちゃい子に
怒られなきゃならないッス？
Why is this little girl
so peeved at me?

<Phoenix>
その子、妹さんなんですよ。
‥‥宝月　巴さんの。
She's a relative of the
suspect.
Lana Skye's sister.

<Gumshoe>
うげへェェッ！
主席検事殿のォォッ！
Whoa!!!
The Chief Prosecutor's 
little sister!?

<Ema>
ちゃんと捜査してくださいね！
いわば、その。カガク的にっ！
Just, please investigate
this case carefully, okay?
Scientifically!

<Gumshoe>
はッ！　‥‥あ、そッス。
Yessir! Oh, by the way.

ここであんまり大きな声で
言わないほうがいいッスよ。
You might want to keep your
voices down.

‥‥“デッチ上げ”なんて。
You don't want to be overheard
using words like "faked"...

<Ema>
え‥‥‥
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
ワレワレは今、そのコトバに
ビンカンになってるッスから‥‥
It's just... it's a
sensitive issue with
us these days.




<Ema>
それで‥‥何してるんですか？
こんなトコロで。
So... what are you doing
here, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
いや、その。なんというかあの。
Me? Oh, well... nothing,
really.

追い出されちゃったッス。
‥‥刑事課を。
They kicked me out
of Criminal Affairs...

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事‥‥また、
何かやっちゃったんですか？
Detective Gumshoe!
What did you do this time?

<Gumshoe>
なな、なんスか、“また”とは！
Whaddya mean, "this time"!?

<Ema>
じゃあ、どうしたんですか？
Then, what happened?

今、タイヘンなんですよね？
その‥‥お姉ちゃんのコトで。
I know things are busy
right now...

<Ema>
I mean... with my sister's
case and all...

<Gumshoe>
そッスね。主席検事の殺人なんて
前代未聞ッスから。
It's true. We've never had
a Chief Prosecutor murder
anyone before!

今、刑事課に入れるのは、刑事部長
よりエラいヒトたちだけッス。
Only the highest-ranked
people are being let into
Criminal Affairs now...

<Gumshoe>
The lowest ranking guy in
there is our chief of
detectives.

ワレワレ、ヒラの刑事は‥‥その。
まぜてもらえないッス。
They're not letting any of
us rank-and-file detectives
in at all.

<Ema>
そ、そんな‥‥
None of you?

<Phoenix>
（いくら主席検事の裁判でも‥‥
　さすがに不自然じゃないか？）
(I know this is an important
trial, but isn't that a
little odd?)

<Gumshoe>
とりあえず、自分は今日中にこの
おどりをマスターしようかな、と。
So, anyway, I thought I'd
spend the day getting the
badger dance down pat.

<Ema>
‥‥あの。他にするコトは
ないんですか？
Um... Isn't there anything
else you could be doing?

<Gumshoe>
事件の捜査は、警察局長殿が
ご自身で指揮をとってるッスし‥‥
The Chief of Police himself
is directing this
investigation, pal.

検事局の地下駐車場の捜査には、
ザイモン巡査が任命されたッス。
And Officer Marshall was
assigned to the underground
parking lot.

<Ema>
‥‥ザイモンさん‥‥
Officer Marshall...

<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥茜ちゃん、
　知り合いみたいだったな‥‥）
(Now that I think about it,
Ema did seem to know
that Marshall guy.)

<Gumshoe>
巡査が現場の指揮を任される‥‥
これまた、前代未聞ッス！
A patrolman in charge of
a crime scene...
It's unheard of, pal!




<Phoenix>
このＩＤカード‥‥
被害者のものだったんですね。
So... this ID card belonged
to the victim?

<Gumshoe>
彼は、自分と同じく捜査官‥‥
いわゆる、刑事だったッス。
He was a detective, like
myself.

多田敷　道夫
（タダシキミチオ）巡査部長。
Detective Bruce Goodman.

<Ema>
うーん‥‥
なんか、ちょっとフシギですね。
Hmm...
Don't you think it's strange?

被害者のＩＤカードが、どうして
あんなところに落ちてたのか‥‥
I mean, why would the victim's
ID card be lying on the ground
where we found it?

<Gumshoe>
きのうは、多田敷刑事は
警察局にいたはずッスよ。
Well, Detective Goodman
should have been at the
Police Department yesterday.

２年前に担当した事件の証拠品の
《申し送り》があったッスから。
There was an evidence
transferal for a case he
handled two years ago.

<Ema>
《申し送り》‥‥御剣検事さんも
そんなコトを言ってましたね。
Evidence transferal...
Mr. Edgeworth mentioned
that too.

でも‥‥多田敷さんが
殺害されたの、検事局でしたよね。
But... Detective Goodman was
killed at the Prosecutor's
Office...

<Gumshoe>
だから‥‥その。
言いにくいッスけど‥‥
Well, that's the thing...
It's hard to say this, but...

宝月主席検事殿が呼び出したッス。
‥‥地下駐車場に。
Word is that Chief Prosecutor
Skye called him out there, to
the parking lot.

<Phoenix>
（ともえさんも、それを認めてる
　ってワケか‥‥）
(And Lana's confessing as
much...)




<Gumshoe>
ツラい立場に立たされているッス。
‥‥今も、なお。
He's in a tough spot,
again...

<Phoenix>
“今も”‥‥？
"Again"...?

<Gumshoe>
キッカケは、あの事件ッス。
生倉弁護士の殺害事件‥‥
Well, it all started with
the murder of that defense
attorney, Hammond.

<Ema>
でも！　御剣検事さんの無実は
立証されたじゃないですか！
But Edgeworth was found
innocent!

<Gumshoe>
検事には、ムカシから
イロイロなウワサがあったッス。
Listen, pal, there have always
been rumors about Edgeworth.

‥‥証拠のねつ造や、
証人との取引とか‥‥
Forging evidence, making
deals with witnesses...

今までは、カゲでひそひそ
ささやかれていたッスが‥‥
Nothing outright, but there
were always whispered rumors.

殺人事件の容疑者になってから、
みんな、もうエンリョなしッス。
Ever since he was accused of
murder, no one's whispering.
They're practically shouting!

<Ema>
そんな！　証拠もないのに！
But... but there's no
evidence against him!

<Gumshoe>
ジッサイ御剣検事は、上層部との
つながりが、不自然に強くて‥‥
Well, Mr. Edgeworth has always
had unusually strong ties
to the department higher-ups.

ちょっぴり、怪しまれても
しかたないというか‥‥その。
It's only natural that people
would be suspicious.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そこまで苦しい立場に
　いたのか、アイツ‥‥）
(I had no idea he was under
the gun...)

<Gumshoe>
今回の件も、そうッス。
Anyway, this latest case
has started a new rumor.

『この法廷を引き受けたのは、
　主席検事の座を狙っているから』
People say the only reason
he took this case...

‥‥そんなウワサも
あるぐらいッス。
is because he's aiming for
the Chief Prosecutor position
himself!

<Phoenix>
なんですって！
W-what!?

<Gumshoe>
‥‥でも！
自分にはわかっているッス！
But I know the truth, pal!

宝月主席検事の法廷なんて、
ダレもやりたくないッス！
Nobody wants to be the one
who has to prosecute the
chief prosecutor!

御剣検事は、あえてビンボークジを
引いたッス。みんなのために‥‥
Mr. Edgeworth is biting the
bullet on this one! He's doing
this for all of us!




<Phoenix>
刑事さん。ほら、これ。
弁護士がつけるバッジですよ。
Detective... here's my
attorney's badge.

<Gumshoe>
‥‥アンタ、会うたびに
見せるッスね、それ。
You show this to me every
time we meet, pal.

男はだまって警察手帳ッス！
Real men show their police
badge. 'Nuff said!

<Ema>
いいなあ。あたしも
早くほしいな、身分証明‥‥
I wish had a badge... Even an
ID card would be nice...

<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥）
(Wait...)

（ぼくも持っていたっけ。
　刑事さんのＩＤカード‥‥）
(Speaking of ID cards, I found
that detective's card, didn't
I...?)




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥イトノコ刑事。
これ、なんですけど‥‥
Um, Detective Gumshoe?
What can you tell me
about this?

<Gumshoe>
お！　アンタ、コレ‥‥
捜査官のＩＤじゃないッスか！
Huh? Hey, pal! This is
a detective's ID card!

ダメッスよ！　拾ったら、
ちゃんと交番に届けないと。
You can't just keep that!
You have to turn it in to
the police!

アンタみたいなのがいるから、
いつも自分、怒られちゃうッス。
It's people like you that
get me into so much trouble
all the time!

<Phoenix>
（イトノコ刑事‥‥いつも
　落とすみたいだな、ＩＤカード）
(Meaning Detective Gumshoe
must drop his card a lot.)

<Gumshoe>
えー、なになに。
“タダシキ　ミチオ”‥‥
Hmm... let's see...
"Bruce Goodman"...

タダシキ‥‥？
最近、どこかで聞いたような。
Goodman...
Sounds familiar...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
気のせいッスね、きっと。
...
Nah, my mistake.

<Ema>
でも、刑事課でいっしょに
シゴトをしてい
But, don't you work together
with him in Criminal Affairs?

<Gumshoe>
うほオオオオオオオオオオオッ！
気のせいじゃなかったッス！
Whoa!!! 
Now I remember!

多田敷　道夫といえば‥‥
今回の事件の被害者ッスゥ！
Bruce Goodman!
He's the victim!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥なんとなく、
　そんな気はしてたんだよな）
(That's what I thought...)

<Ema>
け、刑事さん！
お話、聞かせてくださいっ！
Can you tell us more,
Detective Gumshoe?




<Gumshoe>
事件の被害者・多田敷刑事の
ＩＤカードッス。
This ID card belongs to
the victim, Detective
Bruce Goodman.

今日び、なんでもカードに暗証番号
‥‥気が休まるヒマがないッス。
You can do just about anything
these days with a card and the
right secret number... scary!

<Phoenix>
それは、イトノコ刑事が
ぽろぽろ落とすからですよ。
It's only scary because you
keep dropping your card,
Detective Gumshoe.

<Gumshoe>
暗証番号もぽろぽろ忘れるッス。
‥‥自分がコワくなるッス。
I forget my secret number
a lot, too. It's scary!

ダレが見たって、自分は自分！
それでいいじゃないッスかッ！
But... but I'm me, after all!
And what could be wrong
with that!?

<Phoenix>
（開きなおった‥‥）
(I think I'll stay out of
this conversation.)




<Gumshoe>
お、それ！
Hey, that's it!

きのう御剣検事がもらった
《検事・オブ・ザ・イヤー》ッス！
That's the "King of 
Prosecutors" award that Mr.
Edgeworth got yesterday!

<Phoenix>
授賞式、イトノコ刑事も
出席していたんですか？
Were you at the awards
ceremony, Detective Gumshoe?

<Gumshoe>
そりゃそッス！
自分ももらったッスよ。努力賞。
Of course, pal!
I got an award for diligence,
myself.

<Phoenix>
はあ‥‥おめでとうございます。
Ah... congratulations.

<Ema>
それにしても、
なんで《盾》なんですか？
I was wondering, why is the
award a shield?

‥‥しかも、割れてるし。
And... why is it broken?

<Gumshoe>
それはモチロン、
ちゃーんと理由があるッス。
Oh, there's a reason.

ええと‥‥‥‥‥‥
また、今度教えてあげるッス。
Um...
I'll tell you what it is later.

<Phoenix>
（忘れたらしいな、どうやら）
(Apparently, he's forgotten.)

<Gumshoe>
‥‥でも。御剣検事が
受賞して、自分もうれしいッス。
But, I was proud of Mr.
Edgeworth for winning that
award.

検事局では、彼を認める声
ばかりじゃないッスからねえ。
He's even got naysayers in the
Prosecutor's Office.

<Phoenix>
（“黒いウワサ”‥‥か）
(Yeah, we've heard about
the rumors...)




<Gumshoe>
御剣検事のクルマに、
御剣検事のナイフ‥‥
Found in Mr. Edgeworth's car,
stabbed with Mr. Edgeworth's
knife, huh...

どうして宝月主席検事殿は、
そんなコトをしたッスかねえ‥‥
What would drive Chief
Prosecutor Skye to do
such a thing?

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Gumshoe>
あ。あやや。も、モチロン！
ハンニンは、ベツのニンゲンッス！
W-wait, I didn't mean...
I mean, sure, of course
someone else really did it!

そのハンニンは、まるで‥‥
Someone who must have, um...

御剣検事に、ウラミでも
あるみたいッスねえ‥‥
Someone who must have a 
grudge against Mr. Edgeworth!

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥
　グーゼンとは思えないよな）
(The car and the knife do seem
a little too well-organized
to be a coincidence.)

<Ema>
御剣検事さん‥‥
いったい、何があったんだろ‥‥
Poor Mr. Edgeworth...
What could have happened?

<Phoenix>
（詳しく聞いてみたいな。
　アイツのこと‥‥）
(We have to find out a little
more about what's going on
with Edgeworth...)




<Gumshoe>
イッピキの刑事として、
これだけは断言しておくッス！
As a detective, I have to keep
my mouth shut on that one.

ココロ当たりのないモノには、
断固！　チンモクを守るッス！
I know better than to go
blabbing on about things I
don't know about...

<Phoenix>
か、かまいませんよ、それで。
No, I wouldn't want you to do
that either...

<Gumshoe>
‥‥ホッ。
Good.




< >
２月２２日　某時刻
検事局・地下駐車場
February 22
Prosecutor's Office
Underground Parking Lot

<Phoenix>
（‥‥捜査はまだ
　つづいてるみたいだな）
(Looks like the investigation
is still going...)

<???>
じゃあ‥‥お店に戻るわね。
I have to be getting
back to the shop...

<???>
今日は、この荒野にホネを埋める
コトになりそうさ。
Sorry... Looks like I'll
be stuck in this pit 'til
the sun sleeps.

今夜はユメで会うとしようか、
ベイビイ。
I'll see you in my dreams
tonight, then, baby.

<Angel>
‥‥あら。
またいらしたの。
Oh!
Still here?

<Ema>
あ、ど。どうも‥‥
Ah, h-hello.

<Angel>
どうしたのかしら、その目。
‥‥言いませんでしたかしら。
Why the surprised looks?
Didn't I mention...?

ワタクシ、捜査官にもカレが
いるんですのよ。
I've got a boyfriend in
Criminal Affairs, too.

<Phoenix>
（“守衛室のカレ”は
　なんだったんだよ！）
(What happened to the security
guard!?)

<Marshall>
ヘイ、どうしたバンビーナ。
Hey! What's wrong,
bambina?

カギをなくしたカギっ子‥‥
そんなセツない目、してるぜ。
You're lookin' like a dogie
that's lost its herd!

<Phoenix>
（罪門　恭介‥‥）
(Jake Marshall...)

（たしか、この現場の
　セキニンシャ、だったよな）
(Strange guy to put in charge
of a crime scene.)




<Ema>
あの‥‥
どうですか？　成歩堂さん。
So, well, how are we
doing, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
手がかりは、そろってきたかな。
I guess we've got some
clues...

解剖記録に、被害者のメモに‥‥
携帯電話、か。
We have an autopsy report,
a note from the victim,
and a cell phone...

<Ema>
よかった‥‥
So... you think we'll
be okay?

<Phoenix>
気になるのは‥‥ともえさん自身が
犯行を認めてるコトだね。
Well, the only thing still
bothering me is that Lana
is confessing to the crime.

『私がやった』って。
She says she did it!

<Ema>
大丈夫ですよ！
No problem!

お姉ちゃんがハンニンじゃないのは
あたしが保証しますから！
I can guarantee that she's
not the criminal.

<Phoenix>
‥‥ところで、茜ちゃん。
Oh by the way, Ema?

<Ema>
はい？
Yes?

<Phoenix>
きみの持っている携帯電話の
着信メロディ‥‥知ってるよ。
I know that song your
phone plays when it
rings...

<Ema>
え‥‥‥
What...?

<Cellular>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ピッ
*beep*

<Phoenix>
《大江戸戦士トノサマン》か。
It's the Steel Samurai theme
song, isn't it?

今、ヤングに大人気のヒーロー‥‥
なんだってね。
That popular TV show...
for kids?

<Ema>
‥‥！
...!

<Phoenix>
さっき鳴ったのは、ぼくのデンワ
じゃなかった。
The phone that just rang
wasn't mine... 

そう。
‥‥きみのだよ。あかねちゃん。
it was yours.

宝月　巴さんは、
事件が発生した直後‥‥
At 5:18, just after the
murder took place...

きみにデンワをかけた。
‥‥そうだね？
Your sister called you,
didn't she, Ema?

<Ema>
ご‥‥ごめんなさい‥‥あたし。
I...I'm sorry!

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥

<Phoenix>
聞かせてくれないの？
お姉さんと、何を話したか‥‥
Can you tell me what
you talked about?

<Ema>
‥‥あの。
すぐ、切れちゃったから。
I...
She hung up right away.

<Phoenix>
そう、か‥‥わかった。
I see...

< >
証拠品《携帯電話》のデータを
書きなおした。
Cell Phone added
to the Court Record.

<Phoenix>
（殺害されたのは、現職の捜査官。
　被告人は、検事局のナンバー１）
(A detective is murdered, and
the suspect is the top
prosecutor in the district.)

（もしかしたら、ぼくは‥‥）
(I've got a bad feeling
about this...)

（まだ、この事件のすべてを
　知らないのかもしれない‥‥！）
(Like... maybe I still don't
know everything that went on
here...)


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.


<Marshall>
おっと。そいつを調べるのなら、
オレを倒してからにしなよ。
If you want to take a closer
look, you'll have to deal
with me first, pardner.

<Phoenix>
え‥‥
Huh...

<Marshall>
夕陽の決闘‥‥シカバネを越えた
オトコだけが、真実をつかむ。
A duel at sunset...
The winner leaves the loser
in the dust and takes all.

‥‥それが、ガンマンたちの
血のオキテ、なのさ。
The blood law of the gunman!

<Ema>
‥‥捜査官のナワバリ争いは
撃ち合いで決着をつける、と。
Note to self: jurisdiction
squabbles are settled by
dueling.

<Phoenix>
（殺人事件の調査なのに、死体を
　増やしてどうするんだよ‥‥）
(I think one body per murder
case is enough, thanks.)







<Phoenix>
これは‥‥メモ、かな。
What's this? Looks like
a note of some sort.

<Ema>
あ！　何か書いてありますよ！
Look! Something's
written on it!

<Phoenix>
ホントだ。ええと‥‥
《６－７Ｓ　１２／２》かな。
You're right. Let's see...
"6-7S 12/2"...

<Ema>
上に、名前が印刷されてますね
‥‥タダシキ、って。
There's a name printed on
the paper above that...
"Goodman."

<Phoenix>
（殺害されたときに、
　ポケットから落ちたのか‥‥）
(Maybe it fell out of his
pocket when he was killed.)

<Ema>
で？　で？　どういう
イミなんですか？　成歩堂さん！
Well? So? What does it
mean, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
わかるワケないだろ。
How am I supposed to know?

<Ema>
‥‥成歩堂弁護士と御剣検事さんの
“差”は、このへんにあり、と。
Note to self: for deductive
reasoning, go to Edgeworth,
not Wright.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥御剣でも
　わからないと思うけど）
(I'm sure Edgeworth wouldn't
know what this means either.)

< >
《多田敷のメモ》を
法廷記録に挟んだ。
Goodman's Note added
to the Court Record.



















<Phoenix>
これは‥‥携帯電話だね。
This looks like a cell phone.

<Ema>
カガク的に考えて‥‥被害者のもの
じゃないでしょうか！
Scientific analysis would
suggest this belonged to
the victim!

‥‥他に、思いつかないし。
I can't think of anyone
else it could belong to...

<Phoenix>
（どこがカガク的だよ！）
とにかく、調べてみようか。
(What's so scientific about
that!?)
Should we check it out?



<Phoenix>
やっぱり、やめておこう。
On second thought, let's not.

<Ema>
えー！　どうしてですか？
気になるじゃないですか！
What!? Why not? I mean,
don't you want to know
whose it is?

<Phoenix>
でも、たまたま刑事さんが
落としたものかもしれないよ。
Probably one of the 
Detectives dropped it.

<Ema>
警察には、そんなマヌケな
刑事さんはいませんっ！
Come on! No detective
would be that dumb!

<Phoenix>
（今、一瞬ダレかのカオが
　アタマをよぎったような‥‥）
(I don't know. One detective
in particular comes to mind.)




<Phoenix>
（よし‥‥
　詳しく調べてみよう！）
(Right! Let's check it out.)




<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥これ以上の
　手がかりは見つからないな）
(I think that about does
it for clues here.)




<Ema>
電話のスクリーンを見ると‥‥
リダイヤル表示になってますね。
Hmm. The display is still
on the redial button.

<Phoenix>
リダイヤル‥‥？
Redial...?

<Ema>
はああ‥‥あのね、成歩堂さん。
Um, Mr. Wright?

最近の携帯電話には、
発信と着信の記録が残るんです。
Most phones keep a record
of all the calls you've made
and received.

青いボタンを押せば、最後にかけた
番号を呼び出してくれるんですよ。
You just press the blue button
to dial the last number you
called.

ベンリになったモンでしょ？
成歩堂さんが知らないうちに。
Convenient, isn't it?
I'm surprised you didn't
know about it.

<Phoenix>
‥‥悪いけど、リダイヤルぐらい
知ってるよ、ぼくも。
Sorry to disappoint you, but
even I know about things like
"redial."

<Ema>
え！　ご、ごめんなさい！
Huh? Oh, I'm sorry!

成歩堂さん、ひと時代前のヒトに
見えるから！
It's just, you never know
with people from your
generation.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やれやれ。
　もう少し、調べてみるか）
(Whatever... Let's check
this phone out.)




<Phoenix>
（さてさて。
　ダレにかかったものか‥‥）
(Now, I wonder who the owner
of this phone called last...)

<Ema>
‥‥弁護士は、あとさき考えず
とりあえずボタンを押す、と。
Note to self: a defense
attorney doesn't think first,
he just pushes the button.

<Cellular>
ピッ
*beep*

<Cellular>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
うわ！　こ、このメロディは‥‥
Hey! That song! I know that!




<Marshall>
ヘイ、そこ！　どうしたッ！
Hey! What's going on
over there?

<Cellular>
ピッ
*beep*

<Phoenix>
あ！　いや。すみません。
Ah! Oh, s-sorry.

<Marshall>
見てたぜ、カウボーイ！
I see you, pardner!

‥‥アンタ、今、そのデンワで
リダイヤルをしたな？
You pressed redial on that
there phone, didn't you?

<Phoenix>
は、はあ‥‥まあ。
Uh, well, yeah...

<Ema>
こ。このデンワ、何なんですか？
そこに落ちてたんですけど。
Whose phone is this, anyway?
It was on the ground over
there...

<Marshall>
‥‥そいつはな。
宝月　巴主席検事のモノさ。
Whose is it?
That belongs to Chief
Prospector Skye.

<Ema>
えッ！　お、お姉ちゃんの‥‥？
What? It's my sister's!?

<Marshall>
犯行直後、身柄をカクホされたとき
落としたらしい。
She apparently dropped it when
she was taken into custody,
right after the crime.

<Marshall>
発信記録によると‥‥どうやら、
事件が起こった、まさにその時間。
Look... the last call was
made right when the murder
occurred!

だれかにデンワをかけたようだよ。
‥‥通話時間は数分だがね。
Looks like she was fixing
to call someone.

<Marshall>
Except she only spoke for
a few seconds, according
to this.

<Phoenix>
‥‥！　いったい、ダレに！
Who did she call!?

<Marshall>
それが‥‥わからなかったのさ。
No idea. Sorry, pardner.

<Marshall>
だから、カウボーイ。
質問に答えてもらえるかい。
Now, I got a question for
you, pardner.

たった今、鳴った電話は、
いったい‥‥
I heard a phone ring just
now... one of those new-
fangled ring-tunes.

<Phoenix>
いや‥‥‥その。すみません。
ぼくのデンワだったんですけど。
Oh? That? Oh...
I'm sorry, that was my phone.

<Marshall>
な、な、な‥‥なんだと‥‥？
アンタの‥‥デンワ‥‥！
W-w-what!?
Your phone!?

<Phoenix>
なんというか、
言いにくいんですけど‥‥その。
Yeah, uh, it's kind of
strange, but...

いいタイミングで、かかってきた
みたいです。‥‥まちがいデンワ。
Someone called me right as
we picked up the other phone,
a wrong number...

<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ここがテキサスなら、アンタ‥‥
弾丸を噛んでるところだぜ！
I hope you're not lying...
They shoot you for that
in Texas, pardner!

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥
　怒って行っちまったよ‥‥）
(Uh oh, I've incited the
wrath of the Lone Star
patrolman...)

< >
証拠品《携帯電話》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Cell Phone added to
the Court Record.







<Phoenix>
どうやら‥‥これが、死体が
発見されたクルマ、みたいだね。
This appears to be the
car where the body was
found.

（トランクのカギが
　コワされているみたいだな）
(It looks like the lock on
the trunk is busted.)

<Lana>
現場は、地方検事局の地下駐車場。
The crime took place in the
underground parking lot at
the Prosecutor's Office.

遺体は、私の部下のクルマの
後部トランクから発見されました。
The body was found in the
trunk of my subordinate's
car.

<Ema>
いかにも“カネ持ち”的な
ニオイがしますねー。
Quite a luxury car. It just
screams "I have money to
burn."

<Phoenix>
ううん‥‥
もうかるんだなあ、検事って。
Yeah. Prosecutors get the
big bucks.







<Ema>
《Ａブロック》‥‥
検察関係者のエリアですね。
"A Block"... This area is
reserved for prosecutors.

<Phoenix>
ぼくは弁護士だから、
《Ｂブロック》になるのかな。
Defense attorneys are 
relegated to "B Block."

<Ema>
いつかあたし、ここに
クルマをとめるのがユメなんです！
I dream of the day when 
I will be able to park
my car here!

それで、Ｂブロックの成歩堂さん
から、ハンバーグ弁当を買うの。
I'll go over to B Block to
buy my hamburgers from you,
Mr. Wright.

<Phoenix>
‥‥とうぶん、弁護士を
やめるつもりはないよ。
I'm not planning on giving up
my job that soon...







<Phoenix>
この金網の向こうが《Ｂブロック》
‥‥外来者用のエリアだね。
"B Block" is through there.
That's where visitors park.

<Ema>
あ。遠くにちっちゃく見えます！
ベントーランドのクルマ。
I can see the Lunchland
car over there...far in
the distance.

<Phoenix>
ホントだ。ドアのワキに
かわいい絵が書いてあるね。
Hey, you're right. I like
the cute design on the door.

（ウシのキャラクターが、ジツに
　ウマそうにステーキを食べてる）
(I can see... a cartoon cow
munching down on a juicy
looking steak.)

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そういうのって、なんか
やるせない感じがしませんか‥‥？
Doesn't that strike you
as a little... creepy?

<Phoenix>
か、考えすぎだよ。
Just don't think too deeply
about it and you'll be fine.







<Ema>
このロープ‥‥やっぱり？
This rope... is it...?

<Phoenix>
うん。被害者の死体のカタチを
ロープでなぞってあるんだよ。
Yep. They laid it in the
outline of the victim's body.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

被害者‥‥トランクを閉めるとき、
挟まって死んだのでしょうか！
So wait...The victim must have 
died when the killer closed
the trunk on him!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

（こんな発想をする子、
　他にはゼッタイいないだろうな）
(You have got to be the only
person I know that would
come to that conclusion.)







<Ema>
ここにあったんですよね。
‥‥このメモ。
So the note was in here...

<Phoenix>
被害者・多田敷捜査官の
ポケットから落ちたんだろうね。
It must have fallen out of
Detective Goodman's pocket.

<Ema>
で？　で？　どういう
イミなんですか？　成歩堂さん！
And? And? what does it mean?
Mr. Wright!

<Phoenix>
わかるワケないだろ。
I have no idea.

<Ema>
‥‥成歩堂弁護士と御剣検事さんの
“差”は、このへんにあり、と。
Note to self: for deductive
reasoning, go to Edgeworth,
not Wright.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥御剣でも
　わからないと思うけど）
(I'm sure Edgeworth would
be just as confused...)




<Ema>
あの。聞かせていただきたい
コトがあるんですけど！
There's something I wanted
to ask you!

<Marshall>
‥‥事件の現場は、そう。
ユメ破れたオトコたちの墓場さ。
The scene of the crime...
a cold grave for men 
who've lost their dreams...

オレはそれを見守る、ユメの番人。
砂漠の裁きをユメ見て眠るのさ。
And me? I watch over them
as they sleep... dreaming of
the desert's harsh judgment.

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
寝ちゃった。
He's asleep.

<Phoenix>
とにかく‥‥このならず者の
注意をひくモノを見せてみようか。
Well... should we show this
hopeless case something to
catch his interest?










<Phoenix>
あの、罪門さん。被害者のこと、
聞かせてもらえますか。
Officer Marshall? Could you
tell us more about the
victim?

<Marshall>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

いいヤツは、みんな死んでいく。
これでいいかい、カウボーイ。
Good men always die young.
Remember that, pardner.

<Phoenix>
いやいや！
もう少し詳しくおねがいします。
Um... could you be a little
more specific?

<Ema>
多田敷　道夫さん‥‥
刑事さん、だったんですよね？
Bruce Goodman...
He was a detective, right?

<Marshall>
やれやれ‥‥世話の焼ける
子馬ちゃんたちだね。
Well, well, aren't you a
feisty dogie there now.

多田敷が刺されたのは、ここさ。
‥‥５時１５分ごろのコトだよ。
Detective Goodman was stabbed
here at 5:15...

さすらうマドンナのほほえみが、
オレにそう物語っていたさ。
The smiling Madonna told
me the tale...

<Phoenix>
（おキョウさんの証言、か‥‥）
(I think he means the witness,
Ms. Angel Starr.)

<Marshall>
胸をひと突き。やっつけシゴトに
しちゃあ、上デキの部類だろうね。
One stab to the chest.
A fine piece of work.

‥‥コイツが解剖記録だよ。
This here's the autopsy
report.

< >
証拠品《解剖記録》のデータを
法廷記録にファイルした。
Autopsy Report added
to the Court Record.

<Ema>
‥‥あの。お姉ちゃんと被害者は
どういう関係だったんですか？
Was my sister involved with
the victim in any way?

<Marshall>
それが‥‥妙といえば
妙なのさ、バンビーナ。
Funny you should mention
that, bambina.

<Marshall>
宝月主席検事と多田敷刑事には、
ほとんど接点がないんだよ。
Chief Prospector Skye and
Detective Goodman...
had nothing in common at all.

<Ema>
接点が‥‥ない‥‥
Nothing in common...?

<Marshall>
何年か前に１度、いっしょに
シゴトをしたことがあるが‥‥
They apparently worked
together on a case a few
years back.

<Phoenix>
（つまり‥‥動機がない。
　そういうことか‥‥！）
(So... there's no motive!)

<Marshall>
多田敷は、とりたてて優秀な
捜査官でもなかったんだ。
Goodman wasn't a particularly
gifted detective.

主席検事とシゴトできるチャンスが
なかった‥‥そう言えるようだね。
That's one reason why he
didn't do much work with
the Chief Prospector...

<Ema>
でも‥‥お姉ちゃんは事件当日、
被害者を呼びだしたんですよね？
But, my sister called the
victim here on the day of
the murder, right?

‥‥この駐車場に。
Here... to this parking lot?

<Marshall>
ああ‥‥そのようだ。
人間相手の闘牛をするために、ね。
So it seems.
Like calling an unarmed man
to a shootout at high noon.




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥
こんなコト聞いてアレですけど。
Um, I don't mean any
offense, but...

罪門さん、“巡査”なんですよね？
‥‥“刑事”ではなくて。
Officer Marshall, you're a
patrolman, right? Not a
detective.

<Marshall>
おやおや‥‥ここがテキサスなら、
アンタ。銃殺されているところさ。
You callin' me out? They
shoot you for that in Texas.

<Phoenix>
え。
Huh?

<Marshall>
これでも、２年前までは捜査官
‥‥りっぱな“刑事”だったさ。
I was one of them fancy-shoed
"Detectives" till two years
ago, to tell ya the truth.

<Phoenix>
あ！　そうなんですか。
（‥‥先に言えよ！）
Oh, really?
(Now he tells me!)

<Ema>
でも。“巡査”は捜査の指揮を
とることはできないんじゃあ‥‥？
But, you're a patrolman now.
So how can you be in charge
of a crime scene?

<Marshall>
そのとおりだよ、バンビーナ。
Nothing gets by you,
does it, bambina?

<Phoenix>
じゃあ‥‥なぜ。
巡査のあなたが指揮を？
So, why are you in charge?

<Marshall>
なあに。人手が足りてないだけさ。
オレは、ただの見張り番だよ。
No reason. We're just short on
hands right now. I'm keeping
an eye out in the meantime.

<Ema>
あれ、オカシイなあ。
That's odd, though.

イトノコ刑事さんは、ヒマ‥‥
手があいてるようでしたけど。
Detective Gumshoe was saying
he had nothing to do...
nothing important, at least.

<Marshall>
かわいそうなブルドッグだよ。
ふるべきシッポが見つからない。
He's nothing but a sad ol'
cowdog, that can't find his
tail.

あの、ミツルギといっしょに
いるせいかもしれないね。
Maybe it's because he runs
with that Edgeworth, eh?

<Phoenix>
‥‥御剣‥‥ですか？
Edgeworth...?

<Marshall>
あのブルドッグは、ハズされた。
‥‥警察局長の決定さ。
That cowdog's been kicked out
of this cattle run... by order
of the Chief of Police.

ちなみに本人は、ハズされたコトに
気づいてないみたいだけどね‥‥
Just, he don't realize it yet.

<Phoenix>
（捜査からハズされている‥‥
　イトノコ刑事が！）
(Detective Gumshoe, kicked
out of the investigation!?)




<Ema>
とにかく、接点はないんですよね！
お姉ちゃんと、多田敷捜査官‥‥
So, there's no connection
between Detective Goodman
and my sister!

<Marshall>
そのとおりさ。
しかし、まァ‥‥
That's correct, but...

そいつをおぎなってあまりある、
証拠品のゴールドラッシュだがね。
There's a goldmine of evidence
against her...

<Phoenix>
‥‥！
...!

<Marshall>
それに‥‥明日の法廷に立つ検事が
あのミツルギとくれば‥‥
And the prospector tomorrow
is none other than Edgeworth
himself...

もう、運命は決まったよ。
バンビーナにはキノドクだけど。
I'm afraid your sister's fate
is decided, bambina.
Many condolences.

<Ema>
‥‥ザイモンさん！
Officer Marshall!

<Marshall>
なんだい、バンビーナ。
Yeah, bambina?

<Ema>
どうして‥‥
そんな言い方をするんですか？
H-how can you say that!

ザイモンさん‥‥ムカシは、
お姉ちゃんと‥‥
You and my sister, you were...

<Phoenix>
（“ムカシ”‥‥
　何か、つながりがあったのか？）
(Is there something between 
this cop and her sister that
I don't know about?)

<Marshall>
‥‥‥！
...!

‥‥悪かったね。たしかに‥‥
こんなコト、言うべきじゃないよ。
I apologize, bambina.
Something must have gotten
to me.

検事局に吹きおろす、このイヤな
カラっ風のせいかもしれないね。
Maybe it's that dry wind
that's a-blowin' through the
Prospector's Office.

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥ここには、だれかの
　“悪意”がウズまいている‥‥）
(Dry wind or ill will,
someone's up to something
here... but who?)




<Marshall>
御剣　怜侍の“疑惑”‥‥
早いもんさ。もう、２年はたつよ。
Suspicions about Mr. Edgeworth
have been flying around for
nearly two years now.

<Phoenix>
“証拠のデッチ上げ”や
“証人との取引”ですか‥‥？
Forged evidence... arranging
testimonies, you name it.

<Marshall>
ああ。勝つためには手段は選ばない
‥‥だからこそ、無敗だったのさ。
He was unbeatable because
he did whatever it took to
win.

アンタに会うまでは、な。
Unbeatable that is, until
he met you.

<Ema>
でも‥‥ウワサはあくまでも
ウワサじゃないんですか？
But rumors are just... rumors,
aren't they?

検事さんの世界では、
証拠がすべてじゃないんですか！
These are prosecutors we're
talking about! Evidence is
everything to them!

<Marshall>
御剣の疑惑。そのモトをたどって
いくと‥‥ある人物にたどりつく。
If you follow the rumors about
Edgeworth to their source, you
find one person...

ダレも、口に出すことはできない
‥‥アンタッチャブルの世界さ。
But... they're off limits.
Untouchable, you might say.

<Phoenix>
“ある人物”‥‥？
One person? Who?

<Marshall>
バンビーナ‥‥きみのお姉さんだ。
主席検事・宝月　巴。
Bambina...It's your sister.
Chief Prospector Lana Skye.

<Ema>
え！
‥‥お、お姉ちゃんが‥‥
What!?
My sister...?

<Marshall>
御剣ヒトリでヤンチャな遊びが
できるワケじゃない。
Edgeworth couldn't rustle
all those cattle by himself.

“取引”という名の弾丸を
シリンダーにこめる人間がいる。
Some people load their guns
with bullets, some people load
them with "deals."

<Phoenix>
バカな！　御剣が‥‥
そんなことをするハズがない！
What, you're saying Edgeworth
was making deals to win
trials?

<Marshall>
“弾丸のないところに銃声はない”
‥‥荒野の老人たちのコトバさ。
"Where there's gunshots,
 there's bound to be bullets."

<Marshall>
That's what the old-timers
say.

どこかに、デカいヒミツがある。
みんな、気づいているのさ。
There's a big ol' secret
hidden around here somewhere.
Everyone knows it.

<Phoenix>
（だから‥‥イトノコ刑事は
　捜査からハズされたのか‥‥）
(Is that why Detective 
Gumshoe was taken off
the case...?)

（御剣に、イチバン近いところに
　いるから‥‥！）
(Did they target him because
he was closest to Edgeworth?)




<Phoenix>
えーと、ザイモンさん。
これ、なんですけど‥‥
Officer Marshall? 
Could you take a look at this?

<Marshall>
おやおや‥‥カウボーイ。
Whoa, pardner!

武器をつきつける‥‥ここじゃあ
そいつは決闘の合図だ。
If you're fixing to draw on
me, you best be ready for
a shootout!

ハゲタカのエサになるカクゴが
ある、ってワケかい？
You ready to become food
for the vultures, compadre?

<Ema>
そんなカクゴしてるんですか？
成歩堂さん！
Are you ready, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（どうやら‥‥協力してくれる
　つもりはないみたいだな）
(Somehow I don't think he's
going to help us.)




<Phoenix>
あの‥‥これ、
読んでもらえますか？
Would you mind reading
this for me?

<Marshall>
‥‥なんだい、コイツは。
ファンレターはタンツボにたのむ。
What's this? I warn you,
fan letters to me go right
in the spittoon!

<Phoenix>
イトノコ刑事の《紹介状》です。
捜査、させてもらえませんか？
It's a letter of introduction
from Detective Gumshoe. 
May we investigate?

<Marshall>
イトノコ‥‥ああ。
あのユカイなブルドッグか。
Gumshoe...?
Ah, that old cowdog?

ふうん‥‥バースデイ・パーティー
でも、おっ始めるつもりかい？
Hmm... He holding a birthday
party or something?

<Phoenix>
‥‥え。
Huh?

<Marshall>
見ろよ。《紹介状》のトコロが‥‥
《招待状》になってるぜ。
Look, where it should say
letter of "introduction"...
It says "invitation."

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥か。
書きまちがいだと思います。
Ah...
I think he just miswrote it.

（なんでイトノコ刑事のぶんの
　ハジを、ぼくがかくんだよ！）
(Great, Detective Gumshoe. 
I owe you one...)

<Marshall>
‥‥いいだろうさ。
他ならぬ刑事殿の血判状だ。
No worries. This proves it's
from Detective Gumshoe, better
than a blood test.

巡査ふぜいのオレとしちゃア、
聞かなくちゃならないだろうね。
Guess I'd better let you in,
then. 

<Ema>
あ。ありがとう、ザイモンさん！
Th-thank you, Officer
Marshall!

<Phoenix>
（そういえば‥‥）
(Officer Marshall isn't a
"detective"... he's a 
"patrolman"...)

（罪門さんは“巡査”だ。
　“刑事”じゃない‥‥）
(That reminds me of
something...)

<Ema>
あれ。ヘンだなあ。
That is odd!

‥‥事件現場のセキニンシャは、
刑事以上のハズなのに‥‥
Isn't a crime scene
supposed to be handled
by a detective or higher?

<Marshall>
‥‥さて。
それでは、みなさま。
Well, folks.

手がかりがうなっている、
我らが金鉱へようこそ。
The clues are calling!
Welcome to our gold strike.

オレたちの合い言葉は、開拓精神。
せいぜい、楽しむとしようか！
Be like the settler! Strike
out for lands unknown!

<Marshall>
Manifest Destiny!
Let's have a hootenanny!

<Ema>
‥‥かいたくせいしん、と。
Note to self: police
investigations are like
settling land.

さ。成歩堂さん！
いっちょ、やりますよ！
Well, Mr. Wright,
what do you say!?

<Phoenix>
（コイツはもう、いらないな‥‥）
(I say I won't be needing
this anymore...)

< >
イトノコ刑事の《紹介状》を
丸めて捨てた。
Detective Gumshoe's
Letter of Introduction
crumpled and discarded.







<Marshall>
ほお‥‥アンタのバッジは
まんまる、ってワケか。
I see your badge.
Looks pretty... round.

オレたちのバッジは、コイツさ。
夜空を照らす、スター‥‥星。
Our badge is a star,
a lone star, shining
in the nighttime sky.

闇にまぎれた、おたずね者‥‥
そいつを照らす、一条の光だよ。
A beam of light, illuminating
evildoers who come in the
dark of night!

<Ema>
‥‥おたずね者は
お星さまの光に弱い、と。
Note to self: evildoers
are weak against starlight.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥それ、シェリフの
　バッジじゃないか！）
(Hey, that's a sheriff's
badge!)







<Marshall>
そいつは‥‥
警察官たちのパスポート、かい。
What's that? Some sort of
police passport?

<Phoenix>
多田敷刑事のＩＤカードです。
ちょっとフシギなことに‥‥
This is Detective Goodman's
ID card. Strangely enough...

ずいぶん現場から離れたところに
落ちていたんですよ。
We found it a good distance
away from the crime scene.

<Marshall>
‥‥この国は、ジツにちっぽけだ。
テキサスの砂漠にくらべたらね。
Good distance, in this rat
hole? If you want distance,
get yourself to Texas!

<Ema>
てきさす‥‥
Texas...

<Marshall>
そのちっぽけな国の、ちっぽけな
殺人現場の、ちっぽけな証拠品。
This is a tiny little crime
scene, in a tiny little town,
with tiny little evidence.

たかだか数メートル離れていたから
なんだって言うんだい？
What difference does a few
yards make, compadre?

<Ema>
‥‥不自然な証拠に出会ったら
テキサスを思い浮かべろ、と。
Note to self: if you encounter
suspicious evidence, think
of Texas.

ベンキョウになりますねー。
プロのコトバは、やっぱり。
There's no better way
to study than to hang
out with the pros!







<Marshall>
‥‥午後５時１２分、か‥‥
5:12 PM...

検事殿のまっ赤なじゃじゃ馬が、
トロットで入場してきたワケさ。
The prospector's bright
red steed came in at
a trot, real slow like.

<Ema>
とろっと‥‥？
A... trot?

<Marshall>
オレのマドンナの証言によると、
犯行は、その３分後だった‥‥
My Madonna tells me the
crime occurred three
minutes later...

どうやら、主席検事殿は
待っていたようだな。
So it seems the Chief
Prospector was lying
in wait!

赤い馬に乗った王子サマが
お帰りになるのを‥‥な。
Maybe... waiting for her
prince to ride in on his
bright red horse...

<Phoenix>
（つまり、ハンニンは‥‥）
(So what you mean is...)

（最初から、御剣のクルマを
　犯行に使うつもりだった‥‥？）
(The killer intended to use
Edgeworth's car all along!)







<Marshall>
‥‥ブリキのオモチャか。
お似合いだな、おぼっちゃまには。
Ah, a toy shield!
Suits the boy well.

そんなモノで、何が守れる？
オモチャの騎兵隊のタマぐらいさ。
What exactly could you
shield with that?
A toy knight, maybe?

<Ema>
‥‥罪門さん、さっきから
御剣検事のワルグチばっかり。
Officer Marshall, don't you
have anything good to say
about Mr. Edgeworth?

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥御剣のことがキライ
なのは、よくわかったよ。
You don't like him, right?
We get the point.

<Marshall>
たしか‥‥オレが刑事だったころ、
コイツをもらったことがあったな。
You know, when I was a 
detective, I got one
of these...

<Ema>
もしかして‥‥
“けいじ”の《Ｋ》ですか？
Hmm... Let me guess...
Did it have a "K" for
"King of Detectives" on it?

<Phoenix>
使い回してるぞ。
Hey, they could use the
same shield over and over.

<Ema>
‥‥検事局と警察局は
意外にケチ、と。
Note to self: the Prosecutor's
Office and Criminal Affairs
are surprisingly cheap.

<Marshall>
まったくね！　ムカシよりも
さらにケチになってるようだよ‥‥
You know it! They've gotten
cheaper with every passing
year, I tell you.







<Ema>
‥‥お姉ちゃんの
携帯電話、ですね。
My sister's cell phone.

<Marshall>
発信時刻は、５時１８分‥‥
多田敷が殺害された直後だ。
The last time it was used
was 5:18... Right after
Goodman was killed.

夜のデートをキャンセル
したのかもしれないぜ。
Maybe she was canceling
her date for the night?

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（ともえさん‥‥いったい、
　なんのために電話なんか‥‥？）
(Why did Lana make
that call...?)




<Marshall>
オーライ！
‥‥３つ数えろ、カウボーイ！
Alright, compadre!
Count to three!

<Phoenix>
え！
Huh?

<Marshall>
テキサスで、ヒトに
武器をつきつけるってコトは‥‥
You gotta do that if you're
going to draw evidence on
someone.

それは、決闘の合図なのさ。
That's what we do in Texas.

<Phoenix>
その、テキサスのルールを
持ち出すの、やめましょうよ‥‥
Remind me never to visit
Texas.

