< >
１２月２７日　午後２時１１分
成歩堂法律事務所
December 27, 2:11 PM
Wright & Co. Law Offices

<Maya>
御剣検事‥‥
なんで、あんなことを‥‥？
What was Mr. Edgeworth
talking about...?

<Edgeworth>
私が犯した罪の記憶‥‥。
A memory of a crime...
that I committed.

殺人‥‥の記憶だ。
A memory... of murder.

<Maya>
御剣検事‥‥
まさか、誰かを‥‥？
Do you really think
Mr. Edgeworth killed...?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そんなこと、あるわけがないよ。
I don't believe it.
Not Edgeworth.

たしかに、あいつは今、何かの
記憶に苦しんでいるけど‥‥。
Some painful memory has been
troubling him recently...

誰かの命をうばうなんて‥‥
あり得ない！
But he'd never take
someone's life! Never!

<Maya>
なるほどくん‥‥。
Nick...

<Butz>
よお！　元気かねショクン！
Yo! How's everyone doing?

どうよ？　どうよ？
今日のオレサマの証言ぶり！
Whaddya think of my
performance today?

シビれたっしょ？
真宵ちゃん！
I had 'em swooning in
the aisles! Huh, Maya?

<Maya>
え‥‥あ、あたし？
S-swooning? Me?

そ‥‥そうですね。
ビリッと来ちゃいました。
Oh... Oh, yes.
I do remember feeling faint.

<Butz>
だろ？　だろ？
もう、ホレちゃっただろ？
Right on! Tell me the
truth, it was like love
at first sight, right?

なあ、成歩堂！
Right, Nick?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥ぼ、ぼく？
H-huh? Me!?

そ‥‥そうだな。
キュン、と来たかな‥‥。
I... uh, well, maybe my heart
skipped a beat or two...

<Butz>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

なんか、イマイチ
ピンと来ねぇなあ。
I think you can do
better than that!

御剣が助かったのは、
オレのおかげよ？
C'mon! I saved Edgeworth
in there, dude! Edgey!

もっとこう、カンゲイしてくれよ！
このオレをよぉ！
You guys should be bowing
before me! Yeah!
Bow before your hero!




<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick!

かならず助けようね！
御剣検事。
We have to save Mr. Edgeworth
if it's the last thing we do,
okay?

<Phoenix>
ああ。
Right.
(It very well may be...)

<Maya>
とにかく、あのボート小屋の
オジさん？
First, there's that rental
boat shop caretaker.

あの人のこと、調べようよ！
We need to find out
who or what he is!

<Phoenix>
そうだね。
I'd settle for who.

（とりあえず、もう必要のない
　証拠品を、少し整理するか‥‥）
(I guess I can clean out
some of this evidence
I no longer need...)

（‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥）
(...)

よし、行こうか！
Okay, let's go!




<Phoenix>
千尋さんが“チャーリー”と
名づけてかわいがっていた植物。
Mia's favorite plant.
Its name is "Charley."

最近は、真宵ちゃんも
世話に慣れてきたようで、
Maya's gotten the knack
of watering it lately.

チャーリーくん、元気を
取りもどしたみたいだ。
Charley's been perking
up these days.




<Phoenix>
ムズカシイ法律の本が
あざ笑うように並んでいる。
Difficult-looking legal books
stand in a formidable row.
They mock me.

ちょっと読んでみたら、
アタマが痛くなった。
I tried reading one, 
and it made my head hurt.

しまうとき、落っことして
足まで痛くなった。
When I closed it, it slipped
out of my hand. Then my foot
hurt too.




<Phoenix>
今日も向かいのホテルは
大はんじょうだ。
Looks like it's cleaning
day again at the hotel
across the way.

なんでも今度、支店を
出すそうだ。
I hear they're planning
a second branch outside
the city.

ボーイが、引き出しのドライバーの
角度をなおしているのが見える。
I can see the bellboy,
adjusting the angle of that
screwdriver in the drawer.




<Phoenix>
千尋さんが使っていた
デスクだ。
Mia's desk.

お客がもっと増えれば
座る機会もあるだろうが、
If we had more clients,
I would probably sit here
more often.

今はソファでテレビを
見ていることの方が多い。
Lately, I've been spending
more time on the couch,
watching TV.




<Phoenix>
一度、真宵ちゃんがトノサマンの
ポスターを持ってきて、
Maya brought in a poster
of the Steel Samurai the
other day.

張る、張らないで大ゲンカに
なってしまった。
We had a big fight over
whether to put it up or not.

まだあきらめきれないらしく、
スキをうかがっているみたい。
I know she's just waiting
for a chance to sneak it
up on the wall.




<Phoenix>
矢張。
今日の法廷‥‥助かったよ。
Larry...
You really helped out
in the trial today.

<Maya>
そうだよね。
You did!

ヤッパリさんがいなかったら、
ユーザイだったもんね、御剣検事。
If you weren't there,
Larry, I'm sure Mr. Edgeworth
would have been found guilty!

<Butz>
はっはっはっはっはっはっはっはっ
はっはっはっはっはっはっはっはっ
Hah hah hah hah hah hah
hah hah hah hah hah hah!

でもよ、成歩堂。
But, seriously, Nick.

たしかに、ボート小屋の管理人も
アヤシイけどさあ。
That boat shop caretaker
guy is pretty suspicious...

御剣のウタガイだって、まだ
晴れたワケじゃねえんだぜ。
But Edgey ain't off
the hook yet!

<Maya>
うう‥‥ん。
ヤッパリさん、シビアだなあ。
Way to spoil the mood, Larry.

<Butz>
客席で聞いているとよお。
こう言っちゃナンだけど‥‥、
Hey, I'm just a guy sitting
in the audience, you know?

御剣だって、けっこう
アヤシイ感じがするぜ‥‥。
But from where I was sitting,
Edgey seemed pretty... edgy.

おマエ、なんでそこまで
アイツのこと、信じられるんだ？
I mean, can you really
know he's telling the
truth about that night?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
なるほどくん？
Nick?

<Phoenix>
ぼくは‥‥。
I don't know.

たとえ何があっても、
何が起こっても‥‥
But... what I do know is...

お前たち２人のことだけは、
信じぬくつもりなんだよ。
I'm going to believe in
you two until the end.

<Butz>
２人って？
Us two?

<Maya>
御剣検事と‥‥あたしでしょ？
Edgeworth and... who else?
You mean me right?

<Butz>
ナニ言ってんだよ！
オレだろ？　成歩堂！
Nah! He means me!
Right, Nick?

<Phoenix>
ああ。‥‥お前だよ、矢張。
Yeah, you, Larry.

<Maya>
あたしじゃないんだ‥‥。
Not... me?

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

でも。でも。
どうしてなの！　ヤッパリさん！
B-but why you, Larry!?

<Butz>
‥‥‥‥え。
Huh?

さ‥‥さあ。
どうしてだ？　成歩堂‥‥？
Um, actually, yeah.
Why me, Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
‥‥いつもそこでダマる！
Hmph. Enough with the
silent treatment!




<Maya>
なるほどくん。
Nick...

どうしてそんなに、
御剣検事にこだわるの？
Why do you trust Mr. Edgeworth
so much?

たしかに、最近はちょっと
感じが変わったけど、
I mean, he's changed
recently, true.

ただのイヤな男だったでしょ、
初めて会ったときは。
But when we first met
him, he was kind of a
jerk, don't ya think?

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

真宵ちゃんは、知らないんだよ。
You didn't know him back then.

弁護士を目指していたころの
御剣　怜侍を‥‥。
Back when he wanted to
become a defense attorney.

<Maya>
それって‥‥
Wait...

なるほどくんたちがクラスメート
だったっていう‥‥？
Was that when you two were
classmates?

<Phoenix>
うん。ぼくらが小学生のころの
話だ。
Yes. In grade school...

ぼくは、助けられたんだ。
御剣　怜侍と‥‥
They saved me...
Miles...

矢張　政志にさ。
‥‥一生わすれないよ。
And Larry.
They saved me and I'll
never forget it.

そのおかげで、こうして
弁護士にもなったんだ。
That's why I became a
defense attorney, you know.

<Maya>
ええええええええっ！
Whaaaat!?

ね。ね。矢張さん。
なんのこと‥‥？
Hey, hey, Larry.
What's he talking about?

<Butz>
え！　ええと‥‥その。
Huh? Uh... umm...

‥‥悪ィ。
ゼンゼンおぼえてねえや、オレ。
Er, sorry.
I kinda forgot.

<Maya>
ううう。
Hmph.

こら、なるほどくん！
今日こそ聞くんだからね、その話！
Okay, Nick. Out with it!
I'm going to hear this
story today, and that's final!

<Phoenix>
‥‥わかったよ。
Okay, okay.

少し長くなるかもしれないけど、
聞いてもらおうかな‥‥。
It's kind of a long story,
so hang in there.

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あれは、そう。
小学４年生の夏‥‥。
It was the beginning of
Spring, 4th grade.

ぼくは、学級裁判に
かけられたんだ。
I was on trial. A class trial.

<Maya>
が‥‥、がっきゅうさいばん？
A c-class trial!?




<Phoenix>
矢張、おぼえてないか？
小学４年生の夏だ‥‥。
You remember, Larry?
Spring, 4th grade?

ぼくのクラスの１人の子が、
給食費を盗まれたんだ。
A kid in my class got his
lunch money stolen.

<Maya>
給食費？
Lunch money?

<Phoenix>
ぼくたちの小学校、
とても小さなところでさ。
Our school was really small.

毎月、親がお金を入れてくれた
封筒を、先生に提出するんだ。
Every month, kids would bring
in an envelope with money for
lunch from home.

<Maya>
へええ‥‥。
Huh, I see.

<Phoenix>
その封筒が‥‥消えたんだよ。
３８００円、入っていた。
Anyway, this kid's envelope
disappeared. With $38.00
still inside.

<Butz>
‥‥ああ。そんなことが
あったっけなあ。
Oh... Yeah, now that you
mention it, I do remember
that!

<Phoenix>
お前はよく知らないかも
しれないな、矢張。
I can see why you'd
forget, though.

その日はお前、
学校を休んでいたから。
You were out of school
that day.

とにかく、封筒が盗まれたのは
体育の時間だった。
Anyway, the envelope had
been stolen during PE class.

ぼくはその日、カゼぎみで、
体育の授業を休んでいたんだ。
I was coming down with a cold,
so I'd skipped PE that day.

授業を休んだのは、
ぼくだけだった。
I was the only one not
in class.

<Maya>
だから‥‥うたがわれたの？
So... they thought you did it?

<Phoenix>
うん。クラス中のヤツが‥‥
ぼくをサイバンにかけろ、って。
Yeah. The kids in class said
I should be put on trial.

<Maya>
サイバン‥‥。
Trial...?

<Phoenix>
次の日、学級裁判が開かれた。
‥‥もちろん、被告人はぼくだ。
So the next day we held a
classroom trial, with me
as the defendant.

<Phoenix>
「ぼ‥‥ぼくはやってないよ‥‥」
"I... I didn't do it!"

< >
　「有罪」「ゆうざい」「有罪」　
　「お前だろ！」「どろぼう！」
"Guilty!" "He did it!"
"Guilty!" "It was you!"
"Thief!"

「返してやれよ、お金」「ヒドい人
信じらんない！」「ゼッコーだ！」
"Give me my money back!"
"You're such a meanie!"
"No one play with him!"

「ぼくがやったって言えよ」「かく
すんじゃねえよ」「言いなさいよ」
"Just admit you did it!"
"You can't hide the truth!"
"Tell us the truth!"

「遊んでやらないからな！」「もう
ケシゴム貸してあげないからね！」
"We're not gonna play with
you any more!" "Yeah, and
no borrowing my eraser!"

「リレーの選手、やめさせようよ」
「図書委員もだ」「飼育係もよ！」
"He shouldn't be allowed in
the relay race!" "Or on the
library committee!"

「こないだの５０円返せ」「となり
町の銀行強盗、お前じゃねえのか」
"Gimme back my 50 cents I
loaned you!" "Hey, did you
rob that bank the other day?"

<Teacher>
　　「龍一くん。ダメでしょ？
　　人のお金を盗んじゃあ‥‥」
"Now, Phoenix, you know you
shouldn't steal people's
money! It's not right."

<Phoenix>
‥‥最後に、先生がそう言った。
In the end, even the teacher
thought I'd done it.

<Teacher>
　「あやまりなさい。龍一くん」
"Apologize to the class, 
Phoenix."

<Phoenix>
‥‥その瞬間、ナニがなんだか
わからなくなって‥‥
I... I didn't know what
was happening.

とても悲しくって‥‥
なみだが止まらなくって‥‥
I was so sad...
I couldn't stop crying.

クラス中の視線がぼくに集まった。
“オマエガハンニンダ”って‥‥。
Everyone was staring at me
like I'd done it...

ぼくは、あやまろうとした。
‥‥その子の席の前まで行って。
I tried to apologize.
I went over to where
the boy was sitting...

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そのときだった。
That's when it happened.

< >
「その必要はない！」
"He shouldn't have to
apologize!"

「サイバンでモノを言うのは、
　証拠品だけなのだ！」
"The only thing that belongs
in a trial is evidence!"

「その他のものはすべて、
　沈黙すべし！」
"Anything else has no place!"

「そんなコトも知らないのか‥‥
　シロウトどもめッ！」
"You should all be ashamed...
 amateurs!"

<Teacher>
「ミ‥‥ミツルギくん？」
"M-Miles?"

<Edgeworth>
「キミじゃないのだろう？
　ボクの封筒を盗んだのは‥‥」
"It wasn't you who stole
my money, was it?"

<Phoenix>
「う‥‥うん」
"No..."

<Edgeworth>
「それならば、堂々としたまえ」
"Then you shouldn't
apologize!"

「これだけ話し合ったのに、
　キミがやったという証拠はない」
"Everyone's been shouting
you did it, but no one has
any proof!"

「ということは、裁判長！
　‥‥この少年は、ムザイだ！」
"That is why, Your Honor,
this boy is innocent!"

<Teacher>
「ナニを言ってるの、レイジくん！
盗まれたのは、あなたのお金よ！」
"B-but Miles, it was your
money that was stolen!"

< >
「そうだよ！」
「そいつがやったんだよ！」
"Yeah yeah!"
"He did it! He's the one!"

「証拠なんて必要ないわ」
「あやまらせろよ！」
"We don't need proof!"
"Make him say he's sorry!"

「‥‥イイカゲンにしろよ！‥‥」
"Why don't you all just
 shut up!!!"

<Butz>
「おマエたち、いつもそうやって
　グルになって１人を責めて‥‥」
"This is always how it is,
everybody ganging up and
picking on one person."

「言われるヤツの身にも、
　なってみろってんだよ！」
"Just think how he feels!"

「コイツ、“やってない”って
　言ってるじゃねえかよォ！」
"He said he didn't do it, 
so he didn't do it!"

< >
　　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Teacher>
「わかりました」
"Very well."

「お金は、
　先生が立て替えておきます」
"I will replace the money
myself."

「‥‥学級裁判は、これで
　おしまいにしましょう‥‥」
"This class trial is over."

<Phoenix>
それからだよ。
That's how it happened.

３人がなんとなく、
仲よくなったのは‥‥。
After that, the three of
us were always friends.

<Maya>
‥‥そんなことが
あったんだ‥‥。
Wow... I had no idea!

<Butz>
あ、あったような気も
するなあ‥‥。
Yeah... I had no idea, either!
I mean, I forgot.

<Phoenix>
あのとき、ぼくは
思い知らされたんだよ。
That's when I learned what
it meant to be alone.

味方がいない、究極のコドク。
‥‥その、ツラさをね。
Totally alone, without a
friend in the world.

<Maya>
‥‥ヤッパリさん、
いいヒトだったんですね‥‥。
You did a good thing, Larry!

<Butz>
い、いや、まあ‥‥。
Um, yeah, well...

たまたまその日、学校
休んでたからよかったケド、
I was just lucky that I took
the day off from school.

そうじゃなかったらゼッタイ、
オレがうたがわれてたから。
If I'd been there they would
have thought I'd done it!

ヒトゴトじゃなかったんだわ、
コレが‥‥。
So, I took it kind of
personally, see.

<Phoenix>
（“事件のカゲに、ヤッパリ矢張”
　って言われつづけてたもんな）
("When something smells,
it's usually the Butz.")




<Phoenix>
‥‥学級裁判が終わって、
御剣から聞いたんだ。
Anyway, Edgeworth and I talked
after that class trial.

お父さんが弁護士だってこと。
That's when I heard his
father was a defense attorney.

父親のコトを話すときだけは、
ヤツの目は子供っぽく光ってた。
I remember, his eyes would
shine when he talked about
his father.

<Edgeworth>
「ボクはかならず、父さんのような
　弁護士になるのだよ」
"I'm going to become a defense
attorney, just like my Dad!"

「リッパな弁護士に‥‥」
"A famous defense attorney!"

<Phoenix>
しかし‥‥それから数ヶ月後。
あいつは突然、転校していった。
Then, a few months later,
he suddenly transferred
to another school.

<Maya>
ＤＬ６号事件‥‥。
The DL-6 Incident...

<Phoenix>
そう。たぶん、お父さんが
亡くなったためだろう。
Right. I'm not sure, but the
transfer probably had to do
with his father's death.

<Maya>
かわいそう‥‥。
That's so sad!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

御剣の名前をひさしぶりに
見たのは、数年たってからだ。
It was several years later
when I heard Edgeworth's
name again.

新聞に、彼の名前が大きく
のっていた。
There was an article about him
in the newspaper.

《鬼検事に、黒い疑惑》
とかいう見出しでね。
The headline was something
like "Dark Suspicions of
a Demon Attorney."

証拠のでっち上げ、証言の操作、
もみ消し‥‥。
Fabricating evidence,
manipulating testimonies,
covering up facts...

有罪のためならば、なんでも
する男だ、と書いてあった。
The article said he'd do
anything to get a guilty
verdict. Anything.

<Butz>
‥‥どうしてだ？
But why?

ナニがあったんだよ！
まるで別人じゃねえか！
What happened!? I mean,
that's not the Edgey I
used to know at all!

<Phoenix>
ぼくもそう思った。
That's what I thought too.

ぼくは御剣に会おうと、
何度も連絡をとった。
I tried to get in touch
with him I don't know
how many times...

しかし、彼は返事を
してくれなかった。
He never replied.

<Maya>
ムカシの友だちに‥‥
会いたくなかったんだ‥‥。
I guess he didn't
want to see his
old friends...

<Phoenix>
でもぼくは、
あきらめられなかった。
I couldn't just drop
it, though.

どうしても彼に会って、
ナゾを解くんだ、と‥‥
I wanted to meet him, to
learn why he had become
who he became.

そう決心したんだ。
That's when I decided.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥！
...!

ま‥‥まさか‥‥。
Wait... You don't mean...?

まさか、なるほどくん‥‥
そのために‥‥？
That's why!?

御剣検事に会うために、
弁護士になったの‥‥？
That's why you became
a defense attorney!?
To meet Edgeworth!?

<Phoenix>
弁護士になれば、あいつは
イヤでもぼくに会わざるをえない。
If I was a defense attorney,
I knew he'd have to meet me
whether he wanted to or not.

法廷でね。
In court.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
ぼくを信じてくれた御剣を、
ぼくは信じている。
Edgeworth believed in me,
and I believe in him.

あいつは苦しんでいる。
そして、味方がいない。
He's in pain...
And no one's on his side.

チカラになれるのは、本当の
あいつを知っている、ぼくだけだ。
I'm the only one who knows
the real Edgeworth. I'm the
only one who can help him.

<Butz>
な‥‥成歩堂‥‥。
Whoa... Nick.

じゃあ、おマエがオレを、
タダで助けてくれたのも‥‥？
S-so, is that why you
helped me out for free?

<Phoenix>
ああ。
Uh... yes.

お前を信じていたからだ。
I helped you because
I believed in you.

（‥‥ただし、タダと言った
　おぼえは、ないんだけど‥‥）
(Except I don't remember
saying I'd do it for free...)

<Butz>
‥‥‥‥なるほどうよお‥‥‥‥
Aww, Nick! Nick!!!




<Maya>
あたしに何か見せるより、
調査に行こうよ！
Stop showing me stuff
and let's get cracking!

もう、今日しかないんだよ！
We only have today to
get to the bottom of this!




<Butz>
いやあ、はっはっ。
カッコよかったよなー、オレ。
Woo hoo, I was hot
out there. Hot!

<Phoenix>
（ダメだ‥‥。
　カンゼンに舞い上がってる）
(I'm glad someone's happy
about how this case is
going...)

（今は、
　何を見せてもムダだな‥‥）
(He seems too happy to care
about anything I show him.)




<Maya>
あと１日だね、なるほどくん。
One day left, Nick.

<Phoenix>
‥‥そうだな。
Yeah... I know.

<Maya>
さあ。休んでるヒマはないよ！
出かけようよ！
Well, no time to waste!
Let's get going!




<Phoenix>
どうしようか？
これから‥‥。
What do you think we should
do now, Maya?

<Maya>
それは、なるほどくんが
イチバン、よく知ってるでしょ。
You would know best, Nick!

そのとおりにがんばれば、
いいと思うよ。
Just do what you do!
That should work.




<Phoenix>
どう？
‥‥何か気づいたこと、ある？
Well?
Had any good ideas?

<Maya>
‥‥やっぱり、ＤＬ６号事件‥‥。
This is all tied to the
DL-6 Incident...

明日までに、できるだけ
調べた方がよさそうだよね。
We'd better find out as much
as we can about that murder
before tomorrow!

<Phoenix>
（御剣をがんじがらめにしている、
　運命のクサリ‥‥か）
(Something that happened back
then has a hold on Edgeworth
and it won't let go.)




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
December 27
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

例によって、御剣は
取り調べを受けているらしい。
Looks like Edgeworth is
back in questioning.

<Maya>
御剣検事には、聞かなきゃ
いけないこと、あるよね。
We have our own
questions for him!

あとでまた来ようよ。
Let's come back later.

<Phoenix>
そうだな‥‥。
Yeah, I guess so.

<Maya>
わすれちゃダメだよ。
Don't forget, okay?




<Phoenix>
面会のようすを監視する看守だ。
This guard monitors
the visitor's room.

さっきから、まったく動かない。
さすが、プロだな。
He hasn't moved an inch since
I came in. A real pro.




<Phoenix>
ごていねいに、カメラで
見張っているようだ。
Smile for the camera...




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
留置所　面会室
December 27
Detention Center
Visitor's Room

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
あいかわらず、シブいカオ
してるなあ‥‥。
You look as grim as always.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥フン。
Hmph.

<Maya>
あの、御剣検事。聞きましたよ、
学級裁判の話。
Um, Mr. Edgeworth?
I heard the story about
the class trial...

<Edgeworth>
‥‥学級裁判？　なんのことだ？
Class trial? What do you mean?

<Maya>
え。おぼえてないんですか？
You... don't remember?

<Edgeworth>
ああ、おぼえていない。
No, I don't.

<Maya>
給食費を盗まれたんですよね？
小学校４年生のとき‥‥。
Your lunch money was
stolen, wasn't it?
In 4th grade...?

<Edgeworth>
給食費‥‥？
Lunch money...?

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あ、ああ。
そんなこともあったな‥‥。
Oh... Oh, right.
Yes, I seem to remember
something like that.

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
‥‥誰もおぼえてないよ。
Nick.
I think you're the only
one who really remembers.

<Phoenix>
ま、まあ、ぼく以外の人間には
どうでもいいことだろうからね。
Well, it probably only
really mattered to me
anyway.

<Maya>
御剣検事、知らないんですか？
Mr. Edgeworth, didn't
you know?

なるほどくん、あれがキッカケで
弁護士になったんですよ。
That trial was the reason
Nick became a defense
attorney!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

バカな。
Ridiculous!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥ミもフタもない
　コメントだな‥‥）
(Gee... thanks.)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥しかし。
That said...

とてもキミらしい話だ。
It does sound like the
kind of thing you'd do.

‥‥変わっていないな、成歩堂。
その、あきれるほどの単純さ‥‥。
You haven't changed a bit,
have you, Wright? So...simple.
To a fault, even.

<Phoenix>
まあな。だが‥‥、
Well, maybe yeah, but...

お前は変わっちまったな、御剣。
I think you changed
too much, Edgeworth.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そうだな。
Perhaps.




<Phoenix>
‥‥なんてこった‥‥。
This is bad...

<Maya>
なるほどくん‥‥どうしよう。
とんでもないことに‥‥。
What are we going to do,
Nick? What can we do!?

<Phoenix>
くやしいけど‥‥
I don't know...

ぼくたちじゃ、どうしようも
ないよ‥‥。
I don't think there is
anything we can do.
Like it or not.

ＤＬ６号事件の情報を、
詳しく知っている人がいれば‥‥。
If there's someone else
who knows a lot about
the DL-6 Incident, maybe...

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

いるじゃない、なるほどくん！
There is, Nick!

あの人に、助けてもらおうよ！
There is someone else who
knows about DL-6!




<Phoenix>
なあ、御剣。どうしてお前、
検事になったんだ？
Hey, Edgeworth. Why did you
become a prosecutor, anyway?

あんなに父親を尊敬して、
弁護士にあこがれていたのに‥‥。
You used to look up to your
dad... You said you wanted to
be a defense attorney, right?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

私は、キミほどバカには
なれなかったんだよ。
I couldn't let myself deny
reality like you.

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうことだ？
What do you mean?

<Edgeworth>
オヤジをうばわれ、それでも
犯罪者の味方になれるほど‥‥、
My father was taken from me,
and you want me to defend
criminals?

私はそこまで、お人よしではない！
I'm sorry, Wright, but I'm
not that good of a person!

<Maya>
お父さんが亡くなった事件‥‥
容疑者が１人、逮捕されましたね。
One suspect was apprehended
in your father's murder,
right?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そうだ。父とエレベータに
閉じ込められた男‥‥。
Yes. The man trapped in the
elevator with my father.

灰根　高太郎という名前だ。
His name... was Yanni Yogi.

どう考えたって、犯人は
あいつしかいないんだ！
He had to be the shooter,
any way you look at it!

なのに‥‥無罪になった。
あの弁護士のせいで！
Yet... he was found innocent.
That defense attorney got
him off the hook!

<Phoenix>
（被害者の、
　生倉弁護士のことか‥‥）
(That would be Robert
Hammond...)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥１５年前の、あの日。
On that day, 15 years ago...

我々３人は、５時間、
エレベータに閉じ込められた。
The three of us were trapped
in that elevator for five
hours.

助け出された時は
極度の酸欠状態になっていて、
When we were rescued, we
all suffered oxygen
deprivation.

私は、事件に関する記憶を
なくしていたのだ。
I had lost all memory of
the murder.

<Phoenix>
記憶を‥‥？
Lost your memory?

<Edgeworth>
今も思い出せない。エレベータで、
何があったのか‥‥。
Even now, I can't recall
what happened in that
elevator.

法廷で、灰根の弁護士も
そう主張した。
That was the crux of Yogi's
attorney's argument in court.

酸欠で、灰根は
心神喪失状態にあった、と。
He claimed Yanni Yogi had
been "not of sound mind" due
to the oxygen deprivation.

‥‥結局、灰根は証拠不充分。
無罪になった。
Yogi was released due to a
lack of evidence... innocent.

それからだ。
That's when I changed my mind.

私が、弁護士というものに
憎しみを抱きはじめたのは‥‥。
I started to hate defense
attorneys.




<Phoenix>
狩魔検事とは、どういう‥‥？
What's your relationship
with von Karma?

<Edgeworth>
彼は、私が最も尊敬する先輩だ。
He's my teacher, and a man
who deserves respect.

私の法廷テクニックは、
彼にイチから仕込まれた。
I learned everything I know
of courtroom techniques
from him.

<Maya>
なるほどくんで言えば、
お姉ちゃんみたいなもんだね。
So, he's like my sister
was to you, Nick.

<Edgeworth>
彼はすべてにおいて、
カンペキ主義者だ。
He is a perfectionist
in all things.

法廷においても、
人生においても‥‥。
In court...
In his personal life...

カンペキであることに、
異常なほどのこだわりがあるのだ。
He is obsessed with doing
everything perfectly.

<Maya>
“カンペキ”‥‥？
Perfectly, huh?

<Edgeworth>
彼があつかった事件で、未解決の
まま時効になったものは、
In all the cases he has
taken on, none were left
unsolved.

ただの１つもない。
‥‥もちろん、敗訴も。
And not one suspect was
declared innocent. Ever.

<Maya>
でも‥‥それって‥‥。
But... but that's...

<Edgeworth>
わかっている。
I know.

中には、無実の人間が
いたかもしれない。
It's possible some of the
suspects were indeed innocent.

しかし、私たちに、それを正確に
見抜くことは、不可能なのだ。
However, it is impossible
for us to accurately determine
that in every case.

狩魔検事は、彼のするべき仕事を
カンペキに遂行しているだけだ。
All von Karma does is his
job, to find the suspect
guilty, perfectly.

とにかく。
In any case...

彼の弱みを見つけるのは、
不可能に近い。
It's nigh well impossible
to find a weakness in him.

それをモミ消すためならば、彼は
どんな手段でも使ってくるだろう。
Should a weakness appear,
he would do everything in his
power to make it go away.

<Phoenix>
‥‥あのなあ、御剣。
Um, Edgeworth?

その話が本当なら、
お前も明日、有罪になっちゃうぞ。
If what you're saying is
true, you're headed for
a guilty sentence tomorrow!

<Maya>
そ、そうですよ！
ホメてる場合じゃないでしょ！
H-he's right!
Now's no time to praise
the enemy, Mr. Edgeworth!

<Edgeworth>
ムム‥‥。
Mmph...

それが‥‥ツラいところだ。
It's a strange situation
in which I find myself,
I'll admit.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ‥‥）
(No kidding.)




<Edgeworth>
灰根　高太郎は、
法廷の係官だった。
Yanni Yogi was a court
bailiff at the time.

１５年前。私たちは偶然、
エレベータに乗り合わせた。
We just happened to be in
that elevator together 15
years ago.

　　‥‥ヒドい揺れだった‥‥。
The quake was incredibly
strong...

気がついたら‥‥
我々は、闇の中にいた。
Before I knew it, everything
was dark.

永遠とも思える、長い長い時間。
We were there for so long,
it felt like forever.

うすれてゆく空気‥‥。せまい
箱の中で、闇が迫ってくる‥‥。
The air thinned... and the
darkness closed in on us
in that little box.

‥‥しだいに我々は、落ちつきを
うしなっていった。
We became... unsettled.

< >
「助けてくれッ！　い、息が‥‥」
"H-help! I can't breathe!"

「うるさい！　ダマるんだ！
　‥‥こっちまでおかしくなる！」
"Quiet! I said quiet!
You're not making this
any easier!"

「出せ！　ここから
　出してくれえッ！」
"I want to get out!
Help! Get us out!"

「大声を出すな！　酸素をよけいに
　消費するぞ！」
"Don't shout! You'll just
use up more oxygen!"

「‥‥‥‥‥‥！」
"...!"

<Edgeworth>
‥‥私の記憶は、そこまでだ‥‥。
That's all I remember...

気がついたら、私は病院の
ベッドで、天井をながめていた。
When I came to, I was in 
a hospital bed, staring
up at the ceiling.

裁判では、灰根の精神状態が
問題になった。
In court, Yanni Yogi's
mental condition was
called into question.

酸欠と緊張状態が原因で、
灰根は心神喪失状態にあったとか。
They claimed the oxygen
deprivation and stress
had caused temporary insanity.

結局、その主張が認められて、
灰根は無罪になったのだ‥‥。
In the end, the claim passed
the court, and Yogi was
found innocent.

<Maya>
‥‥でも‥‥。
ちょっと、おかしいですね。
Huh...
But, isn't that strange?

この手紙‥‥。御剣検事に
復讐しろ、って書いてありますよ。
This letter tells him to
"get revenge on Edgeworth"...

なんで“復讐”なんですか？
それも、あなたに‥‥？
Why would he want to take
revenge on you?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

成歩堂。
Wright.

<Phoenix>
ん？
Yeah?

<Edgeworth>
この数日間、ずっと悩んでいた
ことがある。
There's something that's been
troubling me these last few
days.

キミに話すべきかどうか‥‥。
I... didn't know whether or
not I should tell you.

<Phoenix>
もしかして、今日の
法廷で言っていた‥‥
You mean the nightmare?

<Edgeworth>
私の‥‥悪夢の話だ。
It's... a nightmare I've had.

私が犯した罪の記憶‥‥。
A memory of a crime...
that I committed.

<Phoenix>
お前の‥‥罪？
A crime you committed?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

殺人‥‥の記憶だ。
A memory... of a murder.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥どうやら。
I think...

キミに聞いてもらうときが
来たようだな‥‥。
I think the time has
come to tell all.




<Edgeworth>
この１５年間、毎日のように
同じ夢を見る。
For the last 15 years, I've
had the same dream almost
every night.

そのたびに私は、
恐怖にハネ起きるのだ。
I wake up in a fearful
sweat, every time.

<Maya>
‥‥どんな夢なんですか‥‥？
What kind of dream?

<Edgeworth>
あの事件の夢だ。すべてが
闇に閉ざされた、あの事件。
It's a dream about my father's
killing... in the dark.

< >
「助けてくれッ！　い、息が‥‥」
"H-help! I can't breathe!"

「うるさい！　ダマるんだ！
　‥‥こっちまでおかしくなる！」
"Quiet! I said quiet!
You're not making this
any easier!"

「出せ！　ここから
　出してくれえッ！」
"I want to get out!
Help! Get us out!"

「大声を出すな！　酸素をよけいに
　消費するぞ！」
"Don't shout! You'll just
use up more oxygen!"

< >
「い‥‥息ができねえ‥‥！
お前が空気をヨゴすからだ‥‥」
"I... I can't breath!
You... you're using up
my air!"

「な‥‥なんだと！」
"Wh-what!?"

「オレの空気を吸うな！
い‥‥息の根を止めてやる！」
"Stop breathing my air!
I'll... I'll stop you!"

「う‥‥うわっ！
何をする‥‥やめろ‥‥！」
"Aaaah! Wh-what!?
 What are you...!?"

「オレの空気を吸うなァァァァ！」
"Stop breathing my aaaaair!"

< >
　　　　（おとうさんが‥‥）
(No! Father!)

　　（おとうさんが、
　　　おそわれている‥‥！）
(He's attacking Father!)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥ふと気がつくと、足元に
ピストルがころがっている。
Then I see the pistol
lying by my feet.

その日の裁判の証拠品だったのか、
係官の持ちものだったのか‥‥。
I don't know if it was
evidence from that day
in court, or the bailiff's...

私は、夢中でそのピストルを
拾い上げる。
In a daze, I pick up
the pistol...

　（ぼくのおとうさんから‥‥）
(Get away...!)

（おとうさんから、
　はなれろぉっ‥‥！）
(Get away from my father!)

< >
　　　　　‥‥パァン！‥‥
*BANG*

うぐおおおおおおおおおおおおお
をををををををををををををッ！
Uuaaaaaaaaaaaaa
aaaaaaaaaaaaargh!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥その悲鳴で、目がさめるんだ。
And with that scream...
I wake.

ものすごい悲鳴だ。
It's a bone-chilling scream.

この１５年間、耳からはなれたこと
がない、ものすごい悲鳴‥‥。
A scream that has rung in
my ears for the past 15 years.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

で、でも。
B-but...

‥‥それって、ただの“夢”
なんですよね‥‥？
That's just a dream, right?
Right?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

そう思って、この１５年間、
生きてきた。
That thought is the only thing
that has kept me sane for the
last 15 years.

しかし‥‥。
But what if I'm wrong?

これが“現実”だった
としたら‥‥？
What if it's real?

人は、自分の精神を守るため、
記憶を閉ざすことがあるという。
They say that sometimes people
shut out memories in self-
defense.

父親の命をうばったのは、
他ならぬ、私かもしれない！
Maybe it was I who killed
my father!

<Maya>
そ‥‥そんなことって‥‥！
What!?

<Edgeworth>
‥‥そう考えると、この手紙も
なっとくできる。
If you think about it that
way, this letter makes sense.

《御剣　怜侍に復讐しろ》
"Get your revenge on
Miles Edgeworth."

‥‥そう。灰根は本当に無実
だったのだ‥‥。
Think about it. Yogi was
really innocent.

だから、復讐しようとしたのだ
‥‥この、私に。
That's why he wanted revenge
against me!

<Phoenix>
待てよ、御剣！
‥‥それって、つまり‥‥！
Wait, Edgeworth!
You... you mean...!

<Edgeworth>
オヤジを撃ったのは‥‥
ＤＬ６号事件の真犯人は‥‥
It was me.

この‥‥私‥‥ッ！
I was the true criminal
of DL-6. I shot my father!




<Phoenix>
御剣。
‥‥この手紙なんだけど‥‥。
Edgeworth...
See this letter?

<Edgeworth>
？
Hmm?

<Phoenix>
例の、ボート小屋の管理人の
金庫から出てきたんだ。
This came out of the safe
in the shack where that boat
rental caretaker lives.

<Edgeworth>
ほほう‥‥。
I see...

‥‥‥‥‥‥！
...!

この私に‥‥復讐だと‥‥？
Revenge... on me?

<Maya>
いったい、誰なんですか！
あのオジさん‥‥！
Who is that old guy, anyway!?

<Edgeworth>
し‥‥知らん。
I... I don't know.

<Phoenix>
お前がムカシ有罪にした、
無実の被告人、とか‥‥？
Could he be an innocent
defendant you got declared
guilty or something?

<Edgeworth>
イヤなことを言うな。
あんなオジさん、おぼえがないぞ。
Nice, Wright.
But I don't remember that
old man. Not at all.

<Maya>
とにかく、オジさんは、
この手紙どおりに犯行を‥‥。
So, he was following this
letter, then?

<Edgeworth>
つまり、この事件には
黒幕がいた、ということか‥‥。
Which means there was someone
else behind it!

< >
《お前の人生を破滅させた２人の
　男に、今こそ復讐するのだ》
"Now is your time to get
revenge on the two men
who ruined your life!"

<Edgeworth>
２人の男‥‥この私と、
生倉弁護士のこと‥‥か？
Two men... meaning myself
and Robert Hammond?

<Maya>
《これが最後のチャンスだ》
とも書いてありますよ。
It also says: "This is your
last chance!"

<Phoenix>
最後のチャンス‥‥？
もしかして、それって‥‥
Last chance...?
Wait, maybe...

“時効”のことじゃないか？
Maybe he's talking about the
statute of limitations on
the DL-6 Incident!

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥
...

まさか‥‥
Wait...

まさか、あのオジさんが‥‥！
Wait, that old man...!

<Maya>
ど、どうしたんですか！
何かわかったの‥‥？
Wh-what is it!?
Do you know who he is!?

<Edgeworth>
灰根‥‥だったのか‥‥
あのオジさんが‥‥！
Yogi...
Could he be Yogi!?

<Maya>
はいね‥‥
Yogi?

<Edgeworth>
ＤＬ６号事件の容疑者で
無罪になった、あの男だ‥‥。
The suspect in the DL-6
Incident. The one who
was found innocent.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥今さら、こんな写真を
見せて、どうする気だ‥‥？
What are you showing me
this picture for?

<Phoenix>
い、いや、べつに。
Um, uh, no reason.

<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

しかし、今日の法廷での
キミの推理、ミゴトだった。
You know, I was impressed
by your deduction in the
trial today.

苦しまぎれだったとはいえ、
なかなかだったぞ‥‥。
Granted, you were at the
end of your rope, but still.

<Maya>
なるほどくん、バレてるよ。
‥‥苦しまぎれだったコト。
Nick, he noticed.

<Phoenix>
ははは。
Hah hah.




<Edgeworth>
‥‥‥‥‥‥。
...

‥‥私の人生を
変えてしまった事件だ。
It was that case that
changed my life.

１５年前の、１２月２８日‥‥。
明日で、時効か。
And tomorrow, on December 28,
its statute of limitations
runs out.

<Phoenix>
（明日。‥‥偶然なのか‥‥？）
(Tomorrow... Could that be
a coincidence?)

<Edgeworth>
だが‥‥。
書類上では時効になっても‥‥、
But... even if the case is
finally closed on paper...

私の記憶から消すことは
できない‥‥永久に‥‥。
It will never be erased from
my memory. Never...

<Maya>
御剣検事‥‥。
Poor Mr. Edgeworth!




<Maya>
ダメだよ、なるほどくん！
N-Nick! No!

お‥‥お父さんの写真だよ。
そんなの見せたら‥‥。
Th-that's a photo of his
father! Don't show him that!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥そうだな）
(You're right...)

（今さら見せるべきものじゃ
　ないか‥‥）
(Now probably isn't a
good time to dredge
up those memories...)

<Edgeworth>
‥‥なんだ？
What is it?

<Phoenix>
い、いや。‥‥なんでもない。
Uh, um, n-nothing.

<Edgeworth>
？
Huh?




<Edgeworth>
すまないな。
Sorry.

‥‥何も言えることは
ないようだ。
I'm not sure I can
help you with that.




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
ひょうたん湖公園　入口前
December 27
Gourd Lake Park
Entrance

<Gumshoe>
おっ！　ひさしぶりッス！
Hey, pal!
Long time no see!

<Maya>
あ、イトノコ刑事さん。
Oh! Detective Gumshoe!

<Gumshoe>
今日はアブなかったッス！
Close one today, eh!

ハラハラして、ネクタイを１本
食いちぎったッス。
I got so worked up,
I snapped my tie in half!

<Phoenix>
そ、それはどうも
スミマセンでした‥‥。
Uh... Sorry about that.

<Gumshoe>
いいッス！　おかげで、
ハンニンがわかったッスからな！
No prob, pal! Thanks to you,
we now know who really did it!

<Maya>
ボート小屋のオジさんですか？
You mean, the boat shop
caretaker?

<Gumshoe>
約束するッス！
Look, I'll make you a promise.

自分は、明日の開廷時間までに、
必ずアイツをタイホするッス！
I'll have that scoundrel
in my custody by trial
time tomorrow!

ナニがあっても！
Come what may!

‥‥それが、アンタに対する
警察官としてのレイギッス！
It's my duty to you as
a police officer!

では、シツレイするッス！
Now, I'm off to catch me
a criminal!

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥
...

イトノコ刑事、ハリきってたねー。
Detective Gumshoe sure
is... active today.

<Gumshoe>
あ、それから１つ。
Oh, one other thing!

<Maya>
きゃっ！
Eek!

<Gumshoe>
今日は、森の方へは
行けないッス。
No one can go into
the woods today.

<Maya>
もり？
The woods?

<Phoenix>
（ナツミさんがキャンプしていた
　ところか‥‥）
(Where Lotta was camping?)

<Gumshoe>
あそこはキャンプ禁止だったッス。
公園の管理人にバレて、
The woods are off-limits to
camping, and apparently
the park ranger found out.

しばらく、立入禁止になったッス。
He got pretty mad.
No one can go in for a while.

<Maya>
ナツミさん、怒られちゃったんだ。
I guess Lotta's in a 'lotta'
trouble...

<Gumshoe>
ま、そういうことッス。
‥‥じゃ、また明日、会うッス！
Anyway, I'll be seeing
you tomorrow!




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
ひょうたん湖広場
December 27
Gourd Lake
Public Beach

<Phoenix>
あれ。あの目ざわりな
トノサマンがいないな‥‥。
Huh? The Steel Eyesore
is missing...

<Maya>
“目ざわり”って言うな！
"Eyesore"!?

<Phoenix>
屋台も休みみたいだ。
Looks like the hotdog
stand is closed, too.

<Maya>
たしかに、アルバイト
どころじゃないのかもね‥‥。
I guess Larry's been too
busy with the trial to
show up for work...




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
貸しボート小屋前
December 27
Boat Rental Shop

<Maya>
あのオジさん、逃げちゃった
んだよね。
That old caretaker got away...

<Phoenix>
ああ。
Yep.

<Maya>
まさか、あのオジさんが
ハンニンだったなんて‥‥。
I never imagined he might
be the real murderer!

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<???>
ウォッホォン！
*Ah-HHHHEM!*

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
（このセキ払いは‥‥）
...!
(I'd know that clearing-
of-the-throat anywhere!)

<Grossberg>
やあやあチミたち。
‥‥どうした？　こんなところで。
Ah hah, hello!
What might you be doing here?

チミたちもサンポかな？　ん？
Out for a walk, hmm?

“青春の日々はぁ‥‥青いレモンの
　カオリぃ‥‥”とォ。
"Ahh... the days of my
youth... like the scent of
fresh lemon..." you see.

<Maya>
ほ‥‥星影センセイ！
Mr. Grossberg!

なにをノンキなコト
言ってるんですか！
This is no time for idle
reminiscing!

御剣検事の裁判、明日が
最終日なんですよ！
Mr. Edgeworth's trial ends
tomorrow! 

<Grossberg>
‥‥そ、それはそうぢゃが。
Er... that is true, yes.

今日の法廷を見たかぎりでは、
もうあの子はアンシンぢゃろ？
But, from what I saw of
today's trial, Edgeworth
should be fine, right?

<Phoenix>
それが‥‥
そうでもないんです。
Well...
I'm not so sure about that.

<Grossberg>
‥‥どういうことぢゃ？
Ho ho!
What do you mean by that?

<Phoenix>
それが、まだ‥‥
ハッキリしないんですけど。
Well... I'm not sure.

<Grossberg>
‥‥ううむ‥‥。
Hmm...

何かわかったら、
ワシの事務所に来なさい。
If you find anything out,
come by my office at once.

チカラになれることが
あるかもしれん。
I may be able to offer
you some assistance.

<Phoenix>
（センセイ、行っちまったぞ‥‥）
Thanks...
(Bye...)

<Maya>
星影センセイ、何してたのかな？
‥‥こんなところで‥‥。
What do you think
Mr. Grossberg was
doing here anyway?

<Phoenix>
‥‥さあ‥‥。
Who knows...




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
警察署内　刑事課
December 27
Police Department
Criminal Affairs

<Phoenix>
（イトノコさん‥‥
　まだ、もどってないみたいだな）
(Hmm... Looks like
Detective Gumshoe
hasn't gotten back yet.)

<Police>
イトノコなら、今日は
もどらないと思うよ。
Gumshoe? He won't be
coming back today.

<Maya>
あ‥‥そうなんですか。
Oh... really?

<Police>
明日までに、どうしても逮捕
しなくちゃならん男がいるとか。
He said there was some guy
he had to arrest by tomorrow.

<Phoenix>
（管理小屋のオジさんか‥‥）
(The boat shop caretaker...)

<Police>
命にかえても見つけだすッス！
‥‥って叫んで、出ていったよ。
He shouted something about
"catching him if it's the
last thing I do, pal!"

<Phoenix>
（ありがとう‥‥イトノコさん）
(Good luck, Gumshoe!)




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
警察署内　刑事課
December 27
Police Department
Criminal Affairs

<Maya>
‥‥人が少ないね。
There's hardly anyone
here...

<Phoenix>
みんな、オジさん‥‥灰根を
探しに行ってるんだよ。
Everyone must be out looking
for the old guy... Yogi.

<Police>
あ。キミたち。
Ah, it's you.

今日は、イトノコはもう
もどらないよ。
I don't think Gumshoe'll
be coming back today.

徹夜でヒト探しだとさ。
He's staying out late looking
for someone.

<Maya>
イトノコ刑事さんも
がんばってくれてるんだね！
Sounds like Detective Gumshoe
is pounding the pavement
for real!

<Maya>
あの。あたしたち、資料室に
行きたいんですけど‥‥。
Um, we were wondering if
we could check out the
Records Room again...

<Police>
‥‥勝手に入ってもらっちゃ
こまるんだけど‥‥。
Well, now, I can't have
just anyone wandering
around in there.

まあ、今なら狩魔検事が
いると思うから、
But... I guess Mr. von Karma
is in there now, anyway.

彼といっしょなら、資料を
見てもいいよ。
You can go in as long
as he's there.

<Maya>
カルマ検事‥‥？
von Karma...?

<Police>
ああ。
‥‥ついさっき、来たところだ。
Yes.
He just arrived actually.

<Phoenix>
（狩魔検事が、資料室に！）
(von Karma's in the
Records Room!)

<Maya>
い、急ごうよ、なるほどくん！
N-Nick! Let's hurry!




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
星影法律事務所
December 27
Grossberg Law Offices

<Phoenix>
‥‥また、いない。
He's out... again.

<Maya>
あのセンセイ、いつ
シゴトしてるの？
When does he work, anyway?

<Phoenix>
まあまあ。
（また、あとで来てみるか‥‥）
Now, now. Don't be harsh.
(Guess we'll have to come
back later.)




<Phoenix>
星影センセイの絵、
どうやら帰ってこないみたいだな。
I guess Mr. Grossberg
isn't getting that
painting back.

ちょっとかわいそうな
気もする‥‥。
I feel kind of bad
for him...




<Phoenix>
マホガニー製のどっしりした
デスクだ。
A solid mahogany desk.

深いツヤが出るまで
みがき込まれている。
The wood's been polished
to a deep luster.




<Phoenix>
来客用のテーブルだ。
A table for clients.

上品な黒檀のシガレットケースと、
純金製のライター、か？
Hmm... an elegant ebony case,
and if I'm not mistaken, that
lighter's made of solid gold.

なんだかわからないけど、
高そうなことに間違いはない。
Even I can tell someone
here's got money to burn.




<Phoenix>
最高級の観葉植物だ。
An expensive potted plant.

名前はわからないが、
どうせ高いんだろう。
No idea what kind of plant it
is, but it's probably the
most expensive one available.




<Phoenix>
マホガニー製の高そうな本棚に、
高そうな本がズラリ。
Expensive-looking mahogany
bookshelves, filled with
expensive-looking books.

‥‥でも、あまり読まれたような
あとがないのが気になるな‥‥。
Hmm... funny... They don't
look like they've ever been
read.




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
星影法律事務所
December 27
Grossberg Law Offices

<Phoenix>
ほ‥‥星影センセイ！
M-Mr. Grossberg!

<Grossberg>
お。チミたち。‥‥なんぢゃ、
シンコクそうなカオして。
Ah, hello there.
What's wrong?
You look troubled.

<Maya>
センセイこそなんですか！
ノンキなカオして！
No kidding!
I can't believe you're not!

<Grossberg>
‥‥い、いやいやいや。
M-my my my...

いったい、ナニがあったんぢゃ。
‥‥話してみなさい。
Just calm down and tell
me what's happened, hmm?

<Maya>
み、御剣検事が‥‥
みつるぎけんじがああ！
It's M-Mr. Edgeworth!
He... He... *sob*

<Grossberg>
‥‥なんと‥‥
I see...

御剣　信を撃った夢を‥‥のう。
So, Edgeworth dreamt
he shot his own father?

<Maya>
ゆ、“夢”なんですからね！
‥‥あくまで！
It's o-only a dream!
Only a dream!

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

それはどうかのお‥‥。
I wonder...

<Maya>
え‥‥。
W-what...?

<Grossberg>
それならばなぜ、チミたちは
そんなにあわてておるのかね？
If that's the case, then 
why do you two look so
troubled, hmm?

<Maya>
そ、それは‥‥。
W-well...

<Grossberg>
それに。
Also, consider this.

あきらかに灰根は、御剣　怜侍に
対して、悪意を持っておる。
Yogi quite certainly holds
a deep grudge against Miles
Edgeworth.

殺人罪を着せようとするほどの
強く、深い悪意を‥‥。
So deep, he'd want to frame
him for murder.

‥‥おそらく。
This leads me to surmise...

夢ではあるまい。
‥‥現実だったのぢゃよ。
That Mr. Edgeworth's dream
was NOT a dream. It was real.

チミたちの想像どおり、な。
As you imagined.

御剣　怜侍は、父親を助けるために
ピストルを投げつけ‥‥
Miles Edgeworth threw the
pistol to save his father...

そのピストルが‥‥
暴発したんぢゃ。
the pistol fired...
and the deed was done.

<Grossberg>
...

<Maya>
そ‥‥そんな‥‥。
N... No!

そんなの、ヒドすぎるよ‥‥。
I don't believe it!

<Grossberg>
灰根は、その罪を着せられて、
係官としての人生をつぶされた。
Yogi was suspected of murder,
and his career as a bailiff
was irrevocably wrecked.

だから‥‥御剣　怜侍に
復讐しようとしたのだ。
Thus, he sought revenge
on Miles Edgeworth.

時効直前の‥‥今になって、な。
This was his last chance, of
course, with the statute of
limitations so close.




<Maya>
なるほどくん‥‥どうしよう。
What do we do, Nick?

カルマ検事、きっとＤＬ６号事件の
こと、持ち出してくるよ。
von Karma is going to bring
up DL-6, you can bet on it!

御剣検事‥‥もしかしたら‥‥
罪を、認めちゃうかも‥‥。
What if Mr. Edgeworth pleads
guilty to DL-6!?

<Phoenix>
そんなことはさせない！
I won't let him!

<Grossberg>
‥‥ぢゃが、成歩堂くん。
Erm, yes, Mr. Wright...

ザンコクな話かもしれんが‥‥、
I hate to say this...

たとえ過失でも、殺人は
殺人ぢゃよ‥‥？
But even accidental murder
is murder, you know.

<Phoenix>
わかってますよ！
I know that!

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ただ、ぼくはまだ、
信じているんです！　御剣を。
I... I just believe in
Edgeworth's innocence!

あいつが、殺人なんて‥‥！
I can't believe he'd
kill someone!

<Maya>
で‥‥でも！
B-but, Nick!

御剣検事、自分で
認めちゃっているんだよ？
Mr. Edgeworth admits
it himself!

それに、お父さんも、御剣検事を
守るために、ウソを‥‥
His father must have lied
to protect him, from beyond
the grave...

<Phoenix>
‥‥それでも！
I don't care!

それでも、あいつは無実なんだ！
I know he's not guilty!

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

成歩堂くん。
Mr. Wright...

チミがそこまで言うなら‥‥、
もう一度、調べてみるんぢゃ。
If you say so, I suppose
I could go check again.

警察の‥‥資料をな。
The police files might
hold something of interest.

<Phoenix>
星影センセイ‥‥。
Mr. Grossberg... thank you!

<Grossberg>
ほとんど可能性はゼロぢゃが。
‥‥何か、見つかるかもしれん。
I can't promise anything.
In fact, I think the chances
of finding something are slim.

<Phoenix>
わかりました。
I understand.

（警察の‥‥資料か‥‥）
(The police materials... hmm.)




<Phoenix>
御剣の父親って、どういう‥‥？
What do you know about
Edgeworth's father?

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

すばらしい弁護士ぢゃった。
He was a defense attorney
without peer.

月並みな表現ぢゃが、
そうとしか言いようがない。
It sounds trite, but
it's true.

‥‥そういえば、似ておったかも
しれんなあ。
Well, he may have had one peer
now that I think about it.

綾里　千尋クンと‥‥。
Your mentor, Mia Fey.

<Maya>
お姉ちゃんと‥‥？
My sister...?

<Grossberg>
御剣　信は、狩魔検事のやり方に、
強く反発を感じていた。
Gregory Edgeworth was very
disapproving of Mr. von
Karma's techniques.

<Phoenix>
（カルマケンジ‥‥）
(That's no surprise...)

<Grossberg>
狩魔は強引な男ぢゃ。証拠・証言の
でっち上げなど、平気でする‥‥。
von Karma is an extreme man.
Forged testimonies and
evidence are nothing to him.

当然、彼のあつかう事件は、
すべて勝訴だ。
The result: he has a perfect
win record in court.

御剣　信は、狩魔に勝つことで、
ヤツのやり方を否定しようとした。
To beat him, Gregory
Edgeworth tried to call
attention to his methods.

<Maya>
そ‥‥それで？
And...?

<Grossberg>
負けたよ。
He lost.

そして、死んだのぢゃ。
‥‥失意のまま、な。
And died in despair,
as it were.

<Maya>
そうなんですか‥‥。
I see...




<Grossberg>
御剣　信が殺害されて、
１人の霊媒師が呼ばれた。
When Gregory Edgeworth was
killed, the police called
on a spirit medium.

あんたのお母さん‥‥
綾里　舞子ぢゃよ。
That was your mother,
Misty Fey.

< >
『私、御剣　信を殺したのは‥‥』
"I am Gregory Edgeworth...
I have been killed..."

『私を撃ったのは、
　法廷係官の、灰根　高太郎‥‥』
"The one who shot me...
was the bailiff...
Yanni Yogi."

<Grossberg>
‥‥しかし、灰根は無実ぢゃった。
Yet Yogi was found innocent.

<Maya>
おかあさん、そのせいで‥‥
出て行っちゃったんだ‥‥。
That's when my mother left us.

“インチキだ”って、
みんなから言われて‥‥。
Everyone called her a fraud.

<Grossberg>
そう。みんな、そう思った。
綾里　舞子はインチキだ、と。
That's right. Everyone thought
she was, you see.

‥‥ぢゃが‥‥今、思えば‥‥
Yet... now that I think about
it.

ウソをついたのは、御剣　信の霊
だったのではないだろうか？
It seems the one who lied
was Gregory Edgeworth's
ghost...

御剣　信は、知っていたのぢゃ。
本当は、誰が自分を撃ったのかを。
Gregory Edgeworth must have
known who shot him.

<Phoenix>
‥‥まさか‥‥
I don't believe it...

御剣　怜侍を‥‥
自分の息子を守るために、
So you're saying he falsified
his "testimony"?

偽証したって言うんですか？
御剣のオヤジが‥‥！
That Edgeworth's dad lied to
protect his son...?

<Grossberg>
‥‥可能性の話ぢゃ‥‥。
It's only a possibility,
mind you.

しかし。否定はできん。
But... a possibility
nonetheless.




<Grossberg>
この手紙を書いたのが狩魔ならば、
ヤツは当然、知っておるはずぢゃ。
If it truly was von Karma
who wrote this letter, then
he would know the truth.

御剣　怜侍が、あやまって父親を
殺害してしまったということを。
He would know that Miles
Edgeworth had accidentally
killed his own father.

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

<Grossberg>
おそらく明日の法廷で、狩魔は
そのことを持ち出すぢゃろう。
He'll say as much tomorrow
in court, I should think.

御剣　怜侍に“有罪”を
認めさせるために‥‥な。
He'll press the point until
the court finds Miles
Edgeworth "guilty."

<Phoenix>
そ‥‥そんな‥‥。
Oh no!

<Maya>
でも、でも。カルマ検事がなぜ、
御剣検事のことを知ってるの！
B-but how could von Karma
know about Mr. Edgeworth's
past like that?

御剣検事自身、“悪夢”だって
思っていたのに‥‥。
Even Mr. Edgeworth thought
it was just a nightmare!

<Grossberg>
‥‥たしかに‥‥
それは、わからない。
Hmm...
That, I do not know.

しかし。ヤツはカンペキで、
‥‥そして、執念ぶかい。
Yet I do know that von Karma
is both persistent...
and a perfectionist.

御剣　信に対する憎しみを、息子に
ぶつけるつもりかもしれん‥‥。
He may be seeking to satisfy
a grudge against Gregory
Edgeworth by hurting his son.

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうことですか‥‥？
What do you mean?

<Grossberg>
‥‥１５年前‥‥。
It was fifteen years ago...

狩魔は、たしかに
弁護士・御剣　信に勝利した。
von Karma met Gregory
Edgeworth in court, and
von Karma did win...

しかし‥‥、狩魔も、
無傷ではすまなかったのぢゃ。
But he didn't make it
through the trial unscarred.




<Phoenix>
御剣のオヤジと狩魔の
勝負って‥‥どうだったんですか？
What happened in the trial
between Edgeworth's dad
and von Karma?

<Grossberg>
判決は“有罪”‥‥
狩魔の勝利ぢゃった。
von Karma got the "guilty"
verdict he wanted. He won
the trial.

しかし、御剣　信の告発によって、
狩魔の提出した証拠に‥‥、
But Gregory Edgeworth accused
von Karma of faulty evidence.

一部、不正なものがあったことが
立証されたのぢゃ。
And though he lost the trial,
Mr. Edgeworth's accusation
stood.

<Maya>
不正な証拠‥‥。
Faulty evidence?

<Grossberg>
狩魔は、検事生活でただ一度の
処罰を受けた‥‥。
It was the only penalty
von Karma has ever received in
his career as a prosecutor.

御剣　信は、狩魔のカンペキな
経歴に、キズをつけたのぢゃよ。
Gregory Edgeworth dealt a blow
to his perfect trial record.

<Maya>
へええ‥‥。
Wow.

<Grossberg>
そのコトが、よほどショック
だったのぢゃろう‥‥
It must have been quite
a shock for von Karma.

狩魔検事は、その日から数ヶ月、
休暇をとったほどぢゃ。
He took a vacation for
several months after that,
you see.

<Phoenix>
休暇を‥‥？
A vacation...?

<Grossberg>
長い検事生活で、狩魔が
“休暇”をとったのは、
Yes, an unusual event
for the man.

それが最初で‥‥そして、
最後ぢゃったよ。
That was the first, and the
last vacation he's taken in
his many years of prosecuting.

<Maya>
えー！　
お休みしないんですか？
Really!?
He doesn't take vacations!?

海とか、山とか‥‥
それに、ヨーロッパとか！
Like... go to the sea,
or, uh, to the mountains?

<Maya>
Don't tell me he's never been
to Europe!?

<Phoenix>
なんだよ、そのよくわからない
休暇のイメージは。
You have strange ideas
about vacations, Maya.

<Grossberg>
‥‥とにかく。
In any case...

狩魔が休暇をとったのは、
そのときだけぢゃ。
That was the only time he
took a vacation from work.

それだけ、くやしかったの
ぢゃろう‥‥。
I believe the penalty upset
him quite a lot.

<Phoenix>
（でも‥‥）
(Odd... If he wanted to
keep a perfect record
so badly...)

（カンペキな経歴を残したいなら、
　それで休むかな‥‥？）
(why would he take such
a long vacation?)




<Grossberg>
‥‥ほほお。
それが、問題の手紙か‥‥。
Oh ho!
So this is the letter?

たしかに、
灰根はこのとおりに動いて、
It does seem that Yogi was
following this letter...

生倉を殺害したんぢゃろう。
when he killed Hammond.

<Maya>
でも‥‥なぜ生倉弁護士を‥‥？
But, why kill Robert Hammond?

<Grossberg>
‥‥生倉は
ウデの立つ弁護士ぢゃったが‥‥
Hammond was a skilled
defense attorney.

ヤツは依頼人のためではなく、
自分のために弁護をしておった。
But... he defended clients
not for their sake, but
for his own.

<Phoenix>
“自分のため”‥‥？
Huh? His own sake?

<Grossberg>
ヤツは、自分の依頼人を
信じようとはしなかった。
He never trusted his
clients, that one.

信じていたのは、
自分のウデのみぢゃ。
The only thing he trusted
was his own ability.

<Maya>
でも、結果がムザイなら、
同じなんじゃあ‥‥？
But, he got his client
found innocent. So why
should it matter?

<Grossberg>
違うんぢゃよ。
‥‥それはもう、全然な。
Actually, my dear, it's
quite different.

生倉は、自分のために
ムザイ判決を勝ちとった。
He won that innocent verdict
for no one but himself.

その結果、灰根は社会的に
抹殺されてしまったのぢゃ。
Yogi was a free man, but
socially, he was ruined.

<Phoenix>
（どういうことだ‥‥？）
(Huh...?)

<Grossberg>
‥‥チミにも、
今にわかるぢゃろう。
You'll understand soon
enough.

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

はて。
Wait!

<Phoenix>
どうしました？
What is it?

<Grossberg>
この手紙‥‥
この、文字じゃが。
This letter...

見たことがある。この筆跡。
‥‥とおいムカシ、どこかで。
I've seen this handwriting
somewhere before... a long
time ago!

いったい、
誰の字ぢゃったかな‥‥。
Whose handwriting was
this...?




<Grossberg>
チミ、心当りはないかね。
この手紙、誰が書いたか‥‥？
Do you have any idea
who wrote this?




<Phoenix>
御剣　怜侍ですか？
Miles Edgeworth?

<Grossberg>
な、な、なんと！
Wh-wh-whaaat!?

彼がなんのため、こんなものを
書くのぢゃ！
Why in heavens would he
write something like this!?

この手紙は、御剣　怜侍を
おとしいれるためのモノぢゃろが！
Why, this letter is an
attempt to destroy Miles!

もっと、よく考えて
しゃべるんぢゃ！　ヒヨっ子め！
Think before you speak,
greenhorn!

<Phoenix>
（大目玉をくらってしまった‥‥）
(Uh oh. He's angry.)

<Grossberg>
もう一度、聞くぞ。
Think again!


<Phoenix>
灰根　高太郎ではないでしょうか？
Maybe it was Yanni Yogi?

<Grossberg>
灰根　高太郎ぢゃと？
Yanni Yogi!?

‥‥彼が、自分自身に手紙を書き、
自分でそれを実行したと？
You claim he wrote himself
this letter... then followed
his own instructions?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥そ、そうなりますね。
Uh... Yeah, I guess that
would be what happened.

<Grossberg>
なんぢゃ、灰根という男は
２重人格者なのかの？
Harumph! Perhaps you think
Mr. Yogi has a split-
personality, hmm?

<Phoenix>
‥‥可能性は、
あると思いますけど‥‥。
I think that's definitely
a possibility, yes...

<Grossberg>
‥‥ふうん‥‥。
Hmm...

いや。違うの。ワシは、灰根という
男のことを知らん。
No, I think not. I do not
know this Yogi, in any case.

だから、ヤツの字に見おぼえが
あるワケがない。
There's no way I would
recognize his handwriting.

<Phoenix>
はあ、なるほど‥‥。
Oh, right...

<Grossberg>
はあ、ぢゃない。
‥‥もう一度、聞くぞ。
Yes, Wright.
I'll ask you again.


<Phoenix>
もしかして、狩魔　豪ですか？
Hmm... could it be
Manfred von Karma?

<Grossberg>
カルマ？　なんでここに、
ヤツの名前が出てくるんぢゃ？
von Karma? Why would he have
something to do with this?

<Phoenix>
いや、なんで、と言われても‥‥。
Um, well, I'm not sure...

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ん？
‥‥カルマ‥‥。
Hmm?
von Karma... von Karma...

そ、そうぢゃ。
W-wait! You're right, my boy!

たしかに‥‥これは、
狩魔検事の字ぢゃ！
This is von Karma's handwriting,
I'm sure of it!

ムカシ、法廷の書類でよく見た‥‥
彼の字ぢゃよ！
I used to see it all the
time on court reports...

<Maya>
ええええっ！
‥‥じゃ、じゃあ‥‥！
Whaaaaaat!?
But... but that means...!

灰根さんに、殺人の指示を
送ったのは‥‥
Th-the one who told
Mr. Yogi to kill was...

<Grossberg>
‥‥そう。
狩魔　豪‥‥ということになる。
Correct.
Manfred von Karma, himself!

<Phoenix>
ど‥‥どういうことだ‥‥！
What does this mean, then?

なぜ‥‥狩魔検事が、御剣を‥‥？
Why would von Karma want
to frame Edgeworth...?




<Grossberg>
間違いない。この手紙は、
狩魔が書いたものぢゃ。
No doubt about it, this
is von Karma's handwriting.

灰根はこのとおりに動いて、
生倉を殺害したんぢゃろう。
Yogi was following von Karma's
instructions when he killed
Hammond.




‥‥‥‥
...

問題は‥‥。
Now, there's only one
question left.

なぜ、狩魔が今になって、
Why did von Karma write
this?

こんな手紙を書いたか、
ぢゃな‥‥。
And why now?




<Grossberg>
とりあえず、撃っているのが
御剣クンでなくて、何よりぢゃ。
In any case, it's good that
the one shooting isn't Miles.

<Phoenix>
あたりまえですよ！
You bet it's good!

（犯人のヤツ‥‥）
(I can't believe the fiendish
planning that went into this
murder...)

（こんな手のこんだ
　ワナを考えるなんて‥‥）
(And we almost fell right
into his trap!)

<Maya>
ヒドいヤツだよね！
What a creep!




<Grossberg>
美しいヒトぢゃったよ。
Ah, she was a beautiful
woman...

‥‥まこと、スマナイことを
したもんぢゃ‥‥。
I'm truly sorry about
what I did...

<Maya>
‥‥？
Huh?

どうしてセンセイが
あやまるんですか‥‥？
Sorry about what?

<Grossberg>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（ぼくが口を挟むところじゃ
　ないな‥‥）
(I think I'll stay out
of this one...)




<Grossberg>
この事件が起こったのが、
１５年前の明日‥‥。
This incident took place
15 years ago tomorrow.

明日が終わったとき、
この事件も終わるんぢゃよ。
So tomorrow will see the
completion of not one,
but two trials.

“時効”という
ベンリなコトバによってな。
All thanks to the statute of
limitations.

‥‥しかし。
However...

事件は終わることなどない。
‥‥たとえ、カイケツしてもぢゃ。
I'm afraid the damage the DL-6
Incident has done will never
be eased...




<Grossberg>
御剣　信‥‥か。
Gregory Edgeworth...?

優秀なオトコぢゃった。
‥‥ザンネンぢゃよ。
He was a gifted man.
His death was truly a loss.

生きていれば、今、狩魔は
どうなっていたことか‥‥。
I wonder what would have
become of von Karma were
he alive...




<Grossberg>
毎度まいどスマンが‥‥
Er... quite sorry.

特に思い当たることは
ないようぢゃ‥‥。
I have nothing to say
concerning that.




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
管理人の小屋
December 27
Caretaker's Shack

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
‥‥誰もいないね。
Nobody's home.

<Parrot>
“オハヨー、オハヨー”
"Hello! Hello!"
*squawk*

<Maya>
あっ！　サユリさんだ！
Hey! It's Polly!

あなたのご主人、
どこへ行っちゃったのかな‥‥。
I wonder where your
owner's gone, Polly?

<Parrot>
“オハヨー、オハヨー”
"Hello! Hello!"
*squawk*

<Maya>
この子、置いていくなんて
ヒドいよね！
I can't believe he'd run
off and leave his poor
parrot to fend for herself!

<Parrot>
“オハヨー、オハヨー”
"Hello! Hello!"
*squawk*




<Maya>
サユリさん、あたしたちが
引きとろうか。
Maybe I should take
care of Polly, Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥勝手につれていっちゃ
まずいよ。
You probably shouldn't just
kidnap her.

警察の人たちも、こいつのことは
知ってるだろうから、
The police know about her
anyway.

なんとかしてくれるって。
I'm sure they'll do something.

<Maya>
‥‥ううう。
Well... okay...

ゴメンね。サユリさん。
ダメだって。なるほどくんが。
Sorry, Polly.
He says I can't take you.

<Phoenix>
（ワルモノにされてしまった）
(Great, now the bird's
going to hate me.)




<Maya>
そういえばさ、なるほどくん。
That reminds me, Nick!

この金庫の番号、サユリさんが
知ってるんだよね。
Polly here knows the number
to the safe, right?

<Phoenix>
ああ。そうだったね。
Yeah, that's right.

<Maya>
サユリさん。金庫の番号は？
Polly, what's the number
to the safe?

<Parrot>
“‥‥‥‥１２２８”
"1228"!
*squawk*

<Maya>
ねえねえ、開けてみようよ。
Let's open it, Nick!
C'mon!

<Phoenix>
お金なんか入ってないと思うよ。
I'm sure there isn't any
money in there.

<Maya>
ううう‥‥。
Aww...

でもさ。
But, hey!

カギをかけているぐらいだから、
それなりのものが入ってるんだよ。
He keeps it locked, right?
So there must be something
of value in there!

<Phoenix>
そうかなあ‥‥。
I'm not so sure...

<Maya>
ほらほら、なるほどくん。
開ける開ける。
Okay, Nick, let's see
what's in there!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥何か手がかりが入ってるかも
　しれないからな‥‥）
(I guess there might be
a clue or two...)

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

手紙が１通、入ってるだけだ。
The only thing in here
is a letter.

<Maya>
て、手紙？
A letter?

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥

つまんないの。
Aww... boring!

<Phoenix>
（あて名も、差し出し人の
　名前もない）
(Hmm... There's no name or
signature on this thing.)

（手書きの、きちょうめんな文字が
　きれいに並んでいる‥‥）
(It's handwritten in very
precise, clear letters...)

　　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

　《御剣　怜侍に復讐せよ‥‥》
"Get your revenge on
Miles Edgeworth..."

‥‥‥‥ミツルギだと！
Edgeworth!

<Maya>
なな、なるほどくん‥‥
なんで、御剣検事の名前が‥‥？
N-N-Nick! Why would
Mr. Edgeworth's name
be on here...?

<Phoenix>
し、知らないよ！
‥‥とにかく、読んでみるぞ。
How should I know!?
I'm going to read the
whole thing...!

< >
　《御剣　怜侍に復讐せよ‥‥》
"Get your revenge on
Miles Edgeworth..."

　《これが、最後のチャンスだ》
It also says: "This is your
last chance!"

《お前の人生を破滅させた２人の
　男に、今こそ復讐するのだ》
"Now is your time to get
revenge on the two men
who ruined your life!"

　　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（ここから、今回の殺人事件の
　計画が、びっしり書かれている）
(The rest of the letter goes
on to describe the murder
plot in detail!)

（生倉弁護士を殺害して、
　その罪を御剣に着せる方法‥‥）
(How to kill Robert Hammond,
and frame Edgeworth...)

（御剣を呼び出し、ボートに乗り、
　ピストルを２度、撃つ‥‥）
(...Calling Edgeworth out
to the lake, getting on the
boat... firing twice!)

（今日の法廷で、ぼくが苦しまぎれ
　に説明したとおりのやり方が）
(This is exactly what I 
figured out today in court!)

（カンペキに書かれている‥‥）
(It's all here... in perfect
detail!)

　　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
ど‥‥どういうこと？
なるほどくん‥‥。
What do you think it means,
Nick?

<Phoenix>
よくわからないけど、
どうやら、管理人のオジさん‥‥、
I don't know... but it looks
like these are instructions
for that caretaker.

この手紙の指示どおりに動いて、
生倉弁護士を‥‥。
When he killed Robert Hammond
and called out Edgeworth,
he was following instructions!

<Maya>
でも、その手紙‥‥。
いったい、誰が？
But who could have written
that letter?

それに、御剣　怜侍に復讐せよ、
って‥‥どういう意味なの？
And... what does it mean,
to "get revenge on Miles
Edgeworth"...?

<Phoenix>
あのなあ。ぼくにわかるワケ
ないだろ。
Look, I don't know, okay?

‥‥でも。
But one thing's for
certain.

どうやらこの手紙は
スゴい手がかりになりそうだな。
This letter is an
amazing clue!

< >
《金庫の中の手紙》を、
法廷記録にそっと挟んだ。
Added Letter from the Safe
to the Court Record.




<Phoenix>
もう、金庫の中には
何も入っていないぞ。
There's nothing left
in the safe.

<Maya>
でも、オジさん、なんでこの手紙を
持って行かなかったのかな？
I wonder why the caretaker
didn't take the letter
with him?

<Phoenix>
あわてて逃げたからだろ？
もどってきたようすもないし‥‥。
He left in a hurry, right?
I don't think he even came
back here after the trial.




< >
１２月２７日　某時刻
警察署内・資料室
December 27
Police Department
Records Room

<Maya>
‥‥あいかわらず、
ホコリっぽいねー。
Dusty as always!

<Phoenix>
あいかわらずも何も、
昨日来たばっかりだからなあ。
We were only here just
yesterday. I'm sure they just
haven't had time to clean...

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Maya>
どうしたの？　なるほどくん？
What's wrong, Nick?

<Phoenix>
‥‥いや。
いないな、って思って。
Nothing. I was just noticing
that he isn't here.

狩魔検事‥‥。
von Karma...




<Maya>
あれ。ここだけ、開けっぱなしに
なってるよ‥‥。
Huh? One of the drawers
here is open.

<Phoenix>
最近、開けたみたいだね。
Someone must have been
looking in it recently.

<Maya>
《未解決事件・証拠物件》って
ラベルに書いてある‥‥。
The label says,
"Unsolved Cases: Evidence"

<Phoenix>
（《未解決事件》‥‥か）
Hmm... "Unsolved cases"?

<Maya>
なるほどくん！
Nick!

《ＤＬ６号事件》のケースだけ、
カラっぽだよ！
The file for DL-6... it's
completely empty!

<Phoenix>
な‥‥なんだって！
Wh-what!?

<Karma>
‥‥そこで何をしている！
What are you doing in here!

<Maya>
きゃあっ！
Eeek!

かか、かるま検事‥‥。
v-v-von Karma!

<Karma>
‥‥キサマ‥‥
You...!

‥‥‥‥
...

なぜ、ワガハイの名を
知っている‥‥？
How do you know my name?

<Maya>
え。
Huh?

<Karma>
どこかで会ったことが？
Have we met?

<Maya>
なな、ナニ言ってるんですか！
W-w-what are you saying!?

最近おなじみの
カオじゃないですか！
We see each other every
day, don't we?

あたしたち、御剣　怜侍の
弁護士ですよ！
We're Miles Edgeworth's
defense team!

<Karma>
‥‥弁護士‥‥？
Defense team...?

これはシツレイ。
Ahem. I beg your pardon, you
see, I rarely remember defense
attorneys.

弁護士など、目に入らない
ちっぽけな存在なものでな‥‥。
They are like bugs to
me. Needless things,
to be crushed.

<Phoenix>
（うーん‥‥さすが御剣の
　師匠だな‥‥）
(I can see how this guy
was Edgeworth's mentor.)




<Phoenix>
大きな引き出しが
開きっぱなしになっている。
This large drawer is
half-open.

引き出しのラベルの文字は、
《未解決事件・証拠物件》
The label on the drawer reads:
"Unsolved Cases: Evidence."

大小の、ガラクタにしか見えない
証拠が、ひしめいている。
All the stuff in here
looks like random junk.

ＤＬ６号事件の証拠品だけ、
持ち出されている。
Only the evidence for the
DL-6 Incident is missing.

‥‥もちろん、狩魔検事だろう。
I can guess who took it,
too. von Karma.




<Maya>
あ、あの‥‥御剣検事って、
お弟子さんなんですよね‥‥？
Uh, umm... Mr. Edgeworth
was your student, right?

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥アマさが抜けない
ロマンチストだ。
A romanticist who could
never shed that veneer
of amateurism.

父親と同じだ。
‥‥一流にはなれん。
Just like his father.
Always second rate.

<Phoenix>
狩魔検事。
Mr. von Karma...

あなたは、御剣　信弁護士を
ウラんでいますよね？
You had an axe to grind with
Mr. Gregory Edgeworth, didn't
you?

<Karma>
私が？　弁護士ごときを？
‥‥なぜだ？
Me? A grudge against a mere
defense attorney? Why?

<Phoenix>
あなたのカンペキな経歴に
キズをつけたからですよ。
Because he dealt a blow to
your otherwise perfect trial
record?

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥フン。
Hmph.

<Phoenix>
それなのに、なぜ。
So you did... but what I
don't get is...

御剣　怜侍を、検事として
ここまで育てたんですか？
Why did you take his son
under your wing afterwards?

憎いカタキのムスコなのに‥‥。
The son of your most
bitter rival?

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

キサマの知ったことではない。
That, my dear attorney,
is none of your business.




<Karma>
明日の法廷は、最終日だ。
Tomorrow will be the last
day of this trial.

‥‥ひさしぶりだ。最終日まで
もちこたえた弁護士は。
It's been a while since I've
had a defense attorney last
this long.

‥‥しかし、結果は変わらない。
Still, you will lose
in the end.

御剣　怜侍は明日、自らの
罪を認めることになるだろう。
Miles Edgeworth will admit
his own guilt.

<Phoenix>
“１５年前”の罪ですか‥‥？
His guilt of 15 years ago,
you mean?

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

感心な勉強家だな。
You're quite the researcher.

そこまで調べたのなら、
キサマにもわかるだろう。
If you've done your homework
so well, then certainly,
you must understand.

明日の法廷で、御剣　怜侍が
何を語るかを‥‥。
You know what Miles Edgeworth
will tell the court tomorrow.

<Phoenix>
（やはり‥‥）
(We were right...)

（明日の事件で、コイツは
　ＤＬ６号事件のことを‥‥）
(So von Karma is going to
bring up DL-6 in court
tomorrow.)




<Phoenix>
狩魔検事。
‥‥これを見てください。
Mr. von Karma,
have a look at this.

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
あなただったんですね‥‥。
This was you, wasn't it?

灰根　高太郎に、殺人の
指示を送ったのは‥‥。
You instructed Yanni Yogi
to commit murder.

<Karma>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

灰根　高太郎‥‥。
Yanni Yogi...

あの男を、その名で呼ぶのを
聞くのは、何年ぶりだ‥‥。
How many years has it been
since I've heard him called
by that name.

‥‥バカな男だ。
He's a fool.

読んだら、必ず焼き捨てるよう
書いておいたのに‥‥。
I told him to burn it after
he read it.

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥！
...!

み‥‥みとめるんですね！
S-so you admit it!

あなたが‥‥あなたが、
灰根さんに、この手紙を‥‥！
You... you wrote Mr. Yogi
this letter!

<Karma>
‥‥さて、弁護士。
Yes, my dear defense
attorney.

わざわざ、持ってきてくれて
ありがとう。
Thank you for taking the
trouble to bring it to me.

おかげで、よけいな労力を
はらわずにすんだよ‥‥。
You've saved me from a lot
of needless hassle.

<Phoenix>
な‥‥なんだと！
Wh-what!?

<Maya>
な‥‥なるほどくん‥‥。
な、なに、あれ‥‥？
N-Nick!
What is that thing!?

<Phoenix>
ス‥‥スタンガンだよ。
護身用の武器だ。
A stun gun.
For self defense... usually.

<Karma>
そのとおり。
Indeed.

６０万ボルトの火花が
キサマの身体にハジける‥‥。
600,000 volts will course
through your body like a dog
touching an electric fence.

<Phoenix>
ろ‥‥ろくじゅうまん‥‥。
Six hundred thous...!?

<Karma>
心配はいらない。
死にはしないからな‥‥たぶん。
Oh, don't worry.
People don't die from it,
usually.

さあ。
わたしてもらおうか、手紙を。
Now, give me the letter.

<Phoenix>
（く‥‥くそ‥‥）
(No!!!)

<Maya>
やめてええええええええええっ
Nooooooooooo!

<Karma>
うおッ！　な、何をするかッ！
Whoa! What are you--!?

<Maya>
な、なるほどくん、逃げて‥‥！
N-Nick! Run!!!

きゃああああっ！
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!

<Phoenix>
ま‥‥真宵ちゃん！
M-Maya!

<Karma>
手こずらせおって！
Out of my way!

<Phoenix>
うわああああっ！
Waaaaaaaaaaaah!

< >
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
（‥‥やられた‥‥）
(Ugh... He got us.)

（手紙‥‥‥‥もちろん、
　うばわれちまったなあ‥‥）
(The letter's... gone,
of course.)

（ＤＬ６号事件の証拠品も
　持って行かれて‥‥）
(And he took the DL-6
evidence... all of it.)

（手がかりはゼロ、か‥‥）
(Back to having no clues.)

（‥‥そうだ‥‥）
(Wait... Maya jumped first.)

（真宵ちゃんは、
　だいじょうぶかな‥‥）
(Maya...! Is she okay?)

（‥‥‥‥‥‥）
(...)

ま‥‥真宵ちゃん！
Ma...Maya!

<Maya>
　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
おい！　しっかりしてくれよ！
Maya! Open your eyes!

<Maya>
　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん！
Maya!

<Maya>
　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥とられちゃった？　手紙‥‥
The letter!
Did he take it?

<Phoenix>
え‥‥あ、ああ。
それより、だいじょうぶ‥‥？
Huh!? Oh... yeah.
A-are you okay!?

<Maya>
　　　‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

‥‥ホント‥‥ダメだね‥‥。
I... I couldn't stop him.

イセイよく飛びかかっても、
１発でキゼツしちゃって‥‥。
I jumped as fast as I could,
but one shot from that thing
knocked me out cold.

あたしなんて‥‥
I'm useless.

お姉ちゃんを呼ぶことしか
能がない、ヤク立たずなのに‥‥
I'm no good as a lawyer, or
a medium! I can't even call
my sister.

こんな‥‥一番ダイジなときに、
それもできない。
Not even now, when we need
her the most.

このまま‥‥目がさめなけりゃ
よかったな‥‥。
I wish I hadn't woken up
at all.

<Phoenix>
真宵ちゃん！
Maya!

（クソッ！　なんとかして
　あげられないのか‥‥！）
(Grr! There has to be some
way I can help her!)

（とにかく、自信を回復
　させる方法を探すしかないな‥）
(I'd better do something about
her self-confidence, first.)

‥‥？
...?

（真宵ちゃん‥‥
　何か、にぎりしめているぞ）
(Maya...
She's holding something!)

（これは‥‥弾丸？）
(What is that? A bullet?)

《ＤＬ６号事件　証拠品７号
　御剣　信の心臓部より摘出》
"DL-6 Incident, Evidence No. 7
Taken from the heart of
Gregory Edgeworth."

そうか‥‥。
I remember...

狩魔検事に飛びかかったとき、
夢中でこれをつかんだんだな‥‥。
von Karma was holding this
when Maya jumped him.

< >
《ＤＬ６号事件の弾丸》を、
ポケットにしまった。
Put DL-6 Bullet in pocket.

<Phoenix>
（‥‥証明してやるよ、
　真宵ちゃん）
(I'll prove it to you,
Maya.)

（きみは、
　役立たずじゃない‥‥）
(You're most definitely
not useless!)

（何もかも、証明してやる。
　‥‥最後の法廷で‥‥！）
(I'll prove it to you
in court tomorrow!)


　　　　　　　　　　　　　つづく
              To be continued.


<Karma>
‥‥おろかな。
Fool.

検事が、弁護士に対して
情報を与えると思うか‥‥。
You think I, a prosecutor,
would give you, a defense
attorney, information? Bah!

<Maya>
（けち‥‥！）
(Creep!)




<Phoenix>
“ひょうたん湖　自然公園”
と書いてある。
The sign says "Gourd Lake
Nature Park."

休日は、家族づれでにぎわう、
都会のオアシスといったところだ。
This place is full of families
picnicking on the weekend.

<Maya>
でも、滝はないんだよね。
But... no waterfall.

<Phoenix>
都会の人間は、
修行はしないからね。
Not many picnickers come here
for spiritual training, Maya.




<Phoenix>
葉を落とした木々に、
冬の訪れを感じる今日このごろ。
I feel winter's chill from the
bare leaf trees today...

うーん。冬は人を
詩人にさせるなあ。
*sigh*
What is it about winter that
turns people into poets?

<Maya>
ねー、サムいよなるほどくん。
早くどこか行こうよ。
I don't know, but my toes
are starting to feel numb.

<Phoenix>
（サムいって、ぼくの詩か？）
(Yes... my poetry has that
effect on some people.)




<Maya>
こーんなにサムいのに、ベンチに
座る人、いないよねー。
No one's going to sit
here on a cold day like
today.

まあ、おマンジュウがあれば
別だけどさ。
Well, unless they were
eating a Samurai Dog!

<Phoenix>
（マンジュウがあるのとないのとで
　状況はどう変わるのだろう？）
(How would that change
the temperature, I wonder?)

<Maya>
‥‥‥‥？
なに、むずかしいカオしてるの？
...?
You seem troubled, Nick.

<Phoenix>
べ、べつに‥‥。
N-no, who? Me?




<Phoenix>
妙に目立たない道しるべが
立っている。
Huh... I almost didn't see
that signpost.

“左‥‥ボートのりば”
“右‥‥公園出口”
"Left - Boat Docks"
"Right - Exit"




<Maya>
それにしても、メーワクな
湖だね、ひょうたん湖。
This lake sure likes to cause
problems, doesn't it.

<Phoenix>
何が？
Huh?

<Maya>
ここで起こったこと、
ぜーんぶウソだったもんね。
I mean, everything that
happened here turned out
to be a lie!

ヒョッシーもウソ、御剣検事の
殺人容疑もウソ。
Gourdy was a lie, and the
charges against Mr. Edgeworth
were all lies.

<Phoenix>
そうだなあ。
I guess you're right.

<Maya>
‥‥まあ、ウソでよかったけどね。
I mean, I'm glad the charges
were all lies, but still.




<Phoenix>
矢張のヤツ、今日は
お休みか‥‥。
Guess Larry has today off.

<Maya>
浮かれてるからね。
‥‥御剣検事を助けて。
He was pretty happy about
saving Mr. Edgeworth.

<Phoenix>
たしかに‥‥。アイツには
カンシャしなきゃな。
True. We owe him big.




<Phoenix>
ゴミは入っていない。
A trash can with no trash.

この公園は、管理のよさが
ウリだからな‥‥。
At least the place
is well maintained.




<Phoenix>
貸しボート屋の管理小屋だ。
人のケハイはない。
The boat rental shop.
Doesn't look like anyone
is around.

<Maya>
管理人のオジさん、
やっぱり逃げちゃったのかな‥‥。
The caretaker must have
run for the hills, huh?

<Phoenix>
ああ、たぶんね‥‥。
Yeah, looks like it.

<Maya>
いい人そうに
見えたのになあ‥‥。
He didn't seem like
a bad person...




<Phoenix>
このシゲミの奥は、
森になっている。
There's a forest here
beyond these bushes.

<Maya>
なるほどくん！　森の中、
誰かいるみたいだよ！
Nick! The forest!
There's someone in there!

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

ホントだ。‥‥何人もの
警官のすがたが見える。
You're right. There's a few
policemen in there.

<Maya>
あのオジさんを探してるんだ。
They must be looking for
the caretaker!

<Phoenix>
タイヘンだな‥‥。
Good luck...




<Phoenix>
湖の上に、ボートが浮かんでいる。
There are some boats floating
at the dock.

殺人事件は、このボートの上で
起こったわけか‥‥。
The murder took place in
a boat from this dock...

実際に事件が起こったボートは、
警察が持ち帰ったようだ。
Apparently, the police took
away the actual boat that
was used that night.

ボートが並んでいる場所に、
１そうぶんのスペースが空いてる。
Indeed, there's space for
one more boat at the dock.




<Phoenix>
当然のことながら、
こたつは冷えている。
Hmm. Everything's cold.
Looks like he didn't turn
his heater on.

オジさん、ここには帰って
きていないようだ。
I guess he hasn't been
back here since the trial.




<Maya>
このキッチン、
あんまり使ってないみたい。
It doesn't look like he
used this kitchen much.

<Phoenix>
そうだね。
You're right.

<Maya>
おソバ屋さんていうの、
ウソだったのかな、やっぱり。
I guess the whole pasta
restaurant thing was a lie.

<Phoenix>
‥‥本当だった方が
びっくりするけどなあ。
What, you thought he
was telling the truth!?




<Maya>
あのさ、なるほどくん。
Say, Nick.

魚拓って、“こんな大きいサカナを
釣ったぞ！”っていうことでしょ？
Don't people usually put
pictures of fish up on the
wall to boast about them?

<Phoenix>
よくわからないけど、たしかに
ジマンみたいなもんだろうね。
Uh, yeah, I guess so. You mean
pictures of the fish they
caught, right?

<Maya>
でもさ。なんか、セコいサカナ
ばっかりだよ、このへん。
Right... but don't all the
fish on the wall here look
really puny to you?

<Phoenix>
‥‥まあ、“ジマン”てのは、
“ジコマンゾク”の略だからね。
Well, you know what they
say...

<Phoenix>
"You shoulda seen the one
that got away!"

<Maya>
へええ！　‥‥そうなんだ。
Except the one that got away
from us was the caretaker!
And we did see him!

<Phoenix>
（感心されても困るけど‥‥）
(Why do I feel like we're
having two different
conversations here?)




<Maya>
‥‥あッ！
Aah!

<Phoenix>
ど、どうした？
W-what's wrong?

<Maya>
‥‥え？　う、ううん。
な、なんでもない‥‥。
Huh? Oh...
N-never mind.

<Phoenix>
なんだよ。気になるなあ。
What? Tell me!

<Maya>
あのね。テレビ見たら
思い出したんだけど‥‥、
Just, when I saw the TV,
I remembered...

今週、ヒメサマンの
スペシャル番組があるな、って。
They're showing a 
Pink Princess special
this week...

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

なんだ。
Oh.

<Maya>
うう‥‥だから言いたく
なかったのに‥‥。
See? That's why I didn't
want to tell you.




<Phoenix>
高そうなツリザオだ。
That fishing pole looks
expensive.

<Maya>
イトノコ刑事に
持っていってあげようか。
Maybe we should bring
it to Detective Gumshoe.

<Phoenix>
いやいや、いくらなんでも
オジさんに悪いだろ？
Don't you think the caretaker
would mind?

<Maya>
じゃあさ。かわりに金属探知機を
置いておけばいいよ。
Well, we can just leave him
the metal detector in
exchange!

<Phoenix>
‥‥それは違うだろう。
Uh... maybe we'd better not.




<Phoenix>
警察のマスコットキャラクター
‥‥って、こんなんだったっけ？
Hey, is that the police
department's mascot...?

<Chief>
“タイホくん”だよ。
That's the "Blue Badger"!

ワシが考えて、ワシが作った。
ワシだけのマスコットさ。
It was my idea! I made it!
It's my mascot!

<Phoenix>
そ、そうなんですか。
I... see. How nice.

<Chief>
いよいよ明日、署長にプレゼンする
つもりだよ。
Tomorrow, I'll present him
before the department at last!

いかにこの“タイホくん”が
愛らしいかを、聞いてもらうんだ。
I'm going to make sure they
know how much people like
the Blue Badger!

<Phoenix>
‥‥がんばってください。
Um, good luck!







<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Police>
“たのむ！　考えなおしてくれ、
　ヨシコ‥‥”
"Please! Think about what
you're doing, Jolinda!"

“タカシまでつれていくなんて、
　あんまりだぜ‥‥！”
"Don't take my Tommy away
from me! No!"

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

離婚のシュラ場のイメージ・
トレーニングをしているようだ。
He must be doing image
training for a nasty
divorce argument.




<Phoenix>
刑事さんだろうか。
That must be one of the
detectives.

‥‥何やら、ひとりでぶつぶつ
つぶやいている。
He's mumbling something
to himself.

<Police>
“あの‥‥ごシュミは‥‥？”
"So, um, what are your
hobbies?"

“‥‥はあ。
　張り込みと尾行を少々‥‥”
"Well... I like to do
stake-outs now and then..."

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

お見合いのイメージ・トレーニング
をしているようだ。
He must be doing image
training for a first date.




<Phoenix>
刑事課の課長さんだろう。
This must be the chief
of the detectives here.

‥‥パソコンの画面を、
食いいるように見つめている。
He's glued to his computer
screen.

<Chief>
なにぃ‥‥！
な、なんということだ‥‥！
Wha...!?
Th-that's not possible!

昨日で、世界が終わっていただ
なんて‥‥
The world ended...
yesterday!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥くだらないホームページの
　予言を、真に受けてるみたいだ）
(He must be reading
predictions for the future
on someone's homepage.)




<Phoenix>
刑事たちの机がならんでいる。
These are the detectives'
desks.

パソコンに、資料。
‥‥思ったより片づいているな。
There are computers and files
on each one. Funny, they're a
lot tidier than I'd expect.

たぶん、あまり席にいることが
ないんだろう。
I guess the detectives don't
spend a lot of time at their
desks.




<Phoenix>
婦人警官がビシッと
敬礼している。
A poster of a female
police officer...

‥‥と思ったら、制服を着た
アイドルのグラビアだった。
Wait, no. That's the latest
"Babes in Uniform" calendar.
My bad.




<Phoenix>
ガラスケースの中には、
ファイルが並んでいるみたいだ。
It looks like there are files
inside this glass case.

ガラスに厚くホコリが
かぶっているから、よく見えない。
The case is so dusty I can't
see what's inside.

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
‥‥カギもかかってるよ。
Nick... it's locked.

<Phoenix>
大事な資料がしまってある
みたいだな‥‥。
They must keep important
case files in there.




<Phoenix>
このキャビネットには、
証拠品が保管されているようだ。
This cabinet is where they
keep evidence for current
cases.

あきらかに凶器とわかるものから、
“なんだこりゃ”的なものまで、
Some of the things are
obviously murder weapons
others... are question marks.

ガラクタにしか見えない証拠が
ひしめいている。
Most of it just looks like
random junk.

<Maya>
なるほどくん。
なあに、この洗濯バサミ？
Nick... what do you think
this clothespin is for?

<Phoenix>
だから、さわるなって。
‥‥いちおう、証拠品だから。
Don't touch that.
It's evidence...




<Phoenix>
事件の調書をまとめた
ファイルだ。
Here are files of collected
case reports.

‥‥それにしても、
ものすごい量だな‥‥。
There's quite a large
volume of reports here.

<Maya>
ふえー。‥‥これ、全部
事件のことが書いてあるの？
Wow... these are all
case reports!?

<Phoenix>
そうだよ。ここは、事件の墓場
みたいなもんだから。
Yeah. It's like a graveyard
of police cases.

<Maya>
お姉ちゃんの事件も、ここで
ホコリをかぶっていくんだね‥‥。
I guess my sister's case
report is in here too...
quietly gathering dust.




<Phoenix>
部屋の奥にも、ぎっしりファイルが
詰まった棚が並んでいる。
There are shelves stuffed
with case files in the back
of the room, too.

誰もなつかしむことのない、
事件の亡きがらたちだ。
Forgotten cases, rotting
away for eternity...

<Maya>
なるほどくん。早く
用事をすませちゃおうよ。
Nick, let's get what we
need and get out of here.

肺の中、まっクロに
なっちゃうよー！
All this dust is getting
to me!

