<Ema>
へえ‥‥バッジのウラって、
こうなってるんですね！
So this is what the back of
the badge looks like!

あたし、安全ピンだと
思ってました！
And I always thought it had a
safety pin!

<Phoenix>
バッジには、ナンバーが
刻まれているからね。
Each badge has a number carved
into it.

他の弁護士がつけることは
できないんだ。
That way, you can tell which
attorney it belongs to.

<Ema>
じゃあ、《ニセ弁護士あらわる！》
‥‥なんてコト、ないんですね。
You mean you couldn't lend
your badge to anyone?

<Phoenix>
すぐにバレるんじゃないかな。
ニセモノなんて。
No, I'd be found out right
away.

<Ema>
なーんだ。
つまんないなあ‥‥
Well that's no fun!




<Phoenix>
バッジのウラには、
ナンバーが刻まれている。
A number is engraved on the
back of the badge.

‥‥どうせなら、名前を
刻んでくれればいいのに‥‥
I wish they'd put my name on
it instead...







<Phoenix>
名前と、ＩＤナンバーが
書きこまれているね。
A name and ID number are
written here.

《捜査官：多田敷　道夫
　ＩＤ　：５８４２１８９》
"Detective Bruce Goodman,
ID# 5842189"

<Ema>
でも。どうして《ＩＤ》って
番号ばっかりなんでしょうね。
I wonder why they only use
numbers for IDs.

<Phoenix>
‥‥どういうこと？
What else would they use?

<Ema>
あたし。『ひらがな』だって、
人類の偉大な発明だと思うんです。
Letters, silly! They're the
reason we have a written
language in the first place!

<Phoenix>
はあ。
True...

<Ema>
《捜査官：多田敷　道夫
　ＩＤ　：ぬむろふへもこ》
"Detective: Bruce Goodman,
ID: YABADAB"

‥‥とか。どう思います？
See? Wouldn't that be better?

<Phoenix>
《ぬむろふへもこ》‥‥
なんか、おぼえやすいね。
"YABADAB"?
Well, it does have a certain
ring to it...

<Ema>
ですよね！　ですよね！
‥‥ふふん。
Exactly my point!
Tee-hee!

<Phoenix>
（ゴキゲンになった）
(It doesn't take much to
amuse her.)




<Phoenix>
名前と、ＩＤナンバーが
書きこまれている。
His name and ID number is
written on it.

《捜査官：多田敷　道夫
　ＩＤ　：５８４２１８９》
"Detective Bruce Goodman,
ID# 5842189"







<Ema>
‥‥被害者のヒトの血、
ですよね。
This must be the victim's
blood, right?

<Phoenix>
リンゴをむいてて、指を
切ったワケじゃなさそうだね。
Either that, or Edgeworth cut
himself peeling an apple.

それにしても、御剣のヤツ。
ブッソウなナイフを持ってるなあ。
What's Edgeworth doing with a
knife like this anyway?

<Ema>
週末は、ヤマにこもって
『サバイバル』してるのかも！
Hey! Maybe he spends his
weekends roughing it in the
wild!

<Phoenix>
たき火のそばに座って、
リンゴむいたりしてね。
Edgeworth? In the wild? I
think my fruit-peeling theory
is more likely.

<Ema>
もう！　御剣検事さんといえば、
もっとワイルドなイメージですっ！
Are you kidding? I always
pictured him as an
outdoorsman!

<Phoenix>
（そうかなあ‥‥）
(Now there's a scary
thought...)




<Phoenix>
被害者・多田敷　道夫の血液が
付着している。
The victim Bruce Goodman's
blood still remains on the
blade.

‥‥このナイフのニギリ‥‥
服の色と合わせているのかな。
I wonder if Edgeworth got
this knife because the
handle matches his clothes...?







<Ema>
こんなところに、金属の
プレートがハマってますよ！
Hey, check it out! There's a
metal plate here!

<Phoenix>
どうやら、歴代の受賞者の
名前が刻まれているみたいだ。
Hm. It looks like the names of
all the previous recipients
are engraved on it.

<Ema>
‥‥なんか、やたら同じヒトの
名前が並んでますね。
Wow. One guy's listed a bunch 
of times!

なんて読むんでしょうね、コレ。
えーと。《かり‥‥ま》かな？
"von Karma"... I guess he must
be a foreigner?

<Phoenix>
まあ‥‥
そんなトコじゃないかな。
Uh, yeah. That's probably it.

<Ema>
わあ！　すごいんですねー。
かりま検事さん。
Well wherever he's from, he
must have been an amazing
prosecutor!

一度、会ってみたいです！
かりま検事さんに。
I'd like to meet this Mr.
"von Karma" sometime!

<Phoenix>
（‥‥連呼されると、ちょっと
　おもしろいな。かりま検事）
(When she says it, his name
does have kind of a ring
to it...)




<Phoenix>
《検事・オブ・ザ・イヤー》
歴代の受賞者が刻まれている。
"King of Prosecutors."
The names of past recipients
are etched on the plate.

ならんでいる“狩魔　豪”の名前
‥‥なんか、ヒニクに見える。
Manfred von Karma's name
appears here too...
How ironic.







<Ema>
うわ。ジミなストラップですねー。
Man, what a boring strap!

<Phoenix>
いいんじゃないかな。
好きずきだし。
What's wrong with it?
Everyone has different tastes,
you know.

<Ema>
ちなみに。あたしのストラップ、
《小江戸剣士・ヒメサマン》です！
Here, check out mine. It's a
Pink Princess strap!

なかなか手に入らないんですよ！
いいでしょ。
These are hard to come by, you
know.

<Phoenix>
（やれやれ。あいかわらず、
　はやってるみたいだな‥‥）
(I see he's as popular as ever
with the kids...)




<Phoenix>
ちなみに、ぼくの携帯電話には
ストラップがついていない。
Come to think of it, I don't
have a strap on my mobile
phone at all.

‥‥よけいなものをつけるのが
メンドくさいんだよな。
I hate having useless things
dangling off it.







<Phoenix>
（‥‥もう、
　押す必要はないだろう）
(There's no need to push this
again.)

<Ema>
どうしたんですか？
ムズカシイ顔、して。
What's wrong? You look like I
do during finals!

<Phoenix>
‥‥いや。
なんでもないよ。
Never mind. It's nothing.




<Phoenix>
リダイヤルボタン。最後に
通話したナンバーを呼び出す。
The redial button. It dials
the number of the last person
called.

‥‥あかねちゃんだ。
いったい、何を話したのか‥‥？
The last call was to Ema.
I wonder what they spoke
about...?




<Ema>
‥‥あれ。なんか、文字を
消したアトがありますよ。
Hey, look here! It looks like
something's been erased.

<Phoenix>
へえ。イトノコ刑事あての
手紙かなんか、だったのかな。
Maybe it was a letter or
something to Detective
Gumshoe.

<Ema>
ええと‥‥
《賞与：２４００円在中》
Let's see...
"Annual bonus: $20."

あの。コレ‥‥
ゼロが何個か足りませんよね。
Um...
I think a couple zeros are
missing.

<Phoenix>
こんなモンじゃないのかな。
（あの刑事さんの場合‥‥）
No, that sounds about right.
(At least in that detective's
case...)

<Ema>
‥‥オトナになるのが
イヤになってきました。
...
Maybe I should rethink my
career as an investigator.







<Ema>
この、血‥‥
お姉ちゃんのもの、なんですね。
This blood...
It's my sister's, right?

<Phoenix>
そうみたいだね。
It appears so.

（留置所で見た、ともえさんの
　右手の包帯‥‥）
(Lana's right hand was
bandaged when I saw her in
jail.)

（あのとき、キズを
　負ったんだろうな‥‥）
(She must have cut herself at
the time of the crime...)

<Ema>
お姉ちゃん‥‥
Poor Sis...




<Phoenix>
白いエナメル地に、
細かく血が飛んでいる。
Blood is splattered over the
white enamel surface.

‥‥ともえさんのものだ。
右手の包帯が、そうなんだろう。
It must be Lana's blood, from
the cut on her right hand she
now has bandaged.







<Ema>
きゃあっ！こんなトコロにも、
ぺったり血がついてますッ！
AAAH! There's blood here too!

<Phoenix>
クツの底、か‥‥
被害者自身の血、だろうね。
On the sole of the shoe?
It's got to be the victim's.

どうやら‥‥血だまりの中を
歩いたみたい、だね。
He must have stepped in a
puddle of his own blood.

<Ema>
ううう‥‥ナマナマしいんですね。
サツジン事件って。
All this blood...
It's horrible!

<Phoenix>
（足のウラに、血のアトが
　あるということは‥‥）
(Hmm...)

（当然、血だまりの上を
　歩いたことになる、よな‥‥）
(This blood might be an
important clue...)




<Phoenix>
こちらの血痕は、被害者自身‥‥
多田敷　道夫のものだ。
These blood traces are from
Bruce Goodman, the victim.

刺されたあと、逃げようと
したのだろうか。
He must have tried to run
after he was stabbed.




<Ema>
これ‥‥
血のアト、ですよね？
This is a bloodstain, isn't
it?

<Phoenix>
飛び出しナイフから
付着したんだろうね。
Yeah. It was probably left
behind from the switchblade.

このマフラー‥‥まちがいなく、
ともえさんのモノ、なの？
Are you absolutely sure this
is your sister's muffler?

<Ema>
は、はい‥‥
Yes...

<Phoenix>
（やはり‥‥このナイフを
　かくしたのは、彼女のようだ）
(So she really did hide the
knife.)

（いったい、なぜ‥‥？）
(But why...?)




<Ema>
きゃあああ！　びび、
ビックリさせないでくださいっ！
EEEEEEE!!!
Don't scare me like that!

<Phoenix>
ビックリしたの、こっちだよ！
Scare YOU?
I'm the one who was scared!

<Ema>
‥‥この、ナイフの刃‥‥
先が欠けてますね。
Hey...
The tip of this knife is
missing!

<Phoenix>
（それに、この赤黒いシミ。
“血”かな、やっぱり‥‥）
(There's also a dark red stain
here. It looks like blood...)

<Ema>
とにかく‥‥このナイフは
カガク的に、重要な証拠品です！

<Phoenix>
（たしかに‥‥他にも手がかりが
　あるかもしれない）

<Phoenix>
（このナイフ‥‥もっと
　よく調べたほうがいいな！）







<Ema>
ナイフに、小さなタグが
ついてますね。
There's a small tag on the
knife.

<Phoenix>
《ＳＬ－９》‥‥
そう書かれているみたいだ。
It says,
"SL-9 2."

<Ema>
どういうイミかなあ‥‥
What's that supposed to mean?

<Phoenix>
（似たヒビキのコトバなら
　聞いたことがあるんだけど‥‥）
I'm not sure...
(But it reminds me of a
similar code...)

（ＤＬ６号‥‥“事件”）
("DL-6." Maybe it's a case
number?)

<Ema>
でも‥‥なんだか。
That's weird.

<Phoenix>
？　どうしたの？
What?

<Ema>
なんか‥‥どこかで見たような
気がするんですよねー。
I don't remember where,

<Ema>
but I think I've seen
something like this before.

<Ema>
この、タグの文字と‥‥
“よく似た”文字を‥‥最近。
Something similar to what's
written on this tag. It wasn't
that long ago either...

<Phoenix>
（法廷記録‥‥もう一度、
　カクニンしてみたほうがいいな）
(Maybe I should check the
Court Record again.)




<Phoenix>
小さなタグには、
《ＳＬ－９》と書かれている。
"SL-9" is written on a small
tag attached to the knife.

２年前の、あの事件の凶器で、
多くの被害者の血を吸ったナイフ。
It was the weapon used in that
incident two years ago; and
has known many victims.







<Phoenix>
（油性ペンで名前が書いてある）
(Someone used a marker to
write their name on this.)

《１－３
　ほうづき　あかね》
"Ema Skye"

もしかして‥‥学校にも
持っていってるの？　これ。
Don't tell me you bring this
with you everywhere you go.

<Ema>
そりゃもう。いつ、何が
起こるか、わかりませんからね！
Well, you never know where
something might go down!

<Phoenix>
（いつ、何が起こると
　思ってるんだろう‥‥）
(Just what kind of a world
do you think we live in...?)




<Phoenix>
油性ペンで名前が書いてある。
《１－３》‥‥か。
Ema Skye is written on the
side in permanent marker.

この《１》が《小学１年》だったら
イヤだなあ‥‥
She seems awfully possessive
about a can of luminol.







<Phoenix>
《ＡＩ１６号》‥‥
そう書かれているみたいだ。
The tag says, "AI-16."

<Ema>
それで‥‥なんなんですか、
このドライバー。
What's that got to do with
anything?

<Phoenix>
それは、その。
関係ないんじゃないかな。
Nothing, apparently.

<Phoenix>
御剣も、そう言ってたし。
At least, that's what
Edgeworth said.

<Ema>
でも、“関係ない”って言われる
ほど、気になりますよねー。
Hm. That makes it seem all the
more suspicious.

きっと、トンでもなく重要な
イミがあるんですよ。コレ。
Who knows? This might turn out
to be the clue that breaks the
case!

<Phoenix>
これ以上、ヘンな事件を
かかえこみたくないなあ‥‥
Wouldn't that be nice...




<Phoenix>
《ＡＩ１６号》‥‥
そう書かれているみたいだ。
"AI-16" is written on the tag.

今回の事件とは、関係ない
証拠品ということだ。
That means it has nothing to
do with the current case.







<Ema>
この部分‥‥かすかに、
赤黒いシミがありますけど。
Hey, look here! It's hard to
make out, but there's a dark
red stain here.

<Phoenix>
やっぱり‥‥
“血”みたいだね。
Hmm... 
Looks like blood.

<Ema>
多田敷さんが刺されたときに
ついたんでしょうか？
Do you think Detective
Goodman's blood somehow got 
on it when he was stabbed?

<Phoenix>
どうも‥‥
そうじゃないみたいだね。
Not likely.

ずいぶん、古いものに見えるよ。
ほとんど、消えかかってるし。
This blood looks like it's
been here for months, maybe
longer.

（このツボは、《ＳＬ９号事件》と
　いう事件の証拠品だった‥‥）
(This jar was evidence in the
SL-9 Incident...)

（血は、そのときに
　ついたのかもしれないな）
(That might be when the blood
got on it.)




<Phoenix>
赤黒い“血痕”‥‥
ずいぶん、古いものみたいだ。
There's a trace of old blood
on this jar.

このツボは、《ＳＬ９号事件》と
いう事件の証拠品だった‥‥
This was evidence in the 
SL-9 Incident...

血は、そのときに
ついたのかもしれないな。
The blood must be from
back then.







<Ema>
あ、あれ！
ここ、底がありませんよ！
Huh? This thing doesn't have a
bottom!

<Phoenix>
ホントだ。これじゃあ‥‥
That's weird.

<Ema>
どっちが下か、わかりませんね。
I wonder which side is "up"?

<Phoenix>
いやいや。それより、
そもそも底がなかったら‥‥
Better yet...

コレ、何に使うんだろう？
What's the purpose of a
bottomless jar?

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

うーん。
底の知れないツボですねえ‥‥
At least it doesn't collect
dust inside, right?




<Phoenix>
ポッカリ穴が空いている。
底なしのツボだ。
The jar has no bottom, so the
hole goes right through.

‥‥ホントにツボなのかな。
あるいは、天体望遠鏡、とか‥‥
I wonder if it's really a jar,
or some kind of weird
telescope...?







<Ema>
この部分‥‥かすかに、
赤黒いシミがありますけど。
Hey, look here! It's hard to
make out, but there's a dark
red stain here.

<Phoenix>
やっぱり‥‥
“血”みたいだね。
Hmm...
Looks like blood.

<Ema>
でも。なんかヘンですね。
この、巌徒局長のカケラ‥‥
This piece the Chief has is
different, though.

他の血は、みんな
消えかけた“点”なのに‥‥
The blood stains on the other
pieces are just spots,

この１枚だけ、“線”に
なってますよ！
but this one's a line!

<Phoenix>
（どういうことだろう‥‥）
(That is odd...)




<Phoenix>
この赤黒いシミは‥‥
２年前の血痕だろう。
The dark red stains must be
blood traces from the incident
two years ago.

巌徒局長の部屋から見つかった
カケラだけ、“線”が残っている。
Only the fragment found in
Chief Gant's office still has
lines remaining on it.







<Ema>
ビデオテープにラベルが
貼ってありますね。
This tape has a label on it.

<Phoenix>
どれどれ。記録した時間なんかが
書かれているんじゃないかな。
Let me see. Maybe it lists
the time it was recorded.

<Ema>
《永久保存版！
　湯ケムリ紀行・旅まみれ》
"Hackoholics Anonymous:
Twelve Steps to Recovery"

<Phoenix>
‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

<Ema>
新しいテープが
なかったんですね、きっと。
They must have recorded over
an old tape.

<Phoenix>
そ。それにしても、
警察が提出した証拠だぞ！
Yeah, but this evidence is
from the police department!

<Ema>
《永久保存版》がつく番組って、
ロクなモノがないですからねー。
Why would they have a tape
like that anyway?

<Phoenix>
‥‥なんか、急に
旅に出たくなってきたよ。
Let's just hope they got it
off a criminal.




<Phoenix>
《永久保存版！
　湯ケムリ紀行・旅まみれ》
"Hackoholics Anonymous:
Twelve Steps to Recovery"

この事件が解決したら、
温泉でも行ってみようか。
I wonder what the 12 steps
are...?







<Phoenix>
タグには《ＳＬ９号－１１番》と
書かれているね。
The tag says, "SL-9 11."

これも、例の事件の
証拠品らしいなあ。
I guess this is another piece
of evidence from that case.

<Ema>
あたし、ムカシからキライ
なんですよ。“タグ”ってコトバ。
You know, I never did care for
the word, "tag."
It's confusing.

<Phoenix>
へえ‥‥。なんで？
Huh? What's so confusing about
that?

<Ema>
だって。見た目が
まぎらわしいじゃないですか。
Do you know how many other
words sound like it? "Bag,"
"Gag," "Nag," "Lag," "Xag"...

<Phoenix>
まぎらわしい‥‥？
"Xag"...? Is that a word?

<Ema>
“タグ”か“クダ”か“ゲタ”か
“タダ”か、はたまた“多い”か。
Do you challenge me...?

<Phoenix>
“多い”はないよ、あかねちゃん。
What, are we playing a word
game now?




<Phoenix>
タグには《ＳＬ９号－１１番》と
書かれている。
"SL-9 11" is written on the
tag.

これも、例の事件の
証拠品らしいな。
It seems this is more evidence
from that incident.







<Phoenix>
《ミツルギ　レイジ
　１７：１２》‥‥
"Miles Edgeworth - 17:12"...

日付は、事件当日だ。
This is dated the day of the
crime.

<Ema>
入庫してから、３分後に
事件が起きたわけですね。
The murder took place three
minutes after Edgeworth parked
his car.

どこかで２、３回、
信号に引っかかっていたら‥‥
If only he was held up at a
couple extra red lights...

事件に巻きこまれなくて
すんだかもしれないのに。
he wouldn't have been caught
up in this whole affair.

<Phoenix>
そういう考えかたもあるね。
Perhaps...

<Ema>
成歩堂さんも、信号は
キチンと守りましょうね！
It just goes to show you
never know what'll happen when
you run a yellow light!




<Phoenix>
《ミツルギ　レイジ
　１７：１２》‥‥
"Miles Edgeworth - 17:12"...

日付は、事件当日だ。
It's dated the day of the
murder.







<Ema>
これ‥‥手のアト、ですよね。
This is a handprint, right?

<Phoenix>
カワの布地に、アブラのシミ
みたいに付着している。
Yeah. Someone left behind an
oil stain on the fabric.

アブラっぽい手をした
ヒトだったのかな。
Whoever it was, they must have
had a really oily hand.

<Ema>
成歩堂さん。カガク的に
考えてみましょう！
Mr. Wright, think about it
scientifically!

<Phoenix>
ど。どういうコト？
Huh?

<Ema>
つまり。こういうコトです。
A more likely explanation
is...

ツルツルにワックスをかけた
ばかりのろうかで、転んで‥‥
the person slipped and fell on
a freshly waxed floor,

手が、ワックスで
べたべたになった、とか。
getting wax all over their
hand.

<Phoenix>
なるほど‥‥
意外に、イイ線かもしれないね。
Well, that would account for
this amount of oil I guess.

（どこが“カガク的”か
　わからないけど）
(I don't see what's so
"scientific" about it
though.)

<Ema>
あたしの学校、こないだ
ワックスをかけたばっかりだし。
It happens, you know. I always
slip on the floors at school
after they're waxed.




<Phoenix>
カワの布地に、ハッキリ
手のアトが残っている。
A clear handprint can be seen
on the leather cloth.

指紋のヌシは、あかねちゃんだ。
‥‥彼女にはヒミツにしておこう。
The print belongs to Ema...
I think I'll keep this
information to myself.




<Ema>
《周知の事情により、辞職を決意
　した。よろしくおねがいしたい》
"Due to recent events I hereby
announce my resignation as
public prosecutor."

<Phoenix>
（ほ。本当に、辞表だぞ‥‥）
(He really wrote a resignation
letter...)

<Ema>
さすが、御剣検事さん。
ちょっぴり、エラそうですね。
Wow! Even when resigning,
Mr. Edgeworth is cool and
concise!

でも‥‥御剣検事さんは、
ワルくないのに‥‥
Still, it wasn't his fault...

<Phoenix>
ダレかに、セキニンをとらせる。
それが、オトナの世界なんだよ。
Someone has to be held
responsible. That's how it is
in the grown-up world.

<Ema>
えー！　でも、辞めちゃったら
“セキニン”も何もないですよ？
Yeah, but that responsibility
means nothing if he just
quits!

<Phoenix>
ま。まあ、たしかに‥‥
Well, not everyone sees it
that way.

<Ema>
セキニンを取るのなら‥‥
タダで５年はたらく、とか！
To truly take responsibility
you should have to work the
rest of your life for no pay.

<Phoenix>
（オトナの世界はキビシイな‥‥）
(Sometimes the "grown-up"
world can be tough...)







<Ema>
刑事さん‥‥あんまり、
よくないですね。写真うつり。
Detective Gumshoe isn't very
photogenic, is he?

<Phoenix>
そんなコト言っちゃ
ワルいと思うよ。本人に。
Whatever you do, just don't
say that to his face.

<Ema>
だって、ホラ。
目が半分、閉じちゃってますよ！
Look, his eyes are half shut!

<Phoenix>
そのかわり、クチが半分
開いちゃってるね。
Yeah...
and his mouth is half open.

<Ema>
うわ。シャツのボタン、
１個ずつズレてますよ！
Hey! Each of his shirt buttons
is off a notch!

<Phoenix>
このネクタイ、細いほうが
前に来てるぞ。
And he's got the narrow end of
his tie in front.

‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

“写真うつり”とは
ちょっとちがうみたいだね。
I think this goes beyond being
a "photogenic" issue.




<Phoenix>
キンチョーのあまり、
エガオがひきつっている。
He's wearing a really nervous
smile in this picture.

めずらしく、ヒゲがつるつるに
そり上げられている。
At least for once he's got a
clean-shaven face.




<Ema>
うわ、おいしそう！
Wow, my mouth is watering!

今にも、ニクの焼ける音が
ジューッ、て聞こえそうです！
I can almost hear the sound of
steak frying on the grill!

<Phoenix>
ジッサイは、冷えて
コチコチだけどね。
No doubt it's all cold and
tough by now.

<Ema>
きっと、大丈夫です！
No, I'm sure it's delicious!

おキョウさんが、まごころで
ヤキを入れてますから。
Ms. Starr poured her heart
into making this!

<Phoenix>
‥‥その表現、なんかコワいよ。
So long as she didn't put any
other organs in there...




<Phoenix>
えーと。原材料は‥‥と。
『にく』だって。
Let's see...
"Ingredients: Meat"

<Ema>
も。モチロン、牛肉ですよね。
ハッキリ書いてありませんけど。
She must mean "beef." She
probably just wrote it
generically.

<Phoenix>
そ。そりゃそうだよ！
ハッキリ書いてないけどね。
Uh... yeah. Let's hope so.

<Ema>
カガク者としては、やはり。
食品添加物をチェックしないと。
Of course, as a scientist I
have to check what additives
she used.

<Phoenix>
マニアックだなあ。
Go to town.

<Ema>
『まごころ』
‥‥だそうです。
Huh? It says here...
"Hours of sweat and labor."

<Phoenix>
うーん‥‥
自分で書くかあ。
So that's why the sauce is so
salty...







<Phoenix>
な、なんだ‥‥？
（リストのウラに、ラクガキが！）
I wonder what this is?
(It looks like someone drew
some kind of sketch here!)

<Ema>
なんですか！　ナニか
ありましたか？　成歩堂さん！
What is it? Did you find
something?

<Phoenix>
（なんとも判断しにくい絵だけど
　‥‥今は、ヒミツにしておこう）
(I can't make it out. I'd
better keep quiet about it
for now.)

い、いや。なんでもないよ。
Huh? Oh. No, it's nothing.

<Ema>
成歩堂さん、目が泳いでます‥‥
Why are your eyes moving about
like that, Mr. Wright?

<Phoenix>
（この絵のコト‥‥
　覚えておいたほうがいいな！）
(I'd better not forget about
this picture!)




<Phoenix>
証拠品リストのウラに、
マジックで描かれた絵。
A picture is drawn on the back
of the evidence list in magic
marker.

‥‥なんか、とてつもなく
イヤな予感がする‥‥
I've got a very bad feeling
about this...




<Ema>
うわ。こんなところに
反応しましたよ！
Wow! We got a reaction!

<Phoenix>
キレイに血がついてるね。
サボテンのトゲのまわりに。
Hm. There's clearly blood
around the thorns here.

この部屋、ちらかってるから。
何かにつまづいて‥‥
This room's pretty messy.
Someone must have tripped over
something...

ぐさっと、ヒタイでも
突き刺さったんじゃないかな。
and planted their head right
in these thorns.

<Ema>
‥‥‥‥‥‥‥‥
...

あるイミ、サツジンより
イタい事件ですよね。
I think that might be more
painful than being murdered.




<Ema>
きゃあ！
こんなに、たくさん‥‥
Whoa!
This area must have been
covered in blood!

<Phoenix>
やっぱり、あの事件の‥‥？
Is this from that incident?

<Ema>
罪門　直斗検事さんが
殺害されたときのもの、ですよね。
It must be. When Prosecutor
Neil Marshall was murdered.

２年もたっているから、
かなり反応がウスくなっています。
Two years have passed, so the
reaction's kind of dull.

<Phoenix>
（この場所で事件が起こった、
　というワケか‥‥？）
(So a murder really did take
place here.)




<Ema>
こ。こんなところに
ぽたぽたと、血がっ！
What? It looks like some blood
has dripped down here!

<Phoenix>
この、量‥‥
鼻血、かもしれないね。
Judging by the amount, my
guess is it's from a
nosebleed.

<Ema>
はなぢ‥‥
A nosebleed, hm?

もしかしたら、御剣検事さん。
Maybe in his wrath,

デキのワルい部下の
ほっぺをビンタした、とか。
Mr. Edgeworth slapped someone
for their incompetence.

<Phoenix>
（デキのワルい部下‥‥
　思い当たる人物が１人、いるな）
(Why does Detective Gumshoe's
face come to mind...?)




<Ema>
‥‥‥！
こ。こんなところに、反応が！
...!
Why am I getting a reaction
here?

<Phoenix>
犯人がフツウに逃げたとしたら‥‥
こんなところ、さわるハズがない！
There's no reason for the
murderer to touch this spot
if he fled out the door.

（何か、重要な手がかりになる
　‥‥そう考えるべきだ！）
(This just might be something
significant!)

<Gumshoe>
あ、アンタ‥‥
すげェクスリ、持ってるッス！
Hey...

<Gumshoe>
That's some pretty amazing
stuff you got there, pal!

<Ema>
あ、これですか？
What, this?

《ルミノール試薬》って
いうんですよ！
It's called "Luminol Testing
Fluid"!

<Gumshoe>
どこでッ！　いったい、
どこで売ってるッスかッ！
Where'd you get your hands on
that!?

<Ema>
え。
Huh?

<Gumshoe>
自分も買うッス！
I'd like to get some too!

局長に５０００円借りて、
買ってくるッス！
I'll just borrow 50 bucks from
the Chief!

<Phoenix>
どこで売ってるの？　これ。
Where do you get this, Ema?

<Ema>
‥‥さあ。あたし、いつも
通信販売で買ってますから。
I always buy it by mail order.

<Phoenix>
（とりあえず、上面図に
　書きこんでおこう‥‥！）
(Well, I'd better jot this
down on the floor plans.)




<Ema>
あ‥‥、やっぱり！
これって右手のアト、ですね！
I knew it!
This is someone's right
handprint!

<Gumshoe>
なんッスとほほおおおおおおおッ！
WHAAAAAAT!!?

<Phoenix>
ど、どうしたんですか？
What's the matter, Detective?

<Gumshoe>
コレ‥‥この、保管庫。
よりによって、自分のッス！
Th-this locker...
It's mine!

<Ema>
え。刑事さんの‥‥？
It's yours?

<Gumshoe>
あ、アンタ！　自分が‥‥
自分がタイホされたときは！
Please!

<Gumshoe>
You have to help me...
When they come to take me
away...

ちゃんと証言してほしいッス！
“ニクめないヤツだった”‥‥と！
Promise you'll testify that I
wouldn't harm a fly!

<Gumshoe>
You'll do that for me, won't
you, pals!?

<Phoenix>
（‥‥これは、重要な手がかりだ！
　上面図に書きこんでおこう‥‥）
(This is an important clue!
I'll jot it down on the floor
plans...)

<Gumshoe>
ケーサツは信用できないッス！
ヨロシク証言、たのんだッスよ！
I'm counting on you guys!
Believe me, you can't trust
the police!

<Ema>
刑事さんが言わないでください！
What? But you're a detective!




<Phoenix>
かなり出血があったみたいだ。
（こんなの、初めて見るぞ‥‥）
There must have been a massive
amount of blood here. (I've
never seen so much before...)

どう思いますか？　イトノコ刑事。
ぼく、シロートですから‥‥
I'm not a professional.
What's your opinion,
Detective?

<Gumshoe>
うーム‥‥‥‥
青白い血‥‥ッスか。
Hmm...
Pale blue blood...

多田敷刑事は、もしかしたら‥‥
宇宙人、だったッスかッ！
Maybe Detective Goodman...

<Gumshoe>
was actually an alien?

<Ema>
とにかく、やっぱり‥‥事件は
この保管室で起こったんですね。
This proves that something
really happened in front of
this locker.

<Phoenix>
いちおう、上面図に
書きこんでおこうか。
I'll make a note of it on the
floor plans.

<Gumshoe>
自分のスイリは
ほったらかしッスかッ！
Hey! If you didn't want my
opinion, you shouldn't have
asked!




<Phoenix>
この、血‥‥やっぱり、
ともえさんが‥‥
This blood must be from when
Lana...

<Ema>
お‥‥お姉ちゃんは
ハンニンじゃありません！
No! My sister isn't the
murderer!

<Phoenix>
でも‥‥きみに電話を
かけてきたんだよね？
But she did call you, didn't
she?

事件が起こった時間に。
At the time of the crime?

<Ema>
うううう‥‥
...

<Phoenix>
ジッサイ、右手に
包帯を巻いていたわけだし。
And her right hand is
bandaged.

<Ema>
もう！　成歩堂さん、
どっちのミカタなんですかっ！
Hey! Just whose side are you
on!?

<Phoenix>
そ、そういう
モンダイじゃないよ‥‥
This has nothing to do with
"taking sides."

（ともえさんの手‥‥
　血でよごれていたことになる）
(So... This means that Lana's
hand had blood on it.)

（やっかいだな‥‥）
(This just keeps getting
worse...)




<Phoenix>
（‥‥他の指紋を試してみたいな）
(I think I'd like to try one
of the other fingerprints.)

<Ema>
じゃあ、ベツの“指”に
変えてみましょうか！
Okay, let's move on to a 
different finger!




<Phoenix>
うーん‥‥
いちおう、検出してみたけど。
Hmm...
I gave it my best shot.

<Ema>
これじゃ、さすがに
照合のデータになりませんね。
That kind of result won't be
any good for matching prints,
will it?

<Phoenix>
でも。この指紋、これ以上キレイに
検出するのは、ムリみたいだよ？
But it doesn't look like
we'll get a clearer result
from this print.

<Ema>
じゃあ。気分をかえて、
他のユビを調べてみましょうか！
Ok, let's try a different
finger, then!

